<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ruby on underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/ruby/</link><description>Recent content in ruby on underWater desert Blogging</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/ruby/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Recent Updates to Legal Markdown Gem</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-07-14-updates-to-legal-markdown/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-07-14-updates-to-legal-markdown/</guid><description>Had some time this weekend and have dug pretty deep into my legal_markdown gem. Mostly the changes should be transparent to users. Now that I feel that am getting a better handle on Ruby, I wanted to refactor the code quite a bit. There were a couple of motivations for this. First, I wanted to put the code more inline with common rubyisms and software construction methods. Second, I wanted to make the gem more flexible. It was fairly straightforward as previously conceived. There was only one class, no modules, and all the functionality resided in one huge file. Third, speed. Although most lmd files will be quite tiny and any modern computer can parse them and refactor them into md files within milliseconds, faster is always &amp;gt; slower.</description></item><item><title>Flat Lexie Does Javascript</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-04-25-flat-lexie-does-javascript/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-04-25-flat-lexie-does-javascript/</guid><description>This week I threw together a little site for the daughter of some friends. Lexie is my friends&amp;rsquo; daughter and she is lovely. She had to do a Flat Stanley project but she named it Flat Lexie instead. So they sent me a Flat Lexie and we basically travelled the world together &amp;ndash; flat lexie and I. We had a few adventures so I wanted to try to capture the pictures I took but also to capture the geography and background of the different places.</description></item><item><title>Migrating underWater desert Blogging to Jekyll</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-04-18-migrating-udb-to-jekyll/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-04-18-migrating-udb-to-jekyll/</guid><description>Thoughts and tips on how I migrated from Wordpress to Jekyll.</description></item></channel></rss>