<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/</link><description>Recent content on underWater desert Blogging</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 21:55:57 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A (Re-)Introduction to this Site</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2020/2020-04-09-a-re-introduction/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 21:55:57 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2020/2020-04-09-a-re-introduction/</guid><description>I have maintained a blog for a long time. I'm excited to pick it back up again! There is a lot to think about these days.</description></item><item><title>On the Sovereignty of CryptoCurrencies -- What Bitcoin can Learn from Somaliland</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-08-14-bitcoin-somaliland/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-08-14-bitcoin-somaliland/</guid><description>Anarchy isn't great. People are not immune to the system. These are things which adding a nice payment protocol and some interesting cryptographic hashes does not change.</description></item><item><title>What the Esteemed (and Very Smart) Law Professors Missed at the HLS Ethereum Talk</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-04-16-etherum-visits-harvard/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-04-16-etherum-visits-harvard/</guid><description>My reactions to Ethereum's unveiling at a bastion of American legal and technological thought.</description></item><item><title>Iterating over the Traditional - Legal Approaches to Smart Contract Development</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-04-09-notes-from-my-ethereum-talk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-04-09-notes-from-my-ethereum-talk/</guid><description>Last night I gave a talk at the Amsterdam Ethereum Meetup. Here are my prepared notes. I did not cover all these topics, but the majority of them I covered in the talk.</description></item><item><title>A Proposal for @ethereumproject Provisions, Contracts, and Packages</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-03-06-introducing-ethereum-package-manager/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-03-06-introducing-ethereum-package-manager/</guid><description>This is a proposal for a package manager which will help in the assembly, development, and deployment of virtual automatic contracts within the Ethereum ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>Linking Virtual Automatic Contracts to IRL Events</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-03-04-irl-links-with-virtual-automatic-contracts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-03-04-irl-links-with-virtual-automatic-contracts/</guid><description>How do virtual automatic contracts know that a real world event took place so that it could take a particular action? This is an interesting question that will need to be explored in some detail before virtual automatic contracts can be workable in real life. Here is my early take on three possible linkages I would recommend lawyer|coders build into smart contracts.</description></item><item><title>Automatic Virtual Contracts as Donation Support Mechanism for Humanitarian Crises</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-25-automatic-virtual-contracts-for-humanitarian-relief/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-25-automatic-virtual-contracts-for-humanitarian-relief/</guid><description>How could we leverage automatic contracts and virtual currency to speed up service delivery to populations affected by humanitarian crises in a way which will entrench local markets rather than displace them? Sounds too good to be true, perhaps it is not.</description></item><item><title>Gnome Shell Extensions -- Those Little Bundles of Joy</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-21-gnome-shell-extensions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-21-gnome-shell-extensions/</guid><description>There are two great things about Gnome Extensions. First, what you can do with them. Second, the user experience of installing them via a very slick webapp.</description></item><item><title>The Latent, Natural Synergies Between Virtual Currencies, Open Data Schemes, and International Development</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-20-the-latent-natural-synergies-between-cryptocurrencies-opendata-development/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-20-the-latent-natural-synergies-between-cryptocurrencies-opendata-development/</guid><description>I like it when disparate things work well together. Like fish farming and hydroponic vegetable growing for instance (aka aquaponics). I see some increasing levels of synergy between virtual currencies, open data schemes and international development. Here's why.</description></item><item><title>How I Use Multiple Workspaces</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-19-using-multiple-workspaces/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-19-using-multiple-workspaces/</guid><description>Multiple workspaces took me some getting used to, but now I find them indispensable. Here's how I use them.</description></item><item><title>How I Would Structure Automatic Virtual Contracts</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-17-structuring-automatic-virtual-contracts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-17-structuring-automatic-virtual-contracts/</guid><description>EAutomatic contracts have been occupying a great deal of my free mental energies for the past few weeks since I first learned that there are platforms in the works that will allow for such things to happen. My thoughts on this are quite nascent, as is the technology, but here are my early observations.</description></item><item><title>Working with PDFs in Linux</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-13-pdf-extract/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-13-pdf-extract/</guid><description>Working with PDFs in Linux is not perfect. There is no one program to rule them all as Adobe has done with Acrobat in Windows and OSX. But there are good, viable solutions which can do almost everything that Acrobat will do.</description></item><item><title>Remembering Your Packages</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-11-remember-your-packages/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-11-remember-your-packages/</guid><description>What programs (packages) do I use? This is a perennial problem. It is always easy to remember those packages you use all the time but what about those packages that you do not but you want them there when you need them. Here is a three step system for ensuring that you never forget to reinstall packages you want when you upgrade your system or reinstall you operating system.</description></item><item><title>On Virtual Currencies -- Not Just for Sex and Drugs (But Maybe for Rock 'n' Roll)</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-06-on-virtual-currencies/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-06-on-virtual-currencies/</guid><description>Virtual currencies increase our ability to work faster and smarter. Here's why I am becoming an enthusiast.</description></item><item><title>Conky -- Smooth Operations</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-05-on-conky/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-05-on-conky/</guid><description>Conky is a wonderful addition to your Linux desktop. It is a very lightweight system monitoring application which can be designed to look very different to fit your style. Here's my setup.</description></item><item><title>Why Using Shells are Great</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-04-on-shells/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-04-on-shells/</guid><description>Using a shell in a terminal is fantastic &amp;ndash; like a glassbottom boat view into what your computer is actually doing. Here are some tips and a small tutorial of how I set up my terminal and shell to get you started.</description></item><item><title>Using Dropbox as a Settings Repository</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-01-29-dropbox-as-a-settings-repository/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-01-29-dropbox-as-a-settings-repository/</guid><description>I keep all my program and operating system settings in Dropbox which allows me to easily reinstall a new system completely automated. Here's how I do it.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Sync and Backup Options -- Overview</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-01-28-cloud-sync-and-backup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-01-28-cloud-sync-and-backup/</guid><description>Backup your files. Everyone knows it. Even those who know very, very little about computers understand that you should back things up. But no one does. Let's talk quickly about the options which Linux has for backing up your files..</description></item><item><title>Why Information is Vital to Making Markets Work</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-01-28-information-makes-markets-work/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-01-28-information-makes-markets-work/</guid><description>Information is what makes markets powerful, so why do we not focus our political dialogue on that rather than engaging in reductive arguments that largely miss the point.</description></item><item><title>The Spectrum of Public to Private Service Delivery</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-01-24-spectrum-service-delivery/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-01-24-spectrum-service-delivery/</guid><description>Let's stop thinking in binary terms about the delivery of services. There is a spectrum from purely public (government driven) to purely private (corporate driven) delivery of services. When we think about this as a spectrum rather than a binary situation, my opinion is that political debates about the delivery of services gets a lot easier and we focus on providing solutions rather than zero sum arguments which no one can ever win.</description></item><item><title>Linux 4 Lawyers -- Encrypting your hard drives</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-01-23-encrypting-your-hard-drives/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-01-23-encrypting-your-hard-drives/</guid><description>On why Linux is grand &amp;ndash; this post discusses why you should encrypt your hard drives.</description></item><item><title>Git Based Negotiations - A Concept Piece</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-12-19-git-based-negotiations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-12-19-git-based-negotiations/</guid><description>One of the impetuses for developing legal_markdown was that text based documents, backed by git or another version control system could be a powerful tool for legal practice. But how that would work, in actuality, is still theoretical. This is a concept piece about how git backed negotiation could potentially work.</description></item><item><title>On Chasing Chaos: The best book about "The Life" I've read in ages.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-10-16-on-chasing-chaos/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-10-16-on-chasing-chaos/</guid><description>Chasing Chaos examines the lives that aid workers lead and the work which aid workers do in vivid clarity and with honesty, clarity, and warmth. Highly recommended book; and not only because I know Jess.</description></item><item><title>Recent Updates to Legal Markdown Gem</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-07-14-updates-to-legal-markdown/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-07-14-updates-to-legal-markdown/</guid><description>Had some time this weekend and have dug pretty deep into my legal_markdown gem. Mostly the changes should be transparent to users. Now that I feel that am getting a better handle on Ruby, I wanted to refactor the code quite a bit. There were a couple of motivations for this. First, I wanted to put the code more inline with common rubyisms and software construction methods. Second, I wanted to make the gem more flexible. It was fairly straightforward as previously conceived. There was only one class, no modules, and all the functionality resided in one huge file. Third, speed. Although most lmd files will be quite tiny and any modern computer can parse them and refactor them into md files within milliseconds, faster is always &amp;gt; slower.</description></item><item><title>Taking the E out of M&amp;E for Governance Projects</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-07-12-taking-the-e-out-of-mande/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-07-12-taking-the-e-out-of-mande/</guid><description>A thought exploration of to more properly evaluate governance projects for international development. The title may be clickbait, as the post is less about taking the E out of M&amp;amp;E and more about making the case for the E coming a reasonable amount of time after the project is completed.</description></item><item><title>Flat Lexie Does Javascript</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-04-25-flat-lexie-does-javascript/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-04-25-flat-lexie-does-javascript/</guid><description>This week I threw together a little site for the daughter of some friends. Lexie is my friends&amp;rsquo; daughter and she is lovely. She had to do a Flat Stanley project but she named it Flat Lexie instead. So they sent me a Flat Lexie and we basically travelled the world together &amp;ndash; flat lexie and I. We had a few adventures so I wanted to try to capture the pictures I took but also to capture the geography and background of the different places.</description></item><item><title>Sublime Legal Markdown Package Updated</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-04-19-sublime-legal-markdown-package-pandoc-update/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-04-19-sublime-legal-markdown-package-pandoc-update/</guid><description>Finally had a chance to update my legal markdown package for Sublime. The package is built to fill a couple of holes in the system that I use. Click through to see the details.</description></item><item><title>Migrating underWater desert Blogging to Jekyll</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-04-18-migrating-udb-to-jekyll/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-04-18-migrating-udb-to-jekyll/</guid><description>Thoughts and tips on how I migrated from Wordpress to Jekyll.</description></item><item><title>Autostarting Different Programs in Different Desktops</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-04-12-autostarting-for-different-linux-desktops/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-04-12-autostarting-for-different-linux-desktops/</guid><description>One of the most obvious appeals of Linux to me is the insane levels of customization you can achieve. I mainly use Gnome Shell as my desktop environment, but since I use Ubuntu I keep Unity on my machine. This is how I start different programs when logging into different desktops.</description></item><item><title>Do You Feel Safer Now: Reflections on the Ten Year Anniversary of Iraqi Invasion</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-03-20-do-you-feel-safer-now-reflections-on-the-ten-year-anniversary-of-iraqi-invasion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-03-20-do-you-feel-safer-now-reflections-on-the-ten-year-anniversary-of-iraqi-invasion/</guid><description>We are looking at ten years since America invaded. Here are my thoughts on that topic.</description></item><item><title>My (Current) Transactional Documents Work Flow</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-03-09-transactional-documents-workflow/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-03-09-transactional-documents-workflow/</guid><description>This is an outline of my basic workflow, as of the date of this article and mostly for posterity's sake. There isn't much to it really, but it greatly depends on if I'm writing a memo or building a contract (my, and probably every other transactional attorney's, most frequent tasks). This post will cover my basic workflow when I'm building contracts.</description></item><item><title>Pandoc for Legal Documents</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-01-24-pandoc-legal-documents/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-01-24-pandoc-legal-documents/</guid><description>Lately, I have been writing a lot in markdown. It is a freeing way to write documents because you focus more on the words than the tools around you in the wordprocessing interface. You pick your favorite environment to write &amp;ndash; for me it is Sublime Text &amp;ndash; and then you write. But, clients and courts do not read Github Flavored Markdown.</description></item><item><title>My Unreasonable Optimism and Why John Dickerson&amp;#8217;s (@jdickerson) Series Should Matter</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-10-06-my-unreasonable-optimism-and-why-john-dickersons-jdickerson-series-should-matter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-10-06-my-unreasonable-optimism-and-why-john-dickersons-jdickerson-series-should-matter/</guid><description>My Dad and I have this ongoing debate about campaigns. It has been ongoing for four years that I can remember but perhaps longer. It revolves around the forthrightness of campaigns to speak to the electorate logically, with courage, and while keeping within the bounds of logic and reasonableness. Instead of what I desperately want campaigns to do they do the opposite, spiraling into ever more irrelevant crap. Gaffes and ah ha’s are fun and interesting political theater but that is all it is. Theater. Theater is a farce. And we must stop hiring representatives to govern us based on a farcical audition system. This I have felt deeply for a long time. It colors most of my political worldview, rightly or wrongly.</description></item><item><title>On Marines and Krulak&amp;#8217;s Three Blocks</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-09-18-on-marines-and-krulaks-three-blocks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-09-18-on-marines-and-krulaks-three-blocks/</guid><description>Someone emailed me tonight asking what I thought about the attack on the consulate in Benghazi. Being that I was a Marine officer once upon a moon, this person asked whether my blood was up about them passing away and what I thought about the President putting our people in danger like that. Their words. Yes, of course my blood was up. I felt deeply for their families and for the poor souls who had to notice their families and for the entire situation.</description></item><item><title>My America Band: Wax Fang</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-04-01-my-america-band/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-04-01-my-america-band/</guid><description>When you sit with people from other countries, it is important to have some fall back, standardized way to explain where you are from. Of course we all have these icons, these posters, these fleeting images that remind ourselves of where we came from and are readily recalled by our frontal cortex when asked to explain ourselves. When we trust the person and we know that the question is meant because the other conversant(s) truly does want to understand us, then we are more easily able to open up and to tell the truth.</description></item><item><title>What&amp;#8217;s this about attacking pirates on land?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-03-26-whats-this-about-attacking-pirates-on-land/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-03-26-whats-this-about-attacking-pirates-on-land/</guid><description>On Friday, I was hearing chatter about how the EU issued a new directive authorizing the EUNAVFOR to attack land targets. This is an awful idea that will have strategic and operational consequences - all of which that will be negative. In addition I have serious concerns as to the legality of the application of violence on land as a solution to the so called Piracy Problem.</description></item><item><title>Book Inscription</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-02-03-book-inscription/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-02-03-book-inscription/</guid><description>Here’s to the embarkation on a great journey. Here’s to a massive flop or a spectacular success. Here’s to nothing in between. Here’s to risk. Here’s to reward. Here’s to taking a chance. Here’s to never being satisfied with what is. Here’s to questioning. Here’s to listening. Here’s to excellence. Here’s to professionalism. Here’s to helping everywhere we can in every way we can to everyone we can. Here’s to solving problems. Here’s to trust in unwavering allies. And most of all. Here’s doing our best to impact in those we touch in some small way that truly speaking tomorrow is going to be a better day.</description></item><item><title>Micro-States; Pirates; Terrorists; The London Conference: What a Fascinating Time for Watchers of Somalis</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-01-30-micro-states-pirates-terrorists-the-london-conference-what-a-fascinating-time-for-watchers-of-somalis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-01-30-micro-states-pirates-terrorists-the-london-conference-what-a-fascinating-time-for-watchers-of-somalis/</guid><description>For almost four years now I’ve been a careful observer of Somali politicians. For three of those years I was paid to try to be their lawyer. To provide them expert international legal assistance tied to a deep network full of some of the finest international practitioners and thinkers in the world. But they rarely, if ever, wanted that help. So largely I invented work, I went into meetings and had a product to sell. &lt;em>I can’t buy you new computers, but I how about I help you write that legal framework that Parliament has required you to do&lt;/em>?</description></item><item><title>A Day in My Life: Somaliland Edition</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-01-29-day-in-life-somaliland/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-01-29-day-in-life-somaliland/</guid><description>The other day, my dad asked me to write a short piece about what my daily life is like in Somaliland. I usually refrain from such things, but I think it is a good opportunity to show how &lt;em>normal&lt;/em> everything is here. With a few caveats.</description></item><item><title>Compromise &amp;amp; Governing: On Reading @ryanlizza&amp;#8217;s The Obama Memos</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-01-27-compromise-and-governing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-01-27-compromise-and-governing/</guid><description>Ryan Lizza has again written a marvelous piece on Obama and his team. Just as he did with his watershed piece on the Obama campaign, he has written a long and worthwhile piece on Obama's first term to date. If you want to understand the fundamental contradictions that come with governing, and if you want to learn what you elect a President to truly do, read it - after you read my thoughts.</description></item><item><title>My Barber in Den Haag</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-01-03-my-barber-in-den-haag/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-01-03-my-barber-in-den-haag/</guid><description>We are smack in the middle of a heck of a travelling ten days. Left Chattanooga where we had Christmas for Glasgow where we had New Years via Atlanta (shuttle), London (plane), and Edinburgh (rental car). Then down to L’s farm in Southwest corner of Scotland. Then up to Edinburgh for a nap then to Den Haag via Amsterdam (plane and train). Thursday I trek down to Hargeisa via Zurich, Dubai, and Berbera.</description></item><item><title>Its 3 AM and I know where One of My Friends is</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-10-26-its-3-am-and-i-know-where-one-of-my-friends-is/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-10-26-its-3-am-and-i-know-where-one-of-my-friends-is/</guid><description>Sitting in a concrete cube, impersonal and loud with tiled floor and cinder walls that echo his fears, frustrations, and rage my friend is pacing in a provincial town in Somalia. He waits for a call that he hopes will end the worst purgatory he has ever felt. He waits for a call that will shatter his world. Will it be ne or the other, or the continuation of time stiff arming his attempts to do….something. Anything. For fuck’s sake this happens to other people, not to my people. I know these things because I know my friend. I know he will not sleep tonight, even though I told him to. I know this because I can see the green dot of presence when I incessant check facebook, just as impotently emasculated as he. For news. Of something.</description></item><item><title>The Preacher is Back. That&amp;#8217;s What I&amp;#8217;ve Been Waiting For.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-09-09-the-preacher-is-back-thats-what-ive-been-waiting-for/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-09-09-the-preacher-is-back-thats-what-ive-been-waiting-for/</guid><description>I just finished watching Obama's job speech, I haven't read or listened to any of the punditry and here's what I think. I'm happy because FINALLY the human I hoped I was voting for is emerging.</description></item><item><title>What Spotify Means for our Consumptive Tendencies</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-09-08-what-spotify-means-for-our-consumptive-tendencies/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-09-08-what-spotify-means-for-our-consumptive-tendencies/</guid><description>I have been using Spotify for only a couple of days but already it seems that it is supporting rather than detracting from the way the world is going. These days it is less about what you've bought and more about what you've created. It's a great time to be alive.</description></item><item><title>On The Somali Famine: A Thought Collage</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-07-30-somali-famine-collage/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-07-30-somali-famine-collage/</guid><description>This post is a compilation of sources, commentary and thought. It is a collage on the famine in the South of Somalia, the media storm which is surrounding it, and possible things to do.</description></item><item><title>On Colonies, the AU &amp;amp; Borders: Somaliland&amp;#8217;s Recognition Journey</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-07-24-on-colonies-and-borders/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-07-24-on-colonies-and-borders/</guid><description>One of the legal criteria for statehood is established borders. There is a serious and very well, although often, hidden question as to where Somaliland's borders are. In this post I try to parse this a bit mainly from the perspective of international law, but also from the political perspective as well.</description></item><item><title>What Does it Mean to be Independent: Somaliland&amp;#8217;s Recognition Journey</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-07-20-somalilands-recognition-journey/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-07-20-somalilands-recognition-journey/</guid><description>After having been in Somaliland, one of the world's most advanced unrecognized countries, for well over three years I have thought much about what it means to be a state, to have your independence, to maintain your sovereignty and many related issues. In this post, I try to parse the differences between Somaliland, South Sudan and the Libyan Rebels.</description></item><item><title>OK, So He&amp;#8217;s Gone. What Now?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-05-02-ok-so-hes-gone-what-now/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-05-02-ok-so-hes-gone-what-now/</guid><description>So I woke up this morning to the news. Obama Killed Osama. In my groggy state, I couldn't really piece together what was happening on my collated facebook and twitter streams until I saw something similar to the previous sentence. I think the first thing I cognized was a friend's facebook post: &amp;lsquo;Osama, so 10 years ago.&amp;rsquo;</description></item><item><title>Why I Started Watershed Legal Services: My Journey from Expat Aid Worker to Expat Entrepreneur</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-04-23-why-i-started-watershed/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-04-23-why-i-started-watershed/</guid><description>I felt the need to justify (perhaps mostly to myself) why I have started what to many are a fantastically crazy journey of starting a socially-conscious law firm in a very undeveloped country. Here's why I made that decision.</description></item><item><title>For Business or for Pleasure: Which is Aid?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-04-18-for-business-or-for-pleasure-which-is-aid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-04-18-for-business-or-for-pleasure-which-is-aid/</guid><description>Two articles were published this week on opposite sides of an interesting debate, what is the role of profit in the deployment of development services? I think that they both slightly miss the mark and here's why&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Thank You Al Jazeera For a Masterpiece</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-02-12-al-jazeera-masterpiece/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-02-12-al-jazeera-masterpiece/</guid><description>It was a roller coaster three weeks, and for most of it I was watching Al Jazeera English. It is difficult to describe what a fantastic job the network did at telling this story in details big and small such that an Egypt newbie like me could understand and the context and could see the pressure points and things to watch for. In any event, I'd like to try because it was a job phenomenally well done.</description></item><item><title>Egypt is Burning: On Arab Protests</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-01-30-egypt-burning-arab-protests/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-01-30-egypt-burning-arab-protests/</guid><description>The Arab world is only starting. This will be fascinating and its public exposure is going to be studied for generations. Or Not. Hard to tell at this point.</description></item><item><title>On Tea Partiers &amp;amp; Rule-Free Systems: Football, NASCAR &amp;amp; Regulatory Authority</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-01-26-tea-partiers-rule-free-systems-football-nascar-regulatory-authority/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-01-26-tea-partiers-rule-free-systems-football-nascar-regulatory-authority/</guid><description>I know I am generalizing, but since many that I know and love subscribe to many of these philosophies maybe I do have a small bit of perspective here. Let me take a look at the Free Market system and rules. Many have argued that rules are inherrently anti-market. That the opposite of capitalism is rule-making by regulators. Maybe that is right in some areas, but I would argue that it depends on the specific area in mind.</description></item><item><title>On Travelling: I&amp;#8217;m Fed Up Because it&amp;#8217;s all the Same.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-01-22-travelling-fed-same/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-01-22-travelling-fed-same/</guid><description>In which I sit in a bar at Amsterdam and reflect on the oddness of the current life-situation while writing in my Moleskine and almost being late for my flight to Dubai.</description></item><item><title>11 for &amp;#8217;11 (AKA Leigh and Casey make a List)</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-01-04-11-for-11/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-01-04-11-for-11/</guid><description>Instead of resolutions, this year Leigh and I developed our 11 for 11 - a list of the 11 things we want to accomplish in 2011. I thought it was a good idea so I made two more lists, one for the firm and one for myself. Because I like to overkill things.</description></item><item><title>Leaked Wikis, #Cablegate, and Little Else</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-12-02-leaked-wikis-cablegate/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-12-02-leaked-wikis-cablegate/</guid><description>There has been tons of interesting commentary and analysis surrounding cablegate. I have been interested and have read quite a few of the original cables, especially the ones about Somalia as well as much of the journalistic coverage of the story and the analysis (punditry) side of the story. The main thing I was struck upon reading the entirety of this article is that this entire deal is quite anticlimatic.</description></item><item><title>On Aid Professionals &amp;#8211; Random Thoughts on the Meme</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-11-09-on-aid-professionals/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-11-09-on-aid-professionals/</guid><description>There has been an interesting debate lately in the development sphere about professionalism v. amateurism and the pros and cons of each. There has been some great writing and thinking on this topic, but a lot of it seems to be less responsive than it should be because the meme is putting the cart before the horse since we don't have a clear consensus definition as to what &amp;lsquo;development work&amp;rsquo; means it is difficult to have a clear discussion as to what a &amp;lsquo;development professional&amp;rsquo; is.</description></item><item><title>Why I Love America, Norah Jones Edition</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-11-07-norah-jones-love-america/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-11-07-norah-jones-love-america/</guid><description>When you live abroad sometimes it is difficult to express the fact that you are, at heart, a patriot. Indeed, I think that patriotism now that we are moving into the post-states (for all intents and purposes) world has somehow turned into a dirty word. I'm not sure how that happened.</description></item><item><title>On Transparency &amp;amp; Openness in Organizational Behavior</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-27-transparency-openness-organizational-behavior/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-27-transparency-openness-organizational-behavior/</guid><description>I have been a technophile for a long time; indeed, as long as I can remember I've had a computer and used it extensively. Many of my &amp;lsquo;mentors&amp;rsquo; for creating an organization are companies which are currently operating in the technology sector rather than in the legal sector, because being open is more efficient than being closed. Openness is well and good, but there are a few tensions which any organization must navigate in this area.</description></item><item><title>On NGO Marketing</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-25-ngo-marketing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-25-ngo-marketing/</guid><description>Last week our business wanted to set up a booth at the Hargesia Trade Fair but the booths were sold out when we applied. When we visited the fair, however, what we found was mostly NGOs. So what is the point of NGOs marketing here in Hargeisa?</description></item><item><title>Perspectives on Africa -&amp;gt; Its all about the lens</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-25-perspectives-africa-lens/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-25-perspectives-africa-lens/</guid><description>The collective cultural lens which reflects some important baseline assumptions about &amp;lsquo;the state of Africa&amp;rsquo; are slowly beginning to change. The evidence is in economic publications, in NGO marketing documents, and in artistic memes. This is an important predicate for enabling the accountability mechanisms which will solidify progress to be triggered.</description></item><item><title>Decoding the Somali Mind: A Guide for Expats (Anecdotal, Not Definitive Version): Responsibility</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-18-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-responsibility/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-18-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-responsibility/</guid><description>This is a new series containing a few stories which have stood out in my time here in Somaliland and have helped me to understand a bit more a culture that in many ways is very different from my own, but in many ways is not. This series explores those differences. This entry is about relationships in Somaliland.</description></item><item><title>On Going Local: Relationships</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-16-local-relationships-unofficial-chains/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-16-local-relationships-unofficial-chains/</guid><description>On Going Local is a (short) series that I’m running which will attempt to look at my life from an objective perspective as I transition from and NGO worker into an entrepreneur here in the developing world. This post is about relationships.</description></item><item><title>I&amp;#8217;m Supposed to Write on Water, but I Don&amp;#8217;t Have Any&amp;#8230;</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-15-supposed-write-water-any/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-15-supposed-write-water-any/</guid><description>Today the Interweb Gods have deemed is World Blog about water day. Or likely more accurately, the brilliant charity:Water marketers have deemed today as world blog about water:Day. I haven't read every post I have seen come across my various Twitter wires, but the ones I've read talk about the need for us to have water. Seems pretty self-evident and so the rhetoric can turn into a polemic rather quickly. I thought about writing a love post to water, but then I realized that I'm annoyed at water.</description></item><item><title>What I Do Before Work</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-15-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-15-work/</guid><description>My morning workflow. Generally I do the following two things before I shower and get ready. With my coffee pot in hand, I usually begin with a news sweep followed by responding to shorter messages that came in while I was sleeping. The specifics are in the post.</description></item><item><title>On Going Local: Finding Your Happy Place</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-12-local-finding-happy-place/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-12-local-finding-happy-place/</guid><description>On Going Local is a new (short) series that I’ll be running which will attempt to look at my life from an objective perspective as I transition from and NGO worker into an entrepreneur here in the developing world. This post is about finding some personal space.</description></item><item><title>Decoding the Somali Mind: A Guide for Expats (Anecdotal, Not Definitive Version): Wants v. Needs</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-28-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-v/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-28-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-v/</guid><description>This is a new series containing a few stories which have stood out in my time here in Somaliland and have helped me to understand a bit more a culture that in many ways is very different from my own, but in many ways is not. This series explores those differences. This entry is about relationships in Somaliland.</description></item><item><title>Understanding the Somaliland Elections (2 of 3): The Contenders</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-26-understanding-somaliland-elections-2-3-contenders/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-26-understanding-somaliland-elections-2-3-contenders/</guid><description>Today Somaliland is holding its Presidential elections. To understand the significance of this event, one must understand the road that it has taken the Somalilanders to get to this point. This election has been delayed for over two years. This entry contains a small background on the three men on the ballot.</description></item><item><title>Understanding the Somaliland Elections (3 of 3): The Arguments</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-26-understanding-somaliland-elections-3-3-arguments/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-26-understanding-somaliland-elections-3-3-arguments/</guid><description>Today Somaliland is holding its Presidential elections. To understand the significance of this event, one must understand the road that it has taken the Somalilanders to get to this point. This election has been delayed for over two years. This entry contains a small background on the arguments that have been given by three men on the ballot.</description></item><item><title>Understanding the Somaliland Elections (1 of 3): Background</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-25-understanding-somaliland-elections-1-3-background/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-25-understanding-somaliland-elections-1-3-background/</guid><description>Today Somaliland is holding its Presidential elections. To understand the significance of this event, one must understand the road that it has taken the Somalilanders to get to this point. This election has been delayed for over two years. This entry contains a small background on that time.</description></item><item><title>Decoding the Somali Mind: A Guide for Expats (Anecdotal, Not Definitive Version): Introduction</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-21-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-21-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version/</guid><description>A new series from underWater desert Blogging which attempts to bridge some distinct cultural differences via a storytelling format. This is the introduction entry.</description></item><item><title>Happy Dad&amp;#8217;s Day!</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-20-happy-dads-day/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-20-happy-dads-day/</guid><description>I sit here in my house in Hargeisa and reflect upon the fact that I'm missing yet another holiday far away from my father and trying to justify why to myself, the only thing that makes sense is to put on some of my dad's favorite songs.</description></item><item><title>On Going Local: Water</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-17-local-water/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-17-local-water/</guid><description>On Going Local is a new (short) series that I'll be running which will attempt to look at my life from an objective perspective as I transition from and NGO worker into an entrepreneur here in the developing world. The first entry dives into the intricacies of getting water into your house.</description></item><item><title>Annotated Reading: So THAT is Why I Don&amp;#8217;t Fit In</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-04-annotated-reading-fit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-04-annotated-reading-fit/</guid><description>| This week I read a fascinating article which was written by a former high-level DFID individual named Rosalind Eyben. The title of the piece is, &amp;lsquo;Hiding Relations: The Irony of &amp;lsquo;Effective Aid.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;</description></item><item><title>What Does Gerstle Mean Pro-People Development?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-05-27-gerstle-pro-people-development/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-05-27-gerstle-pro-people-development/</guid><description>It is a difficult proposition to project what will happen in Somalia or Somaliland. The problem, as I see it, with the international approaches so far along with the local approaches, is that it is difficult to reconcile the philosophical desires of most Somalis with the history that they have faced in the modern era of authoritarian rule. But someone will come along - eventually, inshallah - that will be able to convince people of his or her vision of how to reconcile the dissonance between the historical predicates of Somalia and the cultural desires for decentralized power. When this unselfish visionary comes along the world should ilaalayaa because these people that I have grown to love will be a powerful force.</description></item><item><title>Chinese Powered Self-Sufficiency in Africa</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-05-26-chinese-powered-self-sufficiency-africa/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-05-26-chinese-powered-self-sufficiency-africa/</guid><description>Madam President Ellen Johnson-Sirleaf the current President of Liberia did a remarkable thing yesterday.  She [told ][2]the world that in ten years Liberia would be self-sufficient and able to stand on its own feet with only further investment &lt;em>and no aid&lt;/em>.</description></item><item><title>#1millionshirts is a Fantastic Fiasco</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-04-30-1millionshirts-fantastic-fiasco/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-04-30-1millionshirts-fantastic-fiasco/</guid><description>[![][2]][2]The twit-verse and blog-osphere have lit up this week (at least in the circles which I tend to troll) with the news of a new project called 1 million shirts. []: http://ldasiaclothing.blogspot.com/2009/07/its-my-birthday-ldasia-on.html The dude in the picture has somehow made a business of wearing other people’s shirts. The guerrilla marketers’ wet dream, perhaps. All I’ll say about his business model is this: this this the apogee of an economy based on circular illusions; when will we begin to realize that this is a house of cards and what we produce / create / add to the world is an important economic metric.</description></item><item><title>Bono Writes About Africa (My Eyes Begin to Roll)</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-04-18-bono-writes-africa-my-eyes-roll/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-04-18-bono-writes-africa-my-eyes-roll/</guid><description>I desperately wanted to hate [this][2] op-ed which the NYT published yesterday and Bono wrote, but at the end it was a rather good piece.  There is this narrative which is beginning to form which is the first coherent, resonant, and positive narrative on Africa that I’ve heard.</description></item><item><title>Understanding War [in Mogadishu]</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-04-17-understanding-war-in-mogadishu/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-04-17-understanding-war-in-mogadishu/</guid><description>This week the World Food Program (WFP) shoved out a press release about how piracy was raising food prices in South-Central Somalia. At first glance, most people who would read such a report will likely think, oh the poor people in Mogadishu. Of course, I share their sentiments. However, there is a deeper issue at work here. One that I'm not sure many people realize. The conclusion (because I'm a lawyer and we put these things up front) is that this rise in cost of business may have drastically good effects for the conflict in the South. Here's how I get there.</description></item><item><title>Powered by Wind and Other Things</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-03-19-powered-wind/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-03-19-powered-wind/</guid><description>Now my feet seem to be a bit under me. I've transferred my own stuff over, first to an absolutely awful hosting company which frustrated the hell out of me, but now to a new one. Problematically, I accidentally deleted the entire wordpress database in the process and so had to rebuild everything from scratch - so it basically took twice as long. In any event, now expect regular dispatches.The wind is up and I'm pretty much ready.</description></item><item><title>Franchising in Africa: An Annotated Reading</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-24-franchising-in-africa-an-annotated-reading/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-24-franchising-in-africa-an-annotated-reading/</guid><description>This week's annotated reading is from Dalberg (who I had not heard of before) and it deals with the lack of McDonalds around Africa.  Original article [here ]&lt;a href="pdf">1&lt;/a>, my thoughts below.</description></item><item><title>Development 2.0 Marries Enterprise 2.0 Marries Web 2.0</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-19-development-2-0-marries-enterprise-2-0-marries-web-2-0/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-19-development-2-0-marries-enterprise-2-0-marries-web-2-0/</guid><description>On the one hand I’m tired of the 2.0 lingo.  On the other hand I find it a useful (if geeky) shortcut for a mindset where technology is used collaboratively rather than in isolation.  The access points in the developing world are continuing to improve and this article really encapsulates well how I see the world.  As the access points continue to get cheaper, people int he developing world will be empowered to leverage technology to effectively create movements and other collective action that will be necessary to turn Africa (especially) around.</description></item><item><title>Gates goes to TED and Few Listen</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-16-gates-goes-to-ted-and-few-listen/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-16-gates-goes-to-ted-and-few-listen/</guid><description>I didn't hear about this until after the fact.  Indeed quite after the fact.  I was reading tweets about how Gates was blowing people's minds at cocktail parties leading up to his big speech about climate change at TED this year.  But then I forgot about them until reading these two articles from [Worldchanging][1].</description></item><item><title>Grow &amp;#8211; Venture Capital 2.0</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-16-grow-venture-capital-2-0/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-16-grow-venture-capital-2-0/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Everyone Funding Startups!!! [Grow VC][1]&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Trail of the Octopus</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-16-trail-of-the-octopus/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-16-trail-of-the-octopus/</guid><description>Last night we were drinking some wine.  I say this because my consumption of alcohol has decreased drastically over the past few years.  Living in a dry country helps!</description></item><item><title>Video of Real Life Minority Report</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-16-video-of-real-life-minority-report/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-16-video-of-real-life-minority-report/</guid><description>I think my hands would sweat in those gloves and probably my arms would get tired from fighting with the computers.  What do you think?  I like the ominous music though!</description></item><item><title>iLove iTunes Genius</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-12-ilove-itunes-genius/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-12-ilove-itunes-genius/</guid><description>[![Itunes_genius_logo][2]][2]In a departure from deeper content, I submit the following. iTunes Genius lives up to its title.
[]: http://www.apple.com/itunes/
I have no idea how the algorithm works, but it does just work. As usual with Apple products, the first few times I used it I was distinctly underwhelmed. But then I came back to it a few months later and I was amazed. From what I can tell, it seems to take into account both subjective and objective criteria.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-11-15/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-11-15/</guid><description>Beaker Twitter = Hilarity. HT – Frank</description></item><item><title>Two Articles on Applying Development Principles to US</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-11-two-articles-on-applying-development-principles-to-us/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-11-two-articles-on-applying-development-principles-to-us/</guid><description>I am still unsure about much of the commentary at [NYT's Triple Pundit blog][1].  Sometimes I genuinely am interested, but the majority of times it seems largely irrelevant and unworkable.  That said, I embrace what they are trying to accomplish.  I especially like two articles that were posted today which show how trends and thinking that has largely been applied to the developing world are leaking into the developed world.  This is really positive.</description></item><item><title>What it feels like to be invaded</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-09-what-it-feels-like-to-be-invaded/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-09-what-it-feels-like-to-be-invaded/</guid><description>[]: http://www.irishtimes.com/newspaper/world/2009/1204/1224260043076.html
Last December a bomb exploded in Mogadishu. Actually, it was the 4th of December. I didn’t remember the date until I looked it up just now. Pictures like the one at the left pretty much fit most people’s world view of Somalia. Yet, I live here and I have a completely different view of the situation. I left my house on the day in question about about 2 or so in the afternoon.</description></item><item><title>Teddy Goes to Big Think</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-08-teddy-goes-to-big-think/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-08-teddy-goes-to-big-think/</guid><description>Am just now getting around to watching Big Think's Editorial Top Ten of the year as I wait until 3 this morning when the SuperBowl will begin.  The premise of [Big Think ][1]is amazing to me: grab a bunch of influential people, ask them a penetrating question and then let them speak for five minutes or more.  It is interesting when you sit and listen to people without the flashing signals and bottom scroll bars and overly enthusiastic reporters that so often are too busy to understand what the hell they are talking about.  The people I respec tthe most, are those that can take a step back from what is happening and try to see the bigger picture.  This site is trying to achieve something akin to that.</description></item><item><title>FP gets it semi-correct on Somalia</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-04-fp-gets-it-semi-correct-on-somalia/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-04-fp-gets-it-semi-correct-on-somalia/</guid><description>FP usually does really good analysis, but I am concerned by a couple of blog posts they have published recently.  The first is [here][1].  While I understand that they are trying to simplify a very complex issue, this is just lazy.  Especially for a group of mostly informed readers.  While I agree with their analysis that Shabaab is running a parallel government (to some extent), it is no where near as pervasive as, for instance, Greater Liberia was.  Shabaab have not issued their own currency, do not enforce “borders” in the same manner, etc. etc.</description></item><item><title>Nice Photo Essay</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-04-nice-photo-essay/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-04-nice-photo-essay/</guid><description>[Water Vanishes on Western Farms][1]</description></item><item><title>My Own Private Pirate Expedition</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2009/2009-09-09-my-own-private-pirate-expedition/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2009/2009-09-09-my-own-private-pirate-expedition/</guid><description>I am trying to return to some modicum of consistency with respect to the exhibitionist nature of this activity.</description></item><item><title>An Homage to My Environment (aka Thanks for the Birthday Greetings)</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2009/2009-09-03-an-homage-to-my-environment-aka-thanks-for-the-birthday-greetings/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2009/2009-09-03-an-homage-to-my-environment-aka-thanks-for-the-birthday-greetings/</guid><description>For those which are curious as to a H-town, birthday this is how it broke down.</description></item><item><title>Wedding</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2009/2009-03-11-wedding/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2009/2009-03-11-wedding/</guid><description>Highlands and I got hitched.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-11-05-23/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-11-05-23/</guid><description>Thank You America.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-11-05-24/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-11-05-24/</guid><description>&amp;lsquo;Things are moving so fast in race relations a Negro could be president</description></item><item><title>GOTV</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-11-04-gotv/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-11-04-gotv/</guid><description>When I was in elementary school both of my parents worked and my younger brother and I used to ride our bikes to school.  It being Florida, I promise not to turn this into a in the snow, uphill both-ways story.  I remember looking at the signs over the years as the cycle eventually became faster and shorter.  Each November they would be there, demanding/requesting/mandating/asking for my vote for School Board or County Commissioner or Water Commissioner.  Other than being annoyed that they would often clip my legs, I wasn't bothered that they were there.  I liked that fact that adults would be milling about the school because it usually meant that we had longer recesses.</description></item><item><title>Cook for Me Donna!</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-10-08-cook-for-me-donna/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-10-08-cook-for-me-donna/</guid><description>I will bypass comment regarding last night’s debate.  It is almost painful to watch the death of the Robertson/Nixon Conservative coalition happen before our eyes.  If it hadn’t have turned so ugly at the end (like new deal liberalism died a violent death with LBJ), it would have been actually painful.</description></item><item><title>Is This the Day the World Changes?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-09-30-is-this-the-day-the-world-changes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-09-30-is-this-the-day-the-world-changes/</guid><description>Maybe that is a bit provocative.  Maybe it is ipso facto.  I don't know.  And we'll have to see.</description></item><item><title>Debate Reaction</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-09-27-debate-reaction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-09-27-debate-reaction/</guid><description>Some initial thoughts.  It is 6:30 in the morning here and I've now been up all night, so maybe this will not be as eloquent or complete as I'd like.</description></item><item><title>Wow.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-09-25-wow/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-09-25-wow/</guid><description>There is simply no other word that I can conjure.</description></item><item><title>Tonight the Following Occured&amp;#8230;</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-09-12-tonight-the-following-occured/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-09-12-tonight-the-following-occured/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>A Masai Bush Pilot attempted to convince me that rural Sudanese women were so turned on by engine noise from his craft that they would masturbate in front of him.  But only when the engines were running.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Eco-Labelling Biofuels</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-08-21-eco-labelling-biofuels/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-08-21-eco-labelling-biofuels/</guid><description>Geez, hippies love their eco-labeling.  Perhaps it comports with their world-view of non-force-ment of normatively superior products.  Perhaps it gives them something to talk about at parties, a consumer status-symbol.  Whatever the case, now there is a labeling standard for biofuels.  From [Triple Pundit][1]:</description></item><item><title>Georgia v. Russia</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-08-18-georgia-v-russia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-08-18-georgia-v-russia/</guid><description>Because I am intellectually inferior and do not have so much time, I have few unique thoughts.</description></item><item><title>DDR fascinates me</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-08-16-ddr-fascinates-me/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-08-16-ddr-fascinates-me/</guid><description>I have been fascinated by disarmament, demobilization and rehabilitation (DDR) initiatives for a long time.  I think that the psychologists who work in DDR camps and most people associated with DDR are very interesting individuals.  I have spoke with a few over the past few years and really am intrigued by the complexities they are forced to struggle with.</description></item><item><title>The Issue of Valor</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-08-16-the-issue-of-valor/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-08-16-the-issue-of-valor/</guid><description>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e200e553e9de388833-pi">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e200e553e9de388833-pi&lt;/a></description></item><item><title>Anti-Americanism</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-07-23-anti-americanism/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-07-23-anti-americanism/</guid><description>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e200e553ceba9c8834-pi">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e200e553ceba9c8834-pi&lt;/a></description></item><item><title>Building (in) a Developing Country</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-07-23-building-in-a-developing-country/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-07-23-building-in-a-developing-country/</guid><description>We had an epic rainstorm last night.  I had been waiting for one since we’ve moved into our compound as I was concerned about the drainage systems.  The soils here are the sandy clay stuff and because the clay makes the water not permeate the soils and because the sand makes the water flow easily, I was worried about what was happening whenever it rains.  We do a lot of gardening and are trying to keep our compound as green as possible here in the high desert.</description></item><item><title>Saddling up the Saharan Sun</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-07-23-saddling-up-the-saharan-sun/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-07-23-saddling-up-the-saharan-sun/</guid><description>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e200e553ceb2078834-pi">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e200e553ceb2078834-pi&lt;/a></description></item><item><title>Barack&amp;#8217;s Foreign Policy</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-07-20-baracks-foreign-policy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-07-20-baracks-foreign-policy/</guid><description>Let me begin by saying that I am jealous of this purported Wunderkind who is helping to shape Obama’s foreign policy and writing many of his speeches on the subject.  OK, that off my chest…to the analysis.</description></item><item><title>Power Grid 2.0</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-28-power-grid-2-0/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-28-power-grid-2-0/</guid><description>[Here][1] is a good article about updating the power grid in the US.</description></item><item><title>My Show is Back!</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-15-my-show-is-back/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-15-my-show-is-back/</guid><description>[][1]</description></item><item><title>Piling it On.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-13-piling-it-on/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-13-piling-it-on/</guid><description>Consider me another addition!  From [Ben Smith][1]:</description></item><item><title>Obama on the Judiciary</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-12-obama-on-the-judiciary/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-12-obama-on-the-judiciary/</guid><description>[This ][1]is very lucid.  Obama wrote it after Roberts&amp;rsquo; nomination.</description></item><item><title>Parenting, Gender Roles and My Wedding</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-12-parenting-gender-roles-and-my-wedding/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-12-parenting-gender-roles-and-my-wedding/</guid><description>As I clicked the category for this posting it occurred to me that for much of the first two years of this blog all I wrote about was categorized as &amp;lsquo;living&amp;rsquo; but that for the past three years or so that has decrescendoed to almost a non-existent situation.  Maybe I have spent much more time looking outward and not so much time looking inward, or maybe I have become a bit reticent to write about &amp;lsquo;me&amp;rsquo; as I embark on something akin to being a professional.</description></item><item><title>Best Political Team Gets Giddy</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-06-best-political-team-gets-giddy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-06-best-political-team-gets-giddy/</guid><description>[Rude Pundit][1] has one of the funniest TV pundit exchanges that I have ever (not) seen where Borger invokes the &amp;lsquo;Money Shot.&amp;rsquo;  Be Aware!  It is pretty graphic.  As is everything he does…. Video here, although the video is pretty low:</description></item><item><title>HRC Showing Some Class, still a bit late</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-05-hrc-showing-some-class-still-a-bit-late/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-05-hrc-showing-some-class-still-a-bit-late/</guid><description>I have been question what her game is for weeks now.  I have been questioning why the DNC elites don't shut her down.  I have been questioning why there isn't droves and droves of supers to him after the election in a show of party unity.  Some of this has begun.  But why now?  What has changed between yesterday and today that HRC only &lt;em>now&lt;/em> is &amp;lsquo;suspending&amp;rsquo; her campaign.  Further, suspending?  Come on.  Drop out, if something catastrophic were to happen (knocking furiously on wood) then she could still be elected at the convention.</description></item><item><title>The Real Deal</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-04-the-real-deal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-04-the-real-deal/</guid><description>[![Bmchipsomodevillagetty][2]][2]
[][2] [(Photo: Chip Somodevilla/Getty.)][2] [Andrew Sullivan][3] has some phenomenal reactions about Barack’s seeming win up today. The first is a story that choked me up told by one of Andrew’s [readers][4]:  My grandfather, 86 years old and a veteran of WWII, just
gave me a call. He was calling all of his grandchildren to let them
know what an important night this was in the history of our country.</description></item><item><title>AFRICOM and WAPO</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-03-africom-and-wapo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-03-africom-and-wapo/</guid><description>I have been fascinated to watch how AFRICOM develops.  [Washington Post][1] has a very interesting article the other day about how AFRICOM has been received on the continent.  The gist of the article contains two interrelated theorems: (1) that Bush's rhetorical fascination with terrorism has pigeon-holed his foreign policy measures that have little to do with terrorism; (2) that African leaders and American policy makers are like Somali Pirates and French Sailors passing each other quietly in the night with little understanding of the other.</description></item><item><title>So, It&amp;#8217;s True What They Say&amp;#8230;</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-05-29-so-its-true-what-they-say/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-05-29-so-its-true-what-they-say/</guid><description>about Russians.  For one they are drunks.  For another they seem to love leaving their country to hang out in the bush and do wild stuff, like fly planes drunk.</description></item><item><title>VeepStakes</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-05-29-veepstakes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-05-29-veepstakes/</guid><description>One of my favorite pundit-ers is [Marc Ambinder][1] who writes for the Atlantic.</description></item><item><title>Sick Around the World, and Random Settled Thoughts.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-05-27-sick-around-the-world-and-random-settled-thoughts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-05-27-sick-around-the-world-and-random-settled-thoughts/</guid><description>In case you missed it, I've posted the first YouTube link to the very excellent PBS Frontline special &amp;lsquo;Sick Around the World.&amp;rsquo;  A Washington Post reporter went to six industrialized nations and asked how they've been able to ensure universal healthcare at a much lower cost than the US has been able to figure out.</description></item><item><title>Arrival Terminal</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-05-18-arrival-terminal/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-05-18-arrival-terminal/</guid><description>Well, for better or worse, I</description></item><item><title>Desalination Update</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-04-29-desalination-update/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-04-29-desalination-update/</guid><description>If you’re like me, you’ve thought long and hard about desalination.  What is the problem?  Why is it taking so long for the Middle Easy countries (especially) to figure out the technology and apply the economies of scale such that desalination costs will fall for the rest of the world?  Well, [Worldwatch Institute][1] provides an update.  The summary:</description></item><item><title>McCain is All Class</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-04-23-mccain-is-all-class/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-04-23-mccain-is-all-class/</guid><description>Link: [Jonathan Martin’s Blog – Politico.com][1].</description></item><item><title>My Boy and His Toy</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-04-23-my-boy-and-his-toy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-04-23-my-boy-and-his-toy/</guid><description>Link: [John King of CNN Revels in His High-Tech Election Night Toy – New York Times][1].</description></item><item><title>My Uncle will Teach your Face Off</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-04-21-my-uncle-will-teach-your-face-off/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-04-21-my-uncle-will-teach-your-face-off/</guid><description>[][1]</description></item><item><title>The Dumbest Debate in America</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-04-17-the-dumbest-debate-in-america/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-04-17-the-dumbest-debate-in-america/</guid><description>Link: [The dumbest debate in America][1].  The Guardian has a great op-ed which I think summarizes exactly how I felt about the debate last night.  The crux of the matter boils down to this very well crafted sentence.</description></item><item><title>Revisiting the Vietnam Syndrome</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-04-11-revisiting-the-vietnam-syndrome/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-04-11-revisiting-the-vietnam-syndrome/</guid><description>I grew up not when Vietnam was happening, but rather, I grew up in the dramatic artistic, historical and cultural shadow of the Vietnam era.  That shadow colored much of what I did and what I valued, especially during the formative years of college where I was forming my world view and sharpening my military instincts.</description></item><item><title>Chinese Strike Back</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-03-27-chinese-strike-back/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-03-27-chinese-strike-back/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Obama&amp;#8217;s First Masterpiece?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-03-19-obamas-first-masterpiece/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-03-19-obamas-first-masterpiece/</guid><description>This speech is 40 minutes long and it will be the best thing that you do today.  Do not let someone else help form your opinions on this speech.  Form your own.  The embed:</description></item><item><title>Beckham went to Salone</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-29-beckham-went-to-salone/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-29-beckham-went-to-salone/</guid><description>Here is a video of it.</description></item><item><title>A Dubious Honor</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-28-a-dubious-honor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-28-a-dubious-honor/</guid><description>My old battalion has achieved [a dubious honor][1].  They are the first military unit to get deployed to Iraq for the Fifth time.  Now that is a bit misleading because of the mobility of the military there are few individuals that have likely gone five times.  But still…..</description></item><item><title>Automated Killer Robots</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-28-automated-killer-robots/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-28-automated-killer-robots/</guid><description>Link: [Automated killer robots ‘threat to humanity’: expert][1].</description></item><item><title>Way to Go Branson</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-25-way-to-go-branson/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-25-way-to-go-branson/</guid><description>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2008/02/25/142471.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2008/02/25/142471.jpg&lt;/a></description></item><item><title>Courting my Boi</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-23-courting-my-boi/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-23-courting-my-boi/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Navy Teaches Old Missiles New Tricks</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-21-navy-teaches-old-missiles-new-tricks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-21-navy-teaches-old-missiles-new-tricks/</guid><description>I’m not sure why, but this whole deal fascinates me.  The Navy re-programmed its intercept missiles (which were built to intercept anti-ship missiles launched from Russian planes in the event of full scale war against the Soviets) to take out satellites in space.  Maybe it is my love of Spies Like Us, but if it only took the Navy three weeks to perform the software calibration on these things then that means that it either wasn’t that complicated or that they had been working on it for much longer than they are releasing.  My theory is that it isn’t that complicated, because satellites should be easier to track and know where they are in 3-Ds then missiles launched.</description></item><item><title>Information for Development Professionals</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-06-information-for-development-professionals/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-06-information-for-development-professionals/</guid><description>[These][1] are the coolest interactive maps I’ve ever seen.</description></item><item><title>Voting Machines</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-06-voting-machines/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-06-voting-machines/</guid><description>Can someone explain to me why we are even hearing about voting machines…?  How flipping difficult can the code be?  Why are these things untrustworthy?  Other than the Chinese State (with its professionals) hacking into our systems, why are we unable to figure this out?  There are a few candidates, you click one of them.  A counter counts.  Maybe I just don’t understand some nuances (which is troubling considering I’m going to do election policy and process reform), but it seems to me to be a non-issue.</description></item><item><title>Why Iraq Matters, but Doesn&amp;#8217;t Matter</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-06-why-iraq-matters-but-doesnt-matter/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-06-why-iraq-matters-but-doesnt-matter/</guid><description>During the last debate, I was talking with Super-Star about Iraq.  The following is my analysis of the situation.</description></item><item><title>Wonk Out</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-06-wonk-out/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-06-wonk-out/</guid><description>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2008/02/05/benazirbhuttocfr.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2008/02/05/benazirbhuttocfr.jpg&lt;/a></description></item><item><title>Another Reason</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-05-another-reason/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-05-another-reason/</guid><description>This is why [I Support][1] [Barack.][2]  Not for the celebrities; Not because of his blatant appeals to people in my demographic; But Because of the Words.  Listen to the Words, Big_Head once told me.  [I’m listening][3].</description></item><item><title>Super Bowl</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-04-super-bowl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-04-super-bowl/</guid><description>Congratulations Giants Fans.  This was my favorite Super Bowl Advert.</description></item><item><title>Debating &amp;amp; Afghanistan</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-02-debating-afghanistan/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-02-debating-afghanistan/</guid><description>Last night I nerded out, as I am wonk to do.  Doug and I watched the entire debate in utter, wonk bliss.  The shivs were there, but both candidates kept them under the table.</description></item><item><title>New Music Friday</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-02-new-music-friday/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-02-new-music-friday/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Why</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-02-the-why/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-02-the-why/</guid><description>When I first told my mom that I was going to do Election Reform in Somalia she paused, sighed and said, &amp;lsquo;Son, do you *LIKE *going to places you may not come home from.&amp;rsquo;  I responded something to the effect that I may not be good at a lot of things, but I can be good at this, and so few others are willing to.</description></item><item><title>Yael Naim</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-01-31-yael-naim/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-01-31-yael-naim/</guid><description>So, if you like the new commercials for Air Jordan’s, I mean [Mac Air ][1]then you likely have wondered who the hell is singing that song and why does it make me so happy.  Well the answer is [Yael Naim][2] to the first question, the song is New Soul.  Apparently she is French, cause the rest of her self-titled album is in French, and there is a song titled Paris.  The answer to the second question, at least for me, is that it makes me want to go to happy things.  It begins an entire stream of day dreaming which inevitably ends somewhere happy.  Not sure what your answer will be.  Her video for the song is below.</description></item><item><title>Semper Fi, Mac.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-01-23-semper-fi-mac/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-01-23-semper-fi-mac/</guid><description>When I was a young Marine Officer, I was in the depths of a dirty used bookstore in DC when this old timer came up to me.  I was in the Military History section trying to find this one book I was supposed to read and we struck up a conversation.  Turns out he had survived Iwo Jima and other battles in the Pacific.  I will always remember the way he slapped me on the back and said with a particular gleam: &amp;lsquo;Semper Fi, Mac, Semper Fi.&amp;rsquo;  He had served his time, now I’ve served mine.  My contractual commitment ended on New Year’s.  It is odd, in a way I miss having that connection hanging over my head.</description></item><item><title>RIP, Great Man of America, RIP</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-01-22-rip-great-man-of-america-rip/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-01-22-rip-great-man-of-america-rip/</guid><description>I meant to post this yesterday but was having technical difficulties.  If you haven’t watched MLK’s speech, if you’ve just seen the clips throughout your life.  Take a moment, or twelve and watch it here.  It is a magnificent achievement, and even if you are not in a position to dedicate your life towards ensuring the equalities that Dr. King was fighting for, even if you think you have no ability to contribute to a world where &amp;lsquo;justice rolls down like water, and righteousness like a mighty stream,&amp;rsquo;  even if you think there is little you can do, just watch it as a piece of Great American Art.  And at the end when Dr. King says &amp;lsquo;Free at last, free at last, thank god almighty we are free at last,&amp;rsquo; think about some small thing that you can do to help.</description></item><item><title>Brown Gets a Few Things</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-01-21-brown-gets-a-few-things/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-01-21-brown-gets-a-few-things/</guid><description>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2008/01/21/gordonbrownblurweb.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2008/01/21/gordonbrownblurweb.jpg&lt;/a></description></item><item><title>Ten things you never knew&amp;#8230;</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-01-21-ten-things-you-never-knew/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-01-21-ten-things-you-never-knew/</guid><description>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2008/01/21/wfp082950.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2008/01/21/wfp082950.jpg&lt;/a></description></item><item><title>Jimmy Carter Speaks the Troof</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-01-15-jimmy-carter-speaks-the-troof/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-01-15-jimmy-carter-speaks-the-troof/</guid><description>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2008/01/15/jimmycarter.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2008/01/15/jimmycarter.jpg&lt;/a></description></item><item><title>Richardson is Out</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-01-12-richardson-is-out/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-01-12-richardson-is-out/</guid><description>I am sad to [see Bill Richardson drop out ][1]of [the Presidential Race][2].  He has had my support for a long time because of his int’l credentials; his moderate but competent domestic policies; and most of all his realism.</description></item><item><title>Sliding Liberia</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-01-10-sliding-liberia/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-01-10-sliding-liberia/</guid><description>So, am back from Europe and getting into the swing of things.</description></item><item><title>Why the Democrats aren&amp;#8217;t ending the war. &amp;#8211; By Fred Kaplan &amp;#8211; Slate Magazine</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-12-21-why-the-democrats-arent-ending-the-war-by-fred-kaplan-slate-magazine/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-12-21-why-the-democrats-arent-ending-the-war-by-fred-kaplan-slate-magazine/</guid><description>[This][1] is one of the most informative and balanced pieces on Iraq I’ve read in AGES.  Not sure of its accuracy, but it certainly isn’t too glowing about either party.  I think this is the level of public debate that needs to really be entered into as I detest the black and white stay or leave debate which really gets no one anywhere.  Some of the musings of politicos lately have been whether the American people are able to hear complexity out of their politicians.  Most times I scream yes, but after a trip to Waffle House I think maybe not.</description></item><item><title>Put this one in your toolkit</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-12-20-put-this-one-in-your-toolkit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-12-20-put-this-one-in-your-toolkit/</guid><description>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/12/20/captainmorgan2.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/12/20/captainmorgan2.jpg&lt;/a></description></item><item><title>Social Networking for Good</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-12-20-social-networking-for-good/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-12-20-social-networking-for-good/</guid><description>So, I’m not really sure what good can come about by &amp;lsquo;friending&amp;rsquo; on MySpace a bunch of organizations that do good work.  I guess on one level it warms the heart of the friender, knowing that they are on the in with these organizations.  I guess it can also bolster the &amp;lsquo;rolls&amp;rsquo; of the friendee, something that poli_sci has consistently told me is key to grassroots organizing as the bigger the rolls the more money they can potentially raise by leveraging that list to similar organizations that need to get a hold of similar people or from foundations who use the rolls as a proxy for the amount of good the organization will be able to accomplish (similar to a business plan for a small-business loan the grant writing proposal (apparently) can swing for or against often times based upon the size of the roll like the amount of the small-business owner’s money that is already invested in the business).</description></item><item><title>Watch This</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-12-20-watch-this/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-12-20-watch-this/</guid><description>Keep an eye on this!</description></item><item><title>Cultural Questionings</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-12-19-cultural-questionings/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-12-19-cultural-questionings/</guid><description>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/12/19/website_santa_hat5.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/12/19/website_santa_hat5.jpg&lt;/a></description></item><item><title>Posner on the HDI: (Surprisingly) A Critique</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-12-17-posner-on-the-hdi-surprisingly-a-critique/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-12-17-posner-on-the-hdi-surprisingly-a-critique/</guid><description>Link: [The Becker-Posner Blog: The UN’s Human Development Index: A Critique–Posner][1].</description></item><item><title>It&amp;#8217;s Time for Christmas Tunes</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-11-27-its-time-for-christmas-tunes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-11-27-its-time-for-christmas-tunes/</guid><description>[![Xmasto][2]][2]Have been listening to John Denver’s Christmas Album. Recorded in 1979, John Denver’s Album “A Christmas Together”
featuring the inchoate inventives of Jim Henson’s LCD flashbacks is officially
one of the trippiest albums ever recorded and produced in a recording studio. Check out track 11, it will blow your mind.
[]: http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/11/26/xmasto.jpg
Now to some Indictments, some Finals and some Outlining all with Indian Food in my belly. Ahh, the Playoffs are approaching.</description></item><item><title>Lower AIDS Rates</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-11-27-lower-aids-rates/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-11-27-lower-aids-rates/</guid><description>Good News from the AIDS front for the first time I can remember.  It seems that we’re starting to get this right.</description></item><item><title>Bioenergy growth must be carefully managed</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-11-14-bioenergy-growth-must-be-carefully-managed/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-11-14-bioenergy-growth-must-be-carefully-managed/</guid><description>Link: [Bioenergy growth must be carefully managed][1].</description></item><item><title>Extreme Development</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-11-14-extreme-development/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-11-14-extreme-development/</guid><description>The [Center for Global Development][1] has posted a [paper][2] that I think is one of the most intellectually challenging papers that I’ve read in a long time.  In case you don’t know, CGD is a think-tank in DC.  Imagine that, a</description></item><item><title>Negroponte&amp;#8217;s Laptops Are HERE!</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-11-13-negropontes-laptops-are-here/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-11-13-negropontes-laptops-are-here/</guid><description>Link: [Negroponte’s laptops: buy two, get one – PSD Blog – World Bank Group][1].</description></item><item><title>Zimbabwe</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-11-13-zimbabwe/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-11-13-zimbabwe/</guid><description>If you wondered a bit about what the hell Mugabe is doing, look [here][1].  The MDC in Zimbabwe is a political party, so there is a political agenda behind this film, but after hearing the testimonies you may be able to put that aside.  The video is below:</description></item><item><title>Admission of Evidence in International Courts</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-11-07-admission-of-evidence-in-international-courts/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-11-07-admission-of-evidence-in-international-courts/</guid><description>[]: &lt;a href="http://sudanwatch.blogspot.com/">http://sudanwatch.blogspot.com/&lt;/a></description></item><item><title>Hold on Saakashvili!</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-11-07-hold-on-saakashvili/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-11-07-hold-on-saakashvili/</guid><description>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/11/07/07georms2650.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/11/07/07georms2650.jpg&lt;/a></description></item><item><title>Bill Clinton on Giving</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-11-05-bill-clinton-on-giving/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-11-05-bill-clinton-on-giving/</guid><description>am slightly annoyed that one must now qualify which clinton one speaks of.  that aside [this podcast ][1]of a speech by Bill Clinton is a worthwhile hour spent in the car.  Clinton gave the keynote at the annual conference of the [Slate 60][2].  These are the 60 largest charitable contributors of the year.  They hold an annual conference gala to celebrate how rich they are and how much they are able to contribute to worthy causes.  outside of the tongue-in-cheek overtones of the event, i think that it is likely that a lot of good things happened.  Bill’s speech is absolutely on point.  I find it fascinating to hear ex-President’s speak when no longer constrained by the various policy choices they are forced to make based upon often competing interests.  Even though politicians rarely have the gumption to do what they think is right, solely for that reason, many do take tough stances after they leave office.  to a certain extent this is the easy road, but it may be an easy road to just go into intellectual exile.  for whatever reason, clinton hasn’t taken that road.  he is still actively engaged, and no matter what one may think of his presidency the man is flippin’ brilliant.  what he says about philanthropy, especially with regards to engagement of people of modest means is spot on.</description></item><item><title>Inserting Development into the Discussion</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-11-05-inserting-development-into-the-discussion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-11-05-inserting-development-into-the-discussion/</guid><description>[![][2]][2] []: http://www.join.cgdev.org/site/R?i=h0s5ebUBZmzJ0sZmUL_oGw.. i generally hesitate to endorse things of this nature, but to be honest have finally found a lobby that I can unequivocally endorse. [Globaldevelopmentmatters.org][2] is seeking to force candidates in the upcoming presidential race to discuss their prospective policy proclivities on aid and development. Since this is where I want to be then I want to hear what they have to say, both for subjective, selfish reasons (it will be nice to know that I’ll be able to work), but also because it is my cause.</description></item><item><title>Sierra Leone bridge house</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-25-sierra-leone-bridge-house/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-25-sierra-leone-bridge-house/</guid><description>Everytime I wonder about what courage is, now I think of Sierra Leoneans.  They are, hands down, the most courageous people I have ever met.   I broke Highland’s car on one side of this bridge:</description></item><item><title>Nobel Racist</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-18-nobel-racist/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-18-nobel-racist/</guid><description>James Watson, pride of American science?  A bloody racist is more like it.  This angers me, it confirms, yet again, to the rest of the world what god damn idiots many Americans are.</description></item><item><title>On carbon offsets</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-16-on-carbon-offsets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-16-on-carbon-offsets/</guid><description>[On carbon offsets][1].  This is a hot topic and one that is growing.  The simple solution is a carbon exchange that is modelled on a social justice model.  Basically a domestic, small-scale implementations of the Clean-Development Mechanisms embodied in the [Kyoto Protocol][2].  The theory is that the rich nations help the poor because of the intertwined nature of humanity.  The principle of technology transfer and that the rich pay is embodied in most international environmental treaties, but was interesting in the Kyoto schema in that offsets that assist the development of an emerging market or under-developed country may be applied to the quota for the developed country that pays.  It is a nice integration of standard liberalist philosophy.  I like it when there is overlap.  I am not sure what the economists may say about these mechanisms, but I certainly like them.</description></item><item><title>Sierra Leone&amp;#8217;s New Leader on NPR</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-16-sierra-leones-new-leader-on-npr/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-16-sierra-leones-new-leader-on-npr/</guid><description>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/10/16/koroma2_full1.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/10/16/koroma2_full1.jpg&lt;/a></description></item><item><title>in Halo&amp;#8217;s</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-13-in-halos/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-13-in-halos/</guid><description>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/10/13/radiohead_in_rainbows2.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/10/13/radiohead_in_rainbows2.jpg&lt;/a></description></item><item><title>Liberia: Post-Conflict Dilemma &amp;#8211; Should Health Care Be Free?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-13-liberia-post-conflict-dilemma-should-health-care-be-free/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-13-liberia-post-conflict-dilemma-should-health-care-be-free/</guid><description>[]: &lt;a href="http://www.worldpress.org/photo_essays/liberia/pg01.html">http://www.worldpress.org/photo_essays/liberia/pg01.html&lt;/a></description></item><item><title>Updated: Gambia</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-13-updated-gambia/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-13-updated-gambia/</guid><description>Gambia has [released the AI investigators][1].  Way to go Gambia.  Now they can get back to telling everyone about your exploitive sex industry and your repressive police state.  Way to go.</description></item><item><title>Death penalty</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-10-death-penalty/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-10-death-penalty/</guid><description>According to Amnesty’s site, today is [Anti-Death Penalty Day][1].  I wonder what color bracelet I’m supposed to be wearing to fit in…</description></item><item><title>&amp;#8216;Goonies 2&amp;#8242; an &amp;#8216;Absolute Certainty&amp;#8217;</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-09-goonies-2-an-absolute-certainty/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-09-goonies-2-an-absolute-certainty/</guid><description>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/10/08/goonies2certain.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/10/08/goonies2certain.jpg&lt;/a></description></item><item><title>Liberian Debt Crisis</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-09-liberian-debt-crisis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-09-liberian-debt-crisis/</guid><description>Although I think that Bono’s typical analysis of third-world debt is in many cases flat and unnuanced, it is important to look at. At least that analysis that gets reported in the press. The LiveAid concert series was the first time I began to think actively about the topics of poverty and from my current perspective is a watershed moment. I kept thinking, &amp;ldquo;yeah, but…&amp;rdquo; where the ellipses were filled with different theories of mixed carrots and sticks.</description></item><item><title>Brits Should Boycott the Gambia</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-08-brits-should-boycott-the-gambia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-08-brits-should-boycott-the-gambia/</guid><description>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/10/08/_39310613_gambia_jammeh203jpg1.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/10/08/_39310613_gambia_jammeh203jpg1.jpg&lt;/a></description></item><item><title>Competition to give green lighting to Africa</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-06-competition-to-give-green-lighting-to-africa/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-06-competition-to-give-green-lighting-to-africa/</guid><description>Link: [edie news centre – Competition to give green lighting to Africa][1].</description></item><item><title>photo-licious</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-09-20-photo-licious/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-09-20-photo-licious/</guid><description>so I finally have up the [photos ][1]from Georgia and Azerbaijan.  It took me a while as I didn’t think that I had the photos, last night in the nether regions of my bag I found the camera card on which the pictures were resting.  The pictures include, possibly, the best picture I’ve ever taken.  At least it is my favorite picture that I’ve ever taken…</description></item><item><title>Kite Runner Movie</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-09-19-kite-runner-movie/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-09-19-kite-runner-movie/</guid><description>Just found out that Mark Forster, who directed Stranger Than Fiction, Finding Neverland and Monster’s Ball is directing the film adaptation of Kite Runner.  A very reputable NGO, International Rescue Group, who focuses on refugee issues among other things, has been consulting on the film.  I’m not sure if that lends the film an inordinate amount of credibility, but I think that it certainly lends some.  Hosseini co-wrote the screenplay so it may have a good following of the novel, which I haven’t read.  It is to be released state-side the beginning of November according to IMDb.</description></item><item><title>Big Weekend for Africa</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-09-18-big-weekend-for-africa/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-09-18-big-weekend-for-africa/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Gorillas head race to extinction</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-09-13-gorillas-head-race-to-extinction/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-09-13-gorillas-head-race-to-extinction/</guid><description>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/09/12/gorilla_1.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/09/12/gorilla_1.jpg&lt;/a></description></item><item><title>updated</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-09-09-updated/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-09-09-updated/</guid><description>finally took the time to upload [the pictures][1] from the germany/prague trip I took a few weeks ago with my dad.</description></item><item><title>Salone votes (again) today</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-09-08-salone-votes-again-today/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-09-08-salone-votes-again-today/</guid><description>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/09/08/_1988075_ap_amputee300.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/09/08/_1988075_ap_amputee300.jpg&lt;/a></description></item><item><title>Chuckie Gets More Charges</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-09-07-chuckie-gets-more-charges/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-09-07-chuckie-gets-more-charges/</guid><description>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/09/07/180pxcharlestaylor.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/09/07/180pxcharlestaylor.jpg&lt;/a></description></item><item><title>howling through the days</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-09-04-howling-through-the-days/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-09-04-howling-through-the-days/</guid><description>![][1]I’m a howler monkey that is investigating the world.</description></item><item><title>ICR Photoessay</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-08-29-icr-photoessay/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-08-29-icr-photoessay/</guid><description>At the junction of heart-breaking and hope is [this][1] photo essay done by the International Rescue Committee.  They are a good NGO, I think, at least on the spectrum of NGO’s.  I knew some people who worked for them in SL.  At least view it.</description></item><item><title>Georgia Politicians Get Jail Terms</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-08-28-georgia-politicians-get-jail-terms/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-08-28-georgia-politicians-get-jail-terms/</guid><description>[This][1] cannot be good for relations between Russia and Georgia.  Highlands and I were just in Georgia a few weeks ago and it was a wonderful country with rugged mountains, wonderful people and a good government that is making many good steps (at least good as defined by Western governments, but this normative relativity varies in proportion to the square of your distance from Moscow).  I fell in love with the country.</description></item><item><title>Gogol Bordello</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-08-28-gogol-bordello/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-08-28-gogol-bordello/</guid><description>So I heard an [NPR podcast][1] that I subscribe to the other day that blew my mind.  NPR podcasts these concerts from the famous 9:30 club in DC that I’ve been to with fisher-man a time of two.  The band, Gogol Bordello describes itself as a Gypsy Rock &amp;amp; Roll Machine…!  Sa-WEET.  The lead singer is from Chernobyl.  Sa-WEET.  If you want to laugh take a look at [their picture][2] on AllMusic.  Sa-WEET!!</description></item><item><title>Iraq, economics, and common sense</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-08-28-iraq-economics-and-common-sense/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-08-28-iraq-economics-and-common-sense/</guid><description>If you ever want to read some good, understandable but highly intellectual stuff, read Professor Rodrik’s blog.  I’m happy to call myself a longtime reader, first-time blogger (about him).</description></item><item><title>return of my jedis</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-08-28-return-of-my-jedis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-08-28-return-of-my-jedis/</guid><description>am back in nashville.  i don’t hate it as much as i thought i was going to.  right now.  arrived in the states a week ago today after three straight weeks of torrid traveling that took me to grand places with two of my favorite people in the world.  that was good.  many stories which will not get published here as i am now out of time.</description></item><item><title>Sub-Saharan Population</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-08-28-sub-saharan-population/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-08-28-sub-saharan-population/</guid><description>listened to an interesting [CFR podcast][1] the other day which discussed population levels in sub-saharan africa, which are currently exploding.  the guy was interesting to listen to as he was eloquent (it must come with the territory when you are the chair of sociology at NYU) and just when I thought he was going to swing naively left he hit me with an unexpected solution.  it was nice to be surprised like that!</description></item><item><title>checking in</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-08-04-checking-in/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-08-04-checking-in/</guid><description>just saying hello.  all is well.  we’ve survived the mountains and crazy tbilisi and are now in the sleepy wine country.  tomorrow we tour the area where wine was invented.  i’ll likely be drunk.</description></item><item><title>spies like us</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-28-spies-like-us/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-28-spies-like-us/</guid><description>i used to love that flipping movie. now i cannot remember how they inserted themselves into the the soviet union. it may have been through afghanistan or one of the other stans, but for the purpose of this trip i’m going to pretend that it was through turkey and then up and over the caucasuses through geogia and azerbaijan (which i realize were part of the soviet strategic envelope (primary version, as opposed to secondary, derivative version…i’ll be there soon).</description></item><item><title>Sleepy Justice: Sierra Leone&amp;#8217;s Lack of Self-Help in Judicial Sector Reform</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-27-sleepy-justice-sierra-leones-lack-of-self-help-in-judicial-sector-reform/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-27-sleepy-justice-sierra-leones-lack-of-self-help-in-judicial-sector-reform/</guid><description>have finally finished a paper i’ve been working on for months.  it isn’t perfect, but it is done done for now.  will take a look at it again when i’ve given it some breathing room.  if you have thoughts, send them my way!</description></item><item><title>africa&amp;#8217;s past, present and future</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-26-africas-past-present-and-future/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-26-africas-past-present-and-future/</guid><description>Moeletsi Mbeki gave the [keynote speech][1] &lt;em>at the Second Conference of the European Association of Centers of African Studies&lt;/em>.</description></item><item><title>Hamdan Redux</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-26-hamdan-redux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-26-hamdan-redux/</guid><description>i’m not as huge a bush hater as many others who score similarly on political spectrum tests.  however, i continued to be amazed at the recalcitrant-ness of his administration.  throughout the short american constitutional history there have been contentious constitutional issues that have pitted the three branches of governance against each other in varying degrees of allied and opposition poses.: executive v. legislative, legislative v. judiciary, executive &amp;amp; legislative v. judiciary, etc.  however, the end to the tension usually comes (at least in the governance sector, even if it lingers in the civil &amp;amp; media sectors) when the supreme court rules on an issue.  if the court rules against one of the other branches in on a constitutional issue, its word is final.  full stop.  however when the court rules on other issues of law, adminsitrative, legislative, international then it may not be the final say.  the executive or legislative often will have a second crack even if one of their actions was nulled by a decision of the court.  that said, most times, the other branches second cracks will show much more deference to the legal reasoning which the court adopted (usually because a constitutional challenge to the second crack may be waiting in the wings and if the court has shown a leaning in a particular decision the legislative and executive would not want to get overturned on constitutional grounds as that would be the end of the story again).  but the bush executive branch seems to evince little of the traditional gentlemanliness with which this country has been governed for years.  latest in the saga of the Hamdan v. Rumsfeld decision is the executive issuing an executive order that CIA interrogation techniques, if conducted for the purpose of eliciting intelligence are per sae legal.  there are a few nuances in the order, first the techniques must not violate the McCain Ammendment against torture or dismemberment (but according to most human rights decisions this leaves a wide berth).  secondly, the techniques must not be conducted with the purpose of degrading the human.  well, shit, that just about guts the protections that the Hamdan decision offered to detainees at Guantanamo (and hopefully by extrapolation to other detention facilities, although there is no jurisprudence on point with regards to that issue — yet).</description></item><item><title>explosions in the sky</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-25-explosions-in-the-sky/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-25-explosions-in-the-sky/</guid><description/></item><item><title>flight of the concords</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-25-flight-of-the-concords/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-25-flight-of-the-concords/</guid><description>i have been sans telly now for about six months, so i’m not sure, but i think that this is a [show on HBO][1].  yeah, so googling proved that youtube is correct.  don’t know what the context/premise of the show is, but this clip that someone sent me is pretty damn hilarious. they also have a video podcast which is available on itunes as well as a bunch of videos on their HBO [page][2].  i’m sitting in a cafe listening to these with my headphones on, trying (and failing) not to look like a fool as i laugh so hard i’m crying.  wow, tv that i want to watch…exciting.</description></item><item><title>Liberia Joins Global Natural Resources Transparency Plan</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-19-liberia-joins-global-natural-resources-transparency-plan/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-19-liberia-joins-global-natural-resources-transparency-plan/</guid><description>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/07/19/ellenjohnsonsirleaf.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/07/19/ellenjohnsonsirleaf.jpg&lt;/a></description></item><item><title>next issue</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-19-next-issue/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-19-next-issue/</guid><description>i like the SNL skit where they make fun of that sunday morning news show.  and they use ‘next issue’ to punctuate debates.  i’ll think of the name of it in a minute.</description></item><item><title>eu planning peace-keeping mission to chad</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-18-eu-planning-peace-keeping-mission-to-chad/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-18-eu-planning-peace-keeping-mission-to-chad/</guid><description>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/07/18/africapol.gif">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/07/18/africapol.gif&lt;/a></description></item><item><title>photothermal cells beginning to show promise</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-18-photothermal-cells-beginning-to-show-promise/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-18-photothermal-cells-beginning-to-show-promise/</guid><description>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/07/18/17thermal600.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/07/18/17thermal600.jpg&lt;/a></description></item><item><title>wow</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-17-wow-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-17-wow-2/</guid><description>i’m not naive enough to think that the causal links for this video can be traced all the way up the leadership chain to bush. whatever happened is probably too complex to comment upon. but what i can comment upon is that i hope to god this is some sick fucking joke, and if it is not then this simple-minded moron should be taken out of the gene pool. i know this much, none of my marines treated any iraqi’s like this and if i would have caught them they would have been taken out of the gene pool.</description></item><item><title>two down, one more to go.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-16-two-down-one-more-to-go/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-16-two-down-one-more-to-go/</guid><description>[![Timetable_2][2]][2] this weekend we went to the north sea jazz festival. i’ve always wanted to go to this one as it is quite a famous show. there were three jazz festivals i always wanted to attend: new orleans, north sea and newport. all that is left is newport!
[]: http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/07/16/timetable_2.jpg
~ # ~</description></item><item><title>irrepressible.info</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-13-irrepressible-info/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-13-irrepressible-info/</guid><description>this is a fantastic idea which i actually wrote about in a paper.  amnesty and an IT company have formed an ngo titled [irrepressible.info][1] which takes content that is banned categorically and decentralized it onto other people’s blogs.  that way countries which have categorical firewalls which block user’s ability to visit certain pages (e.g. HRW, AI, etc.) are enabled to see the content.  way to go technology.  in other news i’m figuring out how to put code onto my blog…</description></item><item><title>more photos</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-13-more-photos/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-13-more-photos/</guid><description>have been able to put up most of my photos onto [picasa.][1]</description></item><item><title>the elections</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-13-the-elections/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-13-the-elections/</guid><description>during the first month i was in africa i did not want to leave.  i was trolling the internet trying to figure out a way that i could stay in west africa.  i looked for jobs in salone, liberia, guinea, ghana, wherever, just to stay there.  i didn’t care if they paid or not, i didn’t care if they were prestigious or not.  as time grew on and i became more and more embroiled in the work i was doing and more and more frustrated with west africa my desires waned.  at the beginning i think it was more a manifestation of my frustration with the states, nashville, law school, etc. than it was a desire to never leave africa again.</description></item><item><title>the dirtiest thing i&amp;#8217;ve ever said</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-11-the-dirtiest-thing-ive-ever-said/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-11-the-dirtiest-thing-ive-ever-said/</guid><description>mongo has a new poem for taylor up on the [indiefeed PP][1] podcast, you, too, can listen with wide-eyed-conspiratorial-wonder. it is funnier than usual, even for TM. mongo also said, and i have yet to verify on TM’s site, that mali will be: (1) releasing a new album this year, &amp;amp; (2) will be guest hosting indiefeed.</description></item><item><title>Videos</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-10-videos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-10-videos/</guid><description>now that i have bandwidth and are experiencing the lack of a firewall i can waste even more time while i’m supposed to be &amp;lsquo;working.&amp;rsquo;  [this][1] is funny SHIT.  it is 60′s bid hair dancing / jazzercising queens messing about to some serious usher songs.</description></item><item><title>stories from right here</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-03-stories-from-right-here/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-03-stories-from-right-here/</guid><description>I think that Nora Ephron thinks that she is hilarious.  I think she is a bore.  And a bitch, but that is a different story predicated on seeing her in Asssspen a few summers ago and being majorly turned off by her snooty attitude.  [Link][1].</description></item><item><title>updates</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-06-27-updates/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-06-27-updates/</guid><description>have added little stories and captions to the pictures which were priorly unannotated in the [Salone][1] photo album, the [Liberia][2] photo album and the [Upcountry][3] photo album.</description></item><item><title>Bo Videos</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-06-12-bo-videos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-06-12-bo-videos/</guid><description>These are some videos we shot while upcountry in SL.</description></item><item><title>saying hello in dutch</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-06-12-saying-hello-in-dutch/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-06-12-saying-hello-in-dutch/</guid><description>have arrived in the cloudy hague.  there are bikes and cold and mexican food and the highlands.</description></item><item><title>how to say good bye in krio</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-06-07-how-to-say-good-bye-in-krio/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-06-07-how-to-say-good-bye-in-krio/</guid><description>this afternoon i fly out of salone and have no plans to return any time in the next two years.</description></item><item><title>drama</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-06-04-drama/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-06-04-drama/</guid><description>[crazy drama][1] in the courtroom today as we went to open our case.</description></item><item><title>it&amp;#8217;s the little things</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-06-04-its-the-little-things/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-06-04-its-the-little-things/</guid><description>my friend, jay, collects coins from evil empires.  he has been wanting me to bring him coins from SL when i go to the netherlands this week.  i told him, no problem.  then i one up-ed him by bringing him coins from an even more evil empire: liberia.</description></item><item><title>Two Little Stories</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-05-29-two-little-stories/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-05-29-two-little-stories/</guid><description>Have been saving two little stories.  Not sure why I have been saving them, but I have.  My time is starting to wind down here now and I feel compelled to clean some things up.  Not yet sure when I’m going to leave Salone, but it is going to be soon.  I think that the absolute latest I will be here will be the 20th, which is only three weeks and two weekends from now.  The soonest I’ll be able to leave will be mid-week next week.  For a lot reasons I’m over this place.  People are leaving at the speed of naught, the rains are coming and we have no Tv, new people are replacing the old and I cannot be bothered to get to know them when I’m such a short timer, and at any event no matter where you are it is difficult when you are a short timer.  I just want to do the few remaining things and get the muck out of here.</description></item><item><title>too much&amp;#8230;.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-05-21-too-much/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-05-21-too-much/</guid><description>finally!  i got up country.  it was beautiful, amazing, heart-breaking, remarkable, human, surprising and wonderful.  my friends had been planning for all week to go upcountry, but seeing that it was highlands next to last weekend here and it was looking like we would be able to spend a good deal of time together that was more important to me.  i thought i could figure out a way to get upcountry later, even though the rains are coming (btw i know now what the phrase feels like…at least a little bit).  then due to some work-related B.S. it turned out that highlands was going to have to work ALL weekend.</description></item><item><title>the king &amp;amp; the texas</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-05-18-the-king-the-texas/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-05-18-the-king-the-texas/</guid><description>two notes on music.</description></item><item><title>irreconcilable?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-05-11-irreconcilable/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-05-11-irreconcilable/</guid><description>so cam and i talked for about two hours the other evening; the conversation began at 0130 my time.  i was tired the next day.</description></item><item><title>transportation</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-05-09-transportation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-05-09-transportation/</guid><description>nobody rides bikes here.  i think it is b/c the roads are crap. one of the first things that people tell me upon returning from liberia is that it &amp;lsquo;feels like america&amp;rsquo; and then they justify this comment by talking about wide roads, good transportation and a grid system.  now, i’m not an urban planner, but i can tell you that freetown may just be the worst designed city i’ve ever lived in, save for parts of D.C.</description></item><item><title>Beam It Down From the Web, Scotty</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-05-08-beam-it-down-from-the-web-scotty/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-05-08-beam-it-down-from-the-web-scotty/</guid><description>if you haven’t seen [this][1] article, you should.  it is flippin’ crazy. i want to print out a nice tulia style burrito from amigos with chips, salsa and some water with that ICE….!!! wonder if this will enable humans to be even more lazy in their shopping and when they shop….could make xmas even an exciting time.</description></item><item><title>hip hop</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-05-08-hip-hop/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-05-08-hip-hop/</guid><description>i have been thinking recently that an interesting sociological study would trace paterns (if they exist) and links between musical genres and poverty and/or conflict.  this is the story that got me thinking these thoughts…</description></item><item><title>my little jazz place</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-04-29-my-little-jazz-place/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-04-29-my-little-jazz-place/</guid><description>so for much of my life i have had this fantasy that i would eventually find a jazz club that would replace in my mind the absence of me not being alive in the late 50′s and early 60′s and being black and living in NYC and therefore unable to stoll down 52d street and hear coltrane and others jamming in real-time and only for themselves.  although i’ve been all over the states, i have yet to find anything that feels/is truly authentic.  everything just seems, kitchy or not good enough to be authentic and have great jaz artists.  i think i came close, in my mind at least, to finding the proper environs in this smoky little underground club on the left banc of paris.  but the artists that cam and i saw there were not totally up to par with my fantasy!</description></item><item><title>Isle de HOLY Crap</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-04-24-isle-de-holy-crap/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-04-24-isle-de-holy-crap/</guid><description>[![Imgp1749][2]][2] So there were two themes that I wanted to clean-up from the Senegal trip. The first is this little artist community that exists on Isle de Goree a thirty minute ferry ride from Dakaar. The second will come later.
[]: http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/04/29/imgp1749.jpg
Isle de Goree has, at various times, been a defensive position protecting the bay where the port of Dakaar is and/or a slave exporting island. Most times the slave traders would take slaves to islands off the coast of West Africa and then barter with the transportation people there on the island.</description></item><item><title>Wow.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-04-21-wow-3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-04-21-wow-3/</guid><description>Senegal = Wow.  There isn’t much else to say.</description></item><item><title>senegalese music</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-04-06-senegalese-music/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-04-06-senegalese-music/</guid><description>i leave for senegal in just a bit on Sloc, some airline that has a less stellar safety record…apparently.  although from what I’ve heard they aren’t as bad as others in west africa, so maybe i’ll be ok.  plus they play backstreet boys loud and on the speakers so everyone is able to enjoy the festivities.</description></item><item><title>still alive</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-03-28-still-alive/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-03-28-still-alive/</guid><description>sorry. not dead, just lost.  no days off, but at least the work is interesting.  we file april 4th, so i will have a life again after that. looking forward to my trip to senegal and the gambia the 6th through the 15th.  right now there is a heated euro politico debate in my office between a right wing german-swiss and a left wing french-swiss. it’s awesome!</description></item><item><title>no rest for the wicked.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-03-08-no-rest-for-the-wicked/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-03-08-no-rest-for-the-wicked/</guid><description>so i’ve worked twenty-three of the last twenty-five days. average day length: 12 hours. average number of documents per day: varies. this week have not left the office before midnight, except for meals. likely this time will creap later and later as we approach our deadline.</description></item><item><title>worrisome coding&amp;#8230;</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-03-08-worrisome-coding/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-03-08-worrisome-coding/</guid><description>i have become increasingly worried about the ubiquity of Times New Roman…as an ethos.</description></item><item><title>i little trip to the mall</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-03-06-i-little-trip-to-the-mall/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-03-06-i-little-trip-to-the-mall/</guid><description>![190207_1921][1]i hate malls. i really really hate everything about them. i hate how large they are. i hate that massive retention ponds must be created to pool the flow of water that is not allowed to seep into the ground properly over a dissipated region, but is instead pooled in isolated areas. the outsourcing of the environmental degredation annoys me. i hate how they all are the same, one or two paradigms determine the layout. i hate the food they sell. i hate that they are owned by all of us who own mutual funds and don’t really care where our money goes to except for the fact that we get something towards our retirement golf community dream.</description></item><item><title>dirty pretty things</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-03-01-dirty-pretty-things/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-03-01-dirty-pretty-things/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Killer</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-03-01-the-killer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-03-01-the-killer/</guid><description>I cannot figure out if this song is a tortured love song or a prayer or both.  Nevertheless, I’ve been listening to it all morning…It fits nicely with the cloudy, humid skys filling up for the rainy season.</description></item><item><title>leadership challenges</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-28-leadership-challenges/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-28-leadership-challenges/</guid><description>This ![160207_0812][1]post is long overdue.  But forgive me, it took a while for me to have a chance to pull the pictures off my phone.  Let me introduce you to the people that have a chance, everyday, to steal my shit and for some reason do not.</description></item><item><title>Pictures</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-28-pictures/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-28-pictures/</guid><description>Added more picts today to the album.</description></item><item><title>taut in the middle again.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-26-taut-in-the-middle-again/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-26-taut-in-the-middle-again/</guid><description>this weekend it became clear to me that i’ve been living in the middle of much tension while here, and before.  i continually try to float between the text and subtext and context of my life and so many times things get lost in translation between the two.  i sometimes confuse myself whether things are internal or external; whether they matter or don’t; whether they are real or imagined.  feelings emoted, are they proper or improper?  at the end of the day the postmodern interpretation would be that, well, all and nothing matters.  yet that doesn’t lessen the poignancy of the dilemma.  at least, i’m not sure that it does.</description></item><item><title>Witness Protection in the Third World</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-20-witness-protection-in-the-third-world/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-20-witness-protection-in-the-third-world/</guid><description>Today I would like to soapbox about something not really close to my heart but that I’ve been pondering lately.  How is protecting high-profile witnesses here different than it is in developed countries?  I mean I’ve seen Joe Dirt and therefore I know most of what there is to know about witness protection in the US.  But I don’t know anything about it here.  Let’s explore.</description></item><item><title>Beaches &amp;amp; Hospitals</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-19-beaches-hospitals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-19-beaches-hospitals/</guid><description>[ ![Imgp1261_edited1][2]][2] This series of pictures is from the beach this weekend.  For a long time I have considered the statement: it has the best beaches in the world, or at least in</description></item><item><title>Be My Anti-Valentine</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-15-be-my-anti-valentine/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-15-be-my-anti-valentine/</guid><description>Check out this site.  My office and I laughed for hours about some of the cards.</description></item><item><title>Picts</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-15-picts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-15-picts/</guid><description>Finally had the bandwidth to upload the rest of the chimp picts.</description></item><item><title>keeping life wild</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-12-keeping-life-wild/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-12-keeping-life-wild/</guid><description>[![100207_1802][2]][2]so this weekend we went to the chimpanzee reserve. when i was first told about this place i thought it was like a natural park that you could walk through and maybe you would see chimpanzees. then we were told about this one chimpanzee who was the alpha male of the lot who ‘broke out’ and killed one tourist and pulled the arms off of another (who subsequently bled to death).</description></item><item><title>o the banality of it all!</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-08-o-the-banality-of-it-all/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-08-o-the-banality-of-it-all/</guid><description>&lt;em>having problems posting these picts, wait for it…..OK.  getting there.&lt;/em></description></item><item><title>media created gaps in propaganda</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-07-media-created-gaps-in-propaganda/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-07-media-created-gaps-in-propaganda/</guid><description>[THiS is][1] a letter from the Prosecutor of the ICC.</description></item><item><title>unilateral v. multilateral humanitarian interventionism</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-07-unilateral-v-multilateral-humanitarian-interventionism/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-07-unilateral-v-multilateral-humanitarian-interventionism/</guid><description>I had a conversation I had with a Swiss woman who I work with about non-feasance as a basis for criminal prosecution.  I would like to proffer my philosophical ramblings about humanitarian interventionism, which is inextricably linked to non-feasance.  Obviously there are other links, to the duties in the genocide convention.  Maybe the best way to delimit the discussion is to speak solely about the Genocide convention.  I understand that without further legal research I may not have full comprehension of the &lt;em>legal&lt;/em> bounds of the duty.  That said, I would like to explore whether humanitarian interventionism is a duty that states should impose upon states.</description></item><item><title>i&amp;#8217;m tired&amp;#8230;now its time to work.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-06-im-tired-now-its-time-to-work/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-06-im-tired-now-its-time-to-work/</guid><description>[![030207_1246][2]][2]
[]: http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/photos/uncategorized/030207_1246.jpg
hello.
this weekend was pretty amazingly long. in a good way i guess. except for i had a lot of work that could have been done, but i never got around to it. it is mitigated by the fact that none of it was actually due this weekend, i just wanted to get started on it. that can happen later i guess.
the weekend basically began on wednesday when we hosted our own welcome aboard party and some friends came over for american game night.</description></item><item><title>The real deal?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-06-the-real-deal-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-06-the-real-deal-2/</guid><description>[The real deal?][1] is an article that addresses real or percieved gaps in the current debate on climate change.  I agree heartily that there are gaps.</description></item><item><title>the grapefruits have more seeds.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-02-the-grapefruits-have-more-seeds/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-02-the-grapefruits-have-more-seeds/</guid><description>[![N557965146_50950_9850][2]][2] on sunday afternoon/evening there was a marching band parade and people just went into this compound (the wall is the background of the picture). they paraded to a compound. this picture doesn’t do it justice b/c there were TONS of people. later we found out that it was a thanksgiving parade. each local school has their own thanksgiving holiday where they march to a church. not sure about the significance of it all, but it was funny nonetheless.</description></item><item><title>And the soapboxing begins&amp;#8230;</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-01-30-and-the-soapboxing-begins/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-01-30-and-the-soapboxing-begins/</guid><description>[![Image001][2]][2]
This is the view from my private balcony along one axis.
[![Image003][3]][3]
And from another axis.
This city so far has been exactly what I had expected. It is fulfilling the picture I had in created over the six months or so of anticipation. People who have been here longer than I tend to ask the obvious question to fill the small talk obligation. “So how do you like Freetown.</description></item><item><title>First of Some</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-01-23-first-of-some/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-01-23-first-of-some/</guid><description>Things have been a bit chaotic with getting settled and then having that paper and another project for school hanging over my head. I finished the paper yesterday and the project just now, so I feel very refreshed. Now I can focus fully on the work here and then having fun. The beaches are delightful, apparently, and I’m excited to visit them soon.</description></item><item><title>A love letter to my music collection</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-01-16-a-love-letter-to-my-music-collection/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-01-16-a-love-letter-to-my-music-collection/</guid><description>dear music collection:</description></item><item><title>from the land where day dreams realize</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-12-02-from-the-land-where-day-dreams-realize/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-12-02-from-the-land-where-day-dreams-realize/</guid><description>finally, after six weeks of punting, i had my phone conversation/interview with the developing firm i’ve been pursuing like a fat girl who hasn’t gotten laid in months chases…..well, a twinkie.</description></item><item><title>HAppy TUrkey</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-11-23-happy-turkey/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-11-23-happy-turkey/</guid><description>Happy Thanksgiving all.  I’ll be at friends drinking mass quantities of rum and beer, eating mass quantitites of meat and watching mass quantities of football.  AHHHHHH, the most masculine of all holidays.</description></item><item><title>my chinese space</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-11-11-my-chinese-space/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-11-11-my-chinese-space/</guid><description>news corp generally, i think, sucks.  however this is a good thing.  the problem is that there are korean and japanese &amp;lsquo;versions&amp;rsquo; of social networking that blow my space’s flat categories and horrible layouts away.  these asain sites are apparently [sic] with 3d anime that is user controlled where people build living spaces and avatars and interact in much more social ways.  myspace is flat, not very interactive, and very western….identifying yourself by your likes in certain predefined categories and then being able to &amp;lsquo;hook up&amp;rsquo; with those of the same preferences.  despite john cusak’s rant in high fidelity, it is a fairly arbitrary way to build and maintain relationships.  that aside it is a good thing if myspace can creap into the chinese market for many reasons.  any additional means of communication that chinese web users have is another way for the rest of the world to get access to the real attrocities that are going on there, if there are any.  and i’m sure there are.  i’m writing an entire paper that is, essentially, railing on the traditional way that law regulates things, how that is not exactly analogizeable to the internet, and how a different approach would work much better for the us companies, for human rights advocates, and for web users in internet suppressing countries.  congress has been extremely myopic in its one publicly contemplated response to the collusion with china by google, yahoo and microsoft.  i intend to show how a different approach, less rooted in traditional legality, would have much better results legally as well as policy-ly.  it will be out after christmas.  now back to writing.</description></item><item><title>to plant a tree</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-11-08-to-plant-a-tree/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-11-08-to-plant-a-tree/</guid><description>the african environmental advocate who is the only african female nobel laureate is now starting a program to plant a billion trees world wide.  advantages: soil stability, carbon sequestration, jobs, beauty.</description></item><item><title>why i do yoga</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-11-01-why-i-do-yoga/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-11-01-why-i-do-yoga/</guid><description>people do stupid shit for stupid reasons all the time.  i do yoga.</description></item><item><title>the dude abides.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-10-31-the-dude-abides/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-10-31-the-dude-abides/</guid><description>i don’t know about you….but this gives me hope.</description></item><item><title>Institutional Allocation as between International Organizations</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-10-26-institutional-allocation-as-between-international-organizations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-10-26-institutional-allocation-as-between-international-organizations/</guid><description>I created the following document in order to get some thoughts straight for a presentation I have tomorrow.  It is longer than my presentation will take, and much of it may be out of view for some of you, but I’m putting it up here b/c I think it is pretty good encapsulation of many of the things I’ve learned this semester.  It is not cited.  If you think I need to cite in a blog, go fuck yourself.</description></item><item><title>Update.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-10-25-update/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-10-25-update/</guid><description>The [New York Post][1] reports that a charity, after hearing about the horrific corporate, imperialistic exploitation of the children paid for the prosthetics.  If Warner Brothers does decide to get off their fat asses, walk across their plush carpetting on their two good (but fat) legs, pick up the phone with either of their good (but plump) hands and place a call to their fat bankers to wire a measly amount of throw-away money (likely less than they spent on condiments for the Leo trailer) to these children, that the charity will instead give the money for prosthetics to 27 other deserving children.</description></item><item><title>Philosophies</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-10-12-philosophies/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-10-12-philosophies/</guid><description>Many of you have asked me what the hell development people do.  I will attempt over the course of the next few posts….which at the rate I’m currently writing other things will be the rest of the semester….to tell you about them.</description></item><item><title>leaving&amp;#8230;on a jet plane</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-10-05-leaving-on-a-jet-plane/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-10-05-leaving-on-a-jet-plane/</guid><description>in case you had not heard or i have been negligent in letting you know, i will be heading to sierra leone next semester to work with [the special court for sierra leone][1].</description></item><item><title>best or optimal?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-08-11-best-or-optimal/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-08-11-best-or-optimal/</guid><description>I have decided to</description></item><item><title>grief</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-08-09-grief/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-08-09-grief/</guid><description>my mamo passed away on friday morning.  i didn’t even know how bad it was until i flew into nashville on thursday.  my mom called after i picked up portlanders and told us to come to the hospital, because she didn’t think that mamo would make it through the night.</description></item><item><title>Chavez in Russia for arms deals</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-07-25-chavez-in-russia-for-arms-deals/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-07-25-chavez-in-russia-for-arms-deals/</guid><description>Chavez signs a deal with Russia.  This is HUGE.  I cannot believe that the US press is not picking up on this.  Understandably there is a lot going on in the world and if you are passionately positioned on either side of the Israel-Arab tension then you would prefer to be hearing of other things and if you are positioned in the heat that is engulfing the entire west coast then you may also have other things on your mind.</description></item><item><title>Scientific Breakdown of Global Warming</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-07-25-scientific-breakdown-of-global-warming/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-07-25-scientific-breakdown-of-global-warming/</guid><description>YOU too should see an Inconvenient Truth.  I saw it for the second time this past weekend when I was home in ORL.  In case you don’t understand the science of it click here and become an informed voter.</description></item><item><title>there isn&amp;#8217;t much you can do, except realize&amp;#8230;</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-07-21-there-isnt-much-you-can-do-except-realize/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-07-21-there-isnt-much-you-can-do-except-realize/</guid><description>[that africa is fucked.][1]</description></item><item><title>this seems (mostly) right</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-07-21-this-seems-mostly-right/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-07-21-this-seems-mostly-right/</guid><description>most of you know where i want to go with my career.  this has been cemented over the course of the summer and my participation in both meaningless and meaningful litigation and policy development here in the US.  my platform: assisting developing countries in pulling themselves out of poverty without mortgaging their environments to do so.</description></item><item><title>Craziness</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-07-18-craziness/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-07-18-craziness/</guid><description>well, life has been crazy.  we’ve been working like fiends.  i saw the sun rise on four straight mornings.  three because of work, one because of partying.  it has been a weird couple of nights, for a lot of reasons.</description></item><item><title>Pirate!</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-07-10-pirate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-07-10-pirate/</guid><description>i saw pirates friday night.  it was….it was.  not disappointing.</description></item><item><title>thun-der. nananananaaaaana. thun-der</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-07-01-thun-der-nananananaaaaana-thun-der/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-07-01-thun-der-nananananaaaaana-thun-der/</guid><description>[]: &lt;a href="http://www.hellsbelles.info/">http://www.hellsbelles.info/&lt;/a></description></item><item><title>backlog</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-30-backlog/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-30-backlog/</guid><description>so i have backlogged the stories from last week while i was in the woods.  they are backdated to the approximate days and times when i constructed and/or experienced their bases.</description></item><item><title>back</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-26-back/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-26-back/</guid><description>i am back from the woods.</description></item><item><title>cultural shorthand</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-24-cultural-shorthand/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-24-cultural-shorthand/</guid><description>so cam, ern, bri and i often use the word gaper.  well that is how i spell it.  it is the verbial noun of &amp;lsquo;to gape,&amp;rsquo; and we therefore pronounce it &amp;lsquo;GAY-per.&amp;rsquo;  not &amp;lsquo;ga-per.&amp;rsquo;</description></item><item><title>lakes</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-23-lakes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-23-lakes/</guid><description>i like to skinny dip in deserted, cold lakes.</description></item><item><title>wolf v. deer</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-23-wolf-v-deer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-23-wolf-v-deer/</guid><description>i’ve been busy.  but i’ve meant to write this story for a while.  last week when i was in the woods i saw the coolest thing i’ve ever seen in the backcountry and maybe the coolest thing i’ve seen — ever!</description></item><item><title>end of the week</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-21-end-of-the-week/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-21-end-of-the-week/</guid><description>i will have something for your consumption after the weekend.  am off tomorrow for the woods.  i am writing (pen and paper) much of what i’ve worked on so far.  i think that i like what i’ve produced so far.  i’ll have it up for your consumption if you wish after the weekend.</description></item><item><title>the gentle flower</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-21-the-gentle-flower/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-21-the-gentle-flower/</guid><description>having sufficiently fucked with my rhythms enough to convince myself that it was OK to wake early, i awoke at dawn and decided to stroll.</description></item><item><title>internship journal for the last week</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-16-internship-journal-for-the-last-week/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-16-internship-journal-for-the-last-week/</guid><description>the following is my excerpt from my last journal entry, which i had to submit to my faculty advisor:</description></item><item><title>places</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-16-places/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-16-places/</guid><description>i think that how i leaves places reminds me of how i break up with women . . . tentatively, with an eye towards salvaging something from the experience in an effort to reinforce that my decision was the right one.</description></item><item><title>no thanks, i&amp;#8217;ll pass</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-12-no-thanks-ill-pass/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-12-no-thanks-ill-pass/</guid><description>this weekend i almost became a marine….again.</description></item><item><title>one more reason</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-12-one-more-reason/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-12-one-more-reason/</guid><description>i’m forgetting another salient reason:  i’d have to shave my face and head.  and i look too good in long hair to do that again.  ever.</description></item><item><title>when it rains it pours</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-09-when-it-rains-it-pours/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-09-when-it-rains-it-pours/</guid><description>for much of my childhood i didn’t understand what that phrase was on the</description></item><item><title>working on a feeling</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-07-working-on-a-feeling/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-07-working-on-a-feeling/</guid><description>[![740759036_l_1][2]][2] tonight i saw this movie. you should too. it contains a decent soundtrack and one of my favorite vehicles for a narrative framework: the roadtrip. some of the scenes in it were so spot on i didn’t know what to do. i lapsed in to an analysis of the femine/masculine perspectives on life but was torn out of it when i realized that all the women around me were laughing at the things happening just as often as i was.</description></item><item><title>clarity through resolution</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-06-clarity-through-resolution/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-06-clarity-through-resolution/</guid><description>so my grades came back today.  they were marginally better than last semester, but again the increase was marginal.  this is disappointing for two reasons.</description></item><item><title>summer lawns</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-06-summer-lawns/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-06-summer-lawns/</guid><description>so i have many reviews and things upon which to comment.  however, those will have to wait until another time.</description></item><item><title>back</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-02-back-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-02-back-2/</guid><description>lacking excuses, i’m forced to return.  deal with it, cause i’m back.</description></item><item><title>work: week 2</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-05-29-work-week-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-05-29-work-week-2/</guid><description>This</description></item><item><title>work: week 1</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-05-23-work-week-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-05-23-work-week-1/</guid><description>I</description></item><item><title>girl scouts</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-02-14-girl-scouts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-02-14-girl-scouts/</guid><description>mom,</description></item><item><title>self-marketing</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-02-11-self-marketing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-02-11-self-marketing/</guid><description>so there are these sites.  some of you know of them.  friendster. my space. facebook.com.  they are all pretty much the same thing.  they are sites that allow you to tell people about your self:  fav movies, fav music, fav TV, quotes, &amp;lsquo;about me,&amp;rsquo; and other blase things.</description></item><item><title>summer</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-02-10-summer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-02-10-summer/</guid><description>ok.  i think that i have it all figured out.  this summer i mean.  other than that i have had reaffirmed to me lately that i don’t have ANYTHING figured out.  and there are even a couple of iterations of this summer worked out.</description></item><item><title>its like an allergy</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-02-03-its-like-an-allergy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-02-03-its-like-an-allergy/</guid><description>so i think that i was born like 5 years too early.  this is different than my usual time shifting desires where i think that i was born either fifty or twenty years too late.  but any way back to my rant of the day.  i think that i was born like 5 years too early.</description></item><item><title>mock trial</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-01-21-mock-trial/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-01-21-mock-trial/</guid><description>so this weekend past we did our mock trial competition.  yale did phenomenally well.  she made it past the preliminaries and is now in the final four (she and her partner found out today).</description></item><item><title>first chances</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-01-14-first-chances/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-01-14-first-chances/</guid><description>today will be my first chance to litigate.  we’ll see how mock trial goes</description></item><item><title>in the time of snow patrols I was a monkey</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-01-13-in-the-time-of-snow-patrols-i-was-a-monkey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-01-13-in-the-time-of-snow-patrols-i-was-a-monkey/</guid><description>so returning wasn’t nearly as difficult as i thought it would be.  i just hopped in the car and left my paradices.  i might have purposefully made some subconscious hedge by going to jackson first and then leaving the west.  easing my way out of the hot tub by sitting on the side with only your feet in before you race into the house over the snow littered deck….?  not sure.</description></item><item><title>riding v. skiing</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-01-03-riding-v-skiing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-01-03-riding-v-skiing/</guid><description>ok.  so most of you know that i’m a rider.  i think that this is kind of odd, yet typical of my history.  i feel like i’m always half an oscillation off from popular culture.  this is what i mean, and really you can apply it to most areas of my hipster life be that fashion, word choices, music, hairstyles or the like.</description></item><item><title>return to paradise</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-12-31-return-to-paradise/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-12-31-return-to-paradise/</guid><description>this is harder than i really thought that it could be.  my mind is racing with what if’s.  i know that i shouldn’t.  i know what it does to me.  trust me.  i know.  but it is an unstoppable, irrestistable, uncompressible force that is pushing my mind around.</description></item><item><title>memory</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-12-25-memory/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-12-25-memory/</guid><description>it has been so long even my computer didn’t &amp;lsquo;Remember Me.&amp;rsquo; and I had to relog in to typepad.  How aweful of me.</description></item><item><title>cities</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-11-22-cities/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-11-22-cities/</guid><description>tiny cities ARE made of ashes.</description></item><item><title>homer</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-10-19-homer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-10-19-homer/</guid><description>go home puppies.</description></item><item><title>t-shirt ideas</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-09-21-t-shirt-ideas/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-09-21-t-shirt-ideas/</guid><description>so i have the following t-shirt ideas that i thought would be funny.</description></item><item><title>dreamin&amp;#8217;</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-09-20-dreamin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-09-20-dreamin/</guid><description>last night i had this extremely lucid dream where one of my eyebrows was gone and the other was super bushy.</description></item><item><title>mobility</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-09-20-mobility/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-09-20-mobility/</guid><description>the following is a new treatise that represents some of my current thought patterns.  those that know me [everyone that reads this blog] knows of my mobile ways in geography but in many aspects of my life.</description></item><item><title>take that pat benatar</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-09-19-take-that-pat-benatar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-09-19-take-that-pat-benatar/</guid><description>direct quote:</description></item><item><title>walking the woods</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-09-19-walking-the-woods/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-09-19-walking-the-woods/</guid><description>left nashville this weekend to walk in the woods.  it helped.  spent saturday night buried in my books at a hipster coffee shop smoking rolled cigarettes.</description></item><item><title>mTv in dockers</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-09-15-mtv-in-dockers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-09-15-mtv-in-dockers/</guid><description>today during my lunch i decided to watch some bubble gum, so i flipped using my ever so handy quatro-surf buttons on my remote control to the preprogrammed (so you don’t even have to remember the channel number, as a side note in what context are we now required to remember ANY number….I cannot think of such a context myself, my cell contains phone numbers, my car contains addresses, my tv remote contains my favorite channels, shit what else is there to life?  the study of ancient bath techniques and rub downs as a greecian mating ritual/alpha male dominance performance….besides that one.) channel for MTV.  ahhh, laguna beach usually makes me cough, curse and flip back to VH1, OLN HGN or BET but that wasn’t the case today as the only quote i heard was, &amp;lsquo;i’m like so totally stoked we’re going up to mammoth.&amp;rsquo;  well this could be interesting.</description></item><item><title>footBall&amp;#8217;s back</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-09-12-footballs-back/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-09-12-footballs-back/</guid><description>today i gave myself a sabatical.  all football, all day.  it was fantastic.  just finished up watching PRIMETIME.  visions of big dog nachos dancing in my head.</description></item><item><title>Old Men Rule?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-09-04-old-men-rule/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-09-04-old-men-rule/</guid><description>Rule #2 is Old Men Rule.  I have a shirt that says as much on it.  Yes, in those words.  I gaurantee you’ve seen it.  There is an interesting duality when I where it to school those as most people now know that I’m older than them.</description></item><item><title>Reasons</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-09-03-reasons/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-09-03-reasons/</guid><description>A friend asked me why I’m here.  This was the best I could come up with:</description></item><item><title>into or out of the mist</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-08-24-into-or-out-of-the-mist/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-08-24-into-or-out-of-the-mist/</guid><description>i’m unsure of where this blog entry will go.  i know that i want it to go somewhere &amp;lsquo;somewhere great&amp;rsquo; [in a patronizing voice].  but i’m not sure where that great will be.  i guess that could be a metaphor for my life.  for my desires towards women, for my desires towards fulfillment, for my desires, for my life.</description></item><item><title>inevitability?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-08-19-inevitability/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-08-19-inevitability/</guid><description>so tonight it happened.  i had been dreading it happening, in fact it was one of the main reasons i had for not wanting to move to nashville.  but nonetheless it happened.  on the way to a bar to meet some new &amp;lsquo;friends&amp;rsquo; i ran into katie’s parents.</description></item><item><title>incoherenCy</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-08-14-incoherency/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-08-14-incoherency/</guid><description>well.  i’m on 36 straight hours.  i think.  i have lost all cognitive and reasoning powers.  my back is about to explode.  i need to dumpster dive like 40 cubic feet of trash into random dumpsters that do not belong to me with the hopes that their cameras don’t see me.</description></item><item><title>Confluence of Space and Non-Space</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-08-12-confluence-of-space-and-non-space/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-08-12-confluence-of-space-and-non-space/</guid><description>the internet is a fabulous, and deadly, weapon for mass destruction of society.  or maybe mass creation of different societies.  i’m not certain.</description></item><item><title>Signatories and Their Significance</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-08-09-signatories-and-their-significance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-08-09-signatories-and-their-significance/</guid><description>finished kundera tonight, but it will stay on the list as i’m going to reread it through.  it was fucking intense.  it was my favorite book that i’ve read in the past three years, easily.</description></item><item><title>Decisions</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-08-08-decisions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-08-08-decisions/</guid><description>everyone around me suddenly appears to be suspect.  like they have morphed from being just humans, to having some sort of alien aura about them.  like i put on a magic pair of sun glasses and can see that they are all out to get me.  but i’m not paranoid about it, merely concerned.  and so i just don’t talk to them.  i just stifle it all and let it settle into a ball of goo in the lower regions of my stomach.  let it cause ulcers or maybe hemmeroids.  and then what?  what the fuck happens after?  not sure.</description></item><item><title>All Moved In.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-08-06-all-moved-in/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-08-06-all-moved-in/</guid><description>OK kids.  The pizza is half-eaten, cold, and greasing up the coffeetable for me.  There are beer bottles in a pile somewhere near THAT corner of the room, in the vicinity of the empty boxes that are broken down into flat cardboard for storage in the garage somewhere.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-08-05-251/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-08-05-251/</guid><description>am reading kundera for the first time.  it is outlandish.  i’m learning so fucking much.  and i don’t even know czech to read it in the original.  am going to reread this flipping thing as soon as i finish it b/c there is too much here.  there are two basic things that i’m learning from him.  first, how to weave a narrative outside of time.  this thing is like a tarratino flick in that he likes to tell the story along certain lines other than a linear (based on time) slide.  there is organization here and i haven’t quite figured it out.  it isn’t completely, merely, just thematical separation, although there is an element of that.  it isn’t just isolated on one character out of the four in this particular section, b/c how can you tell the story of one without another.  and that is the point.  there is the essence of perspective, and i’m not completely unconvinced that he isn’t using each section to change perspective, but not exclusively, in other words he is not limiting himself to that.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-07-21-252/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-07-21-252/</guid><description>am i on a treadmill or actually road running.  cannot tell.  hopefully will know something soon</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-07-20-253/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-07-20-253/</guid><description>went and saw the young dubliners tonight at the little club in town.  the open band was called the saucy monkeys.  or something of the sort.  they were two artsy chicks with acoustic guitars.  for some reason i was reminded of the two chicas who opened for bush in 94 when i saw them with eric in orlando.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-07-18-254/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-07-18-254/</guid><description>the following things happened during my evening hike today:  i was startled by a fairly large brown bear when i rounded the corner and there he/she was 15 yards from me.  luckily she/he sauntered off.  i gave blood to the mosquito blood bank of the roaring fork valley….don’t they know i’ve been given the anthrax and small pox vaccinations and cannot give blood for another five years.  i startled a beaver and he made a pop sound with his tail and for a while i couldn’t figure out what had happened until i saw his dam and his house, which were directly in front of me the entire time.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-04-07-255/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-04-07-255/</guid><description>does anyone else wonder what happens when you actually blast one of the ipod’s?  does it show up at your doorstep in a couple of days with a &amp;lsquo;thanks for playing our carnival game&amp;rsquo; note on the inside of the cubic apple box?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-04-05-256/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-04-05-256/</guid><description>the pope passing on is significant.  i wonder how much of that significance will be lost on the seventh-day adventist church because of its complete anti-catholicism stance.  or will it perhaps spawn a thought process, one of reevaluation of that stance.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-03-29-257/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-03-29-257/</guid><description>i feel sated. a snake on a warm spring afternoon curled on a sandstone deposit, belly full of mouse, jaw reattached, water near, people and mongeese far.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-03-26-258/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-03-26-258/</guid><description>today i shall bew bland and newsy b/c i’m too warped to be funny and too jaded to be artsy.  i feel like complete shit today for no real reason.  last night was a our big, the ski season’s almost over fuckers party.  as per my usual i got on the near side of trashed, just coherent enough to convince many others that i’m not trashed and just trashed enough to through out my ensemble of social conditionings, self-loathings and general wallflowerness.  then i went home with a woman.  nothing happened, as half-way home i realized what the fuck, over? and ended up sleeping in the guest bed, on top of the covers, still in my gorilla suit.  but alas, everyone saw me leave with her.  now don’t get me wrong, she isn’t an unattractive woman, but i had quite the reputation brewing up here and now i’m wondering if that isn’t just a little bit altered.  had i had one less vodka drink i think everything would have been OK as i would have come to my WTF, mate epiphany a few minutes earlier and wouldn’t have left with her.  but whatever, i don’t really really care.  plus i think that my boss lady friend is seeing someone else, a friend of mine, on the sly.  that is another aspect to my feeling like shit today.  stir in a teaspoon of good ole’ hungover and you got yourself quite a dish of crap.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-03-24-259/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-03-24-259/</guid><description>impressions of an evening in aspen.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-03-20-260/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-03-20-260/</guid><description>is no artistic output better than bad artistic output?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-03-06-261/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-03-06-261/</guid><description>it is saturday night and i’m typing and enjoying wine and then going to sit down with my book for the rest of the evening.  damn i’m boring!</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-03-04-262/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-03-04-262/</guid><description>i think that in the past i’ve been very patronizing towards hot chocolate and have made a conscious decision to rethink my position on the substance.  maybe it should be legalized afterall.  what do you think?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-03-03-263/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-03-03-263/</guid><description>i am quite tired and sore this evening.  not sure what i’m sore from, probably life beating me about my head and neck relentlessly without me really giving a damn and just taking it lick by fucking lick.  and i’m not talking about the tongue against ice cream cone kind either.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-03-01-264/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-03-01-264/</guid><description>WARNING:  this shit is VERY graphic and ENTIRELY conjecture.  just painting a picture of one way it could have gone down.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-02-23-265/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-02-23-265/</guid><description>Now, I must do this justice, and to do that I need to back up.  First, some background. His name is Hunter S. Thompson, if you don’t know that name, google him.  I find some odd parallel’s in my living in the same town with the counterculture icon when he dies and with Eric’s story of his friend farting next to Allen Ginsberg’s coffin during some candlelit vigil to the old beat-en poet.  Fast-forwarding and keeping my vile flatulence under control I paint the background of the piece before revealing the subject.  He died two nights ago now, shot himself in the head with a .45.  The rumors around town vary, but the prevailing story is he was old and dying and he just sped up the process.  Many have discounted my first thought that it was  drunken accident by the posterboy for &amp;lsquo;alcoholics among us.&amp;rsquo;  His &amp;lsquo;compound&amp;rsquo; [paragraphical insert: he didn't have a house, the local's tend to pay him some sort of weird homage among the castles that litter the countryside up in the extremely posh neighborhood where he lives, he doesn't have a simple house like Michael Douglas or Prince Bandar, but a fortified compound&amp;hellip;.I guess that is how you can standout in a place like Assssspen.] was two doors down from where my landlord lives.  We stop the story there merely to rewind a bit, because I don’t think you know this part of the story.  I rent a townhouse in a small &amp;lsquo;suburb&amp;rsquo; of the spotlight in the valley that is aspen from a lady who is the personal assistant to some bigwig Aspen-ite.  She was married before and currently a widow and her late-hubby was some 18 trillion-th generational Aspen-ite.  So she is very ingrained with the local history of the place.  Well she is in this odd relationship that after months of observation I cannot commit to any sort of vague or clear categorization–with my roommate.  To summarize, I live with the &amp;lsquo;boyfriend,&amp;rsquo; becuase she is still the personal assistant and as the bigwig grows older and more senile she must spend more time up there near him.  So she has a guest house beside the castle, nothing special in this fucked up world.  Her house is a few acres away from the compound.  The first time I went up to her house to sign my lease I was jolted into some flashbacks when the windows of her house rumbled and the floor of her elevated treated hardwood flooring shook under my dirty new balance shoes.  When I got up from my involuntary temporary fetal position she told me not to worry that it was just Hunter blowing dynamite which was much worse than the naval flare guns or the simple handguns and shotguns.  Me being the Assssspen virgin I wondered aloud, Hunter who?  She told me HST, and I thought, oh, that freak.  Well, I put that memory away on some unused shelf beside the time in gradeschool when Justin Birmele and I were filling out some form and he said &amp;lsquo;sex, yes please,&amp;rsquo; in response to the &amp;lsquo;male or female&amp;rsquo; response we were supposed to give–until the last few days.  I was speaking with my terribly off roommate about HST tonight and how I had grabbed a few of the Aspen Daily New’s to send to a few lucky friends and then he responded in his burnt-out-smoked-as-much-hash-as-cheech way that he had something to show me.  The he dug for a while and came to my room, a rare occurance and asked if I wanted to read the greatest HST shit ever.  I said, why not, I don’t have anything going on, being between books and waiting on many things to happen before Jim will take our next proposal to the street even though it is close to finished.  Then matt, the roommate, brought out these rolled up things that his &amp;lsquo;girlfriend&amp;rsquo; my landlord had gotten many years ago, 1970 in fact.  That year HST was going to run for sheriff and to bolster his campaign and also to promote his personal racket and other things he and a local artist, thomas benton, made these &amp;lsquo;newspapers.&amp;rsquo;  I am not sure how many of them were done, but the following excerpt was taken from the June 30, 1970 edition, Wallpapers No. 2.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-01-14-266/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-01-14-266/</guid><description>i spent the entire day cuddling with myself and reveling in the peacefulness.  odd roommate has been conspicuously absent for the past few days and i have barely ventured outside for more than a solitary walk to convince myself that the sun puts out vitamins that i needed to or could actually soak in through all my layers as i walked around in the teen-something degree air and tried to maintain breathing through a stuffed up nose that was pierced by the freezing cold air.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-12-04-267/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-12-04-267/</guid><description>i’m sore.  and i don’t mean butt-hurt, even though my butt does hurt.  well, the ass muscles hurt.  i’ve been riding hard for the past two days, and i don’t mean the ladies–the snow baby.  the riding skills are coming back faster than i imagined that they would.  i was jumping natural kickers both in the groomers and in the trees.  i was taking the bumps and the trees without pausing.  i even jammed a few rails.  i was screaming faster than i think i’ve ever ridden. the snow here is really really hard and fast, but you can go fast b/c you know that it isn’t going to ice on you and have your board slip out from you as long as you are riding correctly.  that i something that i’ve had to learn how to do again, ride correctly.  the bottom line is that i haven’t made a complete ass out of myself.  excellent–in my best crazy scientist voice.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-11-22-268/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-11-22-268/</guid><description>i feel like i have come almost full circle, let me explain.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-11-13-269/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-11-13-269/</guid><description>i feel refreshed.  i feel wierd in fact, because there has been some odd vindication that has came at the same time as an odd amount of conflict.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-11-08-270/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-11-08-270/</guid><description>five days later i make my next entry.  this time it is from the boulder public library where i’ve been camped out for a bit and pretending i’m back in college and doing something productive with my time.  i think that i’ve found where i want to live.  boulder has the quadfecta as i’ve deemed it of:  climbing, kayaking, ski, community.  those are the four things that i’ve looking for in places to live.  there are lots of other smaller things, but generally they come with the above four.  this town is beautiful, near the mountians, has decent weather, nice people, a great art scene, bouldering within walking distance, skiing an hour away, kayaking through town, ice climbing an hour and a half, more trad and sport routes within 15 minutes of the town than i could probably do in a lifetime.  coffeeshops with great art, funky music and weird people.  it is just fantastic here.  the college is loud and rambunctious and there is just a great vibe in the town.  everyone works out, i’ve seen like 2 fat people in my two days here so far.  it is fantastic.  well i’ll get off boulder’s crank now i’ve done enough!</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-11-02-271/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-11-02-271/</guid><description>well i’m reading all these things about how the vote has begun. so, in a sign of things to come:  i have lost a toe nail.  and it isn’t one of the small ones, it is the big one on my left foot.  on a hike about four weeks ago i stubbed it terribly bad while i was running down the insanely steep hill and trying to avoid both the rocks and the cacti.  the past two fall seasons i have used that technique to hone my quick feet skills in hopes that it’ll help me on the snow covered mountains. it didn’t really help me that i can pinpoint last year, but i stuck to the technique this year…dumby me, huh?  well, i stubbed my big toe and my middle toe pretty badly and they were f-ed up pretty badly.  so i did the ole’ technique that i’ve seen doc’s use (which BTW joe told me afterthefact was the correct one to use) of heating up a safety pin with a lighter until it was glowing hot and then burning through my toenail until there was a small hole in it.  well after four or five tries i finally burned completely through the nail on the big toe and when i pulled it out that last time five gallons of fluid came pouring out from underneath.  luckily i had at papertowel handy to sop much of it up.  then i burned through my middle toenail in one elegant fell swoop.  and that one was taken care of too.  well i had been anxious about the toenails for a couple of weeks and then randomly the big one fell off two nights ago.  the entire f-ing thing.  i’ve lost toenails before but they were on the smaller nails.  this one is the big one baby. and that is crazy.  so i feel concerned b/c the only other person that i’ve known that has lost a big toenail has been dave and he’s had about 19 different ingrown toenails since then.  so that cannot be good.  but i’m living with a nailless big toe.  it looks odd, because the skin is still there thinking that there is a nail, but there isn’t.  i had all kinds of scabbing and such on the skin that i steadily picked off, but every time i touched the skin where the nail used to be it sent shivers down my spine like fingernails on the proverbial blackboard.  but whatever, i’m growing used to it now.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-10-31-272/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-10-31-272/</guid><description>decisions decisions decisions.  i guess that i have made my bed and now i’ll revel in it.  i put in the applications at aspen and heard back from the chica there yesterday.  she seemed anxious to interview me, i’m sure i can talk my way into the job.  i was already planning to leave on friday to get there for vail’s job fair on saturday.  now i suspect that i’ll leave here as soon as i close the loops on two different things.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-10-24-273/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-10-24-273/</guid><description>i think that something interesting to study would be the history of companionship.  at what points in history have people really desired true companionship and partnership out of their significant others?  the victorians and all that flowery poetry shit that they wrote were supposed to be significant steps in the history of love.  however, i wonder if it was love like we would call it.  whenever i read any of elizabeth barrett browning or any of her contemporaries it seems that it is only infatuation.  it doesn’t seem deep seated; just surface-al.  then the sixties were all about free love.  they probably made up a lot of grounds on the front of sexual equality but it was such an open society that i wonder sometimes how much they valued the individual.  many of the communes were probably against the individual.  without the individual then there can be no love of someone specific.  you could love a group of people but you could love someone specifically i would suggest.  i guess that was good for the polygamous types.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-10-08-274/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-10-08-274/</guid><description>tonight’s thematique du jour is loneliness for two reasons.  firstly because i think that i’m essentially a completely lonely person, even when surrounded by people.  secondly, and more presently, because i watched parts (most) of about schmidt.  that movie is basically a film students study in the emotion.  at least that is my take on the piece.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-10-04-275/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-10-04-275/</guid><description>the one thing that i’ve learned as i ease into the hottub of the blogging culture is that late sunday night is the time for the big ‘weekend recap.’   so let me see, what did i do this weekend.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-09-30-276/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-09-30-276/</guid><description>&amp;lsquo;chasing amy&amp;rsquo; is on tonite.  i’m watching my past.  i’m amused by the scene where they throw darts.  i also like jason lee’s character, it’s one of the internally truest characters in movie-dom.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-09-26-277/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-09-26-277/</guid><description>just back from the getty for the afternoon.  went down the hill to my friend’s house for the first night.  actually was one of my ex’s.  she’s fairly intense, and likes it that way so she plays it up.  we drank wine on her porch while i sweated in my jeans and too long of sleeve shirt because its been cold up here and my dumb ass was relishing the cold enough that i dressed for it when i shouldn’t have.</description></item><item><title>underWater Desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/about/</guid><description>Casey Kuhlman's Blog.</description></item></channel></rss>