<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/</link><description>A Site About Resilience and Authoritarianism</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</managingEditor><webMaster>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</webMaster><copyright>All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/law/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>On the Sovereignty of CryptoCurrencies -- What Bitcoin can Learn from Somaliland</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-08-14-bitcoin-somaliland/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-08-14-bitcoin-somaliland/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently a video was made: &amp;ldquo;The Declaration of Bitcoin's Independence&amp;rdquo;. Here's the video.&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XQqZ9b0S0BY" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>For those of you not involved with the, all in all, rather small cryptocurrency community the people in that video are some of the bigger names within the community. The village elders if you will. Not sure the village actually chose them, but elders tend to be self appointed anyway &amp;ndash; at least at first.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My friend and business partner, Preston, provided his response in &lt;a href="http://prestonbyrne.com/2014/08/14/tory-2/">this fine article&lt;/a>. I take an analogous, but distinct, view from Preston's.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="anarchists-go-experience-anarchy-or-shut-up">Anarchists: Go Experience Anarchy, Or Shut Up&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>One of the overarching points of the video is that Bitcoin is somehow sovereign, which I assume means a system unto itself. And I'm not simply picking out one word from many and obsessing about it. That is the entire point of a &amp;ldquo;Declaration of Independence&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; for a group to declare that it is no longer beholden to a prior sovereign and is now beholden to a different sovereign.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But who is the sovereign in which these individuals of common purpose are beholden to? Who knows.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I'm a relative outsider to this whole cryptocurrency thing. Sure, I'm trying to &lt;a href="https://erisindustries.com">build a business&lt;/a> which will utilize some of the technology underpinning cryptocurrencies. However, I am by no means a believer that a few cryptographic hashes and a fancy database somehow changes any of the real human dynamics which scientists, artists, philosophers, and the like have been pondering for a couple millennia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As an outsider, it is (anthropologically) interesting to watch a bunch of (predominantly) white (predominantly) Americans (and Canadians) purport to claim that an interesting payment protocol will solve world peace, governmental overreach, and all the other ills of modernity. The idea that somehow because there are cryptographic hashes and p2p communications protocol that those will suddenly shift the paradigm of modernity and that we can reach a point where governments are unnecessary is&amp;hellip; I'm not sure what it is actually.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I've lived in anarchy. I know what it looks like when governance systems collapse. I have felt how easy elite capture becomes in such situations. I have tasted hyper inflation. I challenge anyone who identifies as an anarchist to actually go to Somalia &amp;ndash; or another area where governance systems have collapsed for a significant amount of time. Spend some time there. Talk to people about their lives. Understand what the hell you're talking about.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Whatever the participants&amp;rsquo; individual motives are I cannot speak to, I suspect that many would identify more with libertarian thinking than pure anarchical thinking. For those that do have anarchical tendencies, please see above. For those that have libertarian thinking, please see below.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="lesson-1-declaring-independence-is-an-emotional-exercise-building-a-system-is-a-rational-exercise">Lesson 1: Declaring Independence is an Emotional Exercise; Building a System is a Rational Exercise&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In 1991 the elites of the Somalilanders &amp;ldquo;freedom&amp;rdquo; movement (it wasn't about freedom really, it was about capturing the state in the name of the Somalilanders) were forced by a bunch of emotional people to declare their independence from Somalia. Many at the time, and many today, question whether this heated, emotional, reaction was the correct decision. Nonetheless, it happened.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As most Democracy and Governance, Conflict Studies, and Crisis Situation scholars and practitioners understand declaring independence is the easy bit. Pretty words on paper (or in a video) don't mean anything in reality. They are simply those &amp;ndash; pretty words. They can inspire, sure, but beyond that they mean little.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the case of Somaliland it took about 13 years after the Declaration of Independence to have a really functional Constitution and the state building is still going on &amp;ndash; and likely will be for another two generations. It took a massively important leader with a real commitment to building a functional system who fought tooth and nail to build a constitution which was both responsive to constituent concerns while also setting the framework for a functional system. It took scholars, and discussion, and compromise, and &lt;em>work&lt;/em> to get there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The question I have for those who participated in this video is this: are you actually interested in doing the work necessary to craft a system? Only time will tell.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="lesson-2-if-you-want-to-sit-at-the-adults-table-act-like-adults">Lesson 2: If You Want to Sit At The Adults&amp;rsquo; Table Act Like Adults&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>During my time in Somaliland I said the above more times than I could count. Mostly in response to idiotic stuff whatever Minister or other person of purported power who was sitting in some vaunted chair did. It would drive me crazy that Somalilanders in positions of power would drone on about how they were a &amp;ldquo;real state&amp;rdquo; but how they continued to fail to perform the most basic of governance functions. You can't have it both ways I would tell my friends. Either you need to do the work, make the sacrifices, and be your own state, or else you just need to shut up. More times than I currently care to count, I would watch the Somaliland government act as a rebel organization acts and then go on BBC Somali asking why the world wasn't treating them like a state. Most of the time the reason the &amp;ldquo;world&amp;rdquo; wasn't treating them like a state was because they weren't acting as a state acts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I view the cryptocommunity through a similar lens. It talks &amp;ndash; &lt;strong>at nauseum&lt;/strong> &amp;ndash; about how it &lt;em>deserves&lt;/em> to be taken seriously. Really? Why? What has it done to &lt;em>deserve&lt;/em> being taken seriously? Certainly there is some very interesting technology that has been built. And that technology should be taken seriously. As technology.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But Bitcoiners, and the cryptocommunity more generally, should not somehow be free from the normal rules which apply. If those inside the cryptocommunity want cryptocurrencies to be treated &lt;em>as&lt;/em> currency, then they must abide by the &lt;em>normal&lt;/em> rules which attend to handling money.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These rules &lt;em>are&lt;/em> onerous, precisely because businesses which deal with folks&amp;rsquo; money are, well, dealing with folks&amp;rsquo; money. I do not understand why cryptocurrencies businesses should somehow get a bye as to providing proper safeguards, as has been agreed in the relevant states are necessary.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="lesson-3-real-systems-empower-professionals-and-root-out-scammers">Lesson 3: Real Systems Empower Professionals and Root Out Scammers&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When I was in Hargeisa some of the more interesting people I hung out with were folks who were trying to set up a governmental quality assurance system. There were a lot of problems that needed to be tackled, but foremost on the minds of these scientists (some of who had been trained locally some of whom had been trained abroad) was the difficulty of ensuring that medicines were proper. There was (and likely still is) a huge problem of knock-off drugs, mislabeled drugs, and the like. These scientists were trying to tackle this. Because it was putting the health of community members in jeopardy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I enjoyed my time with these scientists and doers precisely because they saw a collective problem and were trying to do something about it &amp;ndash; despite the odds. The odds being that big importers who supported big actors within the government make more money off fake drugs than real ones. The odds being that quality assurance of medicines is not one of aid's current hot topics (and therefore there was no aid money to support their activities). The odds being that of all the problems in Hargeisa this was not the one that was on the tip of folks&amp;rsquo; minds &amp;ndash; except for when those folks had sick kids. Despite those odds, these guys were trying to do something to protect folks. And that was awesome from my perspective. They are a &lt;strong>long&lt;/strong> way from solving this issue, but they are trying.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What is the cryptocommunity doing about rooting out scammers? There are, indeed, some efforts. And I hope that they continue, because the cryptocommunity has a huge scammers problem that needs to be addressed in a fundamental way. It isn't likely to happen with a technological solution; it is much more likely to happen via legal or social mechanisms. But so far we've only seen a few of these take place.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Time will tell how this all plays out. Indeed, most of this is about the community more generally than a response to the specifics of that video. I think there is some very interesting technology which bitcoin has brought to people's attention. It would be a shame if that technology was overshadowed by people projecting their issues and complaints with bigger systemic issues on it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How I Would Structure Automatic Virtual Contracts</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-17-structuring-automatic-virtual-contracts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-17-structuring-automatic-virtual-contracts/</guid><description>&lt;p>Automatic contracts have been occupying a great deal of my free mental energies for the past few weeks since I first learned that there are platforms in the works that will allow for such things to happen. My thoughts on this are quite nascent, as is the technology, but here are my early observations.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Automatic virtual contracts are, essentially, small computer scripts which are linked to virtual currency wallets. The basic idea is that a financial transaction and the terms and conditions governing the transaction collapse into a singular instrument &amp;ndash; or script.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An example will probably make this easier to visualize. You and I want to make a contract, say, for me to deliver to you X widgets at Y time at Z price. Perhaps you don't trust that I will be able to deliver to you the widgets at the time. Perhaps I don't trust that you will be able to pay me for the widgets when I have delivered them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a traditional contract scenario, we would overcome this lack of trust in a couple of ways. Either we would put the money into an escrow account controlled &amp;ndash; likely &amp;ndash; by one of our banks. Or you would execute a Letter of Credit from your bank (which really only addresses the latter of the trust issues). Or we would just trust each other based on our reputations or our past business dealings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Virtual automatic contracts overcome the trust issues in roughly the same ways. One of the key differences is that the computers act as the intermediaries rather than a large, stable financial institution such as a bank. While it is true that many people who operate in the global marketplace do have banks, it is also true that there are significant numbers who do not have or do not want bank accounts. Virtual automatic currencies would offer these individuals (as well as the banked individuals) a mechanism to operate in the global economy just as effectively and (perhaps more) efficiently than those individuals who are banked.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The analogous transaction to the escrow scenario would probably follow a sequence such as: I offer you the contract by sending you the script; you accept the contract by transferring the cost of the contract (or part of it) to a virtual currency &amp;ldquo;account&amp;rdquo; which is controlled solely by the script; we both &amp;ldquo;push&amp;rdquo; the script out into the network which verifies all of the aspects of the contract; when I deliver and you certify delivery the script automatically transfers the virtual currency to an &amp;ldquo;account&amp;rdquo; which I control from the &amp;ldquo;account&amp;rdquo; controlled solely by the script.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The analogous transaction to the letter of credit scenario or to the &amp;ldquo;just trust me&amp;rdquo; scenario would probably follow a sequence such as: I offer you the contract by sending you the script; you accept the contract by placing your &amp;ldquo;account&amp;rdquo; details into a field on the script; we both &amp;ldquo;push&amp;rdquo; the script out to into the network which verifies all of the aspects of the contract; when I deliver and you certify delivery the script automatically transfers the virtual currency to an &amp;ldquo;account&amp;rdquo; which I control from your &amp;ldquo;account&amp;rdquo;. There are a few varietals of this script which could be developed which would (1) verify you have enough currency to pay for the delivery upon the occurrence of one or more events along the trajectory of completion of the contract and (2) structure payment schemes besides a one off payment upon delivery to other schemes staggered throughout the contract's trajectory and based upon the occurrence of one or more events.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Beyond being able to have some amount of trust in complex commercial transactions for unbanked individuals, there are numerous other benefits to virtual automatic currencies which would extend to both unbanked and banked individuals.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="speed-and-transaction-costs">Speed and Transaction Costs&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Banks are slow. Escrow and letters of credit are costly. International wire transfers are slow and costly. Automatic virtual currencies would collapse this. Currently transaction costs in the bitcoin network for instance are on the order of 10%-50% of the costs for accepting credit cards. In low margin industries which have a lot of transactions this is a significant reduction in transaction costs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition, bitcoin transactions are fast. Even getting money into your bank from a bitcoin transaction is not very slow. Most payment providers in the developed world will give you the money to your account that evening after you have developed a history with them. If you and I were both to keep some not trivial amount of our working and operating capital in bitcoin already then the payment speed dividend increases dramatically because the real time sink in the network at this point is moving from the virtual currency (bitcoin) to a &amp;ldquo;fiat&amp;rdquo; currency and depositing that fiat currency into your bank account.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Those are two huge advantages. For me, the seller, I would receive the value almost instantly upon certification of the delivery by the buyer. For both of us, reducing the transaction costs (which are traditionally priced into the overall transaction and either shared between the seller and the buyer or just paid for by the buyer) will be reduced and thus the cost to the buyer for the widgets should be reduced.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="uncertainty-and-ambiguity">Uncertainty and Ambiguity&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>One of the things that is most promising aspects to automatic virtual contracts, but also perhaps one of the most difficult aspects in contracting generally, is their ability to reduce uncertainty and ambiguity within the contract.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Automatic virtual contracts are computer scripts. Computer scripts do not like ambiguity. Indeed, computers are mostly too dumb to handle ambiguity. Presumably, it will be the role of the cryptography network supporting the contract's dissemination and execution to ensure that there is a lack of ambiguity. It is unlikely that simple transactions such as the one I've been using here will have any significant level of ambiguity to the contract whether it is virtual or traditional &amp;ndash; but for other types of contracts or bylaws (think trust establishment documents or a corporation's bylaws operating as virtual automatic contracts) where ambiguity could potentially be higher this is a bigger concern.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Reducing contractual ambiguity is usually the lawyer's job when drafting or reviewing a contract or other instrument. In a virtual automatic contract network, though, reducing ambiguity would likely be a three prong effort shared between the lawyer, the coder (who will likely be the same in coming generations), and the network. This would put more eyeballs on the problem. Also, programming is very different than drafting a contract because the computer needs precision. This will force lawyers|coders to develop contractual instruments which rely upon verification metrics for various parts of the contract which will inherently reduce its ambiguity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When it comes to scripting, the scripting language itself handles whether a comma should be in a given location or not; there is no argument over whether to include an Oxford comma in an array; there is no argument over whether a defined term is an operative method or not. The nature of computers and scripting languages reduces these typical ambiguities into a binary determination: it is, or it is not. Judges may have to learn how to read computer scripts, but it is likely that they will have less of a role in determining whether A set of words and punctuation should yield B result or C result as that will be handled by the language and the network. This will reduce ambiguity throughout the entire commercial network &amp;ndash; a very good thing if you ask any business person you know.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I'm using uncertainty here as analogous to risk generally, or &amp;ldquo;all the other stuff surrounding the contract&amp;rdquo;. On a simple contract which I have been using as an example in this post, there will be uncertainty for me that you will not find a better price on the widgets and just send them back to me after I have delivered them; there will be uncertainty for you that I will deliver the widgets at the quality specified. Admittedly, automatic virtual contracts cannot be a panacea to address these uncertainties because there are no real strong answers here. However, a few things could be done to address them. If we know that my widgets weigh Q grams, and we have access to a postal or courier's API then we can check that I have sent Q grams * X widgets (plus some packaging weight) to you &amp;ndash; thereby reducing your uncertainty. Of course this wouldn't address the quality of the widgets. That would be nearly impossible to overcome unless we could easily agree to a level of precision that a computer could check.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One potential way to address this uncertainty is by placing some third party &amp;ldquo;referee&amp;rdquo; into the system. These people could operate similar to how insurance adjusters worked in prior economies. They would largely be independent contractors who would work for the network and could be used to certify that I have delivered X widgets to you at Y time and they meet the quality standards we agreed to in the contract. Once the referee certifies the delivery to the network, then the script would automatically execute whatever was next in the series of events (likely, paying me). Potentially in international shipping government customs investigators (married with APIs) could also have a role in such a system. The big take away here is that wherever there is a subjective determination that some event has taken place, any way to build that into an API framework or utilization of a neutral referee would work to reduce the uncertainty. This is not necessarily transformative, indeed such systems are in place today in various capacities. The biggest difference here is that the referees could work independently and be certified and paid by the network itself so they would only have an interest in ensuring the validity of the contract rather than one party or the other succeeding (or course they could always be paid off by one side to say yes or no, but we'll likely always have to live with that uncertainty).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="summation">Summation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This post has examined an extremely simple contract, which is where the ecosystem will have to begin. But once the ecosystem matures a bit the possibilities here for reducing commercial transaction friction and further decentralizing while also globalizing economies is utterly fascinating. A good friend and I are working on a business proposal which would leverage these types of transactions so hopefully there will be more on the horizon to this end.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Obama on the Judiciary</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-12-obama-on-the-judiciary/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-12-obama-on-the-judiciary/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2005/9/30/102745/165">This &lt;/a>is very lucid.  Obama wrote it after Roberts&amp;rsquo; nomination.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>According to the storyline that drives many advocacy groups and Democratic&lt;br>
activists – a storyline often reflected in comments on this blog – we are up&lt;br>
against a sharply partisan, radically conservative, take-no-prisoners Republican&lt;br>
party.  They have beaten us twice by energizing their base with red meat&lt;br>
rhetoric and single-minded devotion and discipline to their agenda.  In order to&lt;br>
beat them, it is necessary for Democrats to get some backbone, give as good as&lt;br>
they get, brook no compromise, drive out Democrats who are interested in&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;appeasing&amp;rdquo; the right wing, and enforce a more clearly progressive agenda.  The&lt;br>
country, finally knowing what we stand for and seeing a sharp contrast, will&lt;br>
rally to our side and thereby usher in a new progressive era. I think this&lt;br>
perspective misreads the American people.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>From traveling throughout Illinois and more recently around the country, I&lt;br>
can tell you that Americans are suspicious of labels and suspicious of jargon. &lt;br>
They don't think George Bush is mean-spirited or prejudiced, but have become&lt;br>
aware that his administration is irresponsible and often incompetent.  They&lt;br>
don't think that corporations are inherently evil (a lot of them work in&lt;br>
corporations), but they recognize that big business, unchecked, can fix the game&lt;br>
to the detriment of working people and small entrepreneurs.  They don't think&lt;br>
America is an imperialist brute, but are angry that the case to invade Iraq was&lt;br>
exaggerated, are worried that we have unnecessarily alienated existing and&lt;br>
potential allies around the world, and are ashamed by events like those at Abu&lt;br>
Ghraib which violate our ideals as a country.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It's this non-ideological lens through which much of the country viewed Judge&lt;br>
Roberts&amp;rsquo; confirmation hearings.   A majority of folks, including a number of&lt;br>
Democrats and Independents, don't think that John Roberts is an ideologue bent&lt;br>
on overturning every vestige of civil rights and civil liberties protections in&lt;br>
our possession.  Instead, they have good reason to believe he is a conservative&lt;br>
judge who is (like it or not) within the mainstream of American jurisprudence, a&lt;br>
judge appointed by a conservative president who could have done much worse (and&lt;br>
probably, I fear, may do worse with the next nominee).  While they hope Roberts&lt;br>
doesn't swing the court too sharply to the right, a majority of Americans think&lt;br>
that the President should probably get the benefit of the doubt on a clearly&lt;br>
qualified nominee.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A plausible argument can be made that too much is at stake here and now, in&lt;br>
terms of privacy issues, civil rights, and civil liberties, to give John Roberts&lt;br>
the benefit of the doubt.  That certainly was the operating assumption of the&lt;br>
advocacy groups involved in the nomination battle. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>I shared enough of these concerns that I voted against Roberts on the floor&lt;br>
this morning.  But short of mounting an all-out filibuster — a quixotic fight I&lt;br>
would not have supported; a fight I believe Democrats would have lost both in&lt;br>
the Senate and in the court of public opinion; a fight that would have been&lt;br>
difficult for Democratic senators defending seats in states like North Dakota&lt;br>
and Nebraska that are essential for Democrats to hold if we hope to recapture&lt;br>
the majority; and a fight that would have effectively signaled an unwillingness&lt;br>
on the part of Democrats to confirm any Bush nominee, an unwillingness which I&lt;br>
believe would have set a dangerous precedent for future administrations –&lt;br>
blocking Roberts was not a realistic option.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In such circumstances, attacks on Pat Leahy, Russ Feingold and the other&lt;br>
Democrats who, after careful consideration, voted for Roberts make no sense. &lt;br>
Russ Feingold, the only Democrat to vote not only against war in Iraq but also&lt;br>
against the Patriot Act, doesn't become complicit in the erosion of civil&lt;br>
liberties simply because he chooses to abide by a deeply held and legitimate&lt;br>
view that a President, having won a popular election, is entitled to some&lt;br>
benefit of the doubt when it comes to judicial appointments. Like it or not,&lt;br>
that view has pretty strong support in the Constitution's design.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Admission of Evidence in International Courts</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-11-07-admission-of-evidence-in-international-courts/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-11-07-admission-of-evidence-in-international-courts/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://chrisblattman.blogspot.com/">&lt;img src="http://chrisblattman.blogspot.com/" alt="11522034_744a83cbd8">&lt;/a>&lt;br>
So, have commented on a blog besides my own for the first time. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://sudanwatch.blogspot.com/">http://sudanwatch.blogspot.com/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have been reading &lt;a href="http://chrisblattman.blogspot.com/">Chris Blattman’s blog&lt;/a> on development for a while, and today he posed a question about the admissibility of evidence.  He was legitimately questioning whether, as a legal or policy reason, drawing made by &lt;a href="http://news.independent.co.uk/world/politics/article3121175.ece#2007-11-02T00:00:01-00:00">children in Darfur &lt;/a>(such as the one presented here) should be admitted if they ever get &lt;a href="http://www.icc-cpi.int/cases/Darfur.html">Harun and Rahman&lt;/a>. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>My response is here.
~ # ~&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://chrisblattman.blogspot.com/2007/11/international-kangaroo-court.html">http://chrisblattman.blogspot.com/2007/11/international-kangaroo-court.html&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Death penalty</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-10-death-penalty/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-10-death-penalty/</guid><description>&lt;p>According to Amnesty’s site, today is &lt;a href="http://www.amnestyusa.org/document.php?lang=e&amp;amp;id=ENGPOL300242007">Anti-Death Penalty Day&lt;/a>.  I wonder what color bracelet I’m supposed to be wearing to fit in…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Conscious that I’m treading in shark-infested waters, especially with my family: I’m not vehemently anti-death penalty.  But I am death penalty. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not so much for the cruel nature of the punishment.  I don’t think the act itself it is normatively worse than keeping someone in prison for their life.  It is cruel.  But I, personally, feel that it is no more worse than many other ways that retributive punishment enacts &amp;ldquo;societies vengence&amp;rdquo; upon an individual. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m anti-death penalty because I think that (1) it has little to no additional deterrent effect, (2) it is intellectually bankrupt and morally anarchic, and (3) it costs too much. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>I fail to see what additional deterrent effect that it has over and above life imprison.  We don’t see more or less Murders in Texas than we do in California.  The empirical evidence is simply conclusive that people are going to murder and having the legal authority to be able to sanction a heart for a heart has no statistical effect.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Come on.  Are we really that uncreative?  I know many people will claim that the point of the criminal justice system is to vindicate victim’s rights.  I am usually a big proponent of this philosophy.  Restorative justice and deterrence are, traditionally, my two favorite justifications for even having a criminal justice system at all.  Well, those and incapacitation, but I have divergent opinions on incapacitation with regards to the domestic and international fora. That aside, I fail to see outside the heat of the moment passions why a victim would care specifically that someone die.  Yes there are so many holes in that statement that an infant could argue through it.  That said, I return to an argument explored above.  There has been no great public outcry by victim’s families in the majority of states in the US who do not have the death penalty.  If it was really that poignant to victim’s families that the perpetrator die than I think you would have strong pro-death penalty rallies.  It isn’t like Republicans (now I fail to see why this is, necessarily, a traditionally conservative political platform, but it has been drawn under the umbrella of being a Republican without a doubt) have no ability to organize a campaign they care strongly about.  See Pro-Life.  Further, isn’t an eye for an eye Old Testament and turn the other cheek New Testament?   &lt;/p>
&lt;p>And,lastly: It costs more to try someone in a death penalty case than in a life imprisonment.  It costs more to the degree than on sum it costs more to kill someone than to imprison them for their life.  Yes, that includes the costs of imprisoning them for life.  I will find the statistics later. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Somehow Tajikistan, Kazakhstan, Burundi, Gabon and Mali are very close to a complete abolition of the penalty.  And here we are.  Although I think it is a dubious legal argument, it is an extremely strong public policy argument: &lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;A total of 133 UN member states, from all regions in the world, have&lt;br>
abolished the death penalty in law or in practice. Only 25 countries&lt;br>
carried out executions in 2006, 91 percent of them in just six&lt;br>
countries: China, Iran, Iraq, Pakistan, Sudan and the USA. Those that&lt;br>
chose this most cruel, inhuman and degrading punishment are&lt;br>
increasingly in the minority.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Is that the list we want to be in?  In all of Africa, the most violent continent in the world there were only six countries who legally sanctioned executions as a criminal penalty in 2006. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chuckie Gets More Charges</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-09-07-chuckie-gets-more-charges/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-09-07-chuckie-gets-more-charges/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.rottentomatoes.com/m/lord_of_war/">&lt;img src="http://www.rottentomatoes.com/m/lord_of_war/" alt="180pxcharlestaylor">&lt;/a>&lt;br>
The DA in Miami has added more counts of torture to Chuckie’s indictment.  His trial is set to begin in Miami in January 2008.  I find it cute that father and son will begin their trials at about the same time. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/09/07/180pxcharlestaylor.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/09/07/180pxcharlestaylor.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chuckie is Charles Taylor’s son, he was the former President (dictator) of Liberia who was one of the most infamous warlords ever.  The African President from &lt;a href="http://www.rottentomatoes.com/m/lord_of_war/">Lord of War&lt;/a> was based (loosely) on Charles Taylor.  Chuckie was born in Boston but raised in Orlando area, and is roughly my age.  I wonder if I ever ran into him at the &lt;a href="http://www.altamonte.org/development/projects/images/AMC.jpg">Altamonte Mall movie theater&lt;/a>. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wonder if the US should give them a group discount.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Link: &lt;a href="http://ap.google.com/article/ALeqM5i0_KNrOkqH3FPQc3bN0F2AtoAwrg" title="The Associated Press: Ex-Liberian Leader's Son Charged Again">The Associated Press: Ex-Liberian Leader’s Son Charged Again&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hamdan Redux</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-26-hamdan-redux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-26-hamdan-redux/</guid><description>&lt;p>i’m not as huge a bush hater as many others who score similarly on political spectrum tests.  however, i continued to be amazed at the recalcitrant-ness of his administration.  throughout the short american constitutional history there have been contentious constitutional issues that have pitted the three branches of governance against each other in varying degrees of allied and opposition poses.: executive v. legislative, legislative v. judiciary, executive &amp;amp; legislative v. judiciary, etc.  however, the end to the tension usually comes (at least in the governance sector, even if it lingers in the civil &amp;amp; media sectors) when the supreme court rules on an issue.  if the court rules against one of the other branches in on a constitutional issue, its word is final.  full stop.  however when the court rules on other issues of law, adminsitrative, legislative, international then it may not be the final say.  the executive or legislative often will have a second crack even if one of their actions was nulled by a decision of the court.  that said, most times, the other branches second cracks will show much more deference to the legal reasoning which the court adopted (usually because a constitutional challenge to the second crack may be waiting in the wings and if the court has shown a leaning in a particular decision the legislative and executive would not want to get overturned on constitutional grounds as that would be the end of the story again).  but the bush executive branch seems to evince little of the traditional gentlemanliness with which this country has been governed for years.  latest in the saga of the Hamdan v. Rumsfeld decision is the executive issuing an executive order that CIA interrogation techniques, if conducted for the purpose of eliciting intelligence are per sae legal.  there are a few nuances in the order, first the techniques must not violate the McCain Ammendment against torture or dismemberment (but according to most human rights decisions this leaves a wide berth).  secondly, the techniques must not be conducted with the purpose of degrading the human.  well, shit, that just about guts the protections that the Hamdan decision offered to detainees at Guantanamo (and hopefully by extrapolation to other detention facilities, although there is no jurisprudence on point with regards to that issue — yet). &lt;/p>
&lt;p>two men with conservative pedigrees which few could attack have written an &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2007/07/25/AR2007072501881.html?nav=rss_opinion/columns">OpEd in the Washington Post calling out the Administration&lt;/a> for this lack of deference and showing how wrong the decision is based upon common international legal interpretation principles. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>i understand that we need to keep the country safe.  i have no quibble with national security scholars who dicker over specifics, but this is a bridge too far for me.  by simply saying that the purpose of the interrogation is paramount in any determination we are gutting the protections found in Common Article 3.  full stop.  the CIA will always be able to argue that it is interrogating for the purpose of eliciting intelligence, in fact it is all it does and even in the most degrading of treatments all they have to do is to ask a question (no matter how obvious or mundane) and then claim that the purpose was to gather intelligence.  once they get through the wicket then they are enable to do whatever they want per the text of the executive order. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>it seems that the administration is digging a hole to bury itself in needlessly.  there are other ways to protect yourself without stooping to tit for tat reciprocity. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>drama</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-06-04-drama/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-06-04-drama/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2007/06/04/world/africa/04cnd-taylor.html?hp">crazy drama&lt;/a> in the courtroom today as we went to open our case.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>no rest for the wicked.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-03-08-no-rest-for-the-wicked/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-03-08-no-rest-for-the-wicked/</guid><description>&lt;p>so i’ve worked twenty-three of the last twenty-five days. average day length: 12 hours. average number of documents per day: varies. this week have not left the office before midnight, except for meals. likely this time will creap later and later as we approach our deadline.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i asked my magic eight ball when i can expect some time off, it replied: the outlook is not good.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>so much for my theory that no one works as hard as americans, and therefore i won’t be working that hard in africa. well, maybe the theory is still intact, but i’m working FOR americans. damn it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>like my officemate and i keep telling each other, to buoy our morale….international justice waits for NO ONE…!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Witness Protection in the Third World</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-20-witness-protection-in-the-third-world/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-20-witness-protection-in-the-third-world/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today I would like to soapbox about something not really close to my heart but that I’ve been pondering lately.  How is protecting high-profile witnesses here different than it is in developed countries?  I mean I’ve seen Joe Dirt and therefore I know most of what there is to know about witness protection in the US.  But I don’t know anything about it here.  Let’s explore.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In some ways it may be easier to hide and protect a witness in a developing country.  The lack of a virtual or real paper-trail may make certain things, such as identity creation, easier.  The lack of credit cards and the imposition of a completely cash based economy also enhances anonymity.  Without having to change credit cards and bank accounts and deeds to property and all the other bread-crumbs of identity that a normal person in the developing world leaves throughout their virtual and real travels, it is easier to make someone reappear.  It may raise eyebrows if someone pays for a plane ticket in cash in the US; whereas, here it is impossible to pay for something with a credit card.  That said, once authorities get the new identity created, it is likely about the same in either a cash-based or in a credit-based economy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Around here compounds are frequent.  This, again, enhances an authority’s ability to protect “insider” witnesses who are genuinely worried about reprisals for their cooperation with investigations and trials.  In a situation where there are not many compounds, emplacing one may raise more eyebrows than in a place like this where everyone who can afford it lives in a compound and everyone who cannot lives in a shack.  There is no in between.  Either you have a wall topped with razor wire or broken glass, with bars on your windows, massive locks on your doors and guards at your gates or you live in a shack hopefully near the streams so you can do your washing easily.  When I was a child riding my bike around and saw a walled place, I would find a way to look inside.  Here the compounds are so frequent that I cannot imagine that I would have bothered to care as a Sierra Leonean child.  This prevalence of security areas makes it easier to protect someone. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>So in some ways the absence of a real infrastructure and large middle class make it easier for authorities to make someone disappear (in a good way, not in the other way).  Yet there are other ways which make it more difficult to make someone disappear. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>To a certain extent the developing world’s connectedness has created a situation where it is dislocated from its real environment and surroundings.  At home I rarely, if ever, talk to my neighbours or know the people I’m passing as I walk around.  Here I’m forced to learn the faces for security reasons and because it is construed as rude if I do not remember them from the last time we chatted.  Because I’m an anomaly and because everyone looks at the white boy who walks to the market every night and remembers my name, I feel socially compelled to remember as many of their names as I can.  My lack of anonymity stems from more than merely my skin color, though.  It also comes from the fact that here people have absolutely nothing to divert them.  I see the same people every night when I walk to the market because they, unfortunately, have nowhere else to go, and thus, are semi-imprisoned in their own surroundings. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>The lack of movies, TV, electricity, book stores, parks &amp;amp; concerts means that people are left to talk — communicating and gossiping is about all you are left with when the other diversions are absent and your work is finished for the day.  The lack of the diversions simultaneously restricts the options that local people here have to talk about.  It is a running joke in my office that Americans talk about movies too much, but that is all we know; here all people know is other people.  This human connectedness, I think, may make it more difficult to provide useful and true witness protection.  It may be easier to create a persona by moving to a different locale in the third world.  The problem is that secrets, once out, spread through the bush quicker than Page Six could ever hope to move rumours about celebrities. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>People love their news here.  It is likely their only source of diversion or break from the monotony of their normal workaday.  There are radio stations.  During the evening you can hear the five stations blasting through cheap, imported radios wherever you are in Freetown.  During the mornings you can see the cheap newspapers sold by the men who have very little else to do with their lives for US$.30 or so.  These newspapers are habitually and blatantly wrong about so many things.  Here, I think that the media can be easily cajoled.  Because corruption is so rife the people with an end in mind can further that by paying off newspapermen.  A little money goes a long way. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Where there is a dearth of reliable or contradictory evidence than, of course, people will take it at face value.  People do that in the states where they have much better access to “alternative” media outlets.  In terms of witness protection, this likely cuts both ways.  I think that whoever gets their hands in the pockets of the newspaper editors in the city of relocation first will be the ones who will be able to control whether it makes it into the media that this person has arrived in the city (with a picture), the reliance on media may prevail and it may be extraordinarily easy for the seekers to find the individual.  If the authorities can pay off the newspaper first so that there is no mention of the sought-after witness then the lack of alternatives may prevail and it would be fairly easy to retain the anonymity. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>So what is the answer?  Maybe the answer is different here than in developed countries.  My notion of witness protection in the US is, concededly tainted by Hollywood notions, but it seems to me that you achieve a new identity and then assurances of that anonymity by becoming part of the masses.  By just being another schlub who drives a Ford Explorer and goes to work five days a week, the mall on Saturday and the golf course on Sunday no one will ask questions.  The people who may be looking for retribution will not really be able to ask a lot of questions if someone lives in a medium-size city and varies where he or she shops and goes to.  The lack of human connections makes it much harder to track someone down by human intelligence measures.  In distinction to this, in the developing world maybe you have to remove someone from the masses.  These people exist here and no one really knows who is behind the blacked out glass.  I think that the trick boils down to removing the witness from the scene entirely and not allowing him or her to be seen by many people.  The curiosity factor is high, but generally people cannot be bothered to care if you don’t give them a reason to do. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>unilateral v. multilateral humanitarian interventionism</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-07-unilateral-v-multilateral-humanitarian-interventionism/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-07-unilateral-v-multilateral-humanitarian-interventionism/</guid><description>&lt;p>I had a conversation I had with a Swiss woman who I work with about non-feasance as a basis for criminal prosecution.  I would like to proffer my philosophical ramblings about humanitarian interventionism, which is inextricably linked to non-feasance.  Obviously there are other links, to the duties in the genocide convention.  Maybe the best way to delimit the discussion is to speak solely about the Genocide convention.  I understand that without further legal research I may not have full comprehension of the &lt;em>legal&lt;/em> bounds of the duty.  That said, I would like to explore whether humanitarian interventionism is a duty that states should impose upon states. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>I pulled three quotes from the Genocide convention that I think are relevant to the discussion. (1) “Being convinced that, in order to liberate mankind from such an odious scourge, international co-operation is required, . . .” Chapeau.  (2)  “The Contracting Parties confirm that genocide, whether committed in time of peace or in time of war, is a crime under international law which they undertake to prevent and to punish.” Art. 1.  (3) “Any Contracting Party may call upon the competent organs of the United Nations to take such action under the Charter of the United Nations as they consider appropriate for the prevention and suppression of acts of genocide or any of the other acts enumerated in Art III.” Art. 8.  In my mind, on the face of these three quotes, this means that all states that are party to the convention are under an obligation to prevent it and to punish it, but not to intervene in situations where genocide is occurring.  It seems that that duty rest with the international community.  Perhaps there is a duty to assist the international community in the sense that if the UN asks a state to send peacekeepers to a given country then they should comply with that request as part of their duty to prevent and punish.  I will return to the multilateral approach in a bit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unilateral humanitarian interventionism seems to me a recipe for disaster. In fact, it seems to me that only in a very limited set of circumstances is unilateralism not a recipe for disaster.  In the conflict here in&lt;br>
Sierra Leone&lt;/p>
&lt;p>, there were unilateral interventions and there were multilateral interventions.  Many here felt that ECOMOG, despite the many atrocities that they committed (which were fewer than the RUF/AFRC, but many more than a western or UN force would have committed), was a legitimate intervention force.  Now it is hard to pin down why people thought that.  I am not sure whether they thought it was correct because they thought the AFRC/RUF were worse, or they preferred the “elected” Kabbah government or because they felt that the international community embodied in this West African regional IO was a legitimate force.  Likely it was a mix of all three of those variables.  NATO in Kosovo, despite the objections at the time, may have only survived because it was a multilateral force. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am not sure all my history is correct, but I think that when the Marines went into&lt;br>
Somalia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>at the very beginning we were alone.  Whether that was the initial thrust of an overarching multilateral plan I am not aware.  I do know that we were the first in and the rest of the world, including the UN came later. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>The history aside, if legitimacy for humanitarian intervention can only come from a multilateral force does this make sense?  There are definite advantages to a multilateral approach: legitimacy derived from the UN and the SC, a healthy debate on the topic, leverage with other states in the region.  However, there may be advantages to a unilateral approach as well: speed and tempo can be achieved by the unity of command, especially with regards to regional interventions the intervening, foreign troops may be more culturally-sensitive to the “target” country. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are a couple of things that trouble me about a unilateral intervention.  The first is fairly realpolitik.  But what are the intervening state’s interests.  It seems to me that if the international community allowed a unilateral intervention to occur then really it would be one step away from allowing an invasion.  Countries in the region would merely incite under the table a genocide, and then intervene to set up a friendly government or continue to occupy “for the protection of the occupied people.”  &lt;em>See Syria/Lebanon&lt;/em>.  The second one is despite the hang-ups that most of my Marine friends have with the UN, a unilateral approach may be less efficient.  Now, I would not argue that it would be inefficient for US Marines to go into&lt;br>
East Timor&lt;/p>
&lt;p>alone and secure that country and keep the peace there for a temporary amount of time before handing over to another body.  I would not argue that it would inefficient for the Brits to do something similar.  But outside a handful of countries that have the capacity to get a fighting force efficiently to other parts of the world, it seems to me that a pooling of resources would be more efficient.  Lastly, genocide is a crime against humanity.  In my mind that means that the world community should be involved.  Even if it was a genocide against an ethnic group in one country and that ethnicity controlled in another country, it is still a crime against the entirety of humanity. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think that by taking it out of the hands of individual states the Genocide convention probably does it properly.  I mainly believe, for myself, that the &lt;em>best&lt;/em> reason is the last that I have listed above.  Placing the decisions in the hands of multilateral bodies means that genocide remains a crime against the entirety of humanity.  A state or non-state actor who perpetrates genocide should feel the entirety of the weight of humanity against him or her.  This is likely to be the most efficient deterrence that can be created.  I must caveat my deterrence argument with the thought that the entirety of humanity must be ready to act when genocide occurs, something that heretofore has not happened. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although I do not believe that the institutional allocation should shift terribly towards the international, I think that in certain ways the current&lt;br>
US&lt;/p>
&lt;p>isolationist approach is costing us much more than we are gaining out of.  While&lt;br>
Europe&lt;/p>
&lt;p>continues to spend money on social services consistently fostering good will throughout the world and&lt;br>
Asia&lt;/p>
&lt;p>spends money on education and infrastructure building (especially with regards to technical infrastructure) we flounder with a bloated defence budget.  This is a different topic entirely, but the point is that by becoming less isolationalist and more multilateralist we will save money that can go towards social services in our country or another or can go to the people directly in the form of tax relief (depending on one’s political proclivities).  It seems that many think that leadership can only come in the form of doing what you want when you want.  This is a medieval king’s approach to sovereignty.  Leadership can come in the form of example.  I will continue to advocate for engagement and leadership by participation until I am have been disproved.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is much more here, but I should work now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Institutional Allocation as between International Organizations</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-10-26-institutional-allocation-as-between-international-organizations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-10-26-institutional-allocation-as-between-international-organizations/</guid><description>&lt;p>I created the following document in order to get some thoughts straight for a presentation I have tomorrow.  It is longer than my presentation will take, and much of it may be out of view for some of you, but I’m putting it up here b/c I think it is pretty good encapsulation of many of the things I’ve learned this semester.  It is not cited.  If you think I need to cite in a blog, go fuck yourself. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wow, Dave, Three posts from me in one day….aren’t you happy?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>——&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The cases we were assigned raise an interesting question of&lt;br>
institutional allocation. The case&lt;br>
addresses unilateral trade sanctions by one of the WTO member States. That said, there is nothing stopping the WTO&lt;br>
from expanding that ruling to include multilateral trade sanctions that could&lt;br>
be imposed by a COP to an environmental treaty. If that expansion were to happen then would all subsequent and earlier&lt;br>
environmental treaties be subject to the provisions of the WTO if it wanted to&lt;br>
adopt a trade sanction as an enforcement mechanism? Could existing environmental treaties that&lt;br>
include other enforcement mechanisms (carbon caps and trading for example) be&lt;br>
construed as dampening effects upon trade and market development and&lt;br>
correlatively must they then pass a WTO test? &lt;/p>
&lt;p> If the answers to these questions were always yes that would&lt;br>
turn the WTO into the defacto authorization body for all&lt;br>
environmental/labor/human rights etc. treaties. That cannot be the case. The&lt;br>
authorizing bodies for all treaties are states that negotiate and ratify and&lt;br>
enforce the treaties. Thus we must ask&lt;br>
how to allocate the power as between institutions. For the purposes of this presentation we will&lt;br>
be examining the WTO as one institution and the COP of an environmental treaty&lt;br>
(such as an RFMO) as the competing institution. &lt;/p>
&lt;p> There are two questions that must be asked when looking to&lt;br>
how to allocate power as between international institutions. (1) What is the power of the States party to&lt;br>
the institution as well as the institution itself to prescribe rules and standards&lt;br>
governing the subject matter of the treaty? This is known in the State context&lt;br>
as &lt;em>prescriptive jurisdiction&lt;/em>. (2) What is the power of the States party to the institution as well as the&lt;br>
institution itself to adjudicate interpretive or substantive disputes that&lt;br>
arise in the course of implementation and execution of the treaty? This is known as &lt;em>adjudicatory jurisdiction&lt;/em>. When you look at competing institutions you are basically asking: how do&lt;br>
we allocate the prescriptive and adjudicatory jurisdiction as between them? &lt;/p>
&lt;p> The institutional allocation issue is not unique to int’l&lt;br>
law.  However the int’l law application&lt;br>
of the issue raises unique questions. Questions&lt;br>
of institutional allocation are familiar to American lawyers in the contexts of&lt;br>
administrative law (how much should Congress legislate and how much should it&lt;br>
leave to the administrative agencies) as well as federalism. Int’l law brings unique questions to the&lt;br>
issue. The two main questions come from:&lt;br>
complete, uniform and absolute sovereignty as well as from the equal footing of&lt;br>
treaties. &lt;/p>
&lt;p> All treaties may not be created equal, but there is no&lt;br>
hierarchy of treaties. The UN Charter&lt;br>
may be the granddaddy of treaties, but outside that there is very little hierarchical&lt;br>
rules. Certainly there is no standard&lt;br>
regime for distributing between treaties. There are three applicable rules of construction from the Vienna&lt;br>
Convention on the Laws of treaties that are applicable. They are all found in Article 30. (1) Lex Specialis could trump lex generalis&lt;br>
if the later treaty contains greater detail and if it regulates the same&lt;br>
subject matter as an earlier treaty. This is only applicable if all relevant States are parties to both treaties. (2) When all applicable States are parties to&lt;br>
the subsequent treaty the later in time rule usually applies. (3) When all applicable States are parties to&lt;br>
only one treaty, that treaty trumps treaties that not all applicable States are&lt;br>
parties to. These rules may cut against&lt;br>
each other in various contexts, but outside of these general rules there are no&lt;br>
specific rules for conflict of laws and conflict of forum scenarios that arise&lt;br>
as between int’l treaties.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> Second, states retain the power. It is only in ceding power to an IO that that&lt;br>
IO gains any power. But all power is&lt;br>
vested in the individual states. This is&lt;br>
extremely familiar to American lawyers as a federalism concern. However, it is different in the int’l context&lt;br>
because there is no absolute inclusion like there is in the
US&lt;/p>
&lt;p>context. This lack of absolute inclusion, or what&lt;br>
could be termed top-down compulsion, adds a level of complexity to the debate&lt;br>
when it turns to rights of dissenters as well as the prescriptive jurisdiction. Just because a state may cede some&lt;br>
prescriptive power to the WTO to set various schedules and rates, that does not&lt;br>
mean that the state necessarily cedes prescriptive power to that body to&lt;br>
regulate domestic environmental policy. When&lt;br>
a State does not like or agree with an action taken by IO, the latter body has&lt;br>
very little power to force its will on the State. If the State finds it more efficient or less&lt;br>
costly it can leave the IO or snub its nose at the IO. B/c the ultimate power is vested in the State&lt;br>
and there is no ability of the IO to force compulsion a State will only comply&lt;br>
with the will of an IO if it is less costly to do so. These costs come in reputational and&lt;br>
political as well as in economic forms. The same cannot be true in the
US&lt;/p>
&lt;p>federal system. If GA doesn’t like a decision or a statute of&lt;br>
the federal government it cannot snub its nose at the federal government and it&lt;br>
cannot pack its bags. &lt;/p>
&lt;p> Now that we have identified a few of the unique questions&lt;br>
that arise when asking institutional allocation questions in the international&lt;br>
context, let’s apply those to our question. First off, when we ask questions of the allocation of prescriptive&lt;br>
jurisdiction as between IO’s that will necessarily alter the jurisdiction as&lt;br>
between states. Some states will have&lt;br>
much more involvement in one treaty than they will in another. States that have more invested in a given&lt;br>
treaty will obviously want that treaty body (or IO) to have more prescriptive&lt;br>
jurisdiction. There are also the questions&lt;br>
of influence over the subject matter, involvement in the “legislative” process,&lt;br>
and expertise over the subject matter.  &lt;/p>
&lt;p> This horizontal allocation of jurisdictional power as&lt;br>
between states becomes especially salient when you look across subject matter&lt;br>
boundaries. Some societies will&lt;br>
obviously value a given subject matter more than they may value other subject&lt;br>
matter (turtles may be more important than money to some). The difference in values placed by each State&lt;br>
on a given subject matter creates a tension as between different IO’s. Some small coastal states, or states with&lt;br>
large fishing fleets will have a lot of social investment, as well as capital&lt;br>
investment, in a RFMO and due to that investment they may wield more influence&lt;br>
in that IO. They will necessarily want&lt;br>
to optimize the jurisdictional power of their IO, often at a cost to IO’s that&lt;br>
regulate a different subject matter where their investments would have paid&lt;br>
smaller dividends.  Since each State&lt;br>
retains its sovereignty, it may be able to minimize the costs associated with&lt;br>
the transference of jurisdictional power as between IO’s by withdrawing from&lt;br>
the IO where power was drawn from or threatening to withdraw or by taking other&lt;br>
political tacks. &lt;/p>
&lt;p> As one commentator has written “the market for transactions&lt;br>
in prescriptive jurisdiction is not yet very liquid.” This creates a problem if states do not&lt;br>
efficiently allocate from the start.  Since int’l law is an iterative process that&lt;br>
allocation can arguably never be efficient from the start, b/c there is no&lt;br>
start. What is time zero for one IO&lt;br>
cannot be time zero for another. Even if&lt;br>
they were to enter force on the same day, the provisions of each treaty are to&lt;br>
be interpreted in light of the context of the treaty. That context is a fluid thing that includes&lt;br>
all the events that gave rise to the negotiation of the treaty as well as the&lt;br>
way the negotiations were handled. Even&lt;br>
if there was a start point getting the initial allocation of prescriptive&lt;br>
jurisdiction efficiently allocated may involve a transaction with costs that&lt;br>
outweigh the benefits in every occasion. The transaction costs are likely to include: negotiating costs,&lt;br>
differing values and preferences and interests, binding, depth, holdouts,&lt;br>
reputational costs and political costs. &lt;/p>
&lt;p> If there is no start point and if there is a very limited&lt;br>
possibility that states are going to efficiently optimize jurisdictional power,&lt;br>
then states must allocate jurisdictional power as between IO’s as efficiently&lt;br>
as possible along the way. This dynamic&lt;br>
component of the int’l law system can be easily analogized to a market system. But what is the market in prescriptive&lt;br>
jurisdiction? It is the int’l community&lt;br>
with a revolving door of relevant actors who have a revolving door of interests&lt;br>
motivating their actions. Or maybe&lt;br>
states could cede all powers in a repository that can allocate prescriptive&lt;br>
jurisdiction as between subject matter or regional IO’s. This centralized authority could bring&lt;br>
certainty to a system as well as stemming externalities in races to the bottom&lt;br>
by allocating prescriptive jurisdiction to the IO most likely to have the power&lt;br>
or influence or wedge that would stem a state’s momentum. This flexibility may be something we&lt;br>
want. If the int’l community wants a&lt;br>
State to live up to a certain norm then a central repository could allocate&lt;br>
prescriptive jurisdiction to an IO where that State has a larger stake than&lt;br>
influence. The targeted State would then&lt;br>
find itself in a position where the costs of non-compliance outweigh the&lt;br>
benefits. &lt;/p>
&lt;p> Next I want to turn to the adjudicatory jurisdictional&lt;br>
issues. The world of treaties may look&lt;br>
to be discreet circles, but basically it represents a web of ven diagrams. This reality necessitates that there are&lt;br>
going to be many instances where there are competing norms and competing&lt;br>
interpretations and competing regulatory/policy responses. But there are two distinct questions&lt;br>
here: choice of law and choice of&lt;br>
forum. &lt;/p>
&lt;p> In Art. 20 of the GATT the WTO said that other int’l&lt;br>
agreements that were entered into as necessary to protect human, animal or&lt;br>
plant life or heath are exempted from the provisions of the GATT. But that exemption has not been adopted. Indeed as the cases here illustrate, the WTO&lt;br>
has  put its fingers in many pots. So which norms should trump which? Which treaty should trump which? Which law should trump which? There is clearly no normative reason why the&lt;br>
provisions of the WTO should trump those of an int’l treaty. Now this is not what the WTO ruled,&lt;br>
ostensibly, even in its formalistic, far-reaching holding in Shrimp/Turtle&lt;br>
I. But if the regulations on trade and&lt;br>
on capture that were adopted by the
US&lt;/p>
&lt;p>had been adopted by a RFMO how&lt;br>
could the WTO rule that its norms trump those of the RFMO’s? How do we choose when faced with such a&lt;br>
conflict of law question? Which treaty&lt;br>
would trump? That treaty which has&lt;br>
primary coverage over the subject matter? That treaty which recognizes the norms of another treaty? That treaty with the most members&lt;br>
trumps? That treaty that has the&lt;br>
strongest enforcement trumps? How we&lt;br>
integrate an allocate these differing bodies of law is becoming an increasingly&lt;br>
important subject for int’l lawyers. &lt;/p>
&lt;p> Lastly, how do we choose the decision maker? Much of the criticism of the WTO in the&lt;br>
aftermath of these cases comes from their perceived or real bias. Should they be dabbling in environmental&lt;br>
protection? More importantly if there&lt;br>
was a buttress, a WEO how would they distribute the decision making as between&lt;br>
them in hard cases. Would they simply&lt;br>
negotiate between them? Would it be&lt;br>
plaintiff’s choice? Would we have to&lt;br>
codify specific choice of forum rules into all future treaties? Would we establish my customary int’l law&lt;br>
certain standards of comity between different forums? What would the comity multifactor test look&lt;br>
like? &lt;/p>
&lt;p> A solution to all this would be to expand the jurisdiction&lt;br>
of the ICJ and the ICC or the WTO, etc. to include all international law. This one-stop shopping for litigants could&lt;br>
prove easy, but is it what the world needs. The difficulties in instituting the ICC are illustrative here. In that instance the ICC was established to&lt;br>
have subject matter jurisdiction over jus cogens norms — norms that are&lt;br>
universally condemned. But yet that&lt;br>
process was long, politically charged and costly on all sides. Its implementation has been far from&lt;br>
perfect. What happens if the int’l&lt;br>
community tries to expand a universal forum to adjudicate norms that are not&lt;br>
nearly as universally condemned. That&lt;br>
lack of moral impetus will probably be the divisive factor. That and the fact that states retain all of&lt;br>
their sovereignty.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>internship journal for the last week</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-16-internship-journal-for-the-last-week/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-16-internship-journal-for-the-last-week/</guid><description>&lt;p>the following is my excerpt from my last journal entry, which i had to submit to my faculty advisor:&lt;/p>
&lt;p> this week&lt;br>
the claim preclusion opinion that i drafted, and was circulated, was&lt;br>
returned. the comments and feedback were&lt;br>
interesting and varied greatly from the judge who is on the campaign trail&lt;br>
right now who signed off without a single pen change to the judge who&lt;br>
“couldn’t” comment because there was “too much work” to be done on it (she also&lt;br>
did not make a single pen change) to actually helpful comments on some of the&lt;br>
reworking of the issues. it made me&lt;br>
think of something a guy said to me last summer. last summer i was a panelist on the aspen&lt;br>
summer words writer’s festival and after we finished the panel i was at the bar&lt;br>
having a drink with one of the other panelists who was a magazine writer. we were talking about editing and he told me&lt;br>
something that stuck. he said “i think&lt;br>
of the editing process as a negotiation between the editor and myself.” that seems an incredibly apt metaphor here&lt;br>
where all the judges either have to sign off on the opinion or draft a new&lt;br>
opinion (which, of course, they are not jumping at the opportunity to do since&lt;br>
they each have their own caseload of opinions to write). i was laughing about that comment to today as&lt;br>
my supervising staff attorney was putting her little side comments on whether&lt;br>
or not i should incorporate wordings and phrasings from a particular&lt;br>
judge. it was evident who had the&lt;br>
negotiating power among them and who did not. “she is a great editor since she was a former english teacher.” [read, incorporate her changes word for&lt;br>
word.] “she just rewrote it the way she&lt;br>
would have originally wrote it were she working on the opinion.” [read, incorporate whatever you think is&lt;br>
valid and discard the rest.] “now this&lt;br>
is incredibly unhelpful.” [read, don’t&lt;br>
even bother to look through it.] &lt;/p>
&lt;p>when we were going over the changes&lt;br>
that she actually wanted me to incorporate she made a comment that i thought&lt;br>
was incredibly helpful thing for me to keep in mind. it went something like this: “you know, you being a published author you&lt;br>
obviously brought with you a certain style for story telling. but when you write it is like you keep&lt;br>
forgetting that you are writing a legal document until the last second you&lt;br>
throw in a legal turn of phrase. it is&lt;br>
really jarring.” i pressed her on the&lt;br>
subject as i was really interested in this observation, mainly because i think&lt;br>
she is right. i asked her to clarify&lt;br>
whether she meant that it was bad that i was writing in a “story-telling way”&lt;br>
or was it bad that i was throwing in legal phrasings or was it bad that my&lt;br>
legal phrasings seemed tacked on and there was no smooth transition between the&lt;br>
two styles. she said that the hardest&lt;br>
thing was the jarring nature and that i need to make the transitions smoother&lt;br>
and stick in one “voice” or “style” for a complete section of a document and&lt;br>
then if i need to change the voice or style to make the transitions smoother or&lt;br>
at least at the beginning of a paragraph. i asked her to show me examples and she did. mainly what she was pinpointing were places&lt;br>
where my writing style was colloquial and simple but instead of using a&lt;br>
colloquial or simple word i would throw in legalese. her observation was dead on as i started to&lt;br>
review some stuff i do that. so it is&lt;br>
something for me to work on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>but i was thinking today about why&lt;br>
and/or whether there should be a noticeable difference between the two writing&lt;br>
styles. i mean, there obviously is a&lt;br>
tangible difference between the two, if there were not then you would have one&lt;br>
job instead of two. i guess much of it&lt;br>
is historical/cultural. the profession&lt;br>
developed with some sort of a need to prove itself and one of the ways that i&lt;br>
think the legal profession justified its existence and filtered out those who&lt;br>
would gain entry to its ranks was by adopting new words, forms of speech and&lt;br>
phrasings. the legal community seems to&lt;br>
pride itself on these distinguishing characteristics. “it is what separates us from the normal&lt;br>
people,” or something to that effect. but, frankly, i think that that is crap. if there is an easier way to say something that does not require you&lt;br>
shoehorning your writing into a certain form why should you have to rearrange&lt;br>
your writing to a form that outside the legal community most people would think&lt;br>
is ineffective and unappealing stylistically just because “it is what judges&lt;br>
and senior partners expect.” (i&lt;br>
reflected on the quote that chicago manual style likes by churchill that is an&lt;br>
incredibly hard to read sentence where he was making the point that often times&lt;br>
it is just easier to end a sentence with a preposition.) i was thinking about that for a bit and then&lt;br>
it occurred to me that that is no different than anything else. all this boils down to is knowing your&lt;br>
audience, an elementary tenant of writing. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>my judge has told me in the past&lt;br>
that he is a very story oriented writer. he knows that he is in the majority, but still thinks that it is ok to&lt;br>
put a little bit of personality into your opinions. as such he let me go with the opinion in my&lt;br>
voice that (stylistically at least) fits with his philosophy on legal&lt;br>
writing. a litigant or staffer that&lt;br>
knows that can be “looser” with his or her writing style when they present&lt;br>
something to him. other judges here at&lt;br>
this court are much more stylistically formal and they require more formal&lt;br>
reasoning and style out of the written documents they receive. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>i guess it simplifies to there&lt;br>
isn’t so much of a conflict between the two writing styles as there is between&lt;br>
the audiences. if i had never been&lt;br>
enabled by my judge to “tell a story, write this opinion like you’re writing it&lt;br>
to your mom,” then i never would have had a conflict. i would have just writing very impersonal and&lt;br>
formal. the staff attorney is a more&lt;br>
formalist person and writer, but she knew that my style is more similar to the&lt;br>
judge’s than it is to hers and she was ok with that. i realized later that what she was really&lt;br>
saying to me is to stick with one thing and be brave enough to continue&lt;br>
that. just because i’m writing a legal&lt;br>
document doesn’t necessitate that i must insert legal phrasings just to lend&lt;br>
them authority. i guess she was saying&lt;br>
that if your argument and reasoning is solid (which most seemed to think that&lt;br>
it was) then you don’t need to bolster it with words and phrasings that&lt;br>
obviously do not fit with the rest of your document.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>work: week 2</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-05-29-work-week-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-05-29-work-week-2/</guid><description>&lt;p> This&lt;br>
was a bit of a transitional week as I finished up with the preclusion case and&lt;br>
settled into quite a monster of a case. The one thing that has struck me as I’ve been reading the briefs is how&lt;br>
(and this isn’t to blow smoke) similar all this legal writing is.  It&lt;br>
seems like things should be fundamentally different, that memos should be&lt;br>
different than briefs, which in turn should be different than opinions. But it seems from my infant amount of exposure&lt;br>
that they are all basically the same, except for the&lt;br>
objective/subjective/decisionary tone or flavor they have. The only one that seems to be different is&lt;br>
academic legal writing, and even that isn’t much different. &lt;/p>
&lt;p> Enough&lt;br>
of that. So my draft decision is on the&lt;br>
judge’s desk: written, proofread and cite-checked. Once the staff attorney gave me some feed&lt;br>
back and subsequently signed off on it then there wasn’t really anything else I&lt;br>
could do on it and we put in on his desk. It is supposed to circulate today or tomorrow depending on when he gets&lt;br>
a chance to give it a read.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> While&lt;br>
I’m waiting on the judge to give me feedback so I can make some modifications&lt;br>
to it they have me starting on a much more intricate and difficult case. Me being the Nuevo-Hippy that I am this&lt;br>
environmental case is right up my alley. Essentially what is happening is that a water conservation public&lt;br>
interest group is suing a city about 35 minutes from Austin and two developers&lt;br>
to stop their development which the interest group thinks is going to kill some&lt;br>
of the springs around here. There are a&lt;br>
couple of pieces more, but I’ll be working on this case for a while. &lt;/p>
&lt;p> What&lt;br>
I’d like to dissertate upon is what I think this is all about. See the major problem is that, although I’ve&lt;br>
read the briefs and started doing the case research, it seems the interest&lt;br>
group may not have standing to bring the suit to enjoin the development, which&lt;br>
is their goal. If the interest group&lt;br>
fails to satisfy standing than I what I’ve been wondering about is what is the&lt;br>
point of it all. This interest group is&lt;br>
apparently very-well funded and their attorney is very well written, their&lt;br>
position is very well supported and from what I can tell they seem very determined. With that in mind, I have been wondering why&lt;br>
did they bring the suit if the excellent attorney knew or at least suspected&lt;br>
(which I must attribute to him since he has lost other suits on standing&lt;br>
grounds) that he would loose “early” in the litigation without even getting to&lt;br>
the merits of their claim. &lt;/p>
&lt;p> It&lt;br>
seems to me that the group is incurring the expense of this litigation for one&lt;br>
of two reasons. Either they want the&lt;br>
city and the developers to pay since they won the political battle (see infra)&lt;br>
or this is a watch-out suit. I love&lt;br>
local politics, especially in a smaller, well-educated town. All of this reminds me so much of
Aspen&lt;/p>
&lt;p>where everyone is&lt;br>
overly educated and therefore has an opinion and the smallest things get bogged&lt;br>
down due to the overload of opinions as to how “this should get done.” &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here there had&lt;br>
been a major political battle fought and the interest group lost. What happened was the city was looking to&lt;br>
lock in these developments within their jurisdiction since they would then&lt;br>
receive the tax revenue. So the city and&lt;br>
the developers signed a contract wherein the developers would promise to build&lt;br>
and the city would promise the developers environmental regulations that remain&lt;br>
constant for fifteen years. The interest&lt;br>
group at that point raised their BS flag and said hold on a minute here, if we&lt;br>
lobby the city council and win stricter environmental regulations (the&lt;br>
subdivisions are both in environmentally sensitive areas that recharge one of&lt;br>
the main aquifers around central Texas) at some point in the future (which they&lt;br>
have and they have) then we’re not getting the benefit of our bargain since the&lt;br>
development contract forecloses our right to democratic process. Since the interest group was getting no where&lt;br>
with the city council they moved on to the state legislature, when they lost&lt;br>
there and the state passed a bill saying that cities could do this, then they&lt;br>
filed suit. So this case has a lot of&lt;br>
vindictive overtones to it. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>The other thing&lt;br>
that could possibly be going on is that this could be watch-out&lt;br>
litigation. I think this is the more&lt;br>
probable scenario. Probably the interest&lt;br>
group is taking a hard line stance here in order to make development more&lt;br>
costly. If a developer was looking to&lt;br>
develop in this part of
Central Texas&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(which&lt;br>
apparently is booming) then the interest group has an interest in them not&lt;br>
developing in the environmentally sensitive areas. At a minimum the interest group’s litigation&lt;br>
would send a message to developers that developing in sensitive areas will be&lt;br>
more costly upfront than normal development, this cost-added should dampen some&lt;br>
of the development. Although certainly&lt;br>
raising the costs some would not preclude destructive development (which I&lt;br>
suspect is the interest group’s end goal). With regard to the city at least, the group may lose this battle, but it&lt;br>
seems they have won the war. The city&lt;br>
passed ordinances that are applicable to both its city limits and to its huge&lt;br>
extra-territorial jurisdiction in 2005 that truly do protect the environment in&lt;br>
the way that the interest group wanted to. I cannot claim to know that it was because of this litigation that the&lt;br>
city changed, but I suspect that to a certain extent it did. If nothing else the litigation raised public&lt;br>
awareness about what the development in environmentally sensitive areas was&lt;br>
doing to the water supply in this part of the state. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>The point of this&lt;br>
is that one of the things that I suspected all along and that is not (and&lt;br>
cannot) be taught to first year law students is that litigation is merely one&lt;br>
tool. Entities have goals, well they should&lt;br>
have goals at least, and they have various tools at their disposal that enable&lt;br>
them to reach their goals: contracts, political process, litigation and other&lt;br>
agreements or dispute resolution systems. The pedagogy of law schools puts such an emphasis on the cases that do&lt;br>
make it pretty far down the litigation road that I think sometimes there is a&lt;br>
danger for law students to lose track of how few those cases are and to what&lt;br>
the other ways to achieve ones goals may be. In this case that I’m working on I really don’t think that they care as&lt;br>
much about this litigation as their two feet high record may attest, I think&lt;br>
they are looking beyond this one development to how they can truly restrict&lt;br>
future harmful development. They have&lt;br>
used this litigation to either raise public awareness or to raise costs to&lt;br>
developers or to raise the political stakes for the city enough that in the end&lt;br>
they got what they wanted, no matter what the outcome of this case may be. **&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>work: week 1</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-05-23-work-week-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-05-23-work-week-1/</guid><description>&lt;p> I&lt;br>
am working on an interesting case. It is&lt;br>
ostensibly a property tax case, but that isn’t really the legal issue at stake&lt;br>
here. The easy rendition of the facts go&lt;br>
as such. 
Texas&lt;/p>
&lt;p>has an ad valoreum taxing system&lt;br>
wherein they tax property owner’s real and profit-producing-personal property&lt;br>
based upon the valuation of that property. In the spring of each year the central appraisal district for each&lt;br>
county notices all the taxpayers (persons and businesses) with what it think&lt;br>
the value of the property owner’s property is. The owners have an opportunity to protest before a quasi-judicial&lt;br>
appraisal review board (an administrative agency that is linked to the CAD) before&lt;br>
the ARB’s orders become final. In this&lt;br>
case the tax rolls (which are “sacred” in TX) were certified by the ARB without&lt;br>
protest by the taxpayers. Then TX was&lt;br>
looking to raise its income to provide financing to its schools, and so the&lt;br>
legislature passed a bill providing taxpayers amnesty. Normally if the CAD finds that you have more&lt;br>
property than they said you had you would be liable for back taxes (five years&lt;br>
back for real property that it didn’t know about and two years back for&lt;br>
personal property that it didn’t know about), but in order to get more&lt;br>
disclosures the legislature relaxed the back taxes if certain conditions were&lt;br>
met. In other words if you disclosed to&lt;br>
the CAD after the tax rolls were certified that you actually had more taxable&lt;br>
property than the CAD thought than you wouldn’t be liable for back taxes. Again, it was all under the guise of raising&lt;br>
financing for the school districts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> The&lt;br>
taxpayers in my case disclosed what they had and then the CAD renoticed their&lt;br>
appraised value, but they did it wrong. Since the CAD didn’t utilize the correct procedures the taxpayers&lt;br>
protested to the ARB. The ARB granted an&lt;br>
administrative hearing where the taxpayers argued both the lack of proper&lt;br>
notice as well as the fact that they didn’t even have property that had&lt;br>
originally been omitted and therefore their tax liability should not&lt;br>
increase. The ARB ruled only that the&lt;br>
tax liability would remain the same as was on the certified rolls. The CAD “thought” this meant they got a re-do&lt;br>
in order to correct their procedural errors, so they renoticed, again, the&lt;br>
taxpayers. The taxpayers protested,&lt;br>
again, and at the hearings the ARB this time ruled in favor of the CAD. The taxpayers appealed to district court who&lt;br>
ruled in their favor and now we have it on appeal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> Ostensibly,&lt;br>
the legal issue is whether claim preclusion is applicable to an administrative&lt;br>
hearing. I think that this is an&lt;br>
interesting question. The policy reasons&lt;br>
generally proffered for claim preclusion in a normal, judicial setting are&lt;br>
economy (we want litigants to bring all of their claims in one case), fairness&lt;br>
(we should not give litigants an opportunity to correct their “lawyering”&lt;br>
mistakes until they finally get it right) and finality (at some point we have&lt;br>
to end this, it is the same argument that supports statute of limitations). While it seems that we generally have adopted&lt;br>
claim preclusion, we have placed certain limitations on the doctrine. For the doctrine to be applicable the second&lt;br>
case must have be a (1) final decision (2) rendered by a competent tribunal (3)&lt;br>
that was resolved on the merits. These&lt;br>
three limits make sense in that if an action is still pending and could end up&lt;br>
either way there should be no preclusion on another case. If the court that rendered judgment on the&lt;br>
case never had any business hearing the case in the first place it also makes&lt;br>
sense that subsequent litigation should not pay homage to that decision. The final one is the most intricate, but it&lt;br>
also makes sense in the abstract, subsequent litigation should not be precluded&lt;br>
by prior litigation that was never “actually litigated.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p> Although&lt;br>
these policies are not that difficult to apply to a judicial setting that has&lt;br>
the pomp, circumstance, rules and societally recognized authority that a court&lt;br>
system maintains, it is more difficult to translate those principles to an&lt;br>
administrative setting. I do see a&lt;br>
certain simple beauty in applying procedural postures from the judicial setting&lt;br>
into the administrative (or quasi-judicial setting). It certainly would make things simple for&lt;br>
those who are advocating for their side of a dispute to prevail. But is it too simple to merely transpose&lt;br>
rules of evidence or rules of form or rules of procedure or other legal rules&lt;br>
and principles into a “foreign” setting? Without anything more than a simple adoption by the “foreign” tribunal I&lt;br>
think that would be fairly foolhardy, but if the same policy issues and&lt;br>
concerns that are supporting the legal principle or rule in the judicial&lt;br>
setting carry over than I think that it does make sense to transpose them to an&lt;br>
administrative setting. So when looking&lt;br>
to see whether a rule or principle would be applicable in a quasi-judicial&lt;br>
administrative hearing I think that courts have two options: (1) what does the&lt;br>
organic statute say, and/or (2) what policy measures support the legal principle&lt;br>
in its organic domain (usually the judicial realm) and whether those would also&lt;br>
support the adoption in the administrative setting. It does seem that the policies supporting&lt;br>
preclusion in the judicial setting would easily be adaptable to the administrative&lt;br>
setting. It does not seem to me that&lt;br>
economy, fairness and finality would NOT be transferable to the administrative&lt;br>
setting. &lt;/p>
&lt;p> That&lt;br>
paragraph is, basically, surplusage since
Texas&lt;/p>
&lt;p>case law has long held that the&lt;br>
principles of both claim and issue preclusion may be applied to administrative&lt;br>
settings under the same three limitations. In the judicial setting where subsequent litigants argue claim&lt;br>
preclusion I suspect that much of the analysis will turn on whether the&lt;br>
decision was on the merits. In the&lt;br>
administrative setting I suspect that much of the analysis in a case of first&lt;br>
impression will have to turn on the competent tribunal setting. This is an important analysis point and an&lt;br>
important limitation on the doctrine when applied to administrative&lt;br>
bodies. I do not suspect that society is&lt;br>
interested in recognizing the authority of a governmental body when that body&lt;br>
does not have the proper statutory or societal authority; or operates under&lt;br>
such a loose set of principles and rules that its decisions are fully&lt;br>
arbitrary; or does not allow grievances to be actually heard but merely makes&lt;br>
the decision that appears the best without giving due process to those who are&lt;br>
protesting. Yet if an administrative&lt;br>
body does operate under a certain grant of authority and does offer due process&lt;br>
and does operate under some guise of rules that lend authority to its rulings&lt;br>
then it makes sense that we should “listen to it.” &lt;/p>
&lt;p> The&lt;br>
other hard analysis is whether the decision of the administrative agency is&lt;br>
final. Obviously subsequent litigation&lt;br>
should not be precluded if the quasi-judicial body was only tabling the matter&lt;br>
until the agency fixed something. Conversely subsequent litigation should be precluded if the quasi-judicial&lt;br>
body was rendering an actual, binding ruling. This analysis, though facially simple, may not always be so easy in the&lt;br>
real world. I am fascinated by municipal&lt;br>
politics and have been known to watch Channel 3 while in
Nashville&lt;/p>
&lt;p>. I have seen the looseness under which some of these Boards operate&lt;br>
under. I have read the entire protest&lt;br>
hearing transcript in this case which only confirms my suspicion that these&lt;br>
hearings are not formal trials (and they should not be). The problem is for this case that at the&lt;br>
first hearings the board merely retained the tax liability as it was prior to&lt;br>
the first renoticing. But did that mean&lt;br>
that they were tabling the matter so the agency could fix the procedural&lt;br>
problems or did it mean that they were ruling on the merits. Although there is some bleed over into the&lt;br>
other element, the crux of the matter is here. &lt;/p>
&lt;p> Our&lt;br>
case tends to resolve itself here since even if they were tabling it they still&lt;br>
sent out a notice that said that it was the final ruling of the ARB. &lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>