<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/</link><description>A Site About Resilience and Authoritarianism</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</managingEditor><webMaster>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</webMaster><copyright>All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/law/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>On the Sovereignty of CryptoCurrencies -- What Bitcoin can Learn from Somaliland</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-08-14-bitcoin-somaliland/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-08-14-bitcoin-somaliland/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently a video was made: &amp;ldquo;The Declaration of Bitcoin's Independence&amp;rdquo;. Here's the video.&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XQqZ9b0S0BY" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>For those of you not involved with the, all in all, rather small cryptocurrency community the people in that video are some of the bigger names within the community. The village elders if you will. Not sure the village actually chose them, but elders tend to be self appointed anyway &amp;ndash; at least at first.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My friend and business partner, Preston, provided his response in &lt;a href="http://prestonbyrne.com/2014/08/14/tory-2/">this fine article&lt;/a>. I take an analogous, but distinct, view from Preston's.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="anarchists-go-experience-anarchy-or-shut-up">Anarchists: Go Experience Anarchy, Or Shut Up&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>One of the overarching points of the video is that Bitcoin is somehow sovereign, which I assume means a system unto itself. And I'm not simply picking out one word from many and obsessing about it. That is the entire point of a &amp;ldquo;Declaration of Independence&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; for a group to declare that it is no longer beholden to a prior sovereign and is now beholden to a different sovereign.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But who is the sovereign in which these individuals of common purpose are beholden to? Who knows.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I'm a relative outsider to this whole cryptocurrency thing. Sure, I'm trying to &lt;a href="https://erisindustries.com">build a business&lt;/a> which will utilize some of the technology underpinning cryptocurrencies. However, I am by no means a believer that a few cryptographic hashes and a fancy database somehow changes any of the real human dynamics which scientists, artists, philosophers, and the like have been pondering for a couple millennia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As an outsider, it is (anthropologically) interesting to watch a bunch of (predominantly) white (predominantly) Americans (and Canadians) purport to claim that an interesting payment protocol will solve world peace, governmental overreach, and all the other ills of modernity. The idea that somehow because there are cryptographic hashes and p2p communications protocol that those will suddenly shift the paradigm of modernity and that we can reach a point where governments are unnecessary is&amp;hellip; I'm not sure what it is actually.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I've lived in anarchy. I know what it looks like when governance systems collapse. I have felt how easy elite capture becomes in such situations. I have tasted hyper inflation. I challenge anyone who identifies as an anarchist to actually go to Somalia &amp;ndash; or another area where governance systems have collapsed for a significant amount of time. Spend some time there. Talk to people about their lives. Understand what the hell you're talking about.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Whatever the participants&amp;rsquo; individual motives are I cannot speak to, I suspect that many would identify more with libertarian thinking than pure anarchical thinking. For those that do have anarchical tendencies, please see above. For those that have libertarian thinking, please see below.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="lesson-1-declaring-independence-is-an-emotional-exercise-building-a-system-is-a-rational-exercise">Lesson 1: Declaring Independence is an Emotional Exercise; Building a System is a Rational Exercise&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In 1991 the elites of the Somalilanders &amp;ldquo;freedom&amp;rdquo; movement (it wasn't about freedom really, it was about capturing the state in the name of the Somalilanders) were forced by a bunch of emotional people to declare their independence from Somalia. Many at the time, and many today, question whether this heated, emotional, reaction was the correct decision. Nonetheless, it happened.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As most Democracy and Governance, Conflict Studies, and Crisis Situation scholars and practitioners understand declaring independence is the easy bit. Pretty words on paper (or in a video) don't mean anything in reality. They are simply those &amp;ndash; pretty words. They can inspire, sure, but beyond that they mean little.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the case of Somaliland it took about 13 years after the Declaration of Independence to have a really functional Constitution and the state building is still going on &amp;ndash; and likely will be for another two generations. It took a massively important leader with a real commitment to building a functional system who fought tooth and nail to build a constitution which was both responsive to constituent concerns while also setting the framework for a functional system. It took scholars, and discussion, and compromise, and &lt;em>work&lt;/em> to get there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The question I have for those who participated in this video is this: are you actually interested in doing the work necessary to craft a system? Only time will tell.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="lesson-2-if-you-want-to-sit-at-the-adults-table-act-like-adults">Lesson 2: If You Want to Sit At The Adults&amp;rsquo; Table Act Like Adults&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>During my time in Somaliland I said the above more times than I could count. Mostly in response to idiotic stuff whatever Minister or other person of purported power who was sitting in some vaunted chair did. It would drive me crazy that Somalilanders in positions of power would drone on about how they were a &amp;ldquo;real state&amp;rdquo; but how they continued to fail to perform the most basic of governance functions. You can't have it both ways I would tell my friends. Either you need to do the work, make the sacrifices, and be your own state, or else you just need to shut up. More times than I currently care to count, I would watch the Somaliland government act as a rebel organization acts and then go on BBC Somali asking why the world wasn't treating them like a state. Most of the time the reason the &amp;ldquo;world&amp;rdquo; wasn't treating them like a state was because they weren't acting as a state acts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I view the cryptocommunity through a similar lens. It talks &amp;ndash; &lt;strong>at nauseum&lt;/strong> &amp;ndash; about how it &lt;em>deserves&lt;/em> to be taken seriously. Really? Why? What has it done to &lt;em>deserve&lt;/em> being taken seriously? Certainly there is some very interesting technology that has been built. And that technology should be taken seriously. As technology.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But Bitcoiners, and the cryptocommunity more generally, should not somehow be free from the normal rules which apply. If those inside the cryptocommunity want cryptocurrencies to be treated &lt;em>as&lt;/em> currency, then they must abide by the &lt;em>normal&lt;/em> rules which attend to handling money.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These rules &lt;em>are&lt;/em> onerous, precisely because businesses which deal with folks&amp;rsquo; money are, well, dealing with folks&amp;rsquo; money. I do not understand why cryptocurrencies businesses should somehow get a bye as to providing proper safeguards, as has been agreed in the relevant states are necessary.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="lesson-3-real-systems-empower-professionals-and-root-out-scammers">Lesson 3: Real Systems Empower Professionals and Root Out Scammers&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When I was in Hargeisa some of the more interesting people I hung out with were folks who were trying to set up a governmental quality assurance system. There were a lot of problems that needed to be tackled, but foremost on the minds of these scientists (some of who had been trained locally some of whom had been trained abroad) was the difficulty of ensuring that medicines were proper. There was (and likely still is) a huge problem of knock-off drugs, mislabeled drugs, and the like. These scientists were trying to tackle this. Because it was putting the health of community members in jeopardy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I enjoyed my time with these scientists and doers precisely because they saw a collective problem and were trying to do something about it &amp;ndash; despite the odds. The odds being that big importers who supported big actors within the government make more money off fake drugs than real ones. The odds being that quality assurance of medicines is not one of aid's current hot topics (and therefore there was no aid money to support their activities). The odds being that of all the problems in Hargeisa this was not the one that was on the tip of folks&amp;rsquo; minds &amp;ndash; except for when those folks had sick kids. Despite those odds, these guys were trying to do something to protect folks. And that was awesome from my perspective. They are a &lt;strong>long&lt;/strong> way from solving this issue, but they are trying.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What is the cryptocommunity doing about rooting out scammers? There are, indeed, some efforts. And I hope that they continue, because the cryptocommunity has a huge scammers problem that needs to be addressed in a fundamental way. It isn't likely to happen with a technological solution; it is much more likely to happen via legal or social mechanisms. But so far we've only seen a few of these take place.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Time will tell how this all plays out. Indeed, most of this is about the community more generally than a response to the specifics of that video. I think there is some very interesting technology which bitcoin has brought to people's attention. It would be a shame if that technology was overshadowed by people projecting their issues and complaints with bigger systemic issues on it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How I Would Structure Automatic Virtual Contracts</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-17-structuring-automatic-virtual-contracts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-17-structuring-automatic-virtual-contracts/</guid><description>&lt;p>Automatic contracts have been occupying a great deal of my free mental energies for the past few weeks since I first learned that there are platforms in the works that will allow for such things to happen. My thoughts on this are quite nascent, as is the technology, but here are my early observations.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Automatic virtual contracts are, essentially, small computer scripts which are linked to virtual currency wallets. The basic idea is that a financial transaction and the terms and conditions governing the transaction collapse into a singular instrument &amp;ndash; or script.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An example will probably make this easier to visualize. You and I want to make a contract, say, for me to deliver to you X widgets at Y time at Z price. Perhaps you don't trust that I will be able to deliver to you the widgets at the time. Perhaps I don't trust that you will be able to pay me for the widgets when I have delivered them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a traditional contract scenario, we would overcome this lack of trust in a couple of ways. Either we would put the money into an escrow account controlled &amp;ndash; likely &amp;ndash; by one of our banks. Or you would execute a Letter of Credit from your bank (which really only addresses the latter of the trust issues). Or we would just trust each other based on our reputations or our past business dealings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Virtual automatic contracts overcome the trust issues in roughly the same ways. One of the key differences is that the computers act as the intermediaries rather than a large, stable financial institution such as a bank. While it is true that many people who operate in the global marketplace do have banks, it is also true that there are significant numbers who do not have or do not want bank accounts. Virtual automatic currencies would offer these individuals (as well as the banked individuals) a mechanism to operate in the global economy just as effectively and (perhaps more) efficiently than those individuals who are banked.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The analogous transaction to the escrow scenario would probably follow a sequence such as: I offer you the contract by sending you the script; you accept the contract by transferring the cost of the contract (or part of it) to a virtual currency &amp;ldquo;account&amp;rdquo; which is controlled solely by the script; we both &amp;ldquo;push&amp;rdquo; the script out into the network which verifies all of the aspects of the contract; when I deliver and you certify delivery the script automatically transfers the virtual currency to an &amp;ldquo;account&amp;rdquo; which I control from the &amp;ldquo;account&amp;rdquo; controlled solely by the script.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The analogous transaction to the letter of credit scenario or to the &amp;ldquo;just trust me&amp;rdquo; scenario would probably follow a sequence such as: I offer you the contract by sending you the script; you accept the contract by placing your &amp;ldquo;account&amp;rdquo; details into a field on the script; we both &amp;ldquo;push&amp;rdquo; the script out to into the network which verifies all of the aspects of the contract; when I deliver and you certify delivery the script automatically transfers the virtual currency to an &amp;ldquo;account&amp;rdquo; which I control from your &amp;ldquo;account&amp;rdquo;. There are a few varietals of this script which could be developed which would (1) verify you have enough currency to pay for the delivery upon the occurrence of one or more events along the trajectory of completion of the contract and (2) structure payment schemes besides a one off payment upon delivery to other schemes staggered throughout the contract's trajectory and based upon the occurrence of one or more events.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Beyond being able to have some amount of trust in complex commercial transactions for unbanked individuals, there are numerous other benefits to virtual automatic currencies which would extend to both unbanked and banked individuals.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="speed-and-transaction-costs">Speed and Transaction Costs&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Banks are slow. Escrow and letters of credit are costly. International wire transfers are slow and costly. Automatic virtual currencies would collapse this. Currently transaction costs in the bitcoin network for instance are on the order of 10%-50% of the costs for accepting credit cards. In low margin industries which have a lot of transactions this is a significant reduction in transaction costs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition, bitcoin transactions are fast. Even getting money into your bank from a bitcoin transaction is not very slow. Most payment providers in the developed world will give you the money to your account that evening after you have developed a history with them. If you and I were both to keep some not trivial amount of our working and operating capital in bitcoin already then the payment speed dividend increases dramatically because the real time sink in the network at this point is moving from the virtual currency (bitcoin) to a &amp;ldquo;fiat&amp;rdquo; currency and depositing that fiat currency into your bank account.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Those are two huge advantages. For me, the seller, I would receive the value almost instantly upon certification of the delivery by the buyer. For both of us, reducing the transaction costs (which are traditionally priced into the overall transaction and either shared between the seller and the buyer or just paid for by the buyer) will be reduced and thus the cost to the buyer for the widgets should be reduced.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="uncertainty-and-ambiguity">Uncertainty and Ambiguity&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>One of the things that is most promising aspects to automatic virtual contracts, but also perhaps one of the most difficult aspects in contracting generally, is their ability to reduce uncertainty and ambiguity within the contract.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Automatic virtual contracts are computer scripts. Computer scripts do not like ambiguity. Indeed, computers are mostly too dumb to handle ambiguity. Presumably, it will be the role of the cryptography network supporting the contract's dissemination and execution to ensure that there is a lack of ambiguity. It is unlikely that simple transactions such as the one I've been using here will have any significant level of ambiguity to the contract whether it is virtual or traditional &amp;ndash; but for other types of contracts or bylaws (think trust establishment documents or a corporation's bylaws operating as virtual automatic contracts) where ambiguity could potentially be higher this is a bigger concern.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Reducing contractual ambiguity is usually the lawyer's job when drafting or reviewing a contract or other instrument. In a virtual automatic contract network, though, reducing ambiguity would likely be a three prong effort shared between the lawyer, the coder (who will likely be the same in coming generations), and the network. This would put more eyeballs on the problem. Also, programming is very different than drafting a contract because the computer needs precision. This will force lawyers|coders to develop contractual instruments which rely upon verification metrics for various parts of the contract which will inherently reduce its ambiguity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When it comes to scripting, the scripting language itself handles whether a comma should be in a given location or not; there is no argument over whether to include an Oxford comma in an array; there is no argument over whether a defined term is an operative method or not. The nature of computers and scripting languages reduces these typical ambiguities into a binary determination: it is, or it is not. Judges may have to learn how to read computer scripts, but it is likely that they will have less of a role in determining whether A set of words and punctuation should yield B result or C result as that will be handled by the language and the network. This will reduce ambiguity throughout the entire commercial network &amp;ndash; a very good thing if you ask any business person you know.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I'm using uncertainty here as analogous to risk generally, or &amp;ldquo;all the other stuff surrounding the contract&amp;rdquo;. On a simple contract which I have been using as an example in this post, there will be uncertainty for me that you will not find a better price on the widgets and just send them back to me after I have delivered them; there will be uncertainty for you that I will deliver the widgets at the quality specified. Admittedly, automatic virtual contracts cannot be a panacea to address these uncertainties because there are no real strong answers here. However, a few things could be done to address them. If we know that my widgets weigh Q grams, and we have access to a postal or courier's API then we can check that I have sent Q grams * X widgets (plus some packaging weight) to you &amp;ndash; thereby reducing your uncertainty. Of course this wouldn't address the quality of the widgets. That would be nearly impossible to overcome unless we could easily agree to a level of precision that a computer could check.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One potential way to address this uncertainty is by placing some third party &amp;ldquo;referee&amp;rdquo; into the system. These people could operate similar to how insurance adjusters worked in prior economies. They would largely be independent contractors who would work for the network and could be used to certify that I have delivered X widgets to you at Y time and they meet the quality standards we agreed to in the contract. Once the referee certifies the delivery to the network, then the script would automatically execute whatever was next in the series of events (likely, paying me). Potentially in international shipping government customs investigators (married with APIs) could also have a role in such a system. The big take away here is that wherever there is a subjective determination that some event has taken place, any way to build that into an API framework or utilization of a neutral referee would work to reduce the uncertainty. This is not necessarily transformative, indeed such systems are in place today in various capacities. The biggest difference here is that the referees could work independently and be certified and paid by the network itself so they would only have an interest in ensuring the validity of the contract rather than one party or the other succeeding (or course they could always be paid off by one side to say yes or no, but we'll likely always have to live with that uncertainty).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="summation">Summation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This post has examined an extremely simple contract, which is where the ecosystem will have to begin. But once the ecosystem matures a bit the possibilities here for reducing commercial transaction friction and further decentralizing while also globalizing economies is utterly fascinating. A good friend and I are working on a business proposal which would leverage these types of transactions so hopefully there will be more on the horizon to this end.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>