<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>law on underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/law/</link><description>Recent content in law on underWater desert Blogging</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/law/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>On the Sovereignty of CryptoCurrencies -- What Bitcoin can Learn from Somaliland</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-08-14-bitcoin-somaliland/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-08-14-bitcoin-somaliland/</guid><description>Anarchy isn't great. People are not immune to the system. These are things which adding a nice payment protocol and some interesting cryptographic hashes does not change.</description></item><item><title>How I Would Structure Automatic Virtual Contracts</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-17-structuring-automatic-virtual-contracts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-17-structuring-automatic-virtual-contracts/</guid><description>EAutomatic contracts have been occupying a great deal of my free mental energies for the past few weeks since I first learned that there are platforms in the works that will allow for such things to happen. My thoughts on this are quite nascent, as is the technology, but here are my early observations.</description></item><item><title>Obama on the Judiciary</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-12-obama-on-the-judiciary/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-12-obama-on-the-judiciary/</guid><description>[This ][1]is very lucid.  Obama wrote it after Roberts&amp;rsquo; nomination.</description></item><item><title>Admission of Evidence in International Courts</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-11-07-admission-of-evidence-in-international-courts/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-11-07-admission-of-evidence-in-international-courts/</guid><description>[]: &lt;a href="http://sudanwatch.blogspot.com/">http://sudanwatch.blogspot.com/&lt;/a></description></item><item><title>Death penalty</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-10-death-penalty/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-10-death-penalty/</guid><description>According to Amnesty’s site, today is [Anti-Death Penalty Day][1].  I wonder what color bracelet I’m supposed to be wearing to fit in…</description></item><item><title>Chuckie Gets More Charges</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-09-07-chuckie-gets-more-charges/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-09-07-chuckie-gets-more-charges/</guid><description>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/09/07/180pxcharlestaylor.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/09/07/180pxcharlestaylor.jpg&lt;/a></description></item><item><title>Hamdan Redux</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-26-hamdan-redux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-26-hamdan-redux/</guid><description>i’m not as huge a bush hater as many others who score similarly on political spectrum tests.  however, i continued to be amazed at the recalcitrant-ness of his administration.  throughout the short american constitutional history there have been contentious constitutional issues that have pitted the three branches of governance against each other in varying degrees of allied and opposition poses.: executive v. legislative, legislative v. judiciary, executive &amp;amp; legislative v. judiciary, etc.  however, the end to the tension usually comes (at least in the governance sector, even if it lingers in the civil &amp;amp; media sectors) when the supreme court rules on an issue.  if the court rules against one of the other branches in on a constitutional issue, its word is final.  full stop.  however when the court rules on other issues of law, adminsitrative, legislative, international then it may not be the final say.  the executive or legislative often will have a second crack even if one of their actions was nulled by a decision of the court.  that said, most times, the other branches second cracks will show much more deference to the legal reasoning which the court adopted (usually because a constitutional challenge to the second crack may be waiting in the wings and if the court has shown a leaning in a particular decision the legislative and executive would not want to get overturned on constitutional grounds as that would be the end of the story again).  but the bush executive branch seems to evince little of the traditional gentlemanliness with which this country has been governed for years.  latest in the saga of the Hamdan v. Rumsfeld decision is the executive issuing an executive order that CIA interrogation techniques, if conducted for the purpose of eliciting intelligence are per sae legal.  there are a few nuances in the order, first the techniques must not violate the McCain Ammendment against torture or dismemberment (but according to most human rights decisions this leaves a wide berth).  secondly, the techniques must not be conducted with the purpose of degrading the human.  well, shit, that just about guts the protections that the Hamdan decision offered to detainees at Guantanamo (and hopefully by extrapolation to other detention facilities, although there is no jurisprudence on point with regards to that issue — yet).</description></item><item><title>drama</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-06-04-drama/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-06-04-drama/</guid><description>[crazy drama][1] in the courtroom today as we went to open our case.</description></item><item><title>no rest for the wicked.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-03-08-no-rest-for-the-wicked/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-03-08-no-rest-for-the-wicked/</guid><description>so i’ve worked twenty-three of the last twenty-five days. average day length: 12 hours. average number of documents per day: varies. this week have not left the office before midnight, except for meals. likely this time will creap later and later as we approach our deadline.</description></item><item><title>Witness Protection in the Third World</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-20-witness-protection-in-the-third-world/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-20-witness-protection-in-the-third-world/</guid><description>Today I would like to soapbox about something not really close to my heart but that I’ve been pondering lately.  How is protecting high-profile witnesses here different than it is in developed countries?  I mean I’ve seen Joe Dirt and therefore I know most of what there is to know about witness protection in the US.  But I don’t know anything about it here.  Let’s explore.</description></item><item><title>unilateral v. multilateral humanitarian interventionism</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-07-unilateral-v-multilateral-humanitarian-interventionism/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-07-unilateral-v-multilateral-humanitarian-interventionism/</guid><description>I had a conversation I had with a Swiss woman who I work with about non-feasance as a basis for criminal prosecution.  I would like to proffer my philosophical ramblings about humanitarian interventionism, which is inextricably linked to non-feasance.  Obviously there are other links, to the duties in the genocide convention.  Maybe the best way to delimit the discussion is to speak solely about the Genocide convention.  I understand that without further legal research I may not have full comprehension of the &lt;em>legal&lt;/em> bounds of the duty.  That said, I would like to explore whether humanitarian interventionism is a duty that states should impose upon states.</description></item><item><title>Institutional Allocation as between International Organizations</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-10-26-institutional-allocation-as-between-international-organizations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-10-26-institutional-allocation-as-between-international-organizations/</guid><description>I created the following document in order to get some thoughts straight for a presentation I have tomorrow.  It is longer than my presentation will take, and much of it may be out of view for some of you, but I’m putting it up here b/c I think it is pretty good encapsulation of many of the things I’ve learned this semester.  It is not cited.  If you think I need to cite in a blog, go fuck yourself.</description></item><item><title>internship journal for the last week</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-16-internship-journal-for-the-last-week/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-16-internship-journal-for-the-last-week/</guid><description>the following is my excerpt from my last journal entry, which i had to submit to my faculty advisor:</description></item><item><title>work: week 2</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-05-29-work-week-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-05-29-work-week-2/</guid><description>This</description></item><item><title>work: week 1</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-05-23-work-week-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-05-23-work-week-1/</guid><description>I</description></item></channel></rss>