<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>law on underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/law/</link><description>Recent content in law on underWater desert Blogging</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Casey Kuhlman</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/law/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>On the Sovereignty of CryptoCurrencies -- What Bitcoin can Learn from Somaliland</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-08-14-bitcoin-somaliland/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-08-14-bitcoin-somaliland/</guid><description>Recently a video was made: &amp;ldquo;The Declaration of Bitcoin's Independence&amp;rdquo;. Here's the video.
For those of you not involved with the, all in all, rather small cryptocurrency community the people in that video are some of the bigger names within the community. The village elders if you will. Not sure the village actually chose them, but elders tend to be self appointed anyway &amp;ndash; at least at first.
My friend and business partner, Preston, provided his response in this fine article.</description></item><item><title>How I Would Structure Automatic Virtual Contracts</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-02-17-structuring-automatic-virtual-contracts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-02-17-structuring-automatic-virtual-contracts/</guid><description>Automatic contracts have been occupying a great deal of my free mental energies for the past few weeks since I first learned that there are platforms in the works that will allow for such things to happen. My thoughts on this are quite nascent, as is the technology, but here are my early observations.
Introduction Automatic virtual contracts are, essentially, small computer scripts which are linked to virtual currency wallets. The basic idea is that a financial transaction and the terms and conditions governing the transaction collapse into a singular instrument &amp;ndash; or script.</description></item><item><title>Obama on the Judiciary</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-06-12-obama-on-the-judiciary/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-06-12-obama-on-the-judiciary/</guid><description>This is very lucid. Obama wrote it after Roberts&amp;rsquo; nomination.
According to the storyline that drives many advocacy groups and Democratic
activists – a storyline often reflected in comments on this blog – we are up
against a sharply partisan, radically conservative, take-no-prisoners Republican
party. They have beaten us twice by energizing their base with red meat
rhetoric and single-minded devotion and discipline to their agenda. In order to</description></item><item><title>Admission of Evidence in International Courts</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-11-07-admission-of-evidence-in-international-courts/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-11-07-admission-of-evidence-in-international-courts/</guid><description>So, have commented on a blog besides my own for the first time. []: http://sudanwatch.blogspot.com/
I have been reading Chris Blattman’s blog on development for a while, and today he posed a question about the admissibility of evidence. He was legitimately questioning whether, as a legal or policy reason, drawing made by children in Darfur (such as the one presented here) should be admitted if they ever get Harun and Rahman.</description></item><item><title>Death penalty</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-10-10-death-penalty/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-10-10-death-penalty/</guid><description>According to Amnesty’s site, today is Anti-Death Penalty Day. I wonder what color bracelet I’m supposed to be wearing to fit in…
Conscious that I’m treading in shark-infested waters, especially with my family: I’m not vehemently anti-death penalty. But I am death penalty. Not so much for the cruel nature of the punishment. I don’t think the act itself it is normatively worse than keeping someone in prison for their life.</description></item><item><title>Chuckie Gets More Charges</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-09-07-chuckie-gets-more-charges/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-09-07-chuckie-gets-more-charges/</guid><description>The DA in Miami has added more counts of torture to Chuckie’s indictment. His trial is set to begin in Miami in January 2008. I find it cute that father and son will begin their trials at about the same time. []: http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/09/07/180pxcharlestaylor.jpg
Chuckie is Charles Taylor’s son, he was the former President (dictator) of Liberia who was one of the most infamous warlords ever. The African President from Lord of War was based (loosely) on Charles Taylor.</description></item><item><title>Hamdan Redux</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-07-26-hamdan-redux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-07-26-hamdan-redux/</guid><description>i’m not as huge a bush hater as many others who score similarly on political spectrum tests. however, i continued to be amazed at the recalcitrant-ness of his administration. throughout the short american constitutional history there have been contentious constitutional issues that have pitted the three branches of governance against each other in varying degrees of allied and opposition poses.: executive v. legislative, legislative v. judiciary, executive &amp;amp; legislative v. judiciary, etc.</description></item><item><title>drama</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-06-04-drama/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-06-04-drama/</guid><description>crazy drama in the courtroom today as we went to open our case.
~ # ~</description></item><item><title>no rest for the wicked.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-03-08-no-rest-for-the-wicked/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-03-08-no-rest-for-the-wicked/</guid><description>so i’ve worked twenty-three of the last twenty-five days. average day length: 12 hours. average number of documents per day: varies. this week have not left the office before midnight, except for meals. likely this time will creap later and later as we approach our deadline.
i asked my magic eight ball when i can expect some time off, it replied: the outlook is not good.
so much for my theory that no one works as hard as americans, and therefore i won’t be working that hard in africa.</description></item><item><title>Witness Protection in the Third World</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-02-20-witness-protection-in-the-third-world/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-02-20-witness-protection-in-the-third-world/</guid><description>Today I would like to soapbox about something not really close to my heart but that I’ve been pondering lately. How is protecting high-profile witnesses here different than it is in developed countries? I mean I’ve seen Joe Dirt and therefore I know most of what there is to know about witness protection in the US. But I don’t know anything about it here. Let’s explore.
In some ways it may be easier to hide and protect a witness in a developing country.</description></item><item><title>unilateral v. multilateral humanitarian interventionism</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-02-07-unilateral-v-multilateral-humanitarian-interventionism/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-02-07-unilateral-v-multilateral-humanitarian-interventionism/</guid><description>I had a conversation I had with a Swiss woman who I work with about non-feasance as a basis for criminal prosecution. I would like to proffer my philosophical ramblings about humanitarian interventionism, which is inextricably linked to non-feasance. Obviously there are other links, to the duties in the genocide convention. Maybe the best way to delimit the discussion is to speak solely about the Genocide convention. I understand that without further legal research I may not have full comprehension of the legal bounds of the duty.</description></item><item><title>Institutional Allocation as between International Organizations</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-10-26-institutional-allocation-as-between-international-organizations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-10-26-institutional-allocation-as-between-international-organizations/</guid><description>I created the following document in order to get some thoughts straight for a presentation I have tomorrow. It is longer than my presentation will take, and much of it may be out of view for some of you, but I’m putting it up here b/c I think it is pretty good encapsulation of many of the things I’ve learned this semester. It is not cited. If you think I need to cite in a blog, go fuck yourself.</description></item><item><title>internship journal for the last week</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-06-16-internship-journal-for-the-last-week/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-06-16-internship-journal-for-the-last-week/</guid><description>the following is my excerpt from my last journal entry, which i had to submit to my faculty advisor:
 this week
the claim preclusion opinion that i drafted, and was circulated, was
returned. the comments and feedback were
interesting and varied greatly from the judge who is on the campaign trail
right now who signed off without a single pen change to the judge who
“couldn’t” comment because there was “too much work” to be done on it (she also</description></item><item><title>work: week 2</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-05-29-work-week-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-05-29-work-week-2/</guid><description>This
was a bit of a transitional week as I finished up with the preclusion case and
settled into quite a monster of a case. The one thing that has struck me as I’ve been reading the briefs is how
(and this isn’t to blow smoke) similar all this legal writing is. It
seems like things should be fundamentally different, that memos should be
different than briefs, which in turn should be different than opinions.</description></item><item><title>work: week 1</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-05-23-work-week-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-05-23-work-week-1/</guid><description>I
am working on an interesting case. It is
ostensibly a property tax case, but that isn’t really the legal issue at stake
here. The easy rendition of the facts go
as such. Texas
has an ad valoreum taxing system
wherein they tax property owner’s real and profit-producing-personal property
based upon the valuation of that property. In the spring of each year the central appraisal district for each
county notices all the taxpayers (persons and businesses) with what it think</description></item></channel></rss>