<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/</link><description>A Site About Resilience and Authoritarianism</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</managingEditor><webMaster>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</webMaster><copyright>All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/living/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Do You Feel Safer Now: Reflections on the Ten Year Anniversary of Iraqi Invasion</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-03-20-do-you-feel-safer-now-reflections-on-the-ten-year-anniversary-of-iraqi-invasion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-03-20-do-you-feel-safer-now-reflections-on-the-ten-year-anniversary-of-iraqi-invasion/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/yatesaustin/237347393">&lt;img src="http://blog.caseykuhlman.com/assets/images/2013/237347393_5b0a2f1121_z.jpg" alt="Peace or V for Victory by yater @ flickr" tit="Peace or V for Victory by yater @ flickr" />&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On a day, of which the tenth anniversary is fast approaching, I was standing on a roundabout watching a bunch of people I knew and a machine I was familiar with rip down a statute. It was a day seared into my memory as I was thoroughly convinced that I was in the midst of an iconic moment. In some ways that belief was correct. Only it was just not the type of icon I was thinking it would be.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="baghdad-early-2003">Baghdad, Early, 2003&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I wrote a book, and sold it based upon simply being present on that day in that locattion. I’ve been asked to give interviews (generally all around March or April of each year) not because I have anything particularly insightful to say about the invasion of Iraq, but merely because I was there. Present. Around. As the color of that day slowly desaturates in a process which only time understands and can justify, I have been reflecting not upon a machine, a chain, and a bronze statute. Instead, I’ve been reflecting upon something else.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At some point in the day, I and some friends were asked to give an interview. This was an exciting opportunity for the 26 year old version of the version of me currently typing this. It was exciting for two reasons in particular. First, I knew that there was a decent chance that word of the interview would float through the social networks of the time to my family. I thought someone somewhere will see this and let someone know and thereon until (hopefully) my family get some word that everything was OK. Second, I was excited about the interview because it was with ABC News. This was the outlet I used to watch as a growing child, a nightly voice, iconography, and color scheme that I knew well. I, along with some other friends, was going to be interviewed by Peter Jennings. And that dude’s a legend.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During the interview, I’m pretty sure that I really only had one line. Too nervous (and star struck perhaps) to say much else. But I did get in a line. Later my mother told me that while she recognized my face during the first part of the interview, she only really &lt;em>knew&lt;/em> it was me when she saw the sarcasm drip from my mouth. The irony is that, for once in my life, I actually wasn’t trying to be sarcastic. Peter asked the group of three or four of us that were gathered on the balcony of the Palestine Hotel if we felt safer now that we were in Baghdad. It was, frankly, a stupid question to ask a group of Marines from an infantry battalion laden with weapons and youthful egos.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My friend Jack, who eventually became my co-author, gave the answer that you are supposed to give in such situations. He said that it did not matter, that our guard was up and we were fully prepared for anything that may come — whether that was a chicken dinner or a bunch of bullets — and that we were ready and capable of responding appropriately. During the days that followed, in the chaos that was the early days of post-invasion Baghdad, we would have to face both of those scenarios, and many more, sometimes at the same moment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The war junky reporter on the ground pointed the mic at me, and (at least as I remember it) I simply asked one question: “Do &lt;em>you&lt;/em> feel safer now that we are here?”&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="twenty-nine-palms-ca-late-2002">Twenty-Nine Palms, CA, Late, 2002&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the run up to the war I did not allow any part of my brain to engage in an intellectual discourse with any other part of my brain as to the rightness or wrongness of the job any idiot could see was coming for us. I had a job to do, and I was damn determined to be good at that job. Or at least, to try my best to be good at it. I was worried that if I allowed the self-felating ethical discourse to overtake and supplant my thinking that I would not be as fast, as precise, as &lt;em>on&lt;/em> as I needed to be in order to actually accomplish the job that was coming for me. Perhaps, upon reflection from the perspective of ten years, that was the incorrect decision.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Perhaps it was the correct decision. Either way, it would not have mattered. I did not meet the religious pre-affiliation rules in order to actually be a conscientious objector and therefore it was going to be an offense that would lead me to a court martial if I did not do my best to accomplish my job. And when I’m brutally honest with myself, I was excited about it. I wanted to go. Because when you go into the Marines, especially into an infantry battalion, if you don’t go to war it is basically just masturbation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During this time, before we deployed to Kuwait, my friend Faith forwarded an email detailing the time and location of upcoming anti-war demonstrations in New Orleans where she was living at the time. To my …@usmc.mil email address. When I first got the email I smiled. I was pleased that anti-war demonstrations were happening. In some ways it made it easier to accept my own, conscious, lack of any ethical discourse within myself. But to my work email address? I saw that it was just to a bunch of people, as many forwarded emails were in the times before facebook. So I didn’t really blame her. Yet, I did respond to the email. Although I don’t fully remember what I wrote, I think it was something along the lines of “Thanks for the email. I fully support your right to do that. Just don’t send any such emails to my work account!”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I do remember thinking at one point after I replied (in probably an overly cold way) that that was their job and I had my job and our jobs were different. Then I simply put it out of my mind and went about preparing what needed to be prepared.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="hargeisa-somaliland-early-2013">Hargeisa, Somaliland, Early, 2013&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>My reply to Peter Jennings was not meant as sarcasm. My reply was meant honestly. Although my voice, combined with my love of sarcasm, led most to believe I meant it sarcastically. After the intensity of the now that was then has dissipated and we Americans are forced to live with the choices of the leaders we chose, and the knowledge that many Iraqis are also forced to live with the choices of the leaders they did not choose, I will ask it again. “Do you feel safer now that we are here?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I will stop at this point and say one thing. If someone wants to put some faux comment on this post saying, “thank you for your service” I will delete it. I absolutely abhor those comments. They ring hollow to me and mean absolutely nothing. I did not really serve. I did a job. Sure those that entered the armed forces after 9/11 knew, in a way that I had no idea of when I signed on the line, or, at a minimum, they had some idea of, what they were getting into. Perhaps they “served” in the sense that word is often used. But I did not. I simply did a job. A job that I was contractually obliged to do. And, perhaps, wanted to do. But either way, it was a job.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yet there’s another, more important, reason that I abhor that phrase.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="champaign-illinois-late-1999">Champaign, Illinois, Late, 1999&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We had a tradition in our Naval Reserve Officer’s Training Corp (ROTC) group that on the last Thursday before anyone graduated they had an opportunity to take the floor. Most used it as a way to proffer vapid “advice” on matters of which they knew not or to provide idiotic thank yous to people they would never see again and perhaps neither liked nor respected. That all seemed quite stupid to my 23 year old self. When my turn came, after some of my best and greatest friends had their chance to say what they felt appropriate to say, I stood up and recited the following.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>John Brown went off to war to fight on a foreign shore
His mama sure was proud of him!
He stood straight and tall in his uniform and all
His mama’s face broke out all in a grin&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Oh son, you look so fine, I’m glad you’re a son of mine
You make me proud to know you hold a gun
Do what the captain says, lots of medals you will get
And we’ll put them on the wall when you come home”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As that old train pulled out, John’s ma began to shout
Tellin’ ev’ryone in the neighborhood:
“That’s my son that’s about to go, he’s a soldier now, you know”
She made well sure her neighbors understood&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She got a letter once in a while and her face broke into a smile
As she showed them to the people from next door
And she bragged about her son with his uniform and gun
And these things you called a good old-fashioned war&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh! Good old-fashioned war!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then the letters ceased to come, for a long time they did not come
They ceased to come for about ten months or more
Then a letter finally came saying, “Go down and meet the train
Your son’s a-coming home from the war”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She smiled and went right down, she looked everywhere around
But she could not see her soldier son in sight
But as all the people passed, she saw her son at last
When she did she could hardly believe her eyes&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh his face was all shot up and his hand was all blown off
And he wore a metal brace around his waist
He whispered kind of slow, in a voice she did not know
While she couldn’t even recognize his face!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh! Lord! Not even recognize his face&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Oh tell me, my darling son, pray tell me what they done
How is it you come to be this way?”
He tried his best to talk but his mouth could hardly move
And the mother had to turn her face away&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Don’t you remember, Ma, when I went off to war
You thought it was the best thing I could do?
I was on the battleground, you were home . . . acting proud
You wasn’t there standing in my shoes”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Oh, and I thought when I was there, God, what am I doing here?
I’m a-tryin’ to kill somebody or die tryin’
But the thing that scared me most was when my enemy came close
And I saw that his face looked just like mine”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh! Lord! Just like mine!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“And I couldn’t help but think, through the thunder rolling and stink
That I was just a puppet in a play
And through the roar and smoke, this string is finally broke
And a cannonball blew my eyes away”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As he turned away to walk, his Ma was still in shock
At seein’ the metal brace that helped him stand
But as he turned to go, he called his mother close
And he dropped his medals down into her hand&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ John Brown by Bob Dylan (lyrics available &lt;a href="http://www.bobdylan.com/us/songs/john-brown#ixzz2O6Kzjo5a" title="Bob Dylan - John Brown">here&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Here I was, 23. Mere days from beginning The Basic School, which is where all Marine Officers begin their journey. Reciting the lyrics of a poet famously known for his anti-war positions to a bunch of people who were only months away from beginning their journeys in the military. But I had a point. A point I still believe deeply in. A point I never explained, as when I finished reciting the poetry that is Dylan’s song I simply walked out of the room (or just sat down, can’t remember exactly).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fourteen years later, let me get to the point. If you are going to do this thing called the military. Called war. Know what the hell you are getting yourself into.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I did not mean don’t do war, and there is nothing within the song (even from my now quite adamant anti-war position) that is actually overtly anti-war. The real message of the song is that those that cheerlead for war without understanding the consequences of what they are saying do a great disservice to those that actually do go to war. Those that go to war, that enter the military, are forced to struggle with what this means to each. This thing we call war. Of course what it means, being an existential question, will differ from person to person. The point is not the answer arrived at by any individual, the point is that the individual took that journey. Dylan was not saying that those people who embark upon this journey and exit it with some conclusion are bad. He was not saying that war was bad or good, right or wrong, or any other other banal symbols lazy people use when they do not want to struggle with a difficult question. What Dylan was saying is that those who cheerlead from the sidelines but do not embark upon this journey themselves — with honesty and self-reflection — are more harming to society than those that hold the guns and fire the rounds.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="hargeisa-somaliland-early-2013-1">Hargeisa, Somaliland, Early, 2013&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>And this is how I find &lt;em>most&lt;/em> of the “thanks for your service”. So let me say it more clearly. Just because Fox News, whose editorial board learned from the heartbreaking stories of Vietnam veterans (who often had no choice whether to go and who often acted in the best way they knew in some crazy situations) returning home to be spat upon, tells people that it is somehow patriotic to thank veterans for their service does not mean that it actually is. Am I saying that it is &lt;em>bad&lt;/em> to say that, or that others will not fully appreciate if one were to say the same phrase to them? Not in the slightest. But I am saying that, to me, the phrase is mostly a vapid self-justification more beneficial to the speaker than to the spoken.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Do you feel safer now?” I meant it when I said it. And I mean it now. It is easy for us that feel the Iraq War was a shameful enterprise to embark upon to blame Bush and Cheney for entering a war unilaterally, without justification that has cost over 4,400 American lives, cost probably a hundred times that in Iraqi lives, brought innumerable wounds, severed innumerable families, and cost over $3T (money which would have solved world hunger twice over by many estimates). In my mind that is not the question. Sure Bush and Cheney were power hungry, manipulative, and greedy. You don’t become President of the United States by being humble. We Americans, we reward the greedy, hungry, manipulative people in business, in politics, in celebrity culture. We have done it for years and there is no abatement in sight. In fact the “American Dream” is simply a less egregious version of this. In other words, we have built it into our Nation’s DNA. While I have problems, big problems, with their legal justification for entering the war and I am wary that we have set a precedent within international law that does not progress us humans down the road of tolerance and dialogue, I don’t blame them any more than I blame America as a whole.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the last few days I’ve seen an onslaught of &lt;em>mea culpas&lt;/em> from media elite saying, why didn’t we do our job as the media? That’s fine. They should feel guilt as they committed gross malpractice. But there was plenty of commentary available, even in those days before social media (did the world exist before social media?), to those that wanted to find it. Hell, I knew it was around and I was actively trying to avoid it. So, if I’m honest with myself they certainly played their part, but I don’t blame them any more than I blame America as a whole.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What I meant when I asked Peter Jennings, and his many American viewers, that question is this. I am doing my job. A job that collectively, you citizens, you media, and you the leaders we all elected collectively, have sent me to do. My own personal views as to my safety is 100% beside the point. I am a Marine. My job is to stand between danger and Americans. I am trying my best to do this. But you, the American people must ask yourself, do YOU feel safer? I’ve done my part, my job. Did you do yours?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Who do I blame the most, if blame is to be apportioned at all? I blame the cheerleaders. All of them. From the bureaucracy to the media to the businessmen licking their chops at the chance to exploit defense budgets to the average citizens putting up yellow ribbons and in their hearts pleased that their son/daughter/brother/sister/friend was “doing their part.” I blame the cheerleaders for not learning from the demonstrators.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So the next time you simply take a politician at their word without a thoughtful examination of what you actually think on the matter, the next time you choose to rename “french fries” to “freedom fries” because the French polity had the gall to challenge their leaders and to demand a continuation of the, admittedly cold, peace. In these times, ask yourself: “Do I feel safer now?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why I Started Watershed Legal Services: My Journey from Expat Aid Worker to Expat Entrepreneur</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-04-23-why-i-started-watershed/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-04-23-why-i-started-watershed/</guid><description>&lt;p>a[![Ninja Law Firm via SolYoung @ flickr][2]][2]
Ninja Law Firm via SolYoung @ flickr&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I read an interesting article yesterday from a man who I referenced in my previous post as one of my favorite development bloggers: Owen Barder. Owen has joined a DC based development think-tank called Center for Global Development and in his [good-bye to Ethiopia post][2] he had an interesting thing to say about aid. He claims, and I heartily support, that development is much broader than simply aid, it is about trade policy, climate policy, monetary policy (which he didn’t actually mention), and numerous other policies which the developed world implements and in the globalized economy has massive effects in the developing world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/entry/why-i-started-watershed/4928948235_9882789b97">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/entry/why-i-started-watershed/4928948235_9882789b97&lt;/a>
[2]: &lt;a href="http://www.owen.org/blog/4540">http://www.owen.org/blog/4540&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The article returned my thoughts to something which I have pondered off and on for the eight months since we have opened the doors on &lt;a href="http://watershedlegal.com">Watershed Legal Services&lt;/a>, my small law firm in this corner of the Horn of Africa.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are an assortment of varied and divergently relevant reasons why I invested my time and money in this entity. It is a hodge-podge, a kaleidoscope which changes its predominant colors over time. For one, I wanted to get off the NGO train, to stop skimming the surface of places and to dig into a country. To plant roots. For another, my marriage wasn’t going to thrive in an environment where we were constantly moving as my wife is also a professional and the chances of two professionals finding professionally satisfying positions in a new country every two or three years was daunting at best. And I simply fell in love with Somalis and Somaliland – despite (or perhaps because of) its craziness, its madness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Those are mainly all personal reasons, but there were also some professional reasons which I have considered at length. Rightly or wrongly I was tired of a culture of giving. Now that is not to say that I have stopped giving, indeed I cannot count the number of pro bono hours that our small firm has performed in our short life. I am not tired of giving, I am tired of the expectation that I am here to give – full stop. I am tired of a culture where nothing will happen without a body with money external to the state saying yes we will  fund that. These are backwards to how I see the world. I have no problems with giving a man a fish. But when there are so many fish givers in a place that the giving of a fish becomes an expectation then I think we have reached a point where things should be reevaluated. It isn’t development, it isn’t sustainable, and something has to give. This is why I was excited to start a for-profit law firm, this is why we don’t chase projects in the same way that NGOs do, this is why we haven’t taken outside funding from foundations or other organizations who have shown willingness to assist organizations such as Watershed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Law is not something that can be given. It is, at its core, a conversation between power centers. This conversation ebbs and flows over time. It changes and must change in order to have life and to enable its success. While it is a conversation which can often be informed by actors abroad, if it is not a conversation within the society in which it is being imposed, it will never be successful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me put some meat on that paragraph. What I see from the other side of the table now that I have switched from a legal reform NGO to a practitioner within the country is a tangled mess of laws which will never be implemented here. I see laws built by consultants from other countries who have never bothered to learn the legal structures of this country and bring their own governance proclivities with them. The simple fact of a Kenyan consultant coming to Somaliland to write a law brings big troubles because until recently Kenya was a fundamentally British parliamentary system. Those types of governments operate in a fundamentally different way than governments on a different part of the spectrum. Somaliland, in contradistinction, is built upon an American model. You cannot simply take ideas of how the conversations between power centers works in one system and transplant them whole sale into a different system. Yes, there are often analogies, but not always. American notions of the separation of power and the reasons that America has been able to make an independent executive work requires a method of thought which differs in so many ways. It is like comparing how you talk to your close friends over a cup of coffee sitting on their couch to how you would talk to a new business associate. You talk fundamentally different because the social modes which develop around each of those situations is vastly different. The same is true about law.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So really it boils down to the fact that I wanted to help Somaliland develop its own way of conversing. I want to stop consultants coming from other countries dropping off finished laws and running away. I want to assist parliament and the government to learn how to converse with each other in a legal sense. I want to give young, sharp lawyers a chance to move beyond a simple contract for an NGO where they will never be pushed where they will stagnate and never have the chance to have the feeling of a bit of hard work pushed out the door and the ultimate relaxation and joy which follows.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That, my friends, is why I do what I do. That, my friends, is why I’m more professionally satisfied in these recent months than I’ve ever been in my life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>11 for &amp;#8217;11 (AKA Leigh and Casey make a List)</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-01-04-11-for-11/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-01-04-11-for-11/</guid><description>&lt;p>Instead of resolutions, this year Leigh and I came up with our 11 for 11 – a list of the 11 specific, controllable, quantifiable things we want to accomplish in 2011.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here were the rules (since we’re lawyers and all).  There is a very long list of three.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(1) &lt;strong>Item SHALL have Boolean Attributes.&lt;/strong> This means that at 2359 on 31 December 2011, the item in question must be able to be given a True/False declaration.  This requires the item to be crafted such that it is definable, measurable, and specific.  Items such as “improve the quality of the services we deliver” are definitely out as they cannot be defined.  Items such as “give are clients great services” are definitely out as they cannot be measured.  You get the picture.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(2) &lt;strong>Achievement of the item SHALL remain within the reasonable control of the declarant at all times.&lt;/strong> This means that items which are wholly out of control are not allowed.  Items such as “get invited to Davos, TED, and Clinton Global Initiative” are not within the control of the declarant at all and may not be on the list.   There is a qualifier on reasonable control wholly within the control of the declarant may require complete isolation – something us social beings can rarely achieve.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(3) &lt;strong>Item SHALL not be overly materialistic&lt;/strong>. We wanted to track things that were fun and simple rather than list out how I want a new iPad.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can follow the progress of the list over &lt;a href="http://elevens.caseykuhlman.com">here&lt;/a>!  I’ll be making small visual storytelling pages for each of the events which lend themselves to such an endeavor.  So, without further adieu: Our 11 for ’11:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Buy Tickets for London Olympics&lt;/li>
&lt;li>One Night of Nothing but Music&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create Tasting Menu w/ Seasonal &amp;amp; Local Products&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ice Skate on a Frozen Pond&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Establish a Home Base&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Eat @ a Restaurant Owned by a Top Chef Winner&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Attend or Host a Wine Tasting&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Attend at least one Outdoor Concert&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Prepare an alfresco picnic by a stream&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Spend our anniversary together&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Spend an afternoon mushrooming&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On Going Local: Relationships</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-16-local-relationships-unofficial-chains/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-16-local-relationships-unofficial-chains/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>On Going Local is a (short) series that I’m running which will attempt to look at my life from an objective perspective as I transition from and NGO worker into an entrepreneur here in the developing world.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?p=421">&lt;img src="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?p=421" alt="PeyoteLeaderCheyenne1927 by Medicinehorse7 @ flickr">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Relationships here in Somaliland are odd, to say the least.  There are two main identifiable cultural divergences.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first is that many relationships are deeper here in Somaliland than similar relationships would be back home.  Deeper in the sense that they are more utilized, more cherished, and more complicated than a similar set of relationships would be in America.  (I will return to these themes, but let me finish my introduction first.  Don’t be in such a hurry!)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The second is that many (other) relationships are shallower that similar relationships would be back home.  They are more shallow in the sense that they are less utilized, less cherished, and less complicated than a similar set of relationships would be in America.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a long time this was opaque to me.  And then the scenery started to open up, but like with the two stories from an earlier &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?p=421">post&lt;/a> on decoding the somali mind there was little cultural alignment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is what I was seeing after I had been here long enough to scratch the surface coating off of the Somalilanders.  On the one hand, I was seeing friends who would actually talk to one another about many different issues.  Friends who would gather and sit and discuss, day after day.  But on the other hand I was seeing romantic relationships that were either business relationships or almost elementary.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="romantic-relationships">Romantic Relationships&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Last week, a woman dumped a jug full of kerosene all over her body and lit herself on fire.  Just 30 meters from the gate of our compound.  Apparently it was because her boyfriend broke up with her. It was in the early evening and there were many people around.  They forced the woman to stop-drop-and-roll.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apparently she survived the initial situation and was taken to the hospital.  Considering the healthcare in this country and her likely third-degree burns I’m unsure whether she survived for very long thereafter. Although my initial reaction was that this was about a passionate, tragic love affair gone wrong – a story which likely any culture can relate to – it was more likely about the stigma which would follow the poor woman after the man refused to marry her after their affair had gone public.  I do not know that for certain, but it is my educated guess.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Relationships between the sexes are tremendously strained here in Somaliland.  While that comes with the territory in many ways, what I’ve noticed is that in many ways relationships, especially romantic relationships, between the sexes are riven with what I would consider immaturities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Twenty-somethings and thirty-somethings that are involved in romantic relationships rarely discuss their relationships, creating a situation of insularity stifling development and deepening of many of the relationships. Of course, arranged marriages are still very customary and prevalent.  In these cases the romance and the business-politics of clan and diyah-paying groups are conflated forcing individuals into catch-22 situations where they are forced to subordinate their own desires for the benefit of their clan or family.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For me personally, it is fascinating to learn about this situation because it seems such a throw-back.  I suspect for much of human history marrying someone for business-political reasons has been more important than many current historians / anthropologists would give credit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A couple of months ago I was chewing with some people including some American-Somalilander diaspora and they were asking me one of the biggest questions I always get: “how do you find Somaliland”?  I like it when diaspora ask me this question because they find themselves in a situation similar to me – somewhere in between the two cultures. Usually when non-diaspora ask me this question I give an white-washed answer.  This time, for whatever reason, I was feeling especially honest.  I replied that for the most part I have not experienced much culture shock as I read and studied a lot before I even arrived.  The thing which has been the biggest cultural shock to me, I told them, has been the cultural response to a widowing. In Somali culture (and I am told but cannot confirm – many Arab cultures) if a husband passes away his brother will be forced to marry the sister-in-law. When I first heard this, I remember shaking my head and furrowing my brow deeply.  But I asked why.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The answer, actually, makes semi-sense.  It is because if the wife remarries someone outside of the family than the children that she had with her deceased husband will be considered outsiders by the new husband and he will abandon them.  So it is a cultural mechanism to ensure that the children were taken care of.  That I can see and understand – to the extent that it is simply a support mechanism.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Later, when I became closer to more Somalis, I asked about the reality and the thing that was really creeping me out – does the brother have to have sex with the former sister-in-law or can it be a show marriage. Their answer was that if the brother doesn’t have sex with the sister-in-law then it isn’t a marriage after all.  Fair enough, but I must say that I’m pleased my own culture has never adopted this situation as it feels too much like incest based upon my own cultural upbringing and proclivities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These anecdotes are a simple reflection of why I say that romantic relationships here in Somaliland are very different than the romantic relationships that I’m accustomed to – tending towards much more shallow.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="friendly-relationships">Friendly Relationships&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>On the other hand, friendly relationships are much deeper than anything that I’m accustomed to.  And here is where I get to the reason for why I chose the picture at the top (aside from his magnificent beauty in austerity).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Somalilanders value their friendships so much.  It is one of the things that I appreciate most about being here.  When you meet someone that you haven’t seen in a while you are guaranteed a big hug, a big smile, a ten minutes of your life you’ll never get back.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The other thing that surprises me is how quickly two people will become friends.  In a short time you go from Mister to Friend to Brother.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For men, especially, there is an avenue by which one can almost fully guarantee they will have a friend for life.  It is what is called fadhigaa or qayilayaa or cunayaa or chewing or sitting together.  Chewing sessions are a great avenue for discussion.  They have a major downside which is that it’s a men’s only club, but that is a deeper issue which I will leave for another time.  Chewing sessions usually last about six hours – although sometimes more, sometimes less depending on the circumstances.  From about 3 pm to 9 pm men will gather in their normal meeting spot.  When you arrive in a majlis (the place for sitting) you get yourself all arranged with your cigarettes in one place, your drinks in another place, your qat over here, your laptop and phone over there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then you sit back take a few deep breathes, and just sit and talk for the next hours.  Like with alcohol or marijuana, qat affects different people differently.  It varies with your state of mind when you begin, with the distinct strain that you always buy, and with your own personal reaction to the qat.  It makes some people retreat into themselves.  You won’t hear from them for hours.  I am not among those.  The other general trend is that it opens people up and is a decent social lubricator.  These people will end up talking and talking and talking much more than when they are sober.  I am among those.  Men come together and listen to the radio, watch BBC or Al Jazeera or the National TV, read the Somali sites, and talk.  This time together in a relaxed environment cements friendships deeply.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On Going Local: Finding Your Happy Place</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-12-local-finding-happy-place/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-12-local-finding-happy-place/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>On Going Local is a new (short) series that I’ll be running which will attempt to look at my life from an objective perspective as I transition from and NGO worker into an entrepreneur here in the developing world.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve been here in Somaliland now for around two and a half years now.  It has been a wonderful time, and I’ve enjoyed every minute of it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are many aspects of Somali / Somaliland society &amp;amp; culture that I have found it easy to adjust too.  But there are a few things which have been difficult.  Not the least of which is the six day work week.  Being an Islamic country, we take Friday off.  But that most people take off.  Going from a two day weekend to a one day weekend with shorter days throughout the six was a big adjustment and I’m not sure that I will ever fully adjust to it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, this is about space.  Physical space.  Like most development workers I lived for a long time in a &lt;a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/caseykuhlman/SomalilandCompound02" title="Gorgorka Luxury Estates">gigantic house&lt;/a> shared among an assortment of other expatriates, cleaners, cooks, guards, and staff.  It can be a fantastically good time having all the excitement of different activities, smells, and languages around you.  For a little while…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a time, though, it becomes stifling.  For one thing, you are never “off duty.”  At any time of the day or night someone may come and knock on your door.  Someone’s family member is sick and they need money; someone’s mobile phone was stolen and they need money; the guards caught two people making out in a dark corner behind the house; all sound tracked to random gunshots due to land disputes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most development or aid workers I know always like to say it’s not a job, it’s a lifestyle.  And that is all well and good, but it isn’t a lifestyle I was very interested in.  Sure you can try to set boundaries, but you don’t want to incentivize the people working with you to not tell you what is happening.   That can lead to all kinds of problems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This balance is incredibly difficult to achieve between having some personal space (when the standard living situation is tenement and shared, college-esque, except we’re not college age anymore) and being “open.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have recently moved out of that mansion into what would be normal to me.  Luckily enough it is also what would be normal to a middle-class Somali.  Instead of ten bedrooms (some of which were office space), I now have three.  Instead of having to walk 15 minutes to get to the kitchen, it now takes me 15 seconds.  I don’t have to worry about staff all of the time as I only have someone who comes to clean for me a few days a week &amp;amp; when I’m at the office.  It is safer this way, as you are a target when you live in a mansion.  You can do what you like without having to worry about being disturbed.  You can metaphorically unpack your bags.  You can find normality in an otherwise frantic existence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The place I’m living now actually feels like a home rather than a dorm.  And that is fantastic.  I love my old roommates dearly, but it is so nice to have something that is “yours.”  And when my wife comes down next year for a bit, my life will be complete!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On Going Local: Water</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-17-local-water/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-17-local-water/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>On Going Local is a new (short) series that I’ll be running which will attempt to look at my life from an objective perspective as I transition from and NGO worker into an entrepreneur here in the developing world.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I first arrived here in S’land, and I would go out to eat, I would use the minimum amount of water possible to wash my hands before and after eating with them.  It is desert afterall.  But later, towards the end I realized that I had adapted and was using more water – letting the water run as I was soaping, washing my face also.  It was never a conscious decision, I just started using more water.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But here at the house, I have always remained conscious of how much water we are using – primarily because at the house we have to pay for the water and it is EXPENSIVE. It is desert afterall.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I just wanted to share a bit about how the water works.  Here in Hargeisa we have a decent supply of water, but it is getting strained by the continuing population growth of the city.  There is this beautiful area about 30 km to the north of Hargeisa, in the Golis Mountains where most of the water comes from.  One of the main problems is that the area is a couple hundred meters of elevation lower than Hargeisa.  That means PUMPS generators performing the difficult job of getting the water up here to Hargeisa.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Hargeisa Water Agency has identified two other locations which could supply Hargeisa and both are higher and would require less pumping power.  The problem is getting the infrastructure built.  The Agency has a difficult time amassing enough capital to even upgrade the pipe network from the original series of wells into Hargeisa.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once the water gets to Hargeisa then it gets routed to different zones.  Typically one or two zones within Hargeisa will get water on a given night, and then the Agency will rotate zones over the course of the week.  Once the water is released to the zones then the zone manager is responsible for routing it into particular customers of the agency.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The irregularity of the water supply means that most compounds have built their own water reservoirs and then we watch these like a hawk.  Our reservoir is underground.  Because it is a totally passive system, what we have to do is each day we check supplemental tanks which are on the highest part of the house.  These tanks provide the house with water pressure, but do it passively.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pretty much each day we pump water from the underground reservoir to the upper holding tanks.  This means that we only have to use the electricity to pump the water up once a day rather than running it continuously (which is important because electricity is also EXPENSIVE).  The system works quite well most of the time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The only problem comes when we let the upper holding tanks run dry.  What happens (because the system is passively pressurized) then is that air runs down through the water lines in the house.  After we fill the upper holding tanks the air pressurizes from the weight of the water above it and keeps the water from flowing through the plumbing system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many of you living in Africa may have experienced this problem.  So here is what you do when the water won’t flow through your house.  You go to the bottom most taps in your system and open all of them that you can find.  This will bleed the air pressure from the system.  When those taps are running well, then you can go upstairs and turn one a couple of taps.  This should bleed the rest of the air from the system and then water should fill all of the lines.  Then you have to run around the house turning off all of the taps because you hate wasting water!  You may have to fiddle with your hot water heaters (if you are lucky enough to have them) as they sometimes become a hassle to bleed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But this is a small hassle – and after a while it becomes second nature to bleed the lines when you know that the upper tanks have run dry.  This is one of my favorite parts of living in the developing world.  You are forced to learn about the world around you which you so often take for granting living in the developed world where you never have to understand fluid dynamics and watershed elevation limitations in order to take a shower!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Powered by Wind and Other Things</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-03-19-powered-wind/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-03-19-powered-wind/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://africaknows.com">&lt;img src="http://africaknows.com" alt="">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(Photo via: &lt;a href="http://africaknows.com">africaknows.com&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like this guy, I’ve been up in the clouds lately.  Luckily our soy is beginning to fabricate.  Things are really coming along with all of my various bits and bobs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the one hand it has passed the time quickly in between when I saw Leigh last and when I will see her again (a week from tonight).  Yet, on the other hand, there’s been some disjunctiveness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The source of so much of my inefficiency as a bad computing environment – top to bottom.  My laptop is getting old and now is a portable desktop which often shuts down whenever I’m least ready.  My internet for the past month has been virtually non-existent, and when the “virtually” modifier was operative, it wasn’t – at least steadily.  Further, I’ve been digging a bit deeper into my own technology usage in preparation for the &lt;a href="http://watershedplatforms.com">Watershed Platforms&lt;/a> launch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I’m wont to do, I have gone a bit overboard in some areas.  I always spread my net quite wide when I’m trying new things as I like to hone it down after being presented with the full buffet.  After I understand things and start to form opinions then I pare it down.  Music, blogs, whatever.  The only problem is that it takes a bunch of time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now my feet seem to be a bit under me.  I’ve transferred my own stuff over, first to an absolutely awful hosting company which frustrated the hell out of me, but now to a new one.  Problematically, I accidentally deleted the entire wordpress database in the process and so had to rebuild everything from scratch – so it basically took twice as long.  In any event, now expect regular dispatches.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The wind is up and I’m pretty much ready.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iLove iTunes Genius</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-12-ilove-itunes-genius/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-12-ilove-itunes-genius/</guid><description>&lt;p>[![Itunes_genius_logo][2]][2]In a departure from deeper content, I submit the following.  iTunes Genius lives up to its title.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/itunes/">http://www.apple.com/itunes/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have no idea how the algorithm works, but it does just work.  As usual with Apple products, the first few times I used it I was distinctly underwhelmed.  But then I came back to it a few months later and I was amazed. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>From what I can tell, it seems to take into account both subjective and objective criteria.  This is key, because I am very anal about how I log, listen, and classify my music collection.  Thanks mom, for that wonderful personality quirk.  I have no idea if the objective criteria are pulled from the iTunes database, crowdsourcing,&lt;br>
or some combination. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yet for whatever reason genius seems to take this into account.  Very little of my music currently has the genre which came when I bought the songs from iTunes.  I have reconfigured everything, and this gets taken into account (from what I can tell) when Genius makes its track decisions.  The other subjective criteria it seems to take into account besides the genres are the ratings, which I’m overly fastidious in using. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yet, it also takes into account some level of objective criteria.  Sometimes if I put on an older track I have the pleasure of many of my old high school favorite tracks.  So it must take into account the year of the album.  Also when I put on a woman singer, most of the tracks selected are women.  &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![Last][3]][3] The last thing, and that which I most appreciate, is that it does a great job of keeping with the overall mood which I’m going for.  If I find one song that fits my particular mood of  the moment – Genius is really good about keeping me in that mood while exploring my music collection in the way that [last.fm][3] allows me to do with an online portfolio outside my music collection.  Last.fm is fantastic, but my bandwidth limitations usually preclude using it.  Sometimes everything is OK, but usually the music is sketchy which is incredibly annoying.  Kudos to Last, by the way, for opening up their interface.  When I first came to Africa I could not listen to my tracks / stations, but now they have fixed that.  Thanks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://www.last.fm/">http://www.last.fm/&lt;/a>
[3]: &lt;a href="http://www.last.fm/user/caseykuhlman">http://www.last.fm/user/caseykuhlman&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![Apple_tv_intro_graphic][5]][5] Generally, I hate listening to my music on my tinny computer speakers.  Luckily, a while ago when I was up in Europe I bought an [AppleTV][5].  This is fantastic for me, because I can plug it into my decent receiver and speakers.  The closed nature of AppleTV is annoying, but there are plenty of hacks.  Yet, even out of the box when combined with Genius it is wonderful.  You get Apple’s stunning, sexy graphic interfaces and your music which can be played on reasonable speakers.  This is a blissful combination for me.  The final thing which I will say is that I use Genius similarly to how I use the web, I wander.  I will find old favorites or new favorites and Genius them to see what else I may be forgetting or never have found within my own music collection.  Genius.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/appletv/">http://www.apple.com/appletv/&lt;/a>
[5]: &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/appletv/">http://www.apple.com/appletv/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>