<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>living on underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/living/</link><description>Recent content in living on underWater desert Blogging</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Casey Kuhlman</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/living/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Do You Feel Safer Now: Reflections on the Ten Year Anniversary of Iraqi Invasion</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2013-03-20-do-you-feel-safer-now-reflections-on-the-ten-year-anniversary-of-iraqi-invasion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2013-03-20-do-you-feel-safer-now-reflections-on-the-ten-year-anniversary-of-iraqi-invasion/</guid><description>On a day, of which the tenth anniversary is fast approaching, I was standing on a roundabout watching a bunch of people I knew and a machine I was familiar with rip down a statute. It was a day seared into my memory as I was thoroughly convinced that I was in the midst of an iconic moment. In some ways that belief was correct. Only it was just not the type of icon I was thinking it would be.</description></item><item><title>Why I Started Watershed Legal Services: My Journey from Expat Aid Worker to Expat Entrepreneur</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2011-04-23-why-i-started-watershed/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2011-04-23-why-i-started-watershed/</guid><description>a[![Ninja Law Firm via SolYoung @ flickr][2]][2] Ninja Law Firm via SolYoung @ flickr
I read an interesting article yesterday from a man who I referenced in my previous post as one of my favorite development bloggers: Owen Barder. Owen has joined a DC based development think-tank called Center for Global Development and in his [good-bye to Ethiopia post][2] he had an interesting thing to say about aid. He claims, and I heartily support, that development is much broader than simply aid, it is about trade policy, climate policy, monetary policy (which he didn’t actually mention), and numerous other policies which the developed world implements and in the globalized economy has massive effects in the developing world.</description></item><item><title>11 for &amp;#8217;11 (AKA Leigh and Casey make a List)</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2011-01-04-11-for-11/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2011-01-04-11-for-11/</guid><description>![11 by loop_oh @ flickr]({{ site.url }}{{ site.root }}{{ site.images_dir }}/{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; }}/3404859720_d9c7a57462.jpg)
Instead of resolutions, this year Leigh and I came up with our 11 for 11 – a list of the 11 specific, controllable, quantifiable things we want to accomplish in 2011.
Here were the rules (since we’re lawyers and all). There is a very long list of three.
(1) Item SHALL have Boolean Attributes. This means that at 2359 on 31 December 2011, the item in question must be able to be given a True/False declaration.</description></item><item><title>On Going Local: Relationships</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-10-16-local-relationships-unofficial-chains/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-10-16-local-relationships-unofficial-chains/</guid><description>On Going Local is a (short) series that I’m running which will attempt to look at my life from an objective perspective as I transition from and NGO worker into an entrepreneur here in the developing world.
Relationships here in Somaliland are odd, to say the least. There are two main identifiable cultural divergences.
The first is that many relationships are deeper here in Somaliland than similar relationships would be back home.</description></item><item><title>On Going Local: Finding Your Happy Place</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-10-12-local-finding-happy-place/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-10-12-local-finding-happy-place/</guid><description>On Going Local is a new (short) series that I’ll be running which will attempt to look at my life from an objective perspective as I transition from and NGO worker into an entrepreneur here in the developing world.
![My Happy Place via Lady_k @ flickr]({{ site.url }}{{ site.root }}{{ site.images_dir }}/{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; }}/4431206216_8eacda9a75_z.jpg) Photo via Lady_k @ flickr
I’ve been here in Somaliland now for around two and a half years now.</description></item><item><title>On Going Local: Water</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-06-17-local-water/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-06-17-local-water/</guid><description>On Going Local is a new (short) series that I’ll be running which will attempt to look at my life from an objective perspective as I transition from and NGO worker into an entrepreneur here in the developing world.
![Washing Hands]({{ site.url }}{{ site.root }}{{ site.images_dir }}/{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; }}/4610058219_4e31ee3ce2.jpg) via dougni @ flickr
When I first arrived here in S’land, and I would go out to eat, I would use the minimum amount of water possible to wash my hands before and after eating with them.</description></item><item><title>Powered by Wind and Other Things</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-03-19-powered-wind/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-03-19-powered-wind/</guid><description>(Photo via: africaknows.com)
Like this guy, I’ve been up in the clouds lately. Luckily our soy is beginning to fabricate. Things are really coming along with all of my various bits and bobs.
On the one hand it has passed the time quickly in between when I saw Leigh last and when I will see her again (a week from tonight). Yet, on the other hand, there’s been some disjunctiveness.</description></item><item><title>iLove iTunes Genius</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-02-12-ilove-itunes-genius/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-02-12-ilove-itunes-genius/</guid><description>[![Itunes_genius_logo][2]][2]In a departure from deeper content, I submit the following. iTunes Genius lives up to its title.
[]: http://www.apple.com/itunes/
I have no idea how the algorithm works, but it does just work. As usual with Apple products, the first few times I used it I was distinctly underwhelmed. But then I came back to it a few months later and I was amazed. From what I can tell, it seems to take into account both subjective and objective criteria.</description></item><item><title>Wedding</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2009-03-11-wedding/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2009-03-11-wedding/</guid><description>Highlands and I got hitched.
This page will have some of the highlights.
Big_head had the first performance. []11111111111
Highland's_Bro had the second performance.
[]2222 The first round of pictures, taken by my father, are here. Another round of pictures, taken by Lance / my mom, are here.
Other pictures for facebookers. From Karen; From Alex.
~ # ~</description></item><item><title>Building (in) a Developing Country</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-07-23-building-in-a-developing-country/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-07-23-building-in-a-developing-country/</guid><description>We had an epic rainstorm last night. I had been waiting for one since we’ve moved into our compound as I was concerned about the drainage systems. The soils here are the sandy clay stuff and because the clay makes the water not permeate the soils and because the sand makes the water flow easily, I was worried about what was happening whenever it rains. We do a lot of gardening and are trying to keep our compound as green as possible here in the high desert.</description></item><item><title>Parenting, Gender Roles and My Wedding</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-06-12-parenting-gender-roles-and-my-wedding/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-06-12-parenting-gender-roles-and-my-wedding/</guid><description>As I clicked the category for this posting it occurred to me that for much of the first two years of this blog all I wrote about was categorized as &amp;ldquo;living&amp;rdquo; but that for the past three years or so that has decrescendoed to almost a non-existent situation. Maybe I have spent much more time looking outward and not so much time looking inward, or maybe I have become a bit reticent to write about &amp;ldquo;me&amp;rdquo; as I embark on something akin to being a professional.</description></item><item><title>Automated Killer Robots</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-02-28-automated-killer-robots/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-02-28-automated-killer-robots/</guid><description>Link: Automated killer robots ‘threat to humanity’: expert.
Yes you read it correct. AFP does the difficult reporting!
I’m surprised that they didn’t interview Yoshimi for this article.
~ # ~</description></item><item><title>Semper Fi, Mac.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-01-23-semper-fi-mac/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-01-23-semper-fi-mac/</guid><description>When I was a young Marine Officer, I was in the depths of a dirty used bookstore in DC when this old timer came up to me. I was in the Military History section trying to find this one book I was supposed to read and we struck up a conversation. Turns out he had survived Iwo Jima and other battles in the Pacific. I will always remember the way he slapped me on the back and said with a particular gleam: &amp;ldquo;Semper Fi, Mac, Semper Fi.</description></item><item><title>RIP, Great Man of America, RIP</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-01-22-rip-great-man-of-america-rip/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-01-22-rip-great-man-of-america-rip/</guid><description>I meant to post this yesterday but was having technical difficulties. If you haven’t watched MLK’s speech, if you’ve just seen the clips throughout your life. Take a moment, or twelve and watch it here. It is a magnificent achievement, and even if you are not in a position to dedicate your life towards ensuring the equalities that Dr. King was fighting for, even if you think you have no ability to contribute to a world where &amp;ldquo;justice rolls down like water, and righteousness like a mighty stream,&amp;rdquo; even if you think there is little you can do, just watch it as a piece of Great American Art.</description></item><item><title>updated</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-09-09-updated/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-09-09-updated/</guid><description>finally took the time to upload the pictures from the germany/prague trip I took a few weeks ago with my dad. the georgia/azerbaijan pictures will come soon…i hope!
~ # ~</description></item><item><title>howling through the days</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-09-04-howling-through-the-days/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-09-04-howling-through-the-days/</guid><description>I’m a howler monkey that is investigating the world.</description></item><item><title>return of my jedis</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-08-28-return-of-my-jedis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-08-28-return-of-my-jedis/</guid><description>am back in nashville. i don’t hate it as much as i thought i was going to. right now. arrived in the states a week ago today after three straight weeks of torrid traveling that took me to grand places with two of my favorite people in the world. that was good. many stories which will not get published here as i am now out of time. spent monday with a friend in miami and then drove to orlando.</description></item><item><title>taut in the middle again.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-02-26-taut-in-the-middle-again/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-02-26-taut-in-the-middle-again/</guid><description>this weekend it became clear to me that i’ve been living in the middle of much tension while here, and before. i continually try to float between the text and subtext and context of my life and so many times things get lost in translation between the two. i sometimes confuse myself whether things are internal or external; whether they matter or don’t; whether they are real or imagined. feelings emoted, are they proper or improper?</description></item><item><title>HAppy TUrkey</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-11-23-happy-turkey/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-11-23-happy-turkey/</guid><description>Happy Thanksgiving all. I’ll be at friends drinking mass quantities of rum and beer, eating mass quantitites of meat and watching mass quantities of football. AHHHHHH, the most masculine of all holidays. Yesterday I was driving somewhere and I saw an entire house decorated up for Thanksgiving. I thought, &amp;ldquo;now there’s some peep’s that know how to give thanksgiving its props.&amp;rdquo; I don’t like it when Thanksgiving doesn’t get its props.</description></item><item><title>why i do yoga</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-11-01-why-i-do-yoga/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-11-01-why-i-do-yoga/</guid><description>people do stupid shit for stupid reasons all the time. i do yoga.
i look around the studio from time to time and i wonder why everyone else is there. i think at my studio here in nashville most people are doing the hot yoga becuase it is, like, so relaxing. that and it is close to their little sorority houses. these are the girls in short tight black shorts, blue sports bras and t-shirts with party titles over them.</description></item><item><title>best or optimal?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-08-11-best-or-optimal/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-08-11-best-or-optimal/</guid><description>I have decided to
return to Vanderbilt this semester. My job possibility with the Program
Director for USAID down in Colombia is coagulating, but slowly. I am
going to try to set it up to be down there from January until August,
and use that time to get a semester long externship from Vanderbilt. Then return and finish up two semesters and be done.
When I came to Law School, as most of you know, I had three career</description></item><item><title>grief</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-08-09-grief/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-08-09-grief/</guid><description>my mamo passed away on friday morning. i didn’t even know how bad it was until i flew into nashville on thursday. my mom called after i picked up portlanders and told us to come to the hospital, because she didn’t think that mamo would make it through the night.
that made for a somber drive.
we arrived at about 3:30 a.m. at the hospital. she was asleep, but not comatose.</description></item><item><title>Craziness</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-07-18-craziness/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-07-18-craziness/</guid><description>well, life has been crazy. we’ve been working like fiends. i saw the sun rise on four straight mornings. three because of work, one because of partying. it has been a weird couple of nights, for a lot of reasons. but now i’ve gotten a break. yesterday i wrote all afternoon at my coffeeshop, then did yoga for the first time in three alcohol and smoke laden days, then ate dinner with two lady-friends then came home to fall asleep to MTV banalities.</description></item><item><title>backlog</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-06-30-backlog/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-06-30-backlog/</guid><description>so i have backlogged the stories from last week while i was in the woods. they are backdated to the approximate days and times when i constructed and/or experienced their bases.
this week has been busy, but good. the woman i’m working for knows MANY MANY people who are very very well connected. this weekend we are to meet McCain, i’m going to give him a copy of shooter. next week even more people will be in town.</description></item><item><title>back</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-06-26-back/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-06-26-back/</guid><description>i am back from the woods.
i have lots of stories i am going to write over the week. it was exciting, hot, fulfilling, it made all my dreams come true.
chapter one of wading is posted.
~ # ~</description></item><item><title>cultural shorthand</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-06-24-cultural-shorthand/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-06-24-cultural-shorthand/</guid><description>so cam, ern, bri and i often use the word gaper. well that is how i spell it. it is the verbial noun of &amp;ldquo;to gape,&amp;rdquo; and we therefore pronounce it &amp;ldquo;GAY-per.&amp;rdquo; not &amp;ldquo;ga-per.&amp;rdquo;
when we use it those that do not KNOW often ask for a definition or description. up till now it had been hard for me to point to an iconic description pulled from pop culture that can help.</description></item><item><title>lakes</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-06-23-lakes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-06-23-lakes/</guid><description>i like to skinny dip in deserted, cold lakes. i do not like the water to be so cold that it induces hyperventilating when my nutsack hits it.
i do not like to be greeted by a veil of mosquitoes when i exit it.
but i do like to skinny dip when i’m skuzzy.
~ # ~</description></item><item><title>the gentle flower</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-06-21-the-gentle-flower/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-06-21-the-gentle-flower/</guid><description>having sufficiently fucked with my rhythms enough to convince myself that it was OK to wake early, i awoke at dawn and decided to stroll.
i was walking around this gigantic lake that was engorged by new deal politics more than the bellies of those beat fuckers who had to dam the damn thing. there was a small trail that i was not sure if it was a human trail or a deer trail, and i felt guilty for if it was the latter maybe i was changing many years of animal patterns because they wouldn’t come this way if they could smell early morning human who has not showered for a few days and doesn’t usually smell that good to begin with.</description></item><item><title>places</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-06-16-places/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-06-16-places/</guid><description>i think that how i leaves places reminds me of how i break up with women . . . tentatively, with an eye towards salvaging something from the experience in an effort to reinforce that my decision was the right one.
i am not prone to regrets, but i am prone to self-reflection in an effort to refine why and how i make decisions so i make them better in the future.</description></item><item><title>no thanks, i&amp;#8217;ll pass</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-06-12-no-thanks-ill-pass/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-06-12-no-thanks-ill-pass/</guid><description>this weekend i almost became a marine….again. a friend that i have known forever came down from ft worth to visit for the night. we were talking about him going back to the sandbox for seven months. he is going with a civil affairs group that will be doing civil/military liasoning, straight civil affairs (government establishment, police coordination, building schools, making sure there is power and water, helping USAID distribute the moneys for aid, ensuring people get paid, etc.</description></item><item><title>when it rains it pours</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-06-09-when-it-rains-it-pours/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-06-09-when-it-rains-it-pours/</guid><description>for much of my childhood i didn’t understand what that phrase was on the
side of the big, round, blue salt container. everytime bri and/or i would
cook i would just look at it and think, &amp;ldquo;shit isn’t that
self-evident,&amp;rdquo; or the equivalent of that thought would enter my young mind
for a pinball session of bouncing around. eventually i asked my mother
who told me that this company had placed an additive in the salt that makes it</description></item><item><title>clarity through resolution</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-06-06-clarity-through-resolution/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-06-06-clarity-through-resolution/</guid><description>so my grades came back today. they were marginally better than last semester, but again the increase was marginal. this is disappointing for two reasons. first, i worked really fucking hard last semester at developing and refining my written communications, apparently i didn’t work smarter since my legal writing grade dropped. but i really thought that i was getting the hang of it, apparently everyone else was too. i also worked really hard on the substantive law (the rules as applied to the class, basically the classwork) this semester, and especially towards finals.</description></item><item><title>back</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-06-02-back-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-06-02-back-2/</guid><description>lacking excuses, i’m forced to return. deal with it, cause i’m back.
so austin. it is pretty sweet. it would be nearly impossible to get a job here when my only link to the city is, &amp;ldquo;i like it,&amp;rdquo; since this town has the highest per capita lawyer rates of anywhere in america (or so i’ve been told). plus it is too flipping hot for me anyway. nevertheless i’m very glad that i have come down here for a few weeks.</description></item><item><title>riding v. skiing</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-01-03-riding-v-skiing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-01-03-riding-v-skiing/</guid><description>ok. so most of you know that i’m a rider. i think that this is kind of odd, yet typical of my history. i feel like i’m always half an oscillation off from popular culture. this is what i mean, and really you can apply it to most areas of my hipster life be that fashion, word choices, music, hairstyles or the like.
see i started riding, really riding my snowboard when i got out of the marine corps, when i was 27.</description></item><item><title>return to paradise</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-12-31-return-to-paradise/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-12-31-return-to-paradise/</guid><description>this is harder than i really thought that it could be. my mind is racing with what if’s. i know that i shouldn’t. i know what it does to me. trust me. i know. but it is an unstoppable, irrestistable, uncompressible force that is pushing my mind around. what if i hadn’t left?
that is the crux of the matter. i’m back in aspen. it is winter (obviously) the snow is immaculate, forgiving, soft, just grabby enough, not skiied out.</description></item><item><title>memory</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-12-25-memory/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-12-25-memory/</guid><description>it has been so long even my computer didn’t &amp;ldquo;Remember Me.&amp;rdquo; and I had to relog in to typepad. How aweful of me.
am in Tennessee for the holidays. It is what it always seems to be, text off family love, subtext of family angst.
See this will be the last Xmas in this house. My aunt has returned for the first time in a while. I have returned for the first time in a while.</description></item><item><title>mobility</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-09-20-mobility/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-09-20-mobility/</guid><description>the following is a new treatise that represents some of my current thought patterns. those that know me [everyone that reads this blog] knows of my mobile ways in geography but in many aspects of my life. my brother has been applying to grad schools and he and i have been bantering regarding his personal statement. he recently told me that he has lost his mojo and he doesn’t seem to have any motivation to really put his heart into the document.</description></item><item><title>footBall&amp;#8217;s back</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-09-12-footballs-back/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-09-12-footballs-back/</guid><description>today i gave myself a sabatical. all football, all day. it was fantastic. just finished up watching PRIMETIME. visions of big dog nachos dancing in my head.
apparently we have a mouse in the house (literally). this will be interesting as i’ve never set mousetraps and had them smash a little fucking rodent and then (worse of all) have to take that diseased fucker down to the trash. ray lewis just hugged some army dudes.</description></item><item><title>inevitability?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-08-19-inevitability/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-08-19-inevitability/</guid><description>so tonight it happened. i had been dreading it happening, in fact it was one of the main reasons i had for not wanting to move to nashville. but nonetheless it happened. on the way to a bar to meet some new &amp;ldquo;friends&amp;rdquo; i ran into katie’s parents.
it fucked my whole dope up and only ended up staying at the bar for a little while b/c i couldn’t concentrate on anything people were saying and couldn’t respond in anything approaching wit.</description></item><item><title>incoherenCy</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-08-14-incoherency/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-08-14-incoherency/</guid><description>well. i’m on 36 straight hours. i think. i have lost all cognitive and reasoning powers. my back is about to explode. i need to dumpster dive like 40 cubic feet of trash into random dumpsters that do not belong to me with the hopes that their cameras don’t see me. it is hot. i’m a sweaty behemoth when i’m not in starbucks finding out that a party to go to is too far to walk and i’m gonna register about a .</description></item><item><title>Signatories and Their Significance</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-08-09-signatories-and-their-significance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-08-09-signatories-and-their-significance/</guid><description>finished kundera tonight, but it will stay on the list as i’m going to reread it through. it was fucking intense. it was my favorite book that i’ve read in the past three years, easily.
signed the lease in nashville today. locked on the moving van for wednesday through friday. dad has his plane tix to help in the move. am depressed as shit and sick of hoping for it to end.</description></item><item><title>Decisions</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-08-08-decisions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-08-08-decisions/</guid><description>everyone around me suddenly appears to be suspect. like they have morphed from being just humans, to having some sort of alien aura about them. like i put on a magic pair of sun glasses and can see that they are all out to get me. but i’m not paranoid about it, merely concerned. and so i just don’t talk to them. i just stifle it all and let it settle into a ball of goo in the lower regions of my stomach.</description></item><item><title>All Moved In.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-08-06-all-moved-in/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-08-06-all-moved-in/</guid><description>OK kids. The pizza is half-eaten, cold, and greasing up the coffeetable for me. There are beer bottles in a pile somewhere near THAT corner of the room, in the vicinity of the empty boxes that are broken down into flat cardboard for storage in the garage somewhere. In other words. I’m all moved in. It took me much of the day to move all that stuff over from xanga but we’re here now.</description></item></channel></rss>