<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/</link><description>A Site About Resilience and Authoritarianism</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</managingEditor><webMaster>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</webMaster><copyright>All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/living/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Do You Feel Safer Now: Reflections on the Ten Year Anniversary of Iraqi Invasion</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-03-20-do-you-feel-safer-now-reflections-on-the-ten-year-anniversary-of-iraqi-invasion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-03-20-do-you-feel-safer-now-reflections-on-the-ten-year-anniversary-of-iraqi-invasion/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/yatesaustin/237347393">&lt;img src="http://blog.caseykuhlman.com/assets/images/2013/237347393_5b0a2f1121_z.jpg" alt="Peace or V for Victory by yater @ flickr" tit="Peace or V for Victory by yater @ flickr" />&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On a day, of which the tenth anniversary is fast approaching, I was standing on a roundabout watching a bunch of people I knew and a machine I was familiar with rip down a statute. It was a day seared into my memory as I was thoroughly convinced that I was in the midst of an iconic moment. In some ways that belief was correct. Only it was just not the type of icon I was thinking it would be.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="baghdad-early-2003">Baghdad, Early, 2003&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I wrote a book, and sold it based upon simply being present on that day in that locattion. I’ve been asked to give interviews (generally all around March or April of each year) not because I have anything particularly insightful to say about the invasion of Iraq, but merely because I was there. Present. Around. As the color of that day slowly desaturates in a process which only time understands and can justify, I have been reflecting not upon a machine, a chain, and a bronze statute. Instead, I’ve been reflecting upon something else.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At some point in the day, I and some friends were asked to give an interview. This was an exciting opportunity for the 26 year old version of the version of me currently typing this. It was exciting for two reasons in particular. First, I knew that there was a decent chance that word of the interview would float through the social networks of the time to my family. I thought someone somewhere will see this and let someone know and thereon until (hopefully) my family get some word that everything was OK. Second, I was excited about the interview because it was with ABC News. This was the outlet I used to watch as a growing child, a nightly voice, iconography, and color scheme that I knew well. I, along with some other friends, was going to be interviewed by Peter Jennings. And that dude’s a legend.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During the interview, I’m pretty sure that I really only had one line. Too nervous (and star struck perhaps) to say much else. But I did get in a line. Later my mother told me that while she recognized my face during the first part of the interview, she only really &lt;em>knew&lt;/em> it was me when she saw the sarcasm drip from my mouth. The irony is that, for once in my life, I actually wasn’t trying to be sarcastic. Peter asked the group of three or four of us that were gathered on the balcony of the Palestine Hotel if we felt safer now that we were in Baghdad. It was, frankly, a stupid question to ask a group of Marines from an infantry battalion laden with weapons and youthful egos.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My friend Jack, who eventually became my co-author, gave the answer that you are supposed to give in such situations. He said that it did not matter, that our guard was up and we were fully prepared for anything that may come — whether that was a chicken dinner or a bunch of bullets — and that we were ready and capable of responding appropriately. During the days that followed, in the chaos that was the early days of post-invasion Baghdad, we would have to face both of those scenarios, and many more, sometimes at the same moment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The war junky reporter on the ground pointed the mic at me, and (at least as I remember it) I simply asked one question: “Do &lt;em>you&lt;/em> feel safer now that we are here?”&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="twenty-nine-palms-ca-late-2002">Twenty-Nine Palms, CA, Late, 2002&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the run up to the war I did not allow any part of my brain to engage in an intellectual discourse with any other part of my brain as to the rightness or wrongness of the job any idiot could see was coming for us. I had a job to do, and I was damn determined to be good at that job. Or at least, to try my best to be good at it. I was worried that if I allowed the self-felating ethical discourse to overtake and supplant my thinking that I would not be as fast, as precise, as &lt;em>on&lt;/em> as I needed to be in order to actually accomplish the job that was coming for me. Perhaps, upon reflection from the perspective of ten years, that was the incorrect decision.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Perhaps it was the correct decision. Either way, it would not have mattered. I did not meet the religious pre-affiliation rules in order to actually be a conscientious objector and therefore it was going to be an offense that would lead me to a court martial if I did not do my best to accomplish my job. And when I’m brutally honest with myself, I was excited about it. I wanted to go. Because when you go into the Marines, especially into an infantry battalion, if you don’t go to war it is basically just masturbation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During this time, before we deployed to Kuwait, my friend Faith forwarded an email detailing the time and location of upcoming anti-war demonstrations in New Orleans where she was living at the time. To my …@usmc.mil email address. When I first got the email I smiled. I was pleased that anti-war demonstrations were happening. In some ways it made it easier to accept my own, conscious, lack of any ethical discourse within myself. But to my work email address? I saw that it was just to a bunch of people, as many forwarded emails were in the times before facebook. So I didn’t really blame her. Yet, I did respond to the email. Although I don’t fully remember what I wrote, I think it was something along the lines of “Thanks for the email. I fully support your right to do that. Just don’t send any such emails to my work account!”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I do remember thinking at one point after I replied (in probably an overly cold way) that that was their job and I had my job and our jobs were different. Then I simply put it out of my mind and went about preparing what needed to be prepared.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="hargeisa-somaliland-early-2013">Hargeisa, Somaliland, Early, 2013&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>My reply to Peter Jennings was not meant as sarcasm. My reply was meant honestly. Although my voice, combined with my love of sarcasm, led most to believe I meant it sarcastically. After the intensity of the now that was then has dissipated and we Americans are forced to live with the choices of the leaders we chose, and the knowledge that many Iraqis are also forced to live with the choices of the leaders they did not choose, I will ask it again. “Do you feel safer now that we are here?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I will stop at this point and say one thing. If someone wants to put some faux comment on this post saying, “thank you for your service” I will delete it. I absolutely abhor those comments. They ring hollow to me and mean absolutely nothing. I did not really serve. I did a job. Sure those that entered the armed forces after 9/11 knew, in a way that I had no idea of when I signed on the line, or, at a minimum, they had some idea of, what they were getting into. Perhaps they “served” in the sense that word is often used. But I did not. I simply did a job. A job that I was contractually obliged to do. And, perhaps, wanted to do. But either way, it was a job.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yet there’s another, more important, reason that I abhor that phrase.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="champaign-illinois-late-1999">Champaign, Illinois, Late, 1999&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We had a tradition in our Naval Reserve Officer’s Training Corp (ROTC) group that on the last Thursday before anyone graduated they had an opportunity to take the floor. Most used it as a way to proffer vapid “advice” on matters of which they knew not or to provide idiotic thank yous to people they would never see again and perhaps neither liked nor respected. That all seemed quite stupid to my 23 year old self. When my turn came, after some of my best and greatest friends had their chance to say what they felt appropriate to say, I stood up and recited the following.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>John Brown went off to war to fight on a foreign shore
His mama sure was proud of him!
He stood straight and tall in his uniform and all
His mama’s face broke out all in a grin&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Oh son, you look so fine, I’m glad you’re a son of mine
You make me proud to know you hold a gun
Do what the captain says, lots of medals you will get
And we’ll put them on the wall when you come home”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As that old train pulled out, John’s ma began to shout
Tellin’ ev’ryone in the neighborhood:
“That’s my son that’s about to go, he’s a soldier now, you know”
She made well sure her neighbors understood&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She got a letter once in a while and her face broke into a smile
As she showed them to the people from next door
And she bragged about her son with his uniform and gun
And these things you called a good old-fashioned war&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh! Good old-fashioned war!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then the letters ceased to come, for a long time they did not come
They ceased to come for about ten months or more
Then a letter finally came saying, “Go down and meet the train
Your son’s a-coming home from the war”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She smiled and went right down, she looked everywhere around
But she could not see her soldier son in sight
But as all the people passed, she saw her son at last
When she did she could hardly believe her eyes&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh his face was all shot up and his hand was all blown off
And he wore a metal brace around his waist
He whispered kind of slow, in a voice she did not know
While she couldn’t even recognize his face!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh! Lord! Not even recognize his face&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Oh tell me, my darling son, pray tell me what they done
How is it you come to be this way?”
He tried his best to talk but his mouth could hardly move
And the mother had to turn her face away&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Don’t you remember, Ma, when I went off to war
You thought it was the best thing I could do?
I was on the battleground, you were home . . . acting proud
You wasn’t there standing in my shoes”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Oh, and I thought when I was there, God, what am I doing here?
I’m a-tryin’ to kill somebody or die tryin’
But the thing that scared me most was when my enemy came close
And I saw that his face looked just like mine”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh! Lord! Just like mine!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“And I couldn’t help but think, through the thunder rolling and stink
That I was just a puppet in a play
And through the roar and smoke, this string is finally broke
And a cannonball blew my eyes away”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As he turned away to walk, his Ma was still in shock
At seein’ the metal brace that helped him stand
But as he turned to go, he called his mother close
And he dropped his medals down into her hand&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ John Brown by Bob Dylan (lyrics available &lt;a href="http://www.bobdylan.com/us/songs/john-brown#ixzz2O6Kzjo5a" title="Bob Dylan - John Brown">here&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Here I was, 23. Mere days from beginning The Basic School, which is where all Marine Officers begin their journey. Reciting the lyrics of a poet famously known for his anti-war positions to a bunch of people who were only months away from beginning their journeys in the military. But I had a point. A point I still believe deeply in. A point I never explained, as when I finished reciting the poetry that is Dylan’s song I simply walked out of the room (or just sat down, can’t remember exactly).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fourteen years later, let me get to the point. If you are going to do this thing called the military. Called war. Know what the hell you are getting yourself into.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I did not mean don’t do war, and there is nothing within the song (even from my now quite adamant anti-war position) that is actually overtly anti-war. The real message of the song is that those that cheerlead for war without understanding the consequences of what they are saying do a great disservice to those that actually do go to war. Those that go to war, that enter the military, are forced to struggle with what this means to each. This thing we call war. Of course what it means, being an existential question, will differ from person to person. The point is not the answer arrived at by any individual, the point is that the individual took that journey. Dylan was not saying that those people who embark upon this journey and exit it with some conclusion are bad. He was not saying that war was bad or good, right or wrong, or any other other banal symbols lazy people use when they do not want to struggle with a difficult question. What Dylan was saying is that those who cheerlead from the sidelines but do not embark upon this journey themselves — with honesty and self-reflection — are more harming to society than those that hold the guns and fire the rounds.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="hargeisa-somaliland-early-2013-1">Hargeisa, Somaliland, Early, 2013&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>And this is how I find &lt;em>most&lt;/em> of the “thanks for your service”. So let me say it more clearly. Just because Fox News, whose editorial board learned from the heartbreaking stories of Vietnam veterans (who often had no choice whether to go and who often acted in the best way they knew in some crazy situations) returning home to be spat upon, tells people that it is somehow patriotic to thank veterans for their service does not mean that it actually is. Am I saying that it is &lt;em>bad&lt;/em> to say that, or that others will not fully appreciate if one were to say the same phrase to them? Not in the slightest. But I am saying that, to me, the phrase is mostly a vapid self-justification more beneficial to the speaker than to the spoken.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Do you feel safer now?” I meant it when I said it. And I mean it now. It is easy for us that feel the Iraq War was a shameful enterprise to embark upon to blame Bush and Cheney for entering a war unilaterally, without justification that has cost over 4,400 American lives, cost probably a hundred times that in Iraqi lives, brought innumerable wounds, severed innumerable families, and cost over $3T (money which would have solved world hunger twice over by many estimates). In my mind that is not the question. Sure Bush and Cheney were power hungry, manipulative, and greedy. You don’t become President of the United States by being humble. We Americans, we reward the greedy, hungry, manipulative people in business, in politics, in celebrity culture. We have done it for years and there is no abatement in sight. In fact the “American Dream” is simply a less egregious version of this. In other words, we have built it into our Nation’s DNA. While I have problems, big problems, with their legal justification for entering the war and I am wary that we have set a precedent within international law that does not progress us humans down the road of tolerance and dialogue, I don’t blame them any more than I blame America as a whole.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the last few days I’ve seen an onslaught of &lt;em>mea culpas&lt;/em> from media elite saying, why didn’t we do our job as the media? That’s fine. They should feel guilt as they committed gross malpractice. But there was plenty of commentary available, even in those days before social media (did the world exist before social media?), to those that wanted to find it. Hell, I knew it was around and I was actively trying to avoid it. So, if I’m honest with myself they certainly played their part, but I don’t blame them any more than I blame America as a whole.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What I meant when I asked Peter Jennings, and his many American viewers, that question is this. I am doing my job. A job that collectively, you citizens, you media, and you the leaders we all elected collectively, have sent me to do. My own personal views as to my safety is 100% beside the point. I am a Marine. My job is to stand between danger and Americans. I am trying my best to do this. But you, the American people must ask yourself, do YOU feel safer? I’ve done my part, my job. Did you do yours?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Who do I blame the most, if blame is to be apportioned at all? I blame the cheerleaders. All of them. From the bureaucracy to the media to the businessmen licking their chops at the chance to exploit defense budgets to the average citizens putting up yellow ribbons and in their hearts pleased that their son/daughter/brother/sister/friend was “doing their part.” I blame the cheerleaders for not learning from the demonstrators.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So the next time you simply take a politician at their word without a thoughtful examination of what you actually think on the matter, the next time you choose to rename “french fries” to “freedom fries” because the French polity had the gall to challenge their leaders and to demand a continuation of the, admittedly cold, peace. In these times, ask yourself: “Do I feel safer now?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why I Started Watershed Legal Services: My Journey from Expat Aid Worker to Expat Entrepreneur</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-04-23-why-i-started-watershed/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-04-23-why-i-started-watershed/</guid><description>&lt;p>a[![Ninja Law Firm via SolYoung @ flickr][2]][2]
Ninja Law Firm via SolYoung @ flickr&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I read an interesting article yesterday from a man who I referenced in my previous post as one of my favorite development bloggers: Owen Barder. Owen has joined a DC based development think-tank called Center for Global Development and in his [good-bye to Ethiopia post][2] he had an interesting thing to say about aid. He claims, and I heartily support, that development is much broader than simply aid, it is about trade policy, climate policy, monetary policy (which he didn’t actually mention), and numerous other policies which the developed world implements and in the globalized economy has massive effects in the developing world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/entry/why-i-started-watershed/4928948235_9882789b97">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/entry/why-i-started-watershed/4928948235_9882789b97&lt;/a>
[2]: &lt;a href="http://www.owen.org/blog/4540">http://www.owen.org/blog/4540&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The article returned my thoughts to something which I have pondered off and on for the eight months since we have opened the doors on &lt;a href="http://watershedlegal.com">Watershed Legal Services&lt;/a>, my small law firm in this corner of the Horn of Africa.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are an assortment of varied and divergently relevant reasons why I invested my time and money in this entity. It is a hodge-podge, a kaleidoscope which changes its predominant colors over time. For one, I wanted to get off the NGO train, to stop skimming the surface of places and to dig into a country. To plant roots. For another, my marriage wasn’t going to thrive in an environment where we were constantly moving as my wife is also a professional and the chances of two professionals finding professionally satisfying positions in a new country every two or three years was daunting at best. And I simply fell in love with Somalis and Somaliland – despite (or perhaps because of) its craziness, its madness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Those are mainly all personal reasons, but there were also some professional reasons which I have considered at length. Rightly or wrongly I was tired of a culture of giving. Now that is not to say that I have stopped giving, indeed I cannot count the number of pro bono hours that our small firm has performed in our short life. I am not tired of giving, I am tired of the expectation that I am here to give – full stop. I am tired of a culture where nothing will happen without a body with money external to the state saying yes we will  fund that. These are backwards to how I see the world. I have no problems with giving a man a fish. But when there are so many fish givers in a place that the giving of a fish becomes an expectation then I think we have reached a point where things should be reevaluated. It isn’t development, it isn’t sustainable, and something has to give. This is why I was excited to start a for-profit law firm, this is why we don’t chase projects in the same way that NGOs do, this is why we haven’t taken outside funding from foundations or other organizations who have shown willingness to assist organizations such as Watershed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Law is not something that can be given. It is, at its core, a conversation between power centers. This conversation ebbs and flows over time. It changes and must change in order to have life and to enable its success. While it is a conversation which can often be informed by actors abroad, if it is not a conversation within the society in which it is being imposed, it will never be successful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me put some meat on that paragraph. What I see from the other side of the table now that I have switched from a legal reform NGO to a practitioner within the country is a tangled mess of laws which will never be implemented here. I see laws built by consultants from other countries who have never bothered to learn the legal structures of this country and bring their own governance proclivities with them. The simple fact of a Kenyan consultant coming to Somaliland to write a law brings big troubles because until recently Kenya was a fundamentally British parliamentary system. Those types of governments operate in a fundamentally different way than governments on a different part of the spectrum. Somaliland, in contradistinction, is built upon an American model. You cannot simply take ideas of how the conversations between power centers works in one system and transplant them whole sale into a different system. Yes, there are often analogies, but not always. American notions of the separation of power and the reasons that America has been able to make an independent executive work requires a method of thought which differs in so many ways. It is like comparing how you talk to your close friends over a cup of coffee sitting on their couch to how you would talk to a new business associate. You talk fundamentally different because the social modes which develop around each of those situations is vastly different. The same is true about law.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So really it boils down to the fact that I wanted to help Somaliland develop its own way of conversing. I want to stop consultants coming from other countries dropping off finished laws and running away. I want to assist parliament and the government to learn how to converse with each other in a legal sense. I want to give young, sharp lawyers a chance to move beyond a simple contract for an NGO where they will never be pushed where they will stagnate and never have the chance to have the feeling of a bit of hard work pushed out the door and the ultimate relaxation and joy which follows.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That, my friends, is why I do what I do. That, my friends, is why I’m more professionally satisfied in these recent months than I’ve ever been in my life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>11 for &amp;#8217;11 (AKA Leigh and Casey make a List)</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-01-04-11-for-11/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-01-04-11-for-11/</guid><description>&lt;p>Instead of resolutions, this year Leigh and I came up with our 11 for 11 – a list of the 11 specific, controllable, quantifiable things we want to accomplish in 2011.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here were the rules (since we’re lawyers and all).  There is a very long list of three.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(1) &lt;strong>Item SHALL have Boolean Attributes.&lt;/strong> This means that at 2359 on 31 December 2011, the item in question must be able to be given a True/False declaration.  This requires the item to be crafted such that it is definable, measurable, and specific.  Items such as “improve the quality of the services we deliver” are definitely out as they cannot be defined.  Items such as “give are clients great services” are definitely out as they cannot be measured.  You get the picture.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(2) &lt;strong>Achievement of the item SHALL remain within the reasonable control of the declarant at all times.&lt;/strong> This means that items which are wholly out of control are not allowed.  Items such as “get invited to Davos, TED, and Clinton Global Initiative” are not within the control of the declarant at all and may not be on the list.   There is a qualifier on reasonable control wholly within the control of the declarant may require complete isolation – something us social beings can rarely achieve.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(3) &lt;strong>Item SHALL not be overly materialistic&lt;/strong>. We wanted to track things that were fun and simple rather than list out how I want a new iPad.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can follow the progress of the list over &lt;a href="http://elevens.caseykuhlman.com">here&lt;/a>!  I’ll be making small visual storytelling pages for each of the events which lend themselves to such an endeavor.  So, without further adieu: Our 11 for ’11:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Buy Tickets for London Olympics&lt;/li>
&lt;li>One Night of Nothing but Music&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create Tasting Menu w/ Seasonal &amp;amp; Local Products&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ice Skate on a Frozen Pond&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Establish a Home Base&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Eat @ a Restaurant Owned by a Top Chef Winner&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Attend or Host a Wine Tasting&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Attend at least one Outdoor Concert&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Prepare an alfresco picnic by a stream&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Spend our anniversary together&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Spend an afternoon mushrooming&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On Going Local: Relationships</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-16-local-relationships-unofficial-chains/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-16-local-relationships-unofficial-chains/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>On Going Local is a (short) series that I’m running which will attempt to look at my life from an objective perspective as I transition from and NGO worker into an entrepreneur here in the developing world.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?p=421">&lt;img src="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?p=421" alt="PeyoteLeaderCheyenne1927 by Medicinehorse7 @ flickr">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Relationships here in Somaliland are odd, to say the least.  There are two main identifiable cultural divergences.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first is that many relationships are deeper here in Somaliland than similar relationships would be back home.  Deeper in the sense that they are more utilized, more cherished, and more complicated than a similar set of relationships would be in America.  (I will return to these themes, but let me finish my introduction first.  Don’t be in such a hurry!)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The second is that many (other) relationships are shallower that similar relationships would be back home.  They are more shallow in the sense that they are less utilized, less cherished, and less complicated than a similar set of relationships would be in America.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a long time this was opaque to me.  And then the scenery started to open up, but like with the two stories from an earlier &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?p=421">post&lt;/a> on decoding the somali mind there was little cultural alignment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is what I was seeing after I had been here long enough to scratch the surface coating off of the Somalilanders.  On the one hand, I was seeing friends who would actually talk to one another about many different issues.  Friends who would gather and sit and discuss, day after day.  But on the other hand I was seeing romantic relationships that were either business relationships or almost elementary.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="romantic-relationships">Romantic Relationships&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Last week, a woman dumped a jug full of kerosene all over her body and lit herself on fire.  Just 30 meters from the gate of our compound.  Apparently it was because her boyfriend broke up with her. It was in the early evening and there were many people around.  They forced the woman to stop-drop-and-roll.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apparently she survived the initial situation and was taken to the hospital.  Considering the healthcare in this country and her likely third-degree burns I’m unsure whether she survived for very long thereafter. Although my initial reaction was that this was about a passionate, tragic love affair gone wrong – a story which likely any culture can relate to – it was more likely about the stigma which would follow the poor woman after the man refused to marry her after their affair had gone public.  I do not know that for certain, but it is my educated guess.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Relationships between the sexes are tremendously strained here in Somaliland.  While that comes with the territory in many ways, what I’ve noticed is that in many ways relationships, especially romantic relationships, between the sexes are riven with what I would consider immaturities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Twenty-somethings and thirty-somethings that are involved in romantic relationships rarely discuss their relationships, creating a situation of insularity stifling development and deepening of many of the relationships. Of course, arranged marriages are still very customary and prevalent.  In these cases the romance and the business-politics of clan and diyah-paying groups are conflated forcing individuals into catch-22 situations where they are forced to subordinate their own desires for the benefit of their clan or family.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For me personally, it is fascinating to learn about this situation because it seems such a throw-back.  I suspect for much of human history marrying someone for business-political reasons has been more important than many current historians / anthropologists would give credit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A couple of months ago I was chewing with some people including some American-Somalilander diaspora and they were asking me one of the biggest questions I always get: “how do you find Somaliland”?  I like it when diaspora ask me this question because they find themselves in a situation similar to me – somewhere in between the two cultures. Usually when non-diaspora ask me this question I give an white-washed answer.  This time, for whatever reason, I was feeling especially honest.  I replied that for the most part I have not experienced much culture shock as I read and studied a lot before I even arrived.  The thing which has been the biggest cultural shock to me, I told them, has been the cultural response to a widowing. In Somali culture (and I am told but cannot confirm – many Arab cultures) if a husband passes away his brother will be forced to marry the sister-in-law. When I first heard this, I remember shaking my head and furrowing my brow deeply.  But I asked why.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The answer, actually, makes semi-sense.  It is because if the wife remarries someone outside of the family than the children that she had with her deceased husband will be considered outsiders by the new husband and he will abandon them.  So it is a cultural mechanism to ensure that the children were taken care of.  That I can see and understand – to the extent that it is simply a support mechanism.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Later, when I became closer to more Somalis, I asked about the reality and the thing that was really creeping me out – does the brother have to have sex with the former sister-in-law or can it be a show marriage. Their answer was that if the brother doesn’t have sex with the sister-in-law then it isn’t a marriage after all.  Fair enough, but I must say that I’m pleased my own culture has never adopted this situation as it feels too much like incest based upon my own cultural upbringing and proclivities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These anecdotes are a simple reflection of why I say that romantic relationships here in Somaliland are very different than the romantic relationships that I’m accustomed to – tending towards much more shallow.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="friendly-relationships">Friendly Relationships&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>On the other hand, friendly relationships are much deeper than anything that I’m accustomed to.  And here is where I get to the reason for why I chose the picture at the top (aside from his magnificent beauty in austerity).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Somalilanders value their friendships so much.  It is one of the things that I appreciate most about being here.  When you meet someone that you haven’t seen in a while you are guaranteed a big hug, a big smile, a ten minutes of your life you’ll never get back.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The other thing that surprises me is how quickly two people will become friends.  In a short time you go from Mister to Friend to Brother.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For men, especially, there is an avenue by which one can almost fully guarantee they will have a friend for life.  It is what is called fadhigaa or qayilayaa or cunayaa or chewing or sitting together.  Chewing sessions are a great avenue for discussion.  They have a major downside which is that it’s a men’s only club, but that is a deeper issue which I will leave for another time.  Chewing sessions usually last about six hours – although sometimes more, sometimes less depending on the circumstances.  From about 3 pm to 9 pm men will gather in their normal meeting spot.  When you arrive in a majlis (the place for sitting) you get yourself all arranged with your cigarettes in one place, your drinks in another place, your qat over here, your laptop and phone over there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then you sit back take a few deep breathes, and just sit and talk for the next hours.  Like with alcohol or marijuana, qat affects different people differently.  It varies with your state of mind when you begin, with the distinct strain that you always buy, and with your own personal reaction to the qat.  It makes some people retreat into themselves.  You won’t hear from them for hours.  I am not among those.  The other general trend is that it opens people up and is a decent social lubricator.  These people will end up talking and talking and talking much more than when they are sober.  I am among those.  Men come together and listen to the radio, watch BBC or Al Jazeera or the National TV, read the Somali sites, and talk.  This time together in a relaxed environment cements friendships deeply.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On Going Local: Finding Your Happy Place</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-12-local-finding-happy-place/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-12-local-finding-happy-place/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>On Going Local is a new (short) series that I’ll be running which will attempt to look at my life from an objective perspective as I transition from and NGO worker into an entrepreneur here in the developing world.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve been here in Somaliland now for around two and a half years now.  It has been a wonderful time, and I’ve enjoyed every minute of it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are many aspects of Somali / Somaliland society &amp;amp; culture that I have found it easy to adjust too.  But there are a few things which have been difficult.  Not the least of which is the six day work week.  Being an Islamic country, we take Friday off.  But that most people take off.  Going from a two day weekend to a one day weekend with shorter days throughout the six was a big adjustment and I’m not sure that I will ever fully adjust to it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, this is about space.  Physical space.  Like most development workers I lived for a long time in a &lt;a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/caseykuhlman/SomalilandCompound02" title="Gorgorka Luxury Estates">gigantic house&lt;/a> shared among an assortment of other expatriates, cleaners, cooks, guards, and staff.  It can be a fantastically good time having all the excitement of different activities, smells, and languages around you.  For a little while…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a time, though, it becomes stifling.  For one thing, you are never “off duty.”  At any time of the day or night someone may come and knock on your door.  Someone’s family member is sick and they need money; someone’s mobile phone was stolen and they need money; the guards caught two people making out in a dark corner behind the house; all sound tracked to random gunshots due to land disputes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most development or aid workers I know always like to say it’s not a job, it’s a lifestyle.  And that is all well and good, but it isn’t a lifestyle I was very interested in.  Sure you can try to set boundaries, but you don’t want to incentivize the people working with you to not tell you what is happening.   That can lead to all kinds of problems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This balance is incredibly difficult to achieve between having some personal space (when the standard living situation is tenement and shared, college-esque, except we’re not college age anymore) and being “open.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have recently moved out of that mansion into what would be normal to me.  Luckily enough it is also what would be normal to a middle-class Somali.  Instead of ten bedrooms (some of which were office space), I now have three.  Instead of having to walk 15 minutes to get to the kitchen, it now takes me 15 seconds.  I don’t have to worry about staff all of the time as I only have someone who comes to clean for me a few days a week &amp;amp; when I’m at the office.  It is safer this way, as you are a target when you live in a mansion.  You can do what you like without having to worry about being disturbed.  You can metaphorically unpack your bags.  You can find normality in an otherwise frantic existence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The place I’m living now actually feels like a home rather than a dorm.  And that is fantastic.  I love my old roommates dearly, but it is so nice to have something that is “yours.”  And when my wife comes down next year for a bit, my life will be complete!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On Going Local: Water</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-17-local-water/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-17-local-water/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>On Going Local is a new (short) series that I’ll be running which will attempt to look at my life from an objective perspective as I transition from and NGO worker into an entrepreneur here in the developing world.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I first arrived here in S’land, and I would go out to eat, I would use the minimum amount of water possible to wash my hands before and after eating with them.  It is desert afterall.  But later, towards the end I realized that I had adapted and was using more water – letting the water run as I was soaping, washing my face also.  It was never a conscious decision, I just started using more water.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But here at the house, I have always remained conscious of how much water we are using – primarily because at the house we have to pay for the water and it is EXPENSIVE. It is desert afterall.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I just wanted to share a bit about how the water works.  Here in Hargeisa we have a decent supply of water, but it is getting strained by the continuing population growth of the city.  There is this beautiful area about 30 km to the north of Hargeisa, in the Golis Mountains where most of the water comes from.  One of the main problems is that the area is a couple hundred meters of elevation lower than Hargeisa.  That means PUMPS generators performing the difficult job of getting the water up here to Hargeisa.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Hargeisa Water Agency has identified two other locations which could supply Hargeisa and both are higher and would require less pumping power.  The problem is getting the infrastructure built.  The Agency has a difficult time amassing enough capital to even upgrade the pipe network from the original series of wells into Hargeisa.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once the water gets to Hargeisa then it gets routed to different zones.  Typically one or two zones within Hargeisa will get water on a given night, and then the Agency will rotate zones over the course of the week.  Once the water is released to the zones then the zone manager is responsible for routing it into particular customers of the agency.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The irregularity of the water supply means that most compounds have built their own water reservoirs and then we watch these like a hawk.  Our reservoir is underground.  Because it is a totally passive system, what we have to do is each day we check supplemental tanks which are on the highest part of the house.  These tanks provide the house with water pressure, but do it passively.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pretty much each day we pump water from the underground reservoir to the upper holding tanks.  This means that we only have to use the electricity to pump the water up once a day rather than running it continuously (which is important because electricity is also EXPENSIVE).  The system works quite well most of the time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The only problem comes when we let the upper holding tanks run dry.  What happens (because the system is passively pressurized) then is that air runs down through the water lines in the house.  After we fill the upper holding tanks the air pressurizes from the weight of the water above it and keeps the water from flowing through the plumbing system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many of you living in Africa may have experienced this problem.  So here is what you do when the water won’t flow through your house.  You go to the bottom most taps in your system and open all of them that you can find.  This will bleed the air pressure from the system.  When those taps are running well, then you can go upstairs and turn one a couple of taps.  This should bleed the rest of the air from the system and then water should fill all of the lines.  Then you have to run around the house turning off all of the taps because you hate wasting water!  You may have to fiddle with your hot water heaters (if you are lucky enough to have them) as they sometimes become a hassle to bleed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But this is a small hassle – and after a while it becomes second nature to bleed the lines when you know that the upper tanks have run dry.  This is one of my favorite parts of living in the developing world.  You are forced to learn about the world around you which you so often take for granting living in the developed world where you never have to understand fluid dynamics and watershed elevation limitations in order to take a shower!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Powered by Wind and Other Things</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-03-19-powered-wind/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-03-19-powered-wind/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://africaknows.com">&lt;img src="http://africaknows.com" alt="">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(Photo via: &lt;a href="http://africaknows.com">africaknows.com&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like this guy, I’ve been up in the clouds lately.  Luckily our soy is beginning to fabricate.  Things are really coming along with all of my various bits and bobs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the one hand it has passed the time quickly in between when I saw Leigh last and when I will see her again (a week from tonight).  Yet, on the other hand, there’s been some disjunctiveness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The source of so much of my inefficiency as a bad computing environment – top to bottom.  My laptop is getting old and now is a portable desktop which often shuts down whenever I’m least ready.  My internet for the past month has been virtually non-existent, and when the “virtually” modifier was operative, it wasn’t – at least steadily.  Further, I’ve been digging a bit deeper into my own technology usage in preparation for the &lt;a href="http://watershedplatforms.com">Watershed Platforms&lt;/a> launch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I’m wont to do, I have gone a bit overboard in some areas.  I always spread my net quite wide when I’m trying new things as I like to hone it down after being presented with the full buffet.  After I understand things and start to form opinions then I pare it down.  Music, blogs, whatever.  The only problem is that it takes a bunch of time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now my feet seem to be a bit under me.  I’ve transferred my own stuff over, first to an absolutely awful hosting company which frustrated the hell out of me, but now to a new one.  Problematically, I accidentally deleted the entire wordpress database in the process and so had to rebuild everything from scratch – so it basically took twice as long.  In any event, now expect regular dispatches.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The wind is up and I’m pretty much ready.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iLove iTunes Genius</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-12-ilove-itunes-genius/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-12-ilove-itunes-genius/</guid><description>&lt;p>[![Itunes_genius_logo][2]][2]In a departure from deeper content, I submit the following.  iTunes Genius lives up to its title.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/itunes/">http://www.apple.com/itunes/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have no idea how the algorithm works, but it does just work.  As usual with Apple products, the first few times I used it I was distinctly underwhelmed.  But then I came back to it a few months later and I was amazed. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>From what I can tell, it seems to take into account both subjective and objective criteria.  This is key, because I am very anal about how I log, listen, and classify my music collection.  Thanks mom, for that wonderful personality quirk.  I have no idea if the objective criteria are pulled from the iTunes database, crowdsourcing,&lt;br>
or some combination. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yet for whatever reason genius seems to take this into account.  Very little of my music currently has the genre which came when I bought the songs from iTunes.  I have reconfigured everything, and this gets taken into account (from what I can tell) when Genius makes its track decisions.  The other subjective criteria it seems to take into account besides the genres are the ratings, which I’m overly fastidious in using. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yet, it also takes into account some level of objective criteria.  Sometimes if I put on an older track I have the pleasure of many of my old high school favorite tracks.  So it must take into account the year of the album.  Also when I put on a woman singer, most of the tracks selected are women.  &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![Last][3]][3] The last thing, and that which I most appreciate, is that it does a great job of keeping with the overall mood which I’m going for.  If I find one song that fits my particular mood of  the moment – Genius is really good about keeping me in that mood while exploring my music collection in the way that [last.fm][3] allows me to do with an online portfolio outside my music collection.  Last.fm is fantastic, but my bandwidth limitations usually preclude using it.  Sometimes everything is OK, but usually the music is sketchy which is incredibly annoying.  Kudos to Last, by the way, for opening up their interface.  When I first came to Africa I could not listen to my tracks / stations, but now they have fixed that.  Thanks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://www.last.fm/">http://www.last.fm/&lt;/a>
[3]: &lt;a href="http://www.last.fm/user/caseykuhlman">http://www.last.fm/user/caseykuhlman&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![Apple_tv_intro_graphic][5]][5] Generally, I hate listening to my music on my tinny computer speakers.  Luckily, a while ago when I was up in Europe I bought an [AppleTV][5].  This is fantastic for me, because I can plug it into my decent receiver and speakers.  The closed nature of AppleTV is annoying, but there are plenty of hacks.  Yet, even out of the box when combined with Genius it is wonderful.  You get Apple’s stunning, sexy graphic interfaces and your music which can be played on reasonable speakers.  This is a blissful combination for me.  The final thing which I will say is that I use Genius similarly to how I use the web, I wander.  I will find old favorites or new favorites and Genius them to see what else I may be forgetting or never have found within my own music collection.  Genius.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/appletv/">http://www.apple.com/appletv/&lt;/a>
[5]: &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/appletv/">http://www.apple.com/appletv/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wedding</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2009/2009-03-11-wedding/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2009/2009-03-11-wedding/</guid><description>&lt;p>Highlands and I got hitched.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This page will have some of the highlights.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Big_head had the first performance. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/XYuBrpJP55g&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">1&lt;/a>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/XYuBrpJP55g&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">1&lt;/a>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/XYuBrpJP55g&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">1&lt;/a>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/XYuBrpJP55g&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">1&lt;/a>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/XYuBrpJP55g&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">1&lt;/a>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/XYuBrpJP55g&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">1&lt;/a>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/XYuBrpJP55g&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">1&lt;/a>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/XYuBrpJP55g&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">1&lt;/a>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/XYuBrpJP55g&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">1&lt;/a>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/XYuBrpJP55g&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">1&lt;/a>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/XYuBrpJP55g&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">1&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Highland's_Bro had the second performance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/mKvwPyhqdh8&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;rel=0" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">2&lt;/a>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/mKvwPyhqdh8&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;rel=0" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">2&lt;/a>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/mKvwPyhqdh8&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;rel=0" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">2&lt;/a>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/mKvwPyhqdh8&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;rel=0" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">2&lt;/a>
The first round of pictures, taken by my father, are &lt;a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/bigdoglk/CaseyLeighWedding02#">here&lt;/a>. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another round of pictures, taken by Lance / my mom, are &lt;a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/sunsailsurf/Scotland#">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Other pictures for facebookers.  From &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/album.php?aid=64810&amp;amp;id=818758675&amp;amp;ref=mf">Karen&lt;/a>; From &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/album.php?aid=226893&amp;amp;id=576085103&amp;amp;ref=mf">Alex&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building (in) a Developing Country</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-07-23-building-in-a-developing-country/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-07-23-building-in-a-developing-country/</guid><description>&lt;p>We had an epic rainstorm last night.  I had been waiting for one since we’ve moved into our compound as I was concerned about the drainage systems.  The soils here are the sandy clay stuff and because the clay makes the water not permeate the soils and because the sand makes the water flow easily, I was worried about what was happening whenever it rains.  We do a lot of gardening and are trying to keep our compound as green as possible here in the high desert.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yet, that requires a lot of water.  And water is expensive, currently $8 per cubic meter if we truck it up or $3 per cubic meter on the nights that the water board decides to pump water into the main.  We do have a big reservoir for holding the water we use inside the house and a pump to pump it to the tanks on the roof to keep some semblance of water pressure.  We also use this water to keep our garden, orchard, bushes and trees alive. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our gardener is really good.  He has created a nice irrigation path for the water that comes into the compound from the hill above as well as much of the water that flows off the roof and around the compound.  Much of this water does get into the garden and orchard.  The problem is that it creates huge puddles that do eventually seep into the soil but generally deteriorate the fragile topsoils as well as create huge runoff problems, bringing all the crap into the compound from outside.  They have done their best with shovels, but now I’m going to have to bring in the heavy equipment!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last night’s rainstorm finally gave me a chance to see how the water was running into, out of, and around the compound.  We found four places where it will be useful and where we are able to build rainwater retention reservoirs.  These will capture the rainwater and let us use it to keep the garden alive with in the between rains.  It will also keep the massive pools of water from wreaking havoc on the top soil.  So we cited and sized the locations for the four new reservoirs.  We went out this morning to purchase most of the equipment we’ll need to dig the two primary reservoirs.  Since it came out of my pocket, I’m going to have to wait until another paycheck to do the final two.  And now we are in the process of creating these things. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the part of living in a developing country that I love.  The freedom to do what you want and know is right; the interaction with people who know different things than you do; and the realization that everything is essentially the same if you look hard enough for it.  You may have to do a lot of things yourself, but that is also exciting to me.  In the States I call someone and they provide me a service.  Here it is not so easy.  Since we’ve moved into this compound I’ve been a plumber or supervised VERY closely another plumber, I’ve also been or supervised electricians, carpenters, IT consultants, glass dealers, gardeners, hydrologic engineers, structural engineer, construction engineer, mechanical engineer, interior designer and many other trades that I never would have had the opportunity to become elsewhere. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Supervising the building of these reservoirs will serve as the beginning of my learning curve for my next major project: building the first pool in this country and making it solar/wind powered and chemical free using a new salt chlorination system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But first, back to my day job.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Parenting, Gender Roles and My Wedding</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-12-parenting-gender-roles-and-my-wedding/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-12-parenting-gender-roles-and-my-wedding/</guid><description>&lt;p>As I clicked the category for this posting it occurred to me that for much of the first two years of this blog all I wrote about was categorized as &amp;ldquo;living&amp;rdquo; but that for the past three years or so that has decrescendoed to almost a non-existent situation.  Maybe I have spent much more time looking outward and not so much time looking inward, or maybe I have become a bit reticent to write about &amp;ldquo;me&amp;rdquo; as I embark on something akin to being a professional.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nevertheless, the &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2008/06/15/magazine/15parenting-t.html?ex=1371009600&amp;amp;en=ec6fd160e6b4089c&amp;amp;ei=5124&amp;amp;partner=permalink&amp;amp;exprod=permalink">NY Times Magazine&lt;/a> has a great piece on shared parenting that has gotten me thinking.  First a few quotes:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The most recent figures from the University of Wisconsin’s National Survey of Families and Households show that the average wife does 31 hours of housework a week while the average husband does 14 — a ratio of slightly more than two to one.&lt;br>
…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The lopsided ratio holds true however you construct and deconstruct&lt;br>
a family. “Working class, middle class, upper class, it stays at two to&lt;br>
one,” says Sampson Lee Blair, an associate professor of sociology at&lt;br>
the University at Buffalo who studies the division of labor in&lt;br>
families.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“And the most sadly comic data is from my own&lt;br>
research,” he adds, which show that in married couples “where she has a&lt;br>
job and he doesn’t, and where you would anticipate a complete reversal,&lt;br>
even then you find the wife doing the majority of the housework.”&lt;br>
…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is one pocket of American parenting in which equality is the norm or, at least, the mutually-agreed-upon goal. Same-sex couples cannot default to gender when deciding who does what at home. How these parents make their decisions, therefore, sheds some light on why married men and women act the way they do. They are the exceptions that both prove and challenge the rules.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Heterosexual couples can learn from gay couples about sharing housework and child care,” says Esther D. Rothblum, a professor in the women’s studies department of San Diego State University whose comparative study of the relationships of 342 couples — lesbian, gay, heterosexual — was published in the journal Developmental Psychology in January. “They are good role models.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>There are a ton of other good nuggets of wisdom in the piece.  But here is the money quote: &lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Sure, some of their tasks would fall along traditional gender lines. The point, they say, is not to spit at tradition for the heck of it but rather to think things through instead of defaulting to gender.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I think that for whatever reason that is almost exactly my world-view.  As my wedding is beginning its slow march towards reality I have been thinking a lot about gender roles, about tradition and about what the word &amp;ldquo;partner&amp;rdquo; really means to me. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>The sad news is that I have few very few answers to any of these solutions.  But I know that I am less tied to traditional views than many.  That does not mean that I eschew traditional gender roles.  At times, for whatever reason, they can be a handy resource.  When in a hurry Highlands cleans better and faster than I do (although my mother ensured that I would not be inadequate at housework, a value which many years of menial jobs reinforced).  I know things like turn on the car heater when your vehicle is overheating. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yet, the thing about these is when they become forced resentment brews.  I like the notion that is teased out in the article that what is important is expectations.  When those diverge and inevitably are not met resentment, frustration and anger build.  What is important?  Communicating what someone's expectations are to one's partner.  Many of the stories in the article are a bit kooky.  I do not foresee making color coded charts, but the themes of communicating expectations and embracing those that vary slightly from your own resonate very much with me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Automated Killer Robots</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-28-automated-killer-robots/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-28-automated-killer-robots/</guid><description>&lt;p>Link: &lt;a href="http://www.breitbart.com/article.php?id=080227111811.y9syyq8p&amp;amp;show_article=1" title="Automated killer robots 'threat to humanity': expert">Automated killer robots ‘threat to humanity’: expert&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes you read it correct.  AFP does the difficult reporting!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m surprised that they didn’t interview Yoshimi for this article.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Semper Fi, Mac.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-01-23-semper-fi-mac/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-01-23-semper-fi-mac/</guid><description>&lt;p>When I was a young Marine Officer, I was in the depths of a dirty used bookstore in DC when this old timer came up to me.  I was in the Military History section trying to find this one book I was supposed to read and we struck up a conversation.  Turns out he had survived Iwo Jima and other battles in the Pacific.  I will always remember the way he slapped me on the back and said with a particular gleam: &amp;ldquo;Semper Fi, Mac, Semper Fi.&amp;rdquo;  He had served his time, now I’ve served mine.  My contractual commitment ended on New Year’s.  It is odd, in a way I miss having that connection hanging over my head. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>RIP, Great Man of America, RIP</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-01-22-rip-great-man-of-america-rip/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-01-22-rip-great-man-of-america-rip/</guid><description>&lt;p>I meant to post this yesterday but was having technical difficulties.  If you haven’t watched MLK’s speech, if you’ve just seen the clips throughout your life.  Take a moment, or twelve and watch it here.  It is a magnificent achievement, and even if you are not in a position to dedicate your life towards ensuring the equalities that Dr. King was fighting for, even if you think you have no ability to contribute to a world where &amp;ldquo;justice rolls down like water, and righteousness like a mighty stream,&amp;rdquo;  even if you think there is little you can do, just watch it as a piece of Great American Art.  And at the end when Dr. King says &amp;ldquo;Free at last, free at last, thank god almighty we are free at last,&amp;rdquo; think about some small thing that you can do to help.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>updated</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-09-09-updated/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-09-09-updated/</guid><description>&lt;p>finally took the time to upload &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/photos/im_so_german/index.html">the pictures&lt;/a> from the germany/prague trip I took a few weeks ago with my dad. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>the georgia/azerbaijan pictures will come soon…i hope!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>howling through the days</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-09-04-howling-through-the-days/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-09-04-howling-through-the-days/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/underwater/090407_1424_test1.png" alt="">I’m a howler monkey that is investigating the world.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>return of my jedis</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-08-28-return-of-my-jedis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-08-28-return-of-my-jedis/</guid><description>&lt;p>am back in nashville.  i don’t hate it as much as i thought i was going to.  right now.  arrived in the states a week ago today after three straight weeks of torrid traveling that took me to grand places with two of my favorite people in the world.  that was good.  many stories which will not get published here as i am now out of time. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>spent monday with a friend in miami and then drove to orlando.  almost instantly after stepping off the plane i acquired a cold that has just now left me despite od’ing on airborne.  spent tuesday in orlando with my mom and then drove on wednesday to chattanooga to see my uncle.  then drove to nashville thursday morning for a meeting with my mentor and orientation for my journal.  crashed thursday afternoon with a massive headache.  spent friday pulling miles of boxes out of my storage unit.  spent saturday constructing and placing the furniture and big stuff in.  spent sunday arranging, decorating and returning all the stuff that i’m not going to be able to keep here to the unit.  then today i started classes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>have a fairly light class load this semester which is good as i’m working on two independent projects which are going to take up much of my time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>one of my best friends, dave, his wife was supposed to go into the hospital today to have their baby.  i hope that it happens…it is overdue and they seem to be getting anxious.  i want to see that child! &lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>taut in the middle again.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-26-taut-in-the-middle-again/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-26-taut-in-the-middle-again/</guid><description>&lt;p>this weekend it became clear to me that i’ve been living in the middle of much tension while here, and before.  i continually try to float between the text and subtext and context of my life and so many times things get lost in translation between the two.  i sometimes confuse myself whether things are internal or external; whether they matter or don’t; whether they are real or imagined.  feelings emoted, are they proper or improper?  at the end of the day the postmodern interpretation would be that, well, all and nothing matters.  yet that doesn’t lessen the poignancy of the dilemma.  at least, i’m not sure that it does. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>at first i was unsure if i was simply experiencing the pangs of homesickness, but i realized quickly that it wasn’t that.  the sense of loss was for something that may or may not have ever existed. a time, a place, a series of events that may have been real or may have been imagined.  my feels were not so external to be able to characterize them as homesickness.  i became unsure if it was so internal as to be my three month, cyclical existential crisis as to what the fuck am i doing with my life.  it is too early for that to be the case, i just went through it.  it was somewhere in between external and internal catalysts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i missed something, there was a distinct sense of loss, but for what? i couldn’t tell, or at least i couldn’t identify it.  everything was mushed together: a crushed pot-pie of thoughts and ideas, of visions and plans.  some will come to fruition and some are lost.  some things were more poignant than others, some problems seemed to crush me and some seemed acceptable or at least cope-able.  then i started wondering about the foreboding nature of the conclusions i was drawing based upon my thoughts.  nothing is that fatalistic, good can still be accomplished.  sometimes it may require a certain amount of subrogation, nevertheless i guess that is what is supposed to happen.  action and inaction, are different sides of the same coin, right?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>it struck me, as i rode with some friends in a small boat down to the beach that i visited five weeks ago, how little time i’ve spent here.  sometimes it seems like a long time, but mostly it feels like i just arrived.  objectively i’m a quarter of the way through my original contract, which ends the end of june.  i wonder how in the hell i’m 25% completed?  i just arrived.  i’ve been here such a small amount of time.  my feet are barely dry from the states.  where has it gone? i still cannot get access to some of the dataBases at work, and yet i’m tracking towards some sort of return at some point in the future. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>the boat was not always up to the waves thrown at it during portions of the hour and a half trip and a few of the Brits (good, sea-faring people that they are) felt it necessary to put on life jackets.  yet, i wondered why they felt it was necessary to don them since shore was no more than a 100 meters away, 200 at most.  i refused. the waves weren’t that big, but the boats here ride low to the water and so maybe the magnitude gets magnified.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i read for a while at the beach and could not focus on the now for thoughts of the past.  it was a history book and i could not help but think about the parrallels to &amp;ldquo;our current situation with that camel fucker in iraq,&amp;rdquo; as well as other current situations on a world-wide scale.  why do we get involved with things only to fuck them up?  why do we stubbornly stick around and take all the blame from the media when most of may be accurate and, yet, most of it is truly reactionary? &lt;/p>
&lt;p>i became tired.  tired of my book, tired of my uncertainties, tired of wondering, tired of planning, tired of caring so damn much about too many fucking things without being able to express or do anything about any of it, tired of making myself feel guilty about everything done and undone and redone and not-done, tired of feeling good and bad about myself, tired of looking forward and back and down and up, tired.  so i took a nap and got sunburned.  which is ok and — likely — symbolically accurate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i came home and later went to the one place where i can have introverted moments.  a small hotel within walking distance of my house where no expats go.  african big men from around the sub-region come to smoke cigars and talk geo-politics.  i wondered when i left if they would think i am a spy.  which would be awesome.  maybe i now have a tail and don’t know it.  which would also be awesome.  i sat and watched the sun set to my left and began again to wonder about the seasonal and daily oscillations and whether i’m destined to continue or whether i can ever actually get them under control.  i wondered if anything was ever going to be able to be reconciled within my head?  would my desires (long-term, medium-term, short-term) ever align?  or have i created a situation that has judged me guilty and set me on a continually self-perpetuating cycle of … of what?  i don’t know, but it all cycles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i walked home and thought about the tension, do i look up?  everyone around here keeps their head up.  not sure if it is because they are so used to carrying things on their head, or if the social norms dictate that you not look down, or if it is a pride thing.  yet, at home i always watch were i’m going on a more specific and less general level.  this has been a skill that serves me well here where the ditches are random and deep and filled with sewage, where the potholes will break your ankle, even while walking, and where the puddles are likely filled with parasites of unthinkable (to me) voracity. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>and yet i don’t know if i’m supposed to look down at where i’m going or up at where i’m going?  am i supposed to look behind me or look ahead and wait for a car or a light to illuminate the shadows of those walking behind me? is it easier to assess their probability of picking my pocket by pretending to not pay attention while keeping aware of their presence, or should i really turn around and assess from a proper perspective?  but at any rate it is usually moot because they couldn’t really care less if i was there or not and they just pass me as i walk at my new-found Africa pace, which is to say…slow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i stopped along the way and helped some men push a dead taxi cab a long ways.  they were amazed that i did it, but thankful for the extra set of legs which were not as strong as their’s, but helpful to some extent.  it put a few things in perspective: the exertion (it was a long ways).  yet, i cannot quite put a finger on what perspective or what things they were.  at least i could see a bit clearer, the fog wasn’t so deep.  i thought of my heritage and how pushing cars and visions of my dad have affected both my perspective and my trajectory.  have i chosen this perpetual longing for something unattainable, or is my climb up the sand dune not my choice, some wierd conflagration of nature and nurture combined to explode in my head like a chemistry experiment gone bad? i certainly could have chosen not to help them push the car, but what would my heritage think about that?  is it better to regret doing or to regret cowardice or to regret both or to not regret at all? &lt;/p>
&lt;p>today? today i cannot concentrate and feel the fog is pervasive. i have been asked questions, serious questions, and am getting them all convuluted.  all of the answers are swirling and i am having difficulty putting together which answer fragment goes with which question. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>maybe i just need some ritalin.  that seems to cure everything, right?  maybe i just need to figure out my entire life.  maybe i just need to stop caring.  maybe i just need to realize that tensions will always exist, without them life would be much more boring.  or maybe, that like two fingers squeezing a slimy watermelon seed, pressure is the only way to move forward, and i should revel that when the fog clears a path may be slightly clearer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>HAppy TUrkey</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-11-23-happy-turkey/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-11-23-happy-turkey/</guid><description>&lt;p>Happy Thanksgiving all.  I’ll be at friends drinking mass quantities of rum and beer, eating mass quantitites of meat and watching mass quantities of football.  AHHHHHH, the most masculine of all holidays. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yesterday I was driving somewhere and I saw an entire house decorated up for Thanksgiving.  I thought, &amp;ldquo;now there’s some peep’s that know how to give thanksgiving its props.&amp;rdquo;  I don’t like it when Thanksgiving doesn’t get its props.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>why i do yoga</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-11-01-why-i-do-yoga/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-11-01-why-i-do-yoga/</guid><description>&lt;p>people do stupid shit for stupid reasons all the time.  i do yoga.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i look around the studio from time to time and i wonder why everyone else is there.  i think at my studio here in nashville most people are doing the hot yoga becuase it is, like, so relaxing.  that and it is close to their little sorority houses.  these are the girls in short tight black shorts, blue sports bras and t-shirts with party titles over them.  they bring their cell phones into class; they bring their mouths into class; they bring their figetting into class; they’ve got it all as i’m sure they are happy to proclaim.  that isn’t why i do yoga.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i think that many other people do it to lose weight.  this seems a much more laudable goal than the passive workout goal that the slut-ority girls take.  these people are very passive as well, but in a different way.  they are their with their loose shorts, their blank t-shirts and a look of determination, pain and hope in their eyes.  that isn’t why i do yoga.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>then there are the workout junkies.  these are the women that i see a couple of times a week and the other guy who i see a bunch.  they are in yoga clothes, they have carriers for their yoga mats.  they bring cockiness, energy, flexibility and happiness into the room.  they are the ones that laugh when the teacher claims that we’re going to be in the pose for only seven more minutes, becuase they are in shape enough to be relaxed enough to laugh.  that isn’t why i do yoga.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>at times during my journey through yoga i have been in each of these three categories.  passive workout, weight loss determined, junkie performance focussed.  i’m not sure how i would categorize myself now, though.  when i first started i was in colorado and was in great shape, running five times a week and attending yoga once.  i just wanted something different.  i was starting down the holistic road that i currently am further along and i had read so many times what good it was for your balance (which i sought for skiing, climbing and kayaking) as well as your strength and focus (which i sought for….life). &lt;/p>
&lt;p>at first i was baffled.  it was a constant mental endeavour that i didn’t really enjoy but took enjoyment at a remove from the masichistic happenings.  i liked that i wasn’t comfortable.  i liked that i wasn’t sane.  i liked that i wasn’t god. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>then after i moved to nashville and started to settle in here i started to go about twice a week and was running about three or so times a week.  at this point i had been running for about 12 years, averaging something like 20 or 25 miles a week on my legs.  that is a lot of miles: do the math.  i was really tight and i was starting to show in the yoga studio.  my hips, my gluts, my quads were all no where near as flexible as they should be for someone who was actually in shape.  i overcompensated for this by forcing my way into poses.  i pulled muscles constantly.  i had no balance, but i had focus and i muscled through poses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>during winter break last year my knees started to give me fits while running and i made a pact with myself to take a year off of running and to just do yoga.  i had been steadily creschendoing my attendence to yoga all along the way and i knew that it could sufice to keep me in shape and slender enough to not kill myself plus it wouldn’t bang my legs as much.  so i started going about four times a week.  that was enough.  i started to get really used to things.  i got used to the sequence.  i got used to my heartrate and when it increased and decreased.  i thought i was figuring it all out.  i wasn’t.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>lately i’ve been steadily instituting half-ass yoga sessions where i force myself to not muscle anything, but to just take a step off of every pose.  go into them 3/4 of what i would normally do.  i started to learn some things.  i started to learn how to relax.  i went much deeper objectively when i relaxed.  it was antithetical to the modern western view of how to work out.  if you want to get bigger you put more weight on the bar.  if you want to get more flexible you relax.  this is becuase muscles have little springs that keep the muscle from ripping away from the bone.  these springs clamp down with you force something, but if you can get them to relax the muscles can generally get looser.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>but this is a story, not a reason.  i go to yoga b/c it is my rock.  it is the only steadiness in my constantly swirling world.  don’t get me wrong i’m not complaining about my swirls.  i create them, i encourage them, i like them.  but there is a side of me that likes sameness.  it is that side that i passify when i walk into the yoga studio.  it is why i do bikram yoga.  he is known as mcYoga and i know that i can walk into one of his studios in boulder, austin, NYC, key west or nashville and it will be the same series.  it is my sameness that i like. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>i think that the woman who owns the studio here discounts that.  her view is that yoga should be like life, constantly flowing and constantly changing, and humans should learn to relax and go with the flow.  i understand that view.  especially from her perspective where the studio is her life.  the studio is not my life, it is my harbor from my life.  i get annoyed when she changes things unilaterally without even telling us so that we can chose differently.  my favorite teacher there is the metronome woman.  she keeps us in poses for the same amount of time each time, ,she starts on time, she finishes on time, she doesn’t do different poses &amp;ldquo;just for fun.&amp;rdquo;  i love her.  she inherently understands why I come to yoga.  this philosophical alignment makes for a better class.  when i can relax my mind i can relax my body.  if you make me think then i cannot relax my body as much. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>i have three rules and after i do a few warm-up stretches i say a little mantra to myself while i lay down with my eyes closed and the little japanese music playing. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>rule number 1: feed, don’t fight.  it is imperative to not fight the energy in the room, don’t fight the teacher, even if you don’t like what she is doing, don’t fight the people in the room.  feed off of their insecurities, off their figetting, off their yogic energy, feed off the energy in the room.  feed, don’t fight.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>rule number 2: you are an amateur.  yoga is a process, it is not a destination.  don’t think that you are going to get there today.  it is ok to not go all out.  it is ok that you don’t go as far as she does.  it is ok that you don’t go as far as you did yesterday.  yoga is a practice, it is immeasurable.  release yourself and enjoy it.  you are an amateur.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>rule number 3: go deep.  go deep into your mind.  enjoy what is inside.  don’t worry about what is around you.  don’t worry what is being said.  don’t worry what others are doing.  go deep into your body.  feel your way into poses.  feel your way inside poses.  feel your way out of poses.  don’t look, feel.  go deep.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i say that mantra every single time.  almost word for word, to myself as i lay there. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>THAT is why i go to yoga….that, and i’m a dirty fucking hippie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>best or optimal?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-08-11-best-or-optimal/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-08-11-best-or-optimal/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have decided to&lt;br>
return to Vanderbilt this semester.  My job possibility with the Program&lt;br>
Director for USAID down in Colombia is coagulating, but slowly.  I am&lt;br>
going to try to set it up to be down there from January until August,&lt;br>
and use that time to get a semester long externship from Vanderbilt. &lt;br>
Then return and finish up two semesters and be done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I came to Law School, as most of you know, I had three career&lt;br>
tracks in mind: environmental lawyer for a plaintiff’s firm,&lt;br>
media/entertainment lawyer centering my practice on the book industry,&lt;br>
and international development (or as I say, helping developing countries&lt;br>
pull themselves out of poverty without mortgaging their environments). &lt;br>
Over the course of the year and this summer I have realized that I&lt;br>
operate best and am most happy in the policy spectrum where I can pull&lt;br>
on my interdisciplinary skills and my abilities to communicate with lay&lt;br>
people.  The minutiae and the drudgery that would be required if I was&lt;br>
in a firm are irreconcilable with my platform, my convictions and my&lt;br>
goals of &amp;ldquo;making a goddamn difference.&amp;rdquo;  I decided earlier this summer&lt;br>
that the third track, international development, was where I needed to&lt;br>
be.  I maintain that position.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After making that decision I started to research my employment&lt;br>
opportunities.  Most of the consulting firms and public agencies were&lt;br>
recruiting their entry level employees from the MPP (masters of public&lt;br>
policy) schools around the country.  When I thought about it, an MPP&lt;br>
sounded enticing, and this degree was even more enticing when I started&lt;br>
to pull the curriculum.  So I thought that maybe I should have an MPP&lt;br>
instead of a JD.  But I was behind the power curve and would not be able&lt;br>
to start for a year.  I thought about what to do during the interim. &lt;br>
That was where I was when I last sent out a mass email.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since then I have realized from talking to friends, family and mentors&lt;br>
(you all) that it was most advantageous to me to graduate with a JD.  A&lt;br>
JD is one of the most marketable degrees available, and I have already&lt;br>
finished the hardest part of it:  the first year.  A JD is also a&lt;br>
sufficient way to get into international development.  Just because the&lt;br>
firms and agencies pull mostly from MPP schools, that does not mean I&lt;br>
cannot get a job with one of them with a JD.  It seems stupid not to&lt;br>
finish my JD, even though I do not want to be a practicing attorney.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After I made that realization I started to think about the possibility&lt;br>
of doing a joint degree (JD/MPP).  I did more research and found out&lt;br>
that I could get joint degrees at Georgetown and at George Washington. &lt;br>
Both of these schools offered a JD curriculum in environmental and&lt;br>
international law that dwarfs the possibilities Vanderbilt offers, not&lt;br>
to mention their MPP curriculum’s.  Both of these schools are in DC and&lt;br>
the experiential opportunities that would be available to me in DC (with&lt;br>
a Presidential campaign, with the State Department, or with a consulting&lt;br>
firm) dwarf the opportunities that would be available in Nashville. &lt;br>
Both of these schools would allow me to start (if I was accepted as a&lt;br>
transfer student) in January.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a very lucrative possibility.  It is sexy.  It is a gamble.  It&lt;br>
appeals to my sense of adventure, my gambling nature, and my&lt;br>
wanderlust.  It would be the optimal solution.  But it would not be the&lt;br>
best solution.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It seems that the best solution, at this point, is to hammer through my&lt;br>
Vanderbilt JD.  The curricular opportunities, if I choose wisely, will&lt;br>
be sufficient to get me where I want to go.  With summers I can get some&lt;br>
modicum of experiential learning to round out my resume.  And, frankly,&lt;br>
it would be easier to not dislodge my entire life, and to just return.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last night I received an email from my connection down in Colombia.  I&lt;br>
thought for a while that this was going to further contemplate my&lt;br>
at-that-point-unresolved decision.  He wants writing samples and it is&lt;br>
looking more and more likely that he will offer me some sort of an&lt;br>
internship.  But it isn’t going to happen quickly.  At this point the&lt;br>
soonest he could reasonably want to see me down there would be October. &lt;br>
If I am offered an internship I will ask to start in January.  This will&lt;br>
allow me to (hopefully) get credit and maintain my matriculation status&lt;br>
as Vanderbilt.  It will keep me on my path to quickly making a&lt;br>
difference.  It would fill in the gaps in my resume (language and&lt;br>
applied experience in international development).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, in a sense, I am taking the easy road.  My wanderlust is modestly&lt;br>
disappointed in me, but if I can get a great summer internship next&lt;br>
summer (or eight months in Colombia) then I will just tell him to shut&lt;br>
the hell up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>grief</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-08-09-grief/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-08-09-grief/</guid><description>&lt;p>my mamo passed away on friday morning.  i didn’t even know how bad it was until i flew into nashville on thursday.  my mom called after i picked up portlanders and told us to come to the hospital, because she didn’t think that mamo would make it through the night.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>that made for a somber drive.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>we arrived at about 3:30 a.m. at the hospital.  she was asleep, but not comatose.  she was responsive, but only with grunts.  she had no conscious muscular control.  when we walked in my mom said that the groans became louder and closer together.  the loudest came when i made a little funny.  i will tell myself she was laughing with us.  it was hard to see her like that.  i couldn’t even hold her hand.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>now i’ve thought about seeing mamo in this condition, but it was too hard to pursue and so i sloughed it off. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>we left about 4:30 or 5 a.m. and headed to the house.  i was on four hours sleep in four days so i was a bit tired.  i feel asleep in my clothes when we got to the house.  the next thing i knew cam walked in my room.  it was 11:35 friday morning, august 4, 2006.  she had just passed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i washed my face and we all piled into a few cars.  we went to the hospital.  the door was closed when we arrived, mom said they were prepping her (taking out the IV’s and catheters, etc.).  the nurse finished up and opened the door for us.  i walked in and lasted about ten seconds.  i could not look at her.  i was a heap, a wreck, a mess.  i ran out into the hall and wept.  after i recovered i forced myself back into the room. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>i sat with her for an hour or two.  people came and went.  we swung from weeping to hillarious laughter.  it was so emotional that the emotions came out forcefully on either side of the spectrum, but never once were they in the middle.  unless you consider numbness and disbelief in the middle.  after everyone left, doni and i were all that remained.  she gave me a minute alone.  i kissed mamo’s forehead.  i told her how much i loved her.  i told her good-bye.  then i gave doni her turn.  i drove home alone and blared this radiohead song that i love over and over.  at one point i pulled to the side of the road, or at least it seemed like the side of the road but i couldn’t tell as i couldn’t see.  i was weeping.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>the next days went in a blur of preparations, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>the funeral came.  i was nervous.  i was unprepared emotionally.  i felt as if i had no more tears to cry, that i was dehydrated to the point of solitude.  i was wrong.  beaner started the service with a wonderful speech, &amp;ldquo;what mamo taught me.&amp;rdquo;  aunt bee ended it with, &amp;ldquo;10 things my mom taught me.&amp;rdquo;  it was beautiful and fitting.  mamo would have approved.  i lasted through the ceremony in my seat only due to the support of my mom, doni and a box of tissues.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i drove UD’s truck to the burial.  the spot is nice.  mamo picked it out.  i think it is near bapa, but i thought it would be rude to go see him that day.  plus by the time they lowered her into the ground and covered her in that sweet georgia red clay–the smell of which i will forever associate with playing during the childhood summers spent at her house: gardening with bapa, mud slides with kelley and marla, and generally just being with HER–i was too spent to shed any more tears. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>i grieved harder than i ever have in my life.  i wept like i have never wept before.  i always knew it would be this way when she passed on.  she was everything to me.  my rock, my solitude, my beacon, my home.  the loss is especially poignant in that since mom and dad have split her home is my only real home.  the only home that remained stationary in my constantly revolving door of a life.  now that home is just a building.  her sister was over for part of the weekend and every time i looked at her sister from an off angle i saw HER and shuddered.  a few times i thought, mamo isn’t gone, she’s right there talking to mom.  and then it clicked that she was gone.  i will never again get to lay my head in her lap and listen to her read a devotional or a story with the best reading voice i’ve ever heard or will ever hear.  i will never again get to thank her for yet another majestic fresh peach cobbler with her biscuit crust.  i will never again get to see her look when i laid a sarcastic wry comment on her and then to get sucked up into her infectious laugh.  she knew me as well as anyone. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>she never cared how long i had been gone.  it could have been a year in a war or fifteen minutes to go to the store.  she always welcomed me with the same smile.  now i must let her go with a similar smile, and relish what she gave me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Craziness</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-07-18-craziness/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-07-18-craziness/</guid><description>&lt;p>well, life has been crazy.  we’ve been working like fiends.  i saw the sun rise on four straight mornings.  three because of work, one because of partying.  it has been a weird couple of nights, for a lot of reasons. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>but now i’ve gotten a break.  yesterday i wrote all afternoon at my coffeeshop, then did yoga for the first time in three alcohol and smoke laden days, then ate dinner with two lady-friends then came home to fall asleep to MTV banalities. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>today i spent much of the time up at the maroon bells, the nation’s most photographed mountain with a couple of friends and one child.  the kid was fucking crazy well behaved.  it restoked my uncle fire.  in case you didn’t know i’ll be an uncle in approximately 7.5 months.  SA-WEET.  then i came  home to type out and make some of the edits that have been pen changed for weeks now.  so finally we have another Wading chapter.  enjoy it if you wanna.  off to stretch my shit out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>backlog</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-30-backlog/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-30-backlog/</guid><description>&lt;p>so i have backlogged the stories from last week while i was in the woods.  they are backdated to the approximate days and times when i constructed and/or experienced their bases.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>this week has been busy, but good.  the woman i’m working for knows MANY MANY people who are very very well connected.  this weekend we are to meet McCain, i’m going to give him a copy of shooter.  next week even more people will be in town.  i’m told we’ll be heading up to a safehouse for some meetings of the intelligence committee.  it will be interesting.  one of her friends is quite high in the state department and lives in columbia doing development work.  &amp;ldquo;he is always looking for lawyers, especially.&amp;rdquo;  i work through the rum fog to remember her telling me the other night.  good.  cause i’m always looking for a job, especially.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>tomorrow night i’m going to hear a lesbian ac/dc cover band.  i’ll give you a review later, although i’m not sure how it could be anything but awesome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>back</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-26-back/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-26-back/</guid><description>&lt;p>i am back from the woods.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i have lots of stories i am going to write over the week.  it was exciting, hot, fulfilling, it made all my dreams come true.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>chapter one of wading is posted.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>cultural shorthand</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-24-cultural-shorthand/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-24-cultural-shorthand/</guid><description>&lt;p>so cam, ern, bri and i often use the word gaper.  well that is how i spell it.  it is the verbial noun of &amp;ldquo;to gape,&amp;rdquo; and we therefore pronounce it &amp;ldquo;GAY-per.&amp;rdquo;  not &amp;ldquo;ga-per.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>when we use it those that do not KNOW often ask for a definition or description.  up till now it had been hard for me to point to an iconic description pulled from pop culture that can help.  this difficulty is often compounded by the fact that if you are asking me what a gaper is it is likely that you are one, and i being the sensitive soul that i am do no want to unnecessarily hurt your feelings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>but now i have one.  i will now attempt to describe to you a gaper.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i had been up on steamboat for the first time.  i really liked the town.  it was like the rest of these mountains that by now i know quite well, except for much of the pompacity of them was conspicuosly absent in steamboat.  i don’t know why.  maybe because it is so far off the beaten path.  there were a few pretentious looking places but for the most part they were hidden behind gates.  all i could see were the millions of kids playing little league and families riding bikes along the river that flows through the town. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>there is the moutain that didn’t look that tough but a veteran told me there was plenty of off-piste stuff, great tree skiing and some in bounds stuff that was fun and pretty tough.  there was a river with at least three play waves that i could see as i walked along it.  that was at a flow that wasn’t great since it’s been a warm spring and runoff happened for the most part before i got there, and it is pretty dry.  there were a few crags that i could see around, some with people on them, some without.  it seemed like an ideal place to me.  all the things without all the attitude.  quite a few real cowboys, like in jackson.  cheaper than jackson or aspen or vail.  the tourists that i could see, this being the weekend before the fourth there were many, were all from casper or denver.  that gives them legitimacy.  if you’re going to be a city dweller you at least have some authenticity if you come from wyoming or from denver, at least you have the rebuttable presumption of authenticity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i decided to head up to this one falls.  i did not know until the road deadended into a forest service pay booth conveniently located around a corner and without a turn around.  i had vehicles in front of and behind me so my only choices were to turn around in the small parking lot on the other side of the booth and head back into town or pay the fee and actually see the falls that were apparently pretty kool, despite the unexpected fees.  i debated while the vehicle in front of me fucked around with some stuff and decided to pay the fee.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i parked and grabbed my nalgene and started walking.  there was really only one way to go, but there was a nice host there at the small map that i glanced at that was willing to give directions to lost souls.  i thought it was a nice way to earn a free place to camp your RV for the summer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i walked along this cement path for like 300 yards to the overlook of the falls dressed in khaki shorts, a t-shirt, flip flops, sunglasses and a nalgene looped to my finger.  my other hand in my pocket.  i mean it was 300 yards along a cement &amp;ldquo;path.&amp;rdquo;  it wasn’t taxing.  i sat on a nice bench that i figured my $5 was going to help maintain for a while pondering life and waterflows and mosquitoes and whether or not i really had contracted west nile disease. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>after a bit i decided to get up and head down to the base of the falls.  the overlook path had one side path that was not cement, but was asphalt, and therefore much more tricky for people i guess, that took you to the bottom of the canyon where you picked up a &amp;ldquo;gasp&amp;rdquo; dirt trail that ran for 200 yards or something along the river floor to near the base of the falls. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>the entire area was about half a square mile and enclosed in a larger canyon.  there were lots of trees around but from the lookout area i was easily able to piece together the three trails that the small area contained.  i flipped back towards the asphalt path and i came upon my icon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>he was dressed in hiking boots, brand new REI shorts, a patagonia capilene layer and a nicearc teryx daypack that was jammed with god knows what.  he was conferring with his wife/friend/sister who was similarly attired.  they were conferring over a MAP.  a fucking MAP.  i paraphrase but i overheard something like this.  &amp;ldquo;hmm, where do you think we should go, honey?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;well, we’ve been to the overlook, maybe we should head to the bottom of the falls, how do we get there?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;i don’t know, let me pull out my GPS to see where we are and then let’s plot our course to the bottom using this handy map the nice lady at the parking lot gave us.&amp;rdquo;  i do not understand how these three trails could have made for ANY discussion much less this discussion that lasted from the time they were in sound until the time i couldn’t hear them any more as i flipped along the asphault trail.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i flipped down the winding switchbacks to the dirt trail at the bottom.  the river path was jammed with hippies and japanese people.  but there was one couple there who had an adolescent nephy.  suddenly i forgot everything and just missed bailey.  i was sad as i walked back to the car not because people are idiots but because i missed my dog.  there wasn’t a strong resemblance since that dog was actually in the water and wasn’t having the shakes due to his fear of the water like bailey would have, but nonetheless bailey was a good boy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>lakes</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-23-lakes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-23-lakes/</guid><description>&lt;p>i like to skinny dip in deserted, cold lakes. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>i do not like the water to be so cold that it induces hyperventilating when my nutsack hits it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i do not like to be greeted by a veil of mosquitoes when i exit it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>but i do like to skinny dip when i’m skuzzy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>the gentle flower</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-21-the-gentle-flower/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-21-the-gentle-flower/</guid><description>&lt;p>having sufficiently fucked with my rhythms enough to convince myself that it was OK to wake early, i awoke at dawn and decided to stroll.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i was walking around this gigantic lake that was engorged by new deal politics more than the bellies of those beat fuckers who had to dam the damn thing. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>there was a small trail that i was not sure if it was a human trail or a deer trail, and i felt guilty for if it was the latter maybe i was changing many years of animal patterns because they wouldn’t come this way if they could smell early morning human who has not showered for a few days and doesn’t usually smell that good to begin with. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>there was the usual flora around that i had seen numerous times on numerous hikes.  but then i saw a flower that i had not seen before. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>it was something straight out of my doodles.  all straight lines and angles that only an engineer’s mind would appreciate.  there was a back-flower of moderately intense blue and a fore-flower of yellow.  it was like two starfish of two colors and of two sizes were stacked on top of one another with the smaller on top and twisted just a bit.  it was beautiful.  for some reason, and i must have seen these flowers before, it was really engaging.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i wanted to get a closer look at it, but i was leaving no trace and was locked into the pathway.  the pathway got close to the flower so i followed it until it got there.  i looked back at the flower after averting my eyes to get closer.  when i knew i was the closest i would be to the flower i squatted down because i’m indian like that.  but when i finally was closest to the flower i was shading the damn thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i became frozen by indecision.  if i never moved the damn thing would wither from lack of sunshine.  if i moved away i would not get to see my flower change and grow.  i did not know what to do so i just moved on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>it was not purposeful.  i did not mean to shade the damn thing.  i just wanted to see it.  it wasn’t my fault that the sun was at an angle such that my closeness shaded it.  but yet that is what happened….aren’t metaphors sometimes perfect?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>places</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-16-places/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-16-places/</guid><description>&lt;p>i think that how i leaves places reminds me of how i break up with women . . . tentatively, with an eye towards salvaging something from the experience in an effort to reinforce that my decision was the right one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i am not prone to regrets, but i am prone to self-reflection in an effort to refine why and how i make decisions so i make them better in the future.  those two things may seem irreconcilable to many but they seem fundamentally different to me.  maybe they are just different ways to express the same thing.  yet i’m not a backwards looker, usually.  in an effort to retain my youth i try to retain my sense of discovery, wanderlust and dreaminess. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>those broad generalizations aside i’m leaving austin soon, on sunday in fact.  this will be my final weekend here and i’m not sure if it will be jammed with activities or jammed with a lack of activites.  it seems that many of taylor’s friends are out of the tiz-own so it may just be him and i man-dating throughout the weekend.  that is fine with me as we truly get along well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>then it is off to see bri for a two or so days and then i’ll spend the remainder of the week off the power grid in the mountains hiking and writing and relaxing. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>writing.  i’ve done a SHITLOad of it at work and haven’t really wanted to do it when i’ve come home in the evenings.  needless to say i haven’t gotten past sketches of characters and a rough chapter by chapter run through of the turrow book.  i am past much of my existential crisis for now and feel comfortable in the decision that i’ve made to pursue my dreams of development and not of money and posh firm lifestyles doing shit that i couldn’t care less about.  that has freed up my mind for reflection on the book.  i really like how it is starting to sift out.  we’ll have to see how it comes out on the paper.  i plan on writing (as in with pen and notebook) for much of my time in the woods next week.  i have to return to my discipline of writing and not let my adhd get the better of my mind.  &amp;ldquo;oo look at the snowfields i could stare at them….pretty elk…pretty pretty el…those fucking flies better fucking leave me alone….fuckers….o yeah where was i?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>no thanks, i&amp;#8217;ll pass</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-12-no-thanks-ill-pass/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-12-no-thanks-ill-pass/</guid><description>&lt;p>this weekend i almost became a marine….again. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>a friend that i have known forever came down from ft worth to visit for the night.  we were talking about him going back to the sandbox for seven months.  he is going with a civil affairs group that will be doing civil/military liasoning, straight civil affairs (government establishment, police coordination, building schools, making sure there is power and water, helping USAID distribute the moneys for aid, ensuring people get paid, etc.). &lt;/p>
&lt;p>this seemed fortuitous to me.  ever since i’ve made my decision to hone in my career choice and stop browsing the shelves at the Walmart SuperCenter, instead going to the little boutique in the strip mall, the focus is now where it was when i came to law school.  however the decision is pretty tentative.  it is scary in that it will be hard to get into this world from my little nashville school.  it will be hard to network my way into a job anyway.  it is also scary in that i am not gauranteed anything as far as cash is concerned. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>but then this news that the_comedian was tossing my way about his job and how short-staffed they were seemed like the fortiuty.  if i took that job: (1)  i would make BANK–something like $55k tax free.  that means my debts would be paid off, my car would also be paid off and i could relax on the finances since vandy will assist with my student loans if i make under a certain threshhold (which is likely). (2) i would learn ARABIC.  this is key as a resume point, as lack of language skills is currently the biggest hold in the thing that would keep me from doing what i wanted to do.  (3) i would be able to NETWORK.  going to iraq again would let me meet lots of people who are in USAID who may be able to help my long-term career prospects, but also it would be like a neon sign on my resume that i’m not scared (the first time i went aside) of hostile places, that i can function in amorphous situations and it would lend credibility when i say this is what i want to do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>those three positives seemed infallible to me for much of the weekend, which, admittedly, was spent in a drunken haze.  after the_comedian left i started to really think.  i smoked about 8900 cigarettes this weekend just to clear the air of my mind and try to focus on the negatives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>then i called activist and miami to run this by them.  to put it mildly they were not anxious to encourage me.  there is the obvious security risk.  but that is negligible to me.  miami told me that there would be no way she could forgive herself if i was to not make it and if she did anything to encourage me to return.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>after talking to them and balancing out the momentum from having the_comedian pitch it to me i really thought long and hard about it.  there are two things that are going to stop me from taking the job.  two arguments that sold the passing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(1) although arabic would look great on my resume in that it is a high need language by most everyone, if i put that on my resume and an organization hires me based upon that then i may be pigeonholed into that region as my specialty region.  now i know that this is how these things work, and i know that i’m going to have to narrow my focus down to one region soon in order to really focus my career goals.  i’m not ready to say that the arabic region is where i want to focus.  i’m not ready to say that it is not either.  the unfortunate thing is that the country within the region that is most fascinating is also the most closed off: iran.  and speaking arabic isn’t going to go very far in a farsi speaking country anyway.  the persian intellectual tradition is fascinating, but i’m not really anxious to get into the arabic cultural tradition.  that isn’t a completely true statement.  what i mean is that i’m not ready to focus on that area at the cost of all others in the developing world.  so there is the pigeonholing argument.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(2) is the dangerous aspect of the job.  now i’m not being a pansy here.  maybe i am, but i don’t think that i am.  this is the thing if i was going to go back with an infantry unit to do infantry stuff i would be surrounded by warriors.  doing this job i’ll be stationed in a small to medium sized town (i’m thinking this is the scenario) working with the locals.  probably staying in the police station or commuting from a nearby base.  but i would only be surrounded by my small team of marines and we would be out there in al anbar province doing it.  the thing that makes this more dangerous than just normal infantry patroling is that you are the symbol to that town of the american occupation.  so if there is anyone disillusioned with the american presence in the country for the many reasons that i can think of to be upset with it, you are their target.  no matter how much good you do if something bad happens you are going to get blamed, you will become the target.  this really crescendoes the danger above the normal level for these teams.  although the security concern was a concern to come later it is also extremely salient.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>and then was the final kicker above the two things that had siezed the momentum:  i just can’t put my family and friends through that again.  it isn’t fair.  it is too selfish.  just like the story i wrote: you don’t really have time or the capacity to get scared, but they are freaked out everytime the phone rings or a knock on the door comes for the entire time i’m gone.  if i don’t HAVE to go then i really can’t do that to them again.  i think the stress really would send mamo to her grave. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>so in the end i passed on the deal, no matter how good of a career move it would have been long term.  the skills and networking and money that i would have gotten by taking the job were simply not enough to overcome the pigeonholing, the focusing of the danger and the stress upon my family and friends. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>when it rains it pours</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-09-when-it-rains-it-pours/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-09-when-it-rains-it-pours/</guid><description>&lt;p>for much of my childhood i didn’t understand what that phrase was on the&lt;br>
side of the big, round, blue salt container.  everytime bri and/or i would&lt;br>
cook i would just look at it and think, &amp;ldquo;shit isn’t that&lt;br>
self-evident,&amp;rdquo; or the equivalent of that thought would enter my young mind&lt;br>
for a pinball session of bouncing around.  eventually i asked my mother&lt;br>
who told me that this company had placed an additive in the salt that makes it&lt;br>
pour out in response to older salts that would absorb the humidity in the air&lt;br>
and clump up in humid environs.  then it made sense.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>so lots have changed, but, i think, for the good.  i may be an ass&lt;br>
hole, but at least i’m being honest to myself.  that may not be a very&lt;br>
good balm for those around me, but it is all i’ve got.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>UPDATE: more things have changed since the last post, which i took down and replaced with this, such as an addition to our community.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>clarity through resolution</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-06-clarity-through-resolution/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-06-clarity-through-resolution/</guid><description>&lt;p>so my grades came back today.  they were marginally better than last semester, but again the increase was marginal.  this is disappointing for two reasons. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>first, i worked really fucking hard last semester at developing and refining my written communications, apparently i didn’t work smarter since my legal writing grade dropped.  but i really thought that i was getting the hang of it, apparently everyone else was too.  i also worked really hard on the substantive law (the rules as applied to the class, basically the classwork) this semester, and especially towards finals.  i knew that stuff backwards and forwards, as well as anyone in my study group.  going into the conlaw final one of my groupmates told Yale that I had a strong chance of booking it.  i got a B.  so i know that i knew the substance of the class and i know that i worked really hard on the precision of my wording and the succinctity of my arguments.  alas, it only sort of paid off.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>second, all my desires are to do things that really do require better grades than i’m getting.  wanna work in a city that does NOT hire vanderbilt grads?  yes!  Portland.  better be near the top.  shit.  wanna work in a big NY, posh law firm?  sort of.  better be near the top.  shit.  wanna be a legal academic?  yes.  better be near the top.  shit. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>so i was burnt about it.  i rationalized all of the why’s, mainly focusing on my lack of undergraduate preparation.  i mean shit, i’m not trying to discount Yale for getting a near 4.0, but i knew that stuff just as well as she did and here i’m sitting with a 3.2 and she’s looking at something much higher.  yes, grades aren’t that important casey, don’t let them define you.  i’m not letting them define me but employers will. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>but then i really got to thinking (it is now almost 3 and i’m not looking at sleeping much tonight).  when i have existential crises like these there are two questions that i ask myself:  (1) if i won the lottery what would i be doing, (2) why did i originally decide to do what i’m now doing.  those have served me well for a long time in starting the internal conversation about where i am, where i’ve been, where i could go and why i should choose case number 17. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>if i won the lottery i would finish law school and then i would form a boutique law firm with really smart, sophisticated, well-travelled people to work with developing nations to establish growth plans that pulled them out of poverty while retaining sustainability of their people, economic resources and natural resources. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>originally i decided to come to law school because of a feeling of powerlessness to accomplish what i wanted to accomplish.  it all came together for me during two events:  (1) on the phone with my mother when she was telling me that for the third hurricane in a month she was going to be stuck working at the hospital for an undisclosed amount of time, (2) watching live 8 on tv in my basalt apartment.  i was thinking that pulling developing countries out of poverty is all well and good, but you know, teach a man to fish.  if we forgive their debt and link it to benchmarks which the country achieves or fails to achieve would kick in or fail to kick in more incentives, then we can actually affect true change in the world.  if we just forgive their debt it would be like handing ten million dollars to the last three guests on jerry springer. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>there are a lot of other links in there.  i’m not going to actually connect the dots for you.  but the gist is that i entered law school because saint martin’s didn’t buy living with death and also that i was ready to go to work and i was ready to change some shit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>so if the money is taken out of the equation, then really everything would still line up and i would still be in the right place to achieve what i’m looking to achieve and i also have made the correct decision to be here. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>yet, it is really hard to remember this when you have firms firms firms firms shoved down your throat constantly.  firm life may be fine for some: those that like to engage in settling.  but when was the last time any one of you remembered me settling.  sure it happens, but i fucking hate it when i’m forced into it.  the simple fact is that i do not have to settle for some firm in portland or even making a hundred and fifty thousand dollars in NY.  i mean, shit, do i even want to really litigate any of these environmental claims.  they are all piddly, and if i’m in the firm it will be a massive compromise of my value system to have to convince juries that my clients’ aren’t really THAT bad.  fuck that.  i mean don’t hold me to this statement, but FUCK THAT. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>if i don’t have to do it than why am i even thinking it.  i know why:  b/c the system is designed that way.  college, don’t know what you want to do but can write, why not law school, law school, don’t know what you want to do but performed fine on their exams, why not a firm in X city, X city, marriage, kids, house, mortgage, car payments.  fuck that. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>plus i’m really over the US in general.  i mean if i’m only interested in living in two cities in this fucking country but can list at least 40 that i would love to live in outside of this country why am i even thinking about staying other than stagnation.  stagnation isn’t a good enough reason for me, although i have no reason to decry it nor to laud it for others.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>further, doing this would utilize what i’m good at:  advocacy, problem&lt;br>
solving, talking and communicating (instead of telling someone this is&lt;br>
how it has to be because the law says it is so), amorphous situations,&lt;br>
creating simplicity out of complexity.  much law school has been about&lt;br>
creating complexity out of simplicity.  this is another of my&lt;br>
justifications, but i don’t really create complexity out of simplicity&lt;br>
easily, i usually just think what is the point?  when you reverse it&lt;br>
and create simplicity out of complexity and simplify things and package&lt;br>
it for a specific audience, this is a skill i have in droves and few&lt;br>
other lawyers possess it.  needless, i just need to be in an&lt;br>
international forum.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>so all off the above reasoning has led me to this:  go abroad, refocus your efforts.  i have done some research tonight and in the past which has only served to show that it is a bright big world out there and i need to participate in it.  university of syndey has a one year LLM (masters of law, semi-PhD equivalent) and Masters of Environmental Science program that you can take in Germany.  England has numerous LLM’s in environmental law.  i could even take classes in Johannesburg i found out.  and afterwards?  well, we’ll figure it out.  perhaps i can find a group of persons who are interested in the same thing at one of these programs and we can figure it all out together.  perhaps there are boutiques out there that i just have to find that could hire me.  who knows. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>but the bottom line is that i cannot think that this semester’s grades are the end of the story.  as i told myself earlier, don’t put the final nail in my life’s coffin (nice metaphor, huh?) yet.  if i’m going to get out from entirely mediocre grades it will be by doing something dramatic, something big, something beyond the scale that these fuckers in their dockers and their dartmouth diplomas have never dreamed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>dream big.  i’ve always done it, i’ve always achieved it.  why stop now?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>back</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-02-back-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-02-back-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>lacking excuses, i’m forced to return.  deal with it, cause i’m back.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>so austin.  it is pretty sweet.  it would be nearly impossible to get a job here when my only link to the city is, &amp;ldquo;i like it,&amp;rdquo; since this town has the highest per capita lawyer rates of anywhere in america (or so i’ve been told).  plus it is too flipping hot for me anyway.  nevertheless i’m very glad that i have come down here for a few weeks.  i feel like i got a good taste of the city during my three weeks here so far, despite being quite busy. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>it really is the fun, loose, hippy, chill town that you’ve heard about containing people who are passionate about issues, nice hills and rivers, great food, &amp;amp; unbelievable music venues.  i’ve done all of the above, including going to the Austin Air Guitar Championships, which neared the funniest things i’ve ever seen.  that competition was absolutely amazing.  there was this kid who did not look like steven tyler, did not act like steven tyler, did not dress like steven tyler.  the kid fucking WAS steven tyler.  it was so amazing, and he had been talked into competing by his friends after he was already in the door.  crazy.  these guys were hamming it up and i could barely drink a beer without snorting.  it defies definition, trust me, i tried to write a story about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>that’s all for now.  yoga calls.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>riding v. skiing</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-01-03-riding-v-skiing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-01-03-riding-v-skiing/</guid><description>&lt;p>ok.  so most of you know that i’m a rider.  i think that this is kind of odd, yet typical of my history.  i feel like i’m always half an oscillation off from popular culture.  this is what i mean, and really you can apply it to most areas of my hipster life be that fashion, word choices, music, hairstyles or the like.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>see i started riding, really riding my snowboard when i got out of the marine corps, when i was 27.  that is old for a rider.  yes, people my age were pretty much the vangaurd of snowboarders, at least on the popular (as opposed to psycho subculture of a few weirdos) level.  yes, i did snowboard when i was in high school and college, albeit awefully (ask joe).  but i really got into the sport when i was already too old to fit in.  when i was in mammoth i was surrounded by riders, there everyone rode.  there everyone was 18 and smoked pot instead of coffee and instead of a nightcap.  so i was the old man.  but it was kool, no one really looked at me too sideways, except for the fact that i was wearing &amp;ldquo;mountaineering&amp;rdquo; clothes probably more suited to a skier than a rider.  but that didn’t seem to phase people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>the next winter i came here (where i am now).  i came to aspen.  it was a good transition, it was what i needed.  as i’ve written at length and told most people i know, this is my heaven, my paradise.  but here people my age do not ride.  they ski.  in fact the only people that ride here are the 15 to 20 crowd.  even the snowboard instructors are all younger than me, and the ones that are my age all tell me that on their days off they prefer to ski.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>but me, obstinate as always, continued last season to ride.  i don’t really regret it.  i did improve to the point where nothing really scares me and i can pretty much get through anything on an area mountain.  backcountry stuff maybe maybe not.  but for the most part i can hold my own. today, however, i was thinking about all of this.  why don’t i ski?  there really is no reason that i can think of.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>it is so much more elegant.  and not that i’m elegant in the slightest, i am the founding member of the alley cat climbing club, but i just seems more me to me.  you don’t have to fuck with strapping yourself in.  you don’t have to bother when you get to bump sections to change your style.  you can get away with wearing what i wear without being an oddity.  nonetheless i have kept riding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>sometimes i wonder if my window has passed.  now i’m a vacationer, i am one of those who i looked down upon while i lived in paradise.  i do not have an entire 100 days of skiing to perfect a new sport, so i am forced to make choices, to compromise.  so tomorrow i ski for the second day.  we’ll see how it goes.  i do like to ride, but i think that i’m bored with it a bit and looking for something new.  riding is fun on powder days, but other than that i think i have it. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>onward as always.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>return to paradise</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-12-31-return-to-paradise/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-12-31-return-to-paradise/</guid><description>&lt;p>this is harder than i really thought that it could be.  my mind is racing with what if’s.  i know that i shouldn’t.  i know what it does to me.  trust me.  i know.  but it is an unstoppable, irrestistable, uncompressible force that is pushing my mind around. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>what if i hadn’t left?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>that is the crux of the matter.  i’m back in aspen.  it is winter (obviously) the snow is immaculate, forgiving, soft, just grabby enough, not skiied out.  the people here are the same.  it is weird how many i feel like i know.  when i arrived i walked down the mall at snowmass, weighted by my board for the first time in months.  as i walked i was self-conscious.  i felt like a sell-out.  but nevertheless there i was, walking down the mall with my snowboard.  as i walked i relaxed and started looking at the faces in the crowd.  there were many that i recognized.  a surprising amount.  i started saying hi to a few people.  then more and more that i knew and before i knew it i was satisfied and happy.  dropped my board off and settled in for a long winter’s ride.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>the coffee shop is closing and so am i.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>memory</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-12-25-memory/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-12-25-memory/</guid><description>&lt;p>it has been so long even my computer didn’t &amp;ldquo;Remember Me.&amp;rdquo; and I had to relog in to typepad.  How aweful of me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>am in Tennessee for the holidays.  It is what it always seems to be, text off family love, subtext of family angst.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See this will be the last Xmas in this house.  My aunt has returned for the first time in a while.  I have returned for the first time in a while.  In fact this is the most complete Christmas my grandmother has had in at least three years if not longer. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>But how does that make me feel?  Hell, that is why all of you pay the subscription fees for this site isn’t it….to hear my ramblings on feelings.  Not sure.  I tend to deal with angst as if it doesn’t exist, to just table something.  I don’t deal with it before I have to, and I barely deal with it when I am forced to.  Ignorance is bliss or something completely as idiotically moronic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am on drugs right now b/c I am sick….of life.  I’m the cough-master and the sneeze-machine and my chest-heaves and my head-aches, but I’ll get through.  Hell I have to since I’m leaving Tuesday for Aspen to ski.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It will be odd returning there, I think.  But we’ll have to see about that then.  More soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>mobility</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-09-20-mobility/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-09-20-mobility/</guid><description>&lt;p>the following is a new treatise that represents some of my current thought patterns.  those that know me [everyone that reads this blog] knows of my mobile ways in geography but in many aspects of my life. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>my brother has been applying to grad schools and he and i have been bantering regarding his personal statement.  he recently told me that he has lost his mojo and he doesn’t seem to have any motivation to really put his heart into the document.  i replied:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>shouldn’t fear of becoming what your stereotypes&lt;br>
dictate you should become enough?  has always been for me.  do you&lt;br>
want THIS to continue?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>to which he replied: &lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t really get your drift…&lt;br>
Do I want WHAT to continue?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>to which i replied:  EXACTLY&lt;/p>
&lt;p>but then i wrote the following.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>was thinking the last few days about what my gist really was in that&lt;br>
last email.  i guess that the gist of it was fairly simply readable, but&lt;br>
there are a lot of consequences that have opened up in my mind regarding&lt;br>
such a premise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>my argument that change is predicated upon some dissatisfaction with the&lt;br>
currency of something is relatively banal and easy to understand. &lt;br>
personal lives, like nature, tend to embrace some semblance of an&lt;br>
inertial existence.  when there is change there is massive change when&lt;br>
there is stagnation there is massive stagnation.  you do not have to&lt;br>
look further than [insert reality tv show here] to figure that one out. &lt;br>
but life, like nature require some sort of energy to take you between&lt;br>
inertial energy states  [action to rest or vice the versa].  thus we&lt;br>
enter the proof of my original theorem whereas dissatisfaction is the&lt;br>
catalyst for change.  not always would it be the only catalyst [just as&lt;br>
there is potential energy and kinetic energy] but generally i would&lt;br>
argue it is the most prevalent catalyst.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>well that is all fine and good and was the beginning and end of my posit&lt;br>
to you.  if you want to change [read: improve] then you have to focus&lt;br>
your dissatisfaction on the current state of your life which you want to&lt;br>
change [improve].  i find that if i do not focus this negative&lt;br>
motivation upon something tangible [or at least graspable] then i will&lt;br>
coherently know that i have to change something [presently i know that i&lt;br>
have to quit smoking] but i won’t do anything about it [as i'm not&lt;br>
focusing upon the fact that i'll die a horribly painful death as&lt;br>
carcinogens violently devour my insides].&lt;/p>
&lt;p>but the real crux of this emails length comes when i take the next&lt;br>
step.  what happens when i say OK, change is created my dissatisfaction&lt;br>
[or pick your own synonym], i can buy that.  so why am i always&lt;br>
changing?  changing jobs, desires, locales, images, personalities,&lt;br>
auras, partners, i’m always changing something.  is it that i’m&lt;br>
dissatisfied with stagnation so my hatred of the stagnant creates a need&lt;br>
for perpetual motion [continuing the metaphor] and thus i feel that i&lt;br>
always  have to change something.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>or is it deeper?  do i have an insatiable appetite to devour everything&lt;br>
i can?  am i not a locus descending upon the egyptians but THE locus&lt;br>
descending upon the egyptians?  once i finish with one project i have to&lt;br>
move on to the next.  whether that is establishing that i really am&lt;br>
smart as i think i am [cum laude from the #1 civil engineering program&lt;br>
in the world with full knowledge i could have done even better] and then&lt;br>
moving on to the next project of establishing my manliness [off to war&lt;br>
leading 228 Marines and responsible for their lives and safety;&lt;br>
unabashedly running into the teeth of enemy fire b/c that is what men&lt;br>
do] and then moving on to the project of establishing my koolness&lt;br>
[ski-bumming].  on and on in this and other facets of my life besides&lt;br>
the professional.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>fine i do that but why?  is it that i find something i want, i achieve&lt;br>
it and find that it isn’t really what i want?  or are these merely steps&lt;br>
along a process to becoming something larger than is definable with a&lt;br>
few words or mere labels?  this is my personal, present, hypothesis.  i&lt;br>
think that i dislike labels so much that i’m willing to change and put&lt;br>
my body and mind through the stress of constant change merely so i&lt;br>
cannot be labeled as this or that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>is that legitimate?  is that stupid?  i don’t know but i think that that&lt;br>
is nevertheless me.  i think that i view life as an iterative process as&lt;br>
opposed to a destination with the white picket fence blah blah.  but&lt;br>
there is a grave danger i think with the way that i’ve come to look at&lt;br>
the world.  i guess the danger as i see it is ending up alone b/c i’m&lt;br>
either too picky or too mobile or too ADHD to stay with someone for very&lt;br>
long.  the danger is further with my lack of wanting to lay down any&lt;br>
roots [the fact that the bar is a massive exam and if i ever move to a&lt;br>
new state i have to retake it and thus i am impetized to stay in one&lt;br>
state scares the living shit out of me] will not let me have any real&lt;br>
true connections outside of my friends who are spread across the country&lt;br>
and who love me and will email and talk on the phone with me and all&lt;br>
that but i only get to experience very little of life with.  we can go&lt;br>
further down this road of my fears but the point is this, will these&lt;br>
fears/dissatisfactions be enough to make me change my changing ways?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>footBall&amp;#8217;s back</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-09-12-footballs-back/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-09-12-footballs-back/</guid><description>&lt;p>today i gave myself a sabatical.  all football, all day.  it was fantastic.  just finished up watching PRIMETIME.  visions of big dog nachos dancing in my head.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>apparently we have a mouse in the house (literally).  this will be interesting as i’ve never set mousetraps and had them smash a little fucking rodent and then (worse of all) have to take that diseased fucker down to the trash.  ray lewis just hugged some army dudes.  i can’t tell if that is a class act or not.  my default is yes, my second thought is it is a stunt.  whatever.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>that is about all i have to say.  just working at school stuff.  hanging out with yale-y.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>last night eric, anthony, yale-y and some other people and i went to see frank black.  he did a solo set on cannery row.  he played for about 45 minutes or so.  it was fantastic, small, intimate, all that shit.  i only knew a few of the songs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>lee greenwood is giving hte national anthem….huh?  that emotional sellout from the first gulf war…?  wacky.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>inevitability?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-08-19-inevitability/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-08-19-inevitability/</guid><description>&lt;p>so tonight it happened.  i had been dreading it happening, in fact it was one of the main reasons i had for not wanting to move to nashville.  but nonetheless it happened.  on the way to a bar to meet some new &amp;ldquo;friends&amp;rdquo; i ran into katie’s parents.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>it fucked my whole dope up and only ended up staying at the bar for a little while b/c i couldn’t concentrate on anything people were saying and couldn’t respond in anything approaching wit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>tomorrow i’ll be better, but for tonight…..shit&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>incoherenCy</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-08-14-incoherency/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-08-14-incoherency/</guid><description>&lt;p>well.  i’m on 36 straight hours.  i think.  i have lost all cognitive and reasoning powers.  my back is about to explode.  i need to dumpster dive like 40 cubic feet of trash into random dumpsters that do not belong to me with the hopes that their cameras don’t see me. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>it is hot.  i’m a sweaty behemoth when i’m not in starbucks finding out that a party to go to is too far to walk and i’m gonna register about a .23 on smoky’s breathalizers he got mail order (his first purchase from eBay).  and i haven’t had a single drink.  am just drunk tired.  but the place looks good.  it is coming along.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>lots of errands tomorrow.  then  plan on spending monday/tuesday just on my computer finishing everything up.  comcast will grace me with their presence on monday, so cam can stop being mad at me for patronizing his nemisous. (i know that isn’t how you spell that word, but i also know i’m an idiot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Signatories and Their Significance</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-08-09-signatories-and-their-significance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-08-09-signatories-and-their-significance/</guid><description>&lt;p>finished kundera tonight, but it will stay on the list as i’m going to reread it through.  it was fucking intense.  it was my favorite book that i’ve read in the past three years, easily.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>signed the lease in nashville today.  locked on the moving van for wednesday through friday.  dad has his plane tix to help in the move.  am depressed as shit and sick of hoping for it to end. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>guess if i just embrace it and then cope with the feelings that that will be better than trying to forestall the inevitable. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>for some reason this place seems to me to be like the apartment dave, natasha and i rented behind the library in champaign.  cannot figure out why, other than it is old.  maybe the presence of ghosts was what did it.  not exactly sure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>last night i had this vivid dream that oscillated between myself being turned into a demon and holding a pillow in the fetal position begging &amp;ldquo;god&amp;rdquo; to have mercy on me,  that i’d do what he wanted.  that i would submit.  it kept oscillating back and forth along two parallel lines moving independently.  in the end i woke with a racing heartbeat and no resolution to it.  later in the evening i dreamnt i was going to marry this really hideous woman who had a fish that looked like a bass.  i kept repeating, &amp;ldquo;but i like her soul, but i like her soul.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>guess i just have to realize that i’m all fucked up right now.  i need a fucking cigarette, but am in the house of protestantism.  fuck.  maybe i’ll just go for a walk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Decisions</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-08-08-decisions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-08-08-decisions/</guid><description>&lt;p>everyone around me suddenly appears to be suspect.  like they have morphed from being just humans, to having some sort of alien aura about them.  like i put on a magic pair of sun glasses and can see that they are all out to get me.  but i’m not paranoid about it, merely concerned.  and so i just don’t talk to them.  i just stifle it all and let it settle into a ball of goo in the lower regions of my stomach.  let it cause ulcers or maybe hemmeroids.  and then what?  what the fuck happens after?  not sure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>this weekend i’ve been subjected to a fullcourt press of strange looks and non-caring sighs from my family.  as if my normal self-deprecating and and self-analyzing nature wasn’t enough.  now i’m subjected to this as well.  as if i wasn’t stressed out enough, now i get to add this.  can no one merely empathize with my position and trust me to make the right decision?  i guess not.  excerpts from a conversation with a hero:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>so why aren’t you going to vanderbilt?  why don’t you want to go to law school?&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>it isn’t that i don’t want to go to law school.  i just want to do other things.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>you know what kind of a pedigree you would give up by not going?  you know how well respected that is?&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>the &amp;ldquo;oooo&amp;rdquo; factor diminishes exponentially with your radius from dixie.  it isn’t exactly harvard, nor is it florida state university. &lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>you know what kind of doors it would open for you?&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>yes.  but at what cost in time and debt do i go into this thing &amp;ldquo;merely for options.&amp;rdquo;  i mean $150K in debt is a pretty fucking big gamble that i’m going to have some major employment opportunities waiting for me on the back side.  if i wanted to just keep writing i’d have to have some massive offers waiting on the table to afford a decent lifestyle plus that kind of a &amp;ldquo;mortgage.&amp;rdquo;  if i don’t go and i keep writing, i only have the minimum of debt and will probably be able to live fine on that.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>you know what kind of ass you would pull at a college campus?&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>yes.  lots.  but is that why i’m going?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>so here i am stressed out of my own mind and then all this stuff is added on top of it.  all my friends and family are asking me constantly what the hell i’m going to be doing in a week.  will it be law school will it be writing.  i know that they all intend well, i know that they were just concerned, but it is overfuckingwhelming on my end of the spectrum.  at least ten emails a day and at least four voicemails a day for the last week all asking the same question.  it would be fuck loads easier if i had an answer to give them.  either way, even if it was the answer that i don’t want to be giving them, right now i’d pick that shit over this ambiguous purgatory where i have to plan for all possibilities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>so here i am in this house of death, watching both of my grandparents deteriorate before my very eyes.  my aunt is departing in tears, thoroughly convinced that one or both will die before she would have a chance to return.  my mother has put the world on her shoulders as usual is playing the martyr to a T.  and here i am.  detached and calloused to death because of my experiences.  when i’ve seen it so vividly, even those close to me become just another person on the battlefield.  how the HELL is that possible.  this is my mamo.  my grandmother.  why do i feel zero emotional attachtment to what is going on.  i realize that it is a coping mechanism, that i’m so terrified of facing my own mortality on any scale (probably because i don’t feel that my morality house is exactly in order) that i don’t deal with death.  that i just isolate it and do not force myself to face it. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>but that is going to change real fast i have a notion.  we’ll just have to see how it all plays out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>this is the most depressed i’ve been in a long, long time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>All Moved In.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-08-06-all-moved-in/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-08-06-all-moved-in/</guid><description>&lt;p>OK kids.  The pizza is half-eaten, cold, and greasing up the coffeetable for me.  There are beer bottles in a pile somewhere near THAT corner of the room, in the vicinity of the empty boxes that are broken down into flat cardboard for storage in the garage somewhere. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>In other words.  I’m all moved in.  It took me much of the day to move all that stuff over from xanga but we’re here now.  While I was scouring the bathroom I was thinking that there had to be an automated script that could move my shit for me and my doesn’t comet smell good.  But there wasn’t, and in fact it is a pain to wash off the sinks. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well it feels good to be here kids.  Lost the comments on my ole’ blog entries and my xanga subscriber (all one of her, poor, lonely shlub schlecking along some tundra screaming, &amp;ldquo;wi-fi, wi-fi, i need some wifi&amp;rdquo;) will feel abandoned now that she will have to bookmark my site.  But this is the wave of the future daddy-o, you just gotta ride it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>