<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>music on underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/music/</link><description>Recent content in music on underWater desert Blogging</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Casey Kuhlman</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My America Band: Wax Fang</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2012-04-01-my-america-band/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2012-04-01-my-america-band/</guid><description>When you sit with people from other countries, it is important to have some fall back, standardized way to explain where you are from. Of course we all have these icons, these posters, these fleeting images that remind ourselves of where we came from and are readily recalled by our frontal cortex when asked to explain ourselves. When we trust the person and we know that the question is meant because the other conversant(s) truly does want to understand us, then we are more easily able to open up and to tell the truth.</description></item><item><title>What Spotify Means for our Consumptive Tendencies</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2011-09-08-what-spotify-means-for-our-consumptive-tendencies/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2011-09-08-what-spotify-means-for-our-consumptive-tendencies/</guid><description>![Spotify on HTC Desire Android by babyben @ flickr]({{ site.url }}{{ site.root }}{{ site.images_dir }}/{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; }}/4756710633_475680f30e.jpg)
I walked to work this morning. While I was getting ready for work my phone was streaming an album which I found last night to be ultra-enjoyable. My headphones were with me; so, I plugged them into the phone and started walking. Got to work; sat down at my desk computer to type this; the album is still playing.</description></item><item><title>Why I Love America, Norah Jones Edition</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-11-07-norah-jones-love-america/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-11-07-norah-jones-love-america/</guid><description>![Norah Jones at Massey Hall via Smaku @flickr]({{ site.url }}{{ site.root }}{{ site.images_dir }}/{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; }}/502916681_0dbab3a7e3_z.jpg)
When you live abroad sometimes it is difficult to express the fact that you are, at heart, a patriot. Indeed, I think that patriotism now that we are moving into the post-states (for all intents and purposes) world has somehow turned into a dirty word. I’m not sure how that happened. Certainly, for us Americans, being the big, dumb, blumbering dude in a room filled with slicker, sleeker, shinier countries hasn’t helped our cause any.</description></item><item><title>New Music Friday</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-02-02-new-music-friday/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-02-02-new-music-friday/</guid><description>[![M_7826ca385b434f5a4dea435cd148cc18][2]][2]My good friend Eric’s baby brother, Ryan is finally on Myspace. [Check it out][2]. []: http://www.myspace.com/ryanfroommusic [2]: http://www.myspace.com/ryanfroommusic
My favorite track he has on here is Summer Breeze, which I think I’ve heard different lower-fi versions of. This one is quite enjoyable. ~ # ~</description></item><item><title>Yael Naim</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-01-31-yael-naim/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-01-31-yael-naim/</guid><description>So, if you like the new commercials for Air Jordan’s, I mean Mac Air then you likely have wondered who the hell is singing that song and why does it make me so happy. Well the answer is Yael Naim to the first question, the song is New Soul. Apparently she is French, cause the rest of her self-titled album is in French, and there is a song titled Paris. The answer to the second question, at least for me, is that it makes me want to go to happy things.</description></item><item><title>It&amp;#8217;s Time for Christmas Tunes</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-11-27-its-time-for-christmas-tunes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-11-27-its-time-for-christmas-tunes/</guid><description>[![Xmasto][2]][2]Have been listening to John Denver’s Christmas Album. Recorded in 1979, John Denver’s Album “A Christmas Together”
featuring the inchoate inventives of Jim Henson’s LCD flashbacks is officially
one of the trippiest albums ever recorded and produced in a recording studio. Check out track 11, it will blow your mind.
[]: http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/11/26/xmasto.jpg
Now to some Indictments, some Finals and some Outlining all with Indian Food in my belly. Ahh, the Playoffs are approaching.</description></item><item><title>in Halo&amp;#8217;s</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-10-13-in-halos/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-10-13-in-halos/</guid><description>[![Radiohead_in_rainbows2][2]][2]
in case you’re an ostrich in a human’s body, or my dad, [radiohead has put out a new album][2], called in Rainbows. it is only downloadable on the internet at this point. it will come out in CD stores at some point in December, which basically requires you to ask WTF is the point of that. nevermind. the interesting thing about this is how they are doing it. they have decided that there is no price point.</description></item><item><title>Gogol Bordello</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-08-28-gogol-bordello/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-08-28-gogol-bordello/</guid><description>So I heard an NPR podcast that I subscribe to the other day that blew my mind. NPR podcasts these concerts from the famous 9:30 club in DC that I’ve been to with fisher-man a time of two. The band, Gogol Bordello describes itself as a Gypsy Rock &amp;amp; Roll Machine…! Sa-WEET. The lead singer is from Chernobyl. Sa-WEET. If you want to laugh take a look at their picture on AllMusic.</description></item><item><title>explosions in the sky</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-07-25-explosions-in-the-sky/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-07-25-explosions-in-the-sky/</guid><description>[![I41853p0pkv][2]][2][explosions in the sky][2] is my favorite band. luckily it looks like they are back on tour, opening for smashing pumpkins, which i think would be a good fit, although i haven’t heard the new SP album. they are coming to nashville in november. i’ll be there. buy their new album – [all of a sudden i miss everyone][3]. if you have any doubts as to the beauty and brilliance, peruse its [metacritic page][4].</description></item><item><title>flight of the concords</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-07-25-flight-of-the-concords/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-07-25-flight-of-the-concords/</guid><description>i have been sans telly now for about six months, so i’m not sure, but i think that this is a show on HBO. yeah, so googling proved that youtube is correct. don’t know what the context/premise of the show is, but this clip that someone sent me is pretty damn hilarious. they also have a video podcast which is available on itunes as well as a bunch of videos on their HBO page.</description></item><item><title>two down, one more to go.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-07-16-two-down-one-more-to-go/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-07-16-two-down-one-more-to-go/</guid><description>[![Timetable_2][2]][2] this weekend we went to the north sea jazz festival. i’ve always wanted to go to this one as it is quite a famous show. there were three jazz festivals i always wanted to attend: new orleans, north sea and newport. all that is left is newport!
[]: http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/07/16/timetable_2.jpg
~ # ~</description></item><item><title>the dirtiest thing i&amp;#8217;ve ever said</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-07-11-the-dirtiest-thing-ive-ever-said/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-07-11-the-dirtiest-thing-ive-ever-said/</guid><description>mongo has a new poem for taylor up on the indiefeed PP podcast, you, too, can listen with wide-eyed-conspiratorial-wonder. it is funnier than usual, even for TM. mongo also said, and i have yet to verify on TM’s site, that mali will be: (1) releasing a new album this year, &amp;amp; (2) will be guest hosting indiefeed.
hot shit said casey, and i gave him a detention…..on the spot.
this poem is straightforward and reminds me of playing grenade wars with beaner using magnolia seed pods which always had the stems attached which we pulled like pins and tossed and then jumped into bushes.</description></item><item><title>Videos</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-07-10-videos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-07-10-videos/</guid><description>now that i have bandwidth and are experiencing the lack of a firewall i can waste even more time while i’m supposed to be &amp;ldquo;working.&amp;rdquo; this is funny SHIT. it is 60′s bid hair dancing / jazzercising queens messing about to some serious usher songs. and then there is this. watch out for the blue steel.
~ # ~</description></item><item><title>the king &amp;amp; the texas</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-05-18-the-king-the-texas/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-05-18-the-king-the-texas/</guid><description>two notes on music.
have decided that elvis deserves his title. we watched this video of his from 1967 or 68 in Vegas. it was wild. he was drunk. he sang. he wooed. simply: he is the flippin’ king. i need to buy that shit, it was so good.
have bought my tix for austin city limits. september 14-16. dig it: dylan, bjork, arcade fire, bloc party, gotan project, joss stone, lucinda williams, indigo girls, decemberists, robert ear keen, lcd soundsystem (which highlands has renamed the cowbell crew), clap your hands say yeah, ben kweller, ziggy marley (were they both there last year?</description></item><item><title>hip hop</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-05-08-hip-hop/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-05-08-hip-hop/</guid><description>i have been thinking recently that an interesting sociological study would trace paterns (if they exist) and links between musical genres and poverty and/or conflict. this is the story that got me thinking these thoughts…
maybe two weeks ago some friends of ours told us of an album launch at the YSC (young sportsmen’s club). thinking that it would be interesting i tried to get a big group of people to go.</description></item><item><title>The Killer</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-03-01-the-killer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-03-01-the-killer/</guid><description>I cannot figure out if this song is a tortured love song or a prayer or both. Nevertheless, I’ve been listening to it all morning…It fits nicely with the cloudy, humid skys filling up for the rainy season. I think we’re lost, don’t worry
I’ve been here before
I’m sure I thought I knew the way
Out of here yesterday
Dove cuesto, mi dolce?
Your driver called, it’s time to go-</description></item><item><title>A love letter to my music collection</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-01-16-a-love-letter-to-my-music-collection/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-01-16-a-love-letter-to-my-music-collection/</guid><description>dear music collection:
i love you. being without you has caused me to do crazy things. i bought an ipod a day before i leave for africa becuase my last one, with you all up in it, decided to blow the fuck up. it was a bastard anyway and i was getting jealous of your involvement with it. it was good to have you back. i looked at you on my computer, felt you when i packed and listened to you via a long series of cords and conundrums on my latest trip becuase the last ipod….</description></item><item><title>thun-der. nananananaaaaana. thun-der</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-07-01-thun-der-nananananaaaaana-thun-der/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-07-01-thun-der-nananananaaaaana-thun-der/</guid><description>[![Hb1sm_1][2]][2]
last night i went to THIS. i flashed back to driving to the keys for one of my first times with all the windows down and gb with me. i was screaming ac/dc at the top of my lungs. she was laughing her ass off. []: http://www.hellsbelles.info/
this is a lesbian ac/dc cover band. there is no other way to say this: they rock fucking hard. the chick who covers angus spent most of the show in a black bra and the little plaid skirt.</description></item><item><title>summer lawns</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-06-06-summer-lawns/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-06-06-summer-lawns/</guid><description>so i have many reviews and things upon which to comment. however, those will have to wait until another time. for now i wanted to tell you about a fantastic new opportunity for your and your loved ones. i’m not talking about the pyramid scheme that i’m deeply involved in, although i would love to talk to YOU about that sometime. maybe we can get a drink, i don’t know you, but i know you’d like to hear what i have to say.</description></item></channel></rss>