<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/</link><description>A Site About Resilience and Authoritarianism</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</managingEditor><webMaster>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</webMaster><copyright>All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/gnome/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gnome Shell Extensions -- Those Little Bundles of Joy</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-21-gnome-shell-extensions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-21-gnome-shell-extensions/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have yet to really get into any of the desktop interfaces other than Gnome. I've tried KDE and Unity. I'd like to try Elementary, but probably on an old laptop I'm going to set up for my in laws rather than my primary machine. Since about Gnome Shell 3.2, though, I've done little more than take tours around other desktop interfaces.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In case you did not know, one of the greatest things about Linux is that you can do this. You can explore different desktop interfaces and find the one that works for you. Gnome works for me. It may not work for you. You may prefer another flavor. That's awesome! Because Linux successfully compartmentalizes different aspects of the computer it is &lt;em>nearly&lt;/em> trivial to change desktop interfaces without having to reinstall the entire Operating System. Especially if you are using one of the major distributions to provide the underlying portions of the operating system.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-extensions-i-use">The Extensions I Use&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I currently use sixteen extensions:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://extensions.gnome.org/extension/766/alternative-activities/">Alternate Activities Menu&lt;/a> has a nice workspace indicator. I do not really use one of its killer features which is to semi control the other extensions and to &amp;ldquo;remember&amp;rdquo; which applications are open in which workspaces (the latter because I'm anally retentive enough to always know where things are).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://extensions.gnome.org/extension/615/appindicator-support/">AppIndicator Support&lt;/a> is one of my favorite extensions right now. I have used some variety of this extension since shell 3.2, but this is the best in class for my (not) money. This extension does a great job of letting me customize where application indicators (tray icons, whatever they are called today) go &amp;ndash; either in the top panel or in the bottom message tray (the former I see much more often than the latter). This allows me to put things that I don't want to visually clutter my panel into the message tray where I don't really need to see them but every once in a while.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://extensions.gnome.org/extension/768/audio-input-switcher/">Audio Input Switcher&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="https://extensions.gnome.org/extension/751/audio-output-switcher/">Audio Output Switcher&lt;/a> are two great little tools that give me a quick way to switch what audio input | output I'm using from the system menu which is always the top right corner of the panel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://extensions.gnome.org/extension/16/auto-move-windows/">Automove Windows&lt;/a> I spoke about this in my post on desktops. It does what it says and automatically moves windows to the specified workspace when you open them. It does not lock them into the workspace so you can move them around after they are opened, but it is nice to know that Spotify always opens in the Third Workspace or however you set it up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://extensions.gnome.org/extension/595/autohide-battery/">Autohide Battery&lt;/a> does what it says and hides the battery icon from the panel when the battery is fully charged.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://extensions.gnome.org/extension/517/caffeine/">Caffeine&lt;/a> this is a great little extension which stops the screensaver and lock screen from being triggered. You can set it up to always turn on upon the occurrence of certain events. For example, I keep chromium on my system and then link Caffeine to always turn on when chromium is open. So if I want to watch videos on my computer I just use chromium rather than chrome which is my daily driver for browsing, and then I do not have to worry about the screensaver turning on. It's the little things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://extensions.gnome.org/extension/111/calculator/">Calculator&lt;/a> when you press the Super (Windows) key in Gnome you go to the activities overview. This extension puts a wee little calculator there which you can use. I'm using it less and less.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://extensions.gnome.org/extension/97/coverflow-alt-tab/">Coverflow Alt-Tab&lt;/a> makes Alt-Tabbing beautiful in Gnome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://extensions.gnome.org/extension/545/hide-top-bar/">Hide Top Bar&lt;/a> this is utterly an essential extension for me. I do not like having wasted pixels &lt;em>always&lt;/em> used at the top of my screen. If I want to see the panel I'm happy to scroll my mouse there or hit Super. Otherwise, leave me alone and let me focus on the task at hand. This is another extension which I have used various flavors of since I started using Gnome and I've resisted upgrading shells until I knew that an extension of this variety was working in the next version.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://extensions.gnome.org/extension/55/media-player-indicator/">Media Player Indicator&lt;/a> is another long-standing (for me) and very popular extension. It puts a summary of whatever media is playing (or open but not playing) into your system menu so you can control or see different things. It has always been good eye candy for the panel and in the latest version of Shell it has collapsed into the system menu which brightens that up a bit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://extensions.gnome.org/extension/695/mediakeys-to-mpris2/">MediaKeys to MPRIS2&lt;/a> transmits my function F8 into a next song for Spotify and other apps.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://extensions.gnome.org/extension/732/message-tray-on-bottom-right-corner/">Message Tray on bottom right corner&lt;/a> over time, Gnome has changed how you get to the message tray. I like being able to fling my mouse at the bottom right corner and having the message tray pop up rather than Super+m. This is a nice to have but not essential extension for me because I care what is going on in the message tray only a couple of times a day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://extensions.gnome.org/extension/53/pomodoro/">Pomodoro&lt;/a> timer. Must have.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://extensions.gnome.org/extension/425/project-hamster-extension/">Project Hamster Extension&lt;/a> how I track my billable and non-billable time fluctuates over time. Have tried many different solutions and I'm here now. Not sure if will stick but have been enjoying it for about a month now. Has a good autocomplete feature and looks a hell of a lot nicer than other applications. Being designed for Gnome specifically makes it appealing as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://extensions.gnome.org/extension/19/user-themes/">User themes&lt;/a> allow me to have different themes for Gnome Shell to make it look, act, and feel different ways. I used Elegance Colors but there are tons of flavors available. This extension has been a must have since the very first version of Shell.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="installing-uninstalling-enabling-disabling-extensions">Installing, Uninstalling, Enabling, Disabling Extensions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you are in gnome and a user of normal variety, do this:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">$ sudo apt-get install gnome-tweak-tool
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>You will be much happier thereafter. Tweak tool allows you to turn extensions on or off and also lets you get to the extension preferences and options interface which you will need from time to time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, you can also get to these things from the &lt;a href="https://extensions.gnome.org/">gnome extensions web app&lt;/a> which is a brilliant tool. From there you can install, uninstall, enable, disable, and go to the preferences for any extension you have installed. It interacts with your desktop in a way which I really like, but could see how some paranoids would hate &amp;ndash; luckily because Gnome is open source those paranoids can see what information the web app is gathering from your desktop. The interface is simple and a very good way to try out different extensions to see the ones that are good for you!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Happy Hacking!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How I Use Multiple Workspaces</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-19-using-multiple-workspaces/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-19-using-multiple-workspaces/</guid><description>&lt;p>When I first moved to Linux from Windows in Ubuntu 11.10, I was confused about multiple workspaces. I thought, coming from a Windows background, that they would be overkill and require significant resources from my very old at that time laptop. My laptop then was about a 5 year old Dell that Windows Vista barely worked on. One of the huge reasons I decided to try Linux at all was the way that it was reported to be able to handle older hardware with style and grace. That said, I am always paranoid about what processes are running at any time and have for years always kept a close eye on system resource allocation (like since about Windows 3 years). Apps which are resource hogs get uninstalled or somehow sandboxed. Apps which I do not think I will need regularly get uninstalled with a vengeance. OS components I do not want get uninstalled &amp;ndash; to the extent the OS will still work if I uninstall them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Coming from a Windows background, and being generally a fairly linear unitask thinker, I failed to see the benefit in multiple workspaces. I tend to keep only a few applications opened at any one time in Windows so why would I need multiple workspaces I thought. Then I installed my first version of Gnome Shell.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of Gnome Shell's biggest achievements as far as I'm concerned is dynamic workspaces. The basic idea is that the desktop system creates one workspace and then if you need additional ones you can either open an application in that workspace (more on this in a moment) or you can move an application to a new workspace. The desktop system will automatically create and delete workspaces based on what you are using at any one time. It is a clutter killer (which I adore) but also extraordinarily functional.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="workspaces-for-different-portions-of-the-computing-brain">Workspaces for Different Portions of the Computing Brain&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I have &amp;ndash; for the most part &amp;ndash; quadroned off how I interact with my computer into a quadrons.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>The first quadron is my terminal workspace. I use Guake and have written about my terminal setup &lt;a href="http://coda.caseykuhlman.com//entries/2014/on-shells.html">here&lt;/a>. Guake is not its own workspace, as it resides &amp;ldquo;above&amp;rdquo; all my workspaces and whenever I need it, it is a simple &lt;code>F12&lt;/code> away. In this quadron is where I install, uninstall apps, generally work &amp;ldquo;on&amp;rdquo; my computer.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The second quadron is my media workspace. This is generally my workspace number 3 (or my bottom workspace in Gnome's vertical configuration of workspaces). I have set up all my media players to open in this window. So from my primary workspace I simply slide down two workspaces if I want to change the album that is playing or do something that I cannot easily do from either media keys or the panel in Gnome.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The third quadron is my reference workspace. This is the workspace where I keep all the things that I need on a regular basis but do not want cluttering my primary workspace. This is the first workspace below my primary workspace. These are, for the most part, Chrome windows which I open as &lt;code>--apps&lt;/code> which allows me to open them with no decoration (which are nothing but wasted pixels if I only want to see what X site says). In this workspace I traditionally keep open four Chrome windows: &lt;a href="https://evernote.com/">Evernote&lt;/a>; my Google Calendar; my Google Drive; and my &lt;a href="https://redbooth.com">Redbooth&lt;/a>. Evernote is my filing cabinet more or less and I use it for tons of different things. They have been quite public that they will not make a desktop application for Linux (which I would use relentlessly) but their web app is not bad. It used to be a resource hog but has improved (or else my new laptop is just better able to handle it). Redbooth is the Project Management Interface we use at Watershed for years now. It handles all our tasks, etc. so I need to have this open. We use Google Drive a lot for Watershed so it is helpful to see the feed rather than simply using a file browser as the feed gives me a view of what attorneys are working on quickly. With the exception of Evernote, I'm quite happy keeping these as webapps. Even when I'm in Somaliland where bandwidth is limited, all of these webapps are extremely efficient in their bandwidth usage so once they are loaded they simply Ajax call their way through the day which saves me bandwidth and also still let's me keep everything in sync.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The fourth quadron is my primary workspace. Unless I'm deep in work on a complex task requiring multiple pdf windows or something, I keep two applications running in this workspace. I keep my primary chrome window here which always has my personal and work gmails up and whatever else I happen to be reading or writing or working on in Chrome. I also keep my Sublime window open at all times. I code in Sublime, write memos in Sublime, draft contracts in Sublime, draft laws in Sublime, generally Sublime is my &amp;ldquo;work&amp;rdquo; hub for documents. If I need to open pdf or doc or odt files I generally will pull them up from Sublime rather than opening a file browser.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="keyboard-shortcuts-for-workspace-bliss">Keyboard Shortcuts for Workspace Bliss&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Keyboard shortcuts. Oh how I love them. So easy to setup. Go to Keyboard in your Applications menu and then click on Shortcuts. For workspace and windows stuff, go to the Navigation sub-tab. Here's the shortcuts I use:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Move window one workspace down: Alt+Super+Up&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Move window one workspace up: Alt+Super+Down&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Move to workspace up: Ctrl+Super+Up&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Move to workspace down: Ctrl+Super+Down&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>That's It! That is really all you need. Move a window up or down, and move your viewer up or down. While you are in here, do yourself a favour and go to Custom Shortcuts, Add a Shortcut, nautilus (as the command), Super+E (or whatever shortcut you fancy). Now you are a shortcut away from your file browser no matter where you are.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="automatic-workspace-management">Automatic Workspace Management&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I lurve automating things. With Gnome Shell it is very easy to ensure that (most) of my windows open in the specific place that I want them to. Gnome Shell extensions are lovely little applets which open up the possibilities of what you can do with your desktop. I should publish a list of the ones I use, but for now, only this &lt;a href="https://extensions.gnome.org/extension/16/auto-move-windows/">one&lt;/a> is relevant. It is an extension which automatically moves windows to a specific workspace. That's it. So whenever I open Spotify, I have set it to open in Workspace 3. Boom! Just that simple. To set up the extensions you will need to have gnome-tweak-tool installed:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">$ sudo apt-get install gnome-tweak-tool
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Then you go to the above link and push the button to install. After that open tweak and go to the Extensions tab to turn it on. You can also go to &amp;ldquo;Installed Extensions&amp;rdquo; in the gnome extensions site to turn on extensions, but generally Tweak Tool is better. Also there will be a link in Tweak Tool Extensions tab to the Extension settings. Click there. Then you will see a place to &amp;ldquo;Add rule&amp;rdquo; click there, then click the program you want and the workspace you want.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you prefer the old school version (as I do) then you can use dconf tool.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">$ sudo apt-get install dconf-editor
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Then from dconf you go to: &lt;code>org -&amp;gt; gnome -&amp;gt; shell -&amp;gt; extensions -&amp;gt; auto-move-windows&lt;/code>. Once you get there then you type in the correct APPLICATION.desktop file and the workspace. So the string should look something like this: &lt;code>['spotify.desktop:3', 'xnoise.desktop:3']&lt;/code>. That's it. Then whenever you open the application it will open in the correct place.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Happy Hacking!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Autostarting Different Programs in Different Desktops</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-04-12-autostarting-for-different-linux-desktops/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-04-12-autostarting-for-different-linux-desktops/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the most obvious appeals of Linux to me is the insane levels of customization you can achieve. I mainly use Gnome Shell as my desktop environment, but since I use Ubuntu I keep Unity on my machine. I'm not a hater of Unity or Gnome as many Linux users (who can be quite vitriolic in their statements as to desktop environments). I &lt;em>mostly&lt;/em> use Gnome, but since Ubuntu has some interesting things going on with Unity sometimes I like to drop into Unity to see what I'm missing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is a problem at least in Ubuntu 12.10 running both desktops. To use Gnome Shell one &lt;em>should&lt;/em> install the &lt;code>gdm&lt;/code> package in order to get the full Gnome desktop experience - including the Gnome lock screen which is beautiful. GDM stands for Gnome Desktop Manager. It is an alternative to &lt;code>lightdm&lt;/code> which Ubuntu installs by default and which Unity uses. When you switch to gdm I found out that just after installing it you should logout of Unity before restarting your machine. But I didn't do that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The result of installing gdm and then restarting your machine is that the X server (which runs most of the linux desktops and lies in the stack underneath both gdm and lightdm) doesn't start correctly for &amp;ldquo;both&amp;rdquo; Unity and Shell. It is something to do with the way that dm loads the XSessions and it is beyond my understanding. In any event the problem for me was that while gdm made Shell work as it should out of the box, Unity would not load when I logged into Unity desktop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I built a small autostart script that for Unity that will load Unity after logging into the Ubuntu desktop. This was straight-forward. But the problem I had is that I didn't want the script to try to load Unity when I logged into Gnome. But, as usual with linux, with a bit of Googling I came across the key. In X session desktop scripts (which are the main way to start/run programs) you can define which desktop environment they should show up in. This means that when you put the script into the autostart folder (~/.config/autostart) you can mark the script to &amp;hellip; &lt;code>OnlyShowIn=GNOME;&lt;/code> or &lt;code>OnlyShowIn=UNITY;&lt;/code> or &lt;code>NotShowIn=GNOME;&lt;/code> or &lt;code>NotShowIn=UNITY;&lt;/code>. You can add multiple environments for the desktop script to be shown or hidden in after the semicolons.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is helpful for showing or hiding certain programs/scripts in your menus in different desktop environments but also when you put it in the scripts in your autostart folder you can tell linux to only load the programs when you log into certain desktop environments. I tested the script and it didn't work at first. The problem was because gdm wasn't loading Unity, the autoload scripts I marked to only load in Unity weren't triggering. Even though gdm sent me to Unity, the desktop environment wasn't loading correctly. So I had to change the script from &lt;code>OnlyShowIn=UNITY;&lt;/code> to &lt;code>NotShowIn=GNOME;&lt;/code>. This meant that when the desktop environment saw that it was not in Shell it triggered the script for Unity. It isn't ideal as the autoload scripts that are linked to Unity don't run &lt;em>after&lt;/em> the Unity reload script runs, but it is a decent enough work around for the amount that I use Unity (minimal).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is very powerful as you usually want Gnome Shell and Unity to load the different sugar packages such as applets, indicators, etc., that help you define the environment you are working in. This is reason 7 million why Linux is awesome. In any event, here's the script I use to reload the Unity desktop after I log into Unity.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span style="color:#f92672">[&lt;/span>Desktop Entry&lt;span style="color:#f92672">]&lt;/span>
Type&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>Application
Exec&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>unity
Hidden&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>false
NoDisplay&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>false
X-GNOME-Autostart-enabled&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>true
Name&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>Unity-Reset
NotShowIn&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>GNOME;&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>
&lt;p>I saved that in ~/.config/autostart and voila all (mostly) working as it should.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Happy Hacking!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>