<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/</link><description>A Site About Resilience and Authoritarianism</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</managingEditor><webMaster>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</webMaster><copyright>All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/election/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Understanding the Somaliland Elections (2 of 3): The Contenders</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-26-understanding-somaliland-elections-2-3-contenders/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-26-understanding-somaliland-elections-2-3-contenders/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Today Somaliland is holding its Presidential elections. To understand the significance of this event, one must understand the road that it has taken the Somalilanders to get to this point. This election has been delayed for over two years. This entry contains a small background on the three men on the ballot.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.ucidparty.com/">&lt;img src="http://www.ucidparty.com/" alt="UCID Chairman Faisal Ali Warabe via Sallaxleynews @ flickr">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="contender-a-faisal-ali-warabe-chairman-ucid-party">Contender A: Faisal Ali “Warabe” Chairman UCID Party&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Faisal and his &lt;a href="http://www.ucidparty.com/">UCID party&lt;/a> have long been seen as the also rans in Somaliland politics.  But UCID seems to have found some resonance in its argument this term and seems to have a growing cadre of supporters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Name:  Faisal Ali “Warabe.” **“Warabe” means hyena in Somali.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Clan: Ciidagaale.&lt;/strong> The Ciidagale are a small-ish (but not a minority) clan within the Somaliland clans.  They are a subclan of the Isaaq who are the majority clan within Somaliland.  The Ciidagaale have a kinship-alliance with one of the major clans within Somaliland politics of the past ten years: the Habar Yunis.  This kinship-alliance is called the Galhajis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Ciidagaale see themselves as the linkage between the major Isaaq subclans from the west of Somaliland (namely the Habar Awal kinship-alliance between the Issa Muse and Sa’ad Muse) and those in the east of Somaliland (namely their “brethren” from the Galhajis as well as the Habar Jaclo).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These two items (their relatively small size and their geographical position between the major players) have long given the Ciidagaale an outsized view of themselves.  They have always played with the big boys, indeed for hundreds of years before and during British colonialism their sultan was one of  the most powerful in all of the northern Somali regions.  They claim that they ruled Somaliland for 500 years, but it is a bit more complicated than that.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="strengths">Strengths:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Not one of the two major players&lt;/strong>.  This underdog position has allowed UCID to campaign nearly without the hassles that the other two “major” parties have had to cope with.  Most of the shots which UDUB and KULMIYE fire across one another’s bows (including claims and counterclaims of terrorist affiliation) are irrelevant to UCID.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Relatively free from the baggage of the SNM / Siad Barre conflict.&lt;/strong> Most Somaliland youth don’t really understand the SNM conflict except in a historical context.  To them this was something that happened before and it does not have the viscerality that it likely had in the prior Presidential elections.  Claims and counterclaims between UDUB and KULMIYE as to whether the prevalence of old SNM fighters who “liberated” Somaliland are waning as a relevant point within Somaliland politics as the years pass.  UCID, who is seen as largely free of this baggage, is in a good position to capitalize on this by pulling in those who see membership in SNM as a hindrance rather than a selling point.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Intellectual vigor.&lt;/strong> The team that Faisal has assembled within the UCID network contains some of the better intellectuals around Somaliland.  This is recognized as a positive by most people that I’ve talked to. UCID seems to have an energy that the other two parties do not have.  Although, this positioning, which is populist in nature, has likely not brought the finances into the campaign coffers required to deal with contingencies after the voting.  They have been very effective at targeting two major centers of the Somaliland electorate: women voters and younger voters.  Most of the rallies held by UCID have seen a larger proportion of woman than any of  the other two parties (from my limited perspective at least).  This definitely will set UCID up for long term success, even if they fail to win this election.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="weaknesses">Weaknesses:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Not one of the major players.&lt;/strong> UCID’s outsider status is also their major weakness.  They have a difficult time capitalizing on the winds which blow through the Somaliland deserts because it is difficult for many to visualize their party in power.  They have difficulty dominating any news cycles or forging forward with their own spin on a given situation.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Wishy-Washy.&lt;/strong> Faisal is seen as wishy-washy by the Somaliland electorate.  I must say that while I understand where they are coming from, I think personally much of this comes from Faisal’s position in between the other two major players.  He is forced into a difficult position where he is required to mediate likely more than he would prefer due to his “third party” status.  This centrist positioning comes across as wishy-washy.  It is unfortunate.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.xisbigaudub.com/">&lt;img src="http://www.xisbigaudub.com/" alt="UDUB Chairman and Incumbent President of Somaliland, Dahir Kahin Riyale via Swiatoslaw Wojtkowiak @ flickr">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="contender-b-dahir-kahin-riyale-chairman-udub-party-incumbent-president">Contender B: Dahir Kahin Riyale, Chairman UDUB Party, Incumbent President&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Riyale and his &lt;a href="http://www.xisbigaudub.com/">UDUB party&lt;/a> have been in power, more or less, since Somaliland declared its independence from Mogadishu and handed over power to a civilian government in the early 1990′s.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Name: Dahir Kahin Riyale.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Clan: Gaadabursi.&lt;/strong> The Gaadabursi are a western clan within Somaliland.  They are probably the largest non-Isaaq clan within Somaliland.  There are some other larger non-Isaaq clans, but the majority of these clans are located outside of Somaliland.  Many feel that having a non-Isaaq President has been beneficial to help keep the Isaaq from imploding and fighting with one another during the years of instability of the 2000′s.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many other Isaaq’s feel that having a non-Isaaq President has given too much power to minority clans within Somaliland.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="strengths-1">Strengths:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Incumbent.&lt;/strong> Let’s be honest.  This is Africa.  The incumbent has numerous advantages that any incumbent would normally have, but also those that may not be available to non-African incumbents.  Already possessing the state gives access to finances that are not available to others within the country.  As Gettleman pointed out in yesterday’s &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/06/26/world/africa/26somaliland.html?hp">piece&lt;/a> for the New York Times, sometimes the voting isn’t what matters, but what happens afterward.  For the afterwards, being the incumbent is a distinct advantage.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Experience.&lt;/strong> Many Somalilanders will endlessly debate whether the Riyale administration has done enough on the development front to get a new chance to run the country.  That said, most Somalilanders will concede that as far as experience governing the current team assembled by Riyale cannot be matched.  Although there are many former Ministers and government officials within KULMIYE’s team, and although UCID brings a lot of intellectual firepower to their team, pure raw experience seems to still be having a decent amount of resonance with those I speak to here in Hargeisa.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>**Continuity. **If Riyale were to stay there would be some continuity to the governing system.  Riyale has proffered two arguments in his favor.  The first is similar to the argument Rove was making in 2004, don’t change horses in the middle of the war.  The Riyale administration has made a big deal out of the current and impending conflict with al-Shabaab operatives that continue to hound Somaliland.  They have argued that they have the right team to tackle this problem.  The second argument has no analogy in American politics, but it is essentially: “we’re already fat, they are skinny, who will really take less from the state coffers.”  For a while this seemed to carry a good amount of weight with the electorate, but has largely been sidelined over the weeks leading up to the election.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="weaknesses-1">Weaknesses:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Background &amp;amp; Baggage.&lt;/strong> Riyale is a former intelligence officer for Siad Barre.  He was not aligned with the SNM, and he sometimes has had to distinguish aside these two arguments.  His response has oscillated between the extremes of hiring lots of SNM veterans and by trying to marginalize the SNM veterans.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>**Engagement Level. **Many question Riyale’s engagement within Somaliland.  Since his wife mostly lives in Paris with their children rather than in Somaliland, lots of voters that I have spoken with have wondered how much Riyale genuinely cares about Somaliland.  He has had to simultaneously deflect attacks that ironically have sought to portray his administration as (1) autocratic, and (2) blind.  While I have seen the evidence pointed to by opposition members in this regard, it is Africa and there will always be some conflating of a Presidential seat vested in institutions with a Kingdom vested in the personality.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.kulmiye.com/">&lt;img src="http://www.kulmiye.com/" alt="Kulmiye Chairman, Ahmed Mohamed Mohamud &amp;ldquo;Silanyo&amp;rdquo; via Berberanews.com @ flickr">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="contender-c-ahmed-mohamed-mohamud-silanyo-chairman-of-the-kulmiye-party">Contender C: Ahmed Mohamed Mohamud “Silanyo” Chairman of the Kulmiye Party&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Silanyo and his &lt;a href="http://www.kulmiye.com/">Kulmiye party&lt;/a> are largely seen as the primary rivals for the Presidency against Riyale. In the last Presidential election Silanyo lost to Riyale by 80 votes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Name: Ahmed Mohamed Mohmoud “Silanyo”&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Clan: Habar Jaclo.&lt;/strong> The Habar Jaclo are one of the largest Isaaq sub-clans in Somaliland.  They traditionally have occupied the farthest east of the Somaliland Isaaq clans, from Burco all the way to Ceerigavo and almost to Las Anood.  This is significant for two reasons.  First, Burco has traditionally felt second-city syndrome to Hargeisa since the British colonial time.  Second, as one of the largest subclans of the majority clan, Habar Jaclo can appeal to parts of the Isaaq electorate that none of the other candidates can due to their majority (semi-majority) status.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many of the Habar Jaclo feel that this is their time, that they have waited as the other major Isaaq clans have had opportunities within the governance framework that they have not had access to (which is a bit of gamesmanship but that is beside the point for how they feel).  They are a tough clan and have shown little hesitation in the past to fight for what they feel they deserve.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="strengths-2">Strengths:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Effective usage of Obama Change Mantra.&lt;/strong> Kulmiye has been exceedingly effective at hijacking the change mantra.  This is hilarious to me, as most of the team within Kulmiye are retreads from prior administrations – either from the SNM times or the post-SNM UDUB days.  However, they have convinced a large portion of the population that they will be the most effective vehicle for change.  This has allowed them to leverage growing discontentment with the current state of Somaliland as a factor in their favor – although many of them were involved in setting the preconditions or implementation of many of the policies they now argue against.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Post-Clanism.&lt;/strong> Another ironic, but effective, political tactic that has been used by the Kulmiye team is to preach post-clanism.  This is also ironic as many Somalilanders feel that among the three parties, Kulmiye is by far the most tied to various clan networks.  I have  no opinion as I’ve never met many of the Kulmiye officials, but certainly they have had that reputation for a long time.   The simple fact that most Habar Jaclo feel that this is their time and that Silanyo, being Habar Jaclo, is their vehicle for political success argues against the post-clanism rhetoric which has been effectively utilized by Kulmiye.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Crowd-sourcing&lt;/strong>.  Kulmiye, among the three parties, has probably had the greatest ability to leverage populism embedded in African big-crowd politics.  They have very energized supporters, especially among the middle-aged former SNM fighters who see their old colonels and central party members as those now wearing suits and up for Ministerial positions and other positions if Kulmiye were to win.   They also have been very effective at energizing supporters among the youth.  Those that have not gone with UCID have largely gone with Kulmiye.  Lastly, Kulmiye seems to understand the power of a crowd and routinely buses in large amounts of supporters before their rallies in order to create a scene which has an undeniable magnetic effect in the Somali world-view.  All of these show an understanding of political process, but I still have seen little evidence that their policies will be effectively implemented.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="weaknesses-2">Weaknesses:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Baggage&lt;/strong>.  As with Riyale, Silanyo comes with his own (very large) baggage.  As the oldest of the three men, and a long-time politician within Somali/Somaliland circles, Silanyo has a long and well-known history.  Silanyo was one of the driving forces behind the formation, training, and equipping of SNM.  However, he was ousted as Chairman soon before SNM’s reentry into Somaliland.  Many claim that this ousting was due to Silanyo cutting a last minute deal with Siad for SNM not to attack Somalia and for the Isaaq to be given more autonomy.  I have no opinion on the truthiness of this claim, however it is a widely disseminated rumor and has made many Somalilanders I’ve talked to question Silanyo’s patriotism and his willingness to make a difficult decision.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Retreads&lt;/strong>.  Much of Silanyo’s team has been there before.  Many were leaders among the SNM and / or the post-SNM UDUB administrations of Egal and Riyale.  In many voters’ eyes this is seen as a negative.  Many within this team are felt to be hardliners that may fight before negotiating.  Whether this is true or not, it is certainly the feeling among a percentage of the Somaliland electorate.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Understanding the Somaliland Elections (3 of 3): The Arguments</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-26-understanding-somaliland-elections-3-3-arguments/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-26-understanding-somaliland-elections-3-3-arguments/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Today Somaliland is holding its Presidential elections. To understand the significance of this event, one must understand the road that it has taken the Somalilanders to get to this point. This election has been delayed for over two years. This entry contains a small background on the arguments that have been given by three men on the ballot.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.garoweonline.com/artman2/publish/Opinion_20/Somaliland_KULMIYE_Formidable_Opposition_Party_or_Troublous_Rebel_Group.shtml">&lt;img src="http://www.garoweonline.com/artman2/publish/Opinion_20/Somaliland_KULMIYE_Formidable_Opposition_Party_or_Troublous_Rebel_Group.shtml" alt="Kulmiye colours by CharlesFred @ flickr">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After discussing some of the background and the personas involved in the election, in this final installment I would like to discuss the arguments that have been raised by each of the three parties.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These are not that complex, so if they seem as if I’ve shortened innumerable hours of speeches by politicians into slogans blithely, let me respond that it is without blitheness and really all I’ve done is distilled the hours of speeches into their core by taking out all of the repetitive words and colorful adjectives which are used by the protagonists with the microphones.  I’ve also tried my best to take out the facial inaccuracies that I see within their arguments, such as &lt;a href="http://www.garoweonline.com/artman2/publish/Opinion_20/Somaliland_KULMIYE_Formidable_Opposition_Party_or_Troublous_Rebel_Group.shtml">this particular article&lt;/a> (from the Kulmiye camp).&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-you-should-vote-for-udub-udub-version">Why You Should Vote &lt;em>For&lt;/em> UDUB (UDUB Version).&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>“We have kept the peace &amp;amp; development will come.”&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-you-should-vote-against-kulmiye-udub-version">Why You Should Vote *Against *Kulmiye (UDUB Version).&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>“They are terrorists.”&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-you-should-vote-for-kulmiye-kulmiye-version">Why You Should Vote &lt;em>For&lt;/em> Kulmiye (Kulmiye Version).&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>“We need change!”&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-you-should-vote-against-udub-kulmiye-version">Why You Should Vote *Against *UDUB (Kulmiye Version).&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>“They are terrorists, and have done nothing for the country.”&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-you-should-vote-for-ucid-ucid-version">Why You Should Vote *For *UCID (UCID Version).&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>“We are the real change.  Here is what we will do for you [insert long list of unobtainables here].”&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-you-should-vote-against-ucid-udub-kulmiye-version">Why You Should Vote *Against *UCID (UDUB Kulmiye Version).&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>[blank] No one seems to make this argument. But when it is made, it goes: “They are terrorists.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Understanding the Somaliland Elections (1 of 3): Background</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-25-understanding-somaliland-elections-1-3-background/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-25-understanding-somaliland-elections-1-3-background/</guid><description>&lt;p>[![Somaliland Victory Monument by Somaliland247 @flickr][2]][2]
Somaliland Victory Monument by Somaliland247 @flickr&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today Somaliland is holding its Presidential elections.  To understand the significance of this event, one must understand the road that it has taken the Somalilanders to get to this point.  This election has been delayed for over two years.  This entry contains a small background on that time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Presidential elections were originally scheduled for August, 2008.  In April 2008, the Council of Elders – Somaliland’s upper house of Parliament (the Guurti) – extended the term of the President until April 6, 2009.  In April 2008, the NEC released a press statement indicating that the elections would take place as originally scheduled and that the Guurti did not have the authority to unilaterally delay the timeline for the elections as the original timeline had been agreed to by all political parties and the House of Representatives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a result of mounting tensions, the President agreed to meet with the leaders of the two opposition parties to negotiate a solution. The negotiations among the parties continued for approximately six weeks, when the three political parties and the NEC held a press conference and ceremony to sign the agreement which appeared to have formally resolved the election dispute. The main points of the agreement were that the presidential election would be held before the President’s term expires on April 6, 2009. The NEC originally scheduled the election to be held on March 29, 2009.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On September 23, 2008, NEC announced that it was accepting applications for temporary workers to administer the voter registration program.  Potential applicants were to attend screening interviews at NEC’s office in Hargeisa, Somaliland.  Several hundred applicants gathered outside the office and an adjacent hotel.  The gathering began to grow agitated upon learning that only several dozen positions would be available.  The police attempted to disperse an increasingly tense situation by firing several gunshots into the air.  Two days later NEC continued the screening process without further incident.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On August 24-26, 2008, a dispute arose within the main opposition party, Kulmiye, over the rules of procedure for electing the party’s candidates for President during the Kulmiye party conference.  Before the conference began several candidates had emerged to oppose the current party chairman and previous Kulmiye Presidential candidate, Ahmed “Silanyo” Mahmoud Mohamed.   These challengers withdrew prior to the party conference in apparent recognition of their slim chances to defeat the incumbent party chairman.  Kulmiye reconciled its differences sometime in the middle of October.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The National Election Commission (NEC) conducted a voter awareness-raising drive during the first week of October, 2008 prior to beginning the actual registration process.  In the midst of this, there was a dispute within the NEC, with four members voting to oust the Chairman of the NEC.  It was never clear what the dispute was centered on, but a settlement was worked out soon thereafter to retain the present NEC Chairman in a meeting between the NEC and the three political parties.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The voter registration process began in the northern port city of Berbera on October 14 and concluded there on October 21.  After Berbera, the voter registration teams moved to Borama and Gabiley for registration of the regions west of Hargeisa.  Hargeisa region, the largest region, was originally scheduled to register voters starting October 28 through to November 3, 2009.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On October 29, 2008, three explosions occurred in Hargeisa.  All three were the result of vehicle suicide bombs.  A group named al-Shabaab claimed credit for the bombings.  Al-Shabaab is a group that claims to have linkages with al Qaeda and has been waging an insurgency in South-Central Somalia for many years.  Although they were known to have operatives in Somaliland throughout their history, this was the first time they acted in such a large-scale and sophisticated fashion.  The Somaliland government quickly and efficiently rooted out many of the remnants of al-Shabaab’s network within Somaliland and brought into custody individuals who have some level of suspected involvement.  More importantly perhaps, the Somaliland citizenry unequivocally rejected al-Shabaab, and many moderate Islamic Clerics spoke out against the attacks and expressed solidarity with the victims and with the Somaliland government.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Somaliland national security apparatus continued to maintain a high state of alert against information relating to ongoing threats.  Specifically, Somaliland officials have reportedly received and responded to numerous pieces of information at various times regarding imminent threats of attack or infiltrations by members of al-Shabaab’s network.  While no such attacks transpired after the initial wave of bombs, throughout this time there was a heightened threat environment and the Somaliland government appeared to be taking all available measures within its capacity to pursue these threats.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Due to the Hargeisa bombings there were a few delays in the registration process for the regions that were originally scheduled to follow Hargeisa region.  The first delay was due to the actual bombings.  The second delay was for staff training as the expatriates supporting the registration effort with information technology services were recalled by their companies and the local Somaliland staff had to be trained.  As a result, voter registration began on December 1 in Hargeisa.  Following the Hargeisa region, the NEC moved towards the eastern regions where it continued with the voter registration process.  The registration teams first went to Burao, the capital of the Togdheer region, followed shortly thereafter in the Sanaag region on December 30, 2008, and then concluded in Sool region.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Somaliland government officials describe the voter registration process as an overwhelming success.  Over 1 million people were registered, according to Somaliland officials, with many Somalilanders presently residing in Bossasso, Puntland reportedly even returning across the border just to register.  Previous population estimates of Somaliland were about 3.5 million, with roughly 30% of that population, or 1.3 million, estimated to be of eligible voting age.  Therefore, the figure of over 1 million voters registered seems close to legitimate. The NEC announced on January 12, 2009 that it had successfully completed the first phase of the voter registration process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As expected, the leaders of both the UDUB and UCID parties were nominated as the Presidential candidate for their respective party in the spring of 2009.  The ruling party, UDUB, nominated the incumbent President as its party’s nominee for the upcoming Presidential election.  The weaker of the two opposition parties, UCID, nominated its chairman, Faisal Ali Warabe, to be its party’s nominee for the upcoming Presidential election.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In February, NEC replaced its chairman.  The preceding chairman resigned on February 2, 2009 from his chairmanship but remained a commissioner.  The new chairman, Mr. Jama Mohamed, entered his position soon thereafter.  On February 23, 2009 NEC announced that it would not be able to hold the elections on the prior agreed date of March 29, 2009.  NEC stated that because of the high number of multiple registrants it would not be able to complete the verification of its database in time.  NEC used computerized software alongside digitized fingerprints and facial photos to identify persons who had registered multiple times.  The complicated computer algorithm that was used to “purge” the database of multiple registrants required outside consultants and extensive computing power – both of which took some time for NEC to acquire.  Additionally, there was a political dispute over the analysis of multiple registrants.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the time when NEC announced that it would not be able to make the March 29 election date, it had yet to complete the identification of multiple registrants.  Following NEC’s announcement that it would be unable to meet the March 29 election date, Kulmiye announced that it would not acknowledge the legitimacy of the current government beyond its allotted mandate – which was set to expire on April 6, 2009.  Kulmiye announced that it would only accept a unified caretaker regime from April 6 until the election was complete.  UDUB, the ruling party, refused to accept any government of unification.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Both parties finally compromised by sending the decision to the Guurti.  After an intense political battle, the Guurti announced on March 28, 2009 that it was extending the President’s mandate another six months, which in turn, extended UDUB’s ability to legally rule Somaliland until October 6, 2009.  Soon thereafter, in the first week of April, NEC announced that it would hold the election on September 27, 2009.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During the first week of April, Kulmiye announced that despite its earlier call to submit the extension of the Presidential mandate to the Guurti, the eventual decision by the Guurti was unconstitutional.  Kulmiye continued to claim that it would not accept UDUB’s legality to rule Somaliland after April 6, 2009.  The party made many claims during this period that it would resort to violence which never came to fruition.  On May 27, 2009 all three of the political parties finally accepted the decision of the mediation committee that the extension of the incumbent’s term by the Guurti, was constitutionally valid and that the election could be held on September 27, 2009.  The leaders of the three parties signed a memorandum of agreement enshrining their current desire to hold the election on that date.  One of the major reasons for the numerous delays was the continued technical difficulties in analyzing the database of registered voters and purging those who registered more than once.  Sometime around the 10th of June, this issue was thought finalized.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Running parallel to the political haggling over the Presidential elections was another battle over control of the Guurti.  On two occasions, first in the middle of February and second at the end of March, 2009 the Guurti brought forward motions to oust the current chairman of the Guurti, Suliman Mahmoud Adan.  Both challenges to the chairman were attributed to his perceived political allegiance to the chairman of Kulmiye, Silanyo.  On both occasions the opposition to the chairman was not able to acquire the quorum of two-thirds of the Guurti constitutionally required to unseat a sitting chairman.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The NEC had its own internal problems during the summer of 2009.  Two of the Commissioners were accused of corruption sometime around June 12 and were sacked by the NEC Chairman about a week later.  Since both of the sacked Commissioners had been appointed by the House of Representatives, that House was vested with the task of replacing them.  Rather than replacing the Commissioners at this late date in the election process, the House decided sometime around the 23rd of June to send the Commissioners back to NEC, despite the corruption allegation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The political gamesmanship between the Government and opposition parties, the Parliament, the National Election Commission (NEC), and the international donors escalated towards the end of July, again jeopardizing the prospects for the election on the scheduled date.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The implementing international NGO, InterPeace, supporting the election process in Somaliland was determined to resolve the technical difficulties associated with the voter registration database and released the final voter registration list to the NEC by July 27.  On July 28 the international donors, providing support to both InterPeace and the presidential elections, announced that the voter list had been released to the NEC on July 27 as agreed, and alleged that the NEC was holding up the process by not releasing the list to the political parties and the general public.  Later that same day, the NEC responded with an announcement that the voter list submitted to them had not resolved the ongoing technical difficulties and was therefore invalid.  The NEC announced further that the election would be conducted on the scheduled date, but without utilizing the voter registration list.  The donors responded with another press announcement that they would withdraw support for the election if the voter registration list was discarded by the NEC.  Meanwhile, the chairmen of both houses of parliament, along with the opposition parties, backed the international donors and announced that the election must only be conducted using the voter registration list.  However, the NEC and Somaliland Government held firm that the election would be conducted without the voter registration list, even going so far as to deport some of InterPeace’s international staff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Throughout August of 2009, the political parties and the National Election Commission (NEC) remained at loggerheads over the decision about whether to hold the election without the voter registration database.  Toward the end of the month, the President decided that the election would take place without the voter list.  This decision inflamed the opposition parties and operated as a catalyst for many relationships to fracture.  The first fissure was between the three parties.  August 3 was the date established by NEC for the political parties to begin campaigning.  On that day, the two opposition parties announced that they would boycott the election if the President continued to maintain his intransigence regarding the voter list.  Meanwhile, the ruling party held rallies for their candidate.  The following day the opposition parties announced, via their MPs, that they would seek the impeachment of the incumbent President.  They cited the Presidential intent to hold the election without the voter list and other unconstitutional actions by the President as their reason.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The drama between the political parties and the President was acted out on two stages.  The first stage was between the Presidential candidates, who participated in numerous mediation committee meetings to resolve their differences regarding whether or not the voter registration list was to be used.  The second stage was between the President and opposition MPs.  On August 15, the Parliament passed a decree allowing the elections to continue as planned without using the list, despite arguments that doing so would be contrary to the Voter Registration Act.  The back and forth between the opposition and ruling parties culminated in at the end of August with an assassination attempt on the Speaker of the House of Representatives by one of the MPs. The Speaker escaped into a prepositioned rally of anti-government supporters.  Following this, pro-government MPs sought the removal of the Speaker.  Meanwhile, anti-government MPs continued to seek the impeachment of the President.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition to the tensions within the Parliament, numerous other tensions were operating within Somaliland over the course of August.  The President and NEC found themselves in a battle with many external actors over the timing and conduct of the election.  On August 20, the Ethiopian Minister of State for Foreign Affairs arrived in Hargeisa in an effort to mediate the differences among the parties on these two issues.  He proved to be unsuccessful in his efforts.  After the Minister departed, a delegation from the African Union arrived in Hargeisa with a similar mission.  Finally, on August 29th, a British diplomat from the UK’s embassy in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia arrived.  All of these missions were unsuccessful and there was no agreement or clarity with regards to the timing and conduct of the Presidential election at the time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In early September, the National Election Commission (NEC) announced that they would be unable to conduct the elections as scheduled on September 27, 2009.  They did not announce a new timetable for when they would be able to conduct the elections.   Toward the end of September, 2009, the President’s mandate was expiring and all of the issues surrounding the election remain unsolved.  On the morning of the day the election was supposed to take place the Guurti finally was able to broker a deal.  The Guurti extended the President’s term indefinitely, but required him to hold the elections in good faith as soon as feasible.  The pro-government supporters agreed to drop their insistence on removing the Speaker of the House, while the anti-government supporters agreed to drop their impeachment motion against the President.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During the first week of October, the seven Commissioners from the National Election Commission (NEC) resigned under domestic and international pressure.  The second and third weeks of October saw seven new Commissioners nominated by the various stakeholders in the process.  Although there was a significant amount of political discourse on the selection of the new NEC, the prior animosity between the various political factions was largely absent from the process.  On October 21, the President forwarded the list of the new Commissioners to the House of Representatives.  On October 24, the House approved the list.  They were sworn in the following week.  The turnover from the old Commissioners to the new Commissioners took place during the first weeks of November.  The new NEC began their work and meetings during November.  They spent a significant portion of the month in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia meeting with donors and participating in training seminars.  NEC returned to Hargeisa from their meetings abroad during the latter part of December.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The NEC came under pressure throughout the early part of 2010 to fix a date for the elections.  The new NEC shied away from media attention and focused itself in the practicalities of conducting elections.  The legal mandate of the 2007 Voter Registration Act placed the NEC in difficult position, as it was required to use the database, but the database it inherited from the previous NEC was largely unusable.  Subsequently, Interpeace sent technicians to try to recover the data that is either lost or in the wrong form.  This effort was largely successful, and the NEC was able to publish the voter list for the political parties in late March without incident.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The NEC spent most of February planning polling station locations and resolving the final technical issues with the voter registration database.  Around the 25th of February information was leaked to the press that the NEC would not be ready to hold the presidential election until the end of the year and that they would distribute new voter registration cards in each region to voters who had not registered twice.  The news was not met with much tension in Hargeisa.  However, later in the quarter different information circulated that the election would take place in June or July of 2010.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Guurti experienced more turmoil during the early part of 2010.  The Chairman of the House left Somaliland in December and went to the United Kingdom for routine medical treatment.  While the Chairman was away, motions were brought before the House to change the by-laws to reduce the current super-majority required to oust a sitting chairman to a simple majority.  Many members of the House felt that this was a first step toward deposing the current Chairman, and members quickly began taking sides on the issue.  When the Chairman returned on January 12, 2010, he immediately began working to resolve the conflict.  In late January, the Deputy Chairman, who was widely seen as the heir apparent to the Chairman’s post if he was ousted, announced his resignation.  This again caused polarization in the House, with numerous back and forth accusations and rebuttals from both camps[[LB4]][2] [[CSK5]][3] .  After more political mediation, the Deputy Chairman retracted his resignation and was reinstated by the plenary chamber of the House.  Both camps agreed to keep the bylaws as they were.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[2]: /Users/Casey/Documents/CSK, ESQ/PILPG/Somaliland/PILPG Somaliland Final Report CK Draft 06.14.10.doc#_msocom_4
[3]: /Users/Casey/Documents/CSK, ESQ/PILPG/Somaliland/PILPG Somaliland Final Report CK Draft 06.14.10.doc#_msocom_5&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Early in April, 2010 the Chairman of the Ghanaian National Election Commission visited and assisted the Somaliland National Election Commission (NEC) in the various preparations necessary for the election.  On April 29 the NEC held a press conference where they confirmed that they would be ready to hold the election in June, 2010.  NEC has prepared all of the polling stations, ordered and accepted the delivery of the ballot boxes, and has delivered the approved and finalized voter registration cards to the electorate.  In May, 2010 the NEC announced that the Presidential elections would take place on June 26, 2010.  The campaigns for the elections began without significant tension on June 5, 2010 and have continued without any significant disruption up to the time of this report.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>