<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>virtual automatic contracts on underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/virtual-automatic-contracts/</link><description>Recent content in virtual automatic contracts on underWater desert Blogging</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Casey Kuhlman</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/virtual-automatic-contracts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What the Esteemed (and Very Smart) Law Professors Missed at the HLS Ethereum Talk</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-04-16-etherum-visits-harvard/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-04-16-etherum-visits-harvard/</guid><description>![Ethereum Logo]({{ site.url }}{{ site.root }}{{ site.images_dir }}/{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; }}/ethereum.png)
Introduction Yesterday a very interesting event happened. And I had the pleasure to listen in. Primavera De Filippi talked Ethereum at a Berkman luncheon.
For those who do not know Berkman is a center at Harvard University. For those who do not know Harvard, welcome to earth. Berkman is officially the Berkman Center for Internet and Society. It is a joint research center housed in Harvard's Law School with the following mission:</description></item><item><title>Iterating over the Traditional - Legal Approaches to Smart Contract Development</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-04-09-notes-from-my-ethereum-talk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-04-09-notes-from-my-ethereum-talk/</guid><description>Audio Talk is Here Introduction ![slide 1]({{ site.url }}{{ site.root }}{{ site.images_dir }}/{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; }}/ethereum-talk-slides-1.png)
Who am I? My name is Casey Kuhlman and I'm an American lawyer. Currently, I'm running a small law firm with our headquarters in Somalia. In particular, we work mainly in the north of Somalia which is a self-declared independent state of Somaliland. I've been in Somaliland for coming up on six years now and my practice has a wide focus on law building, corporate governance work, compliance work, and corporate transactions.</description></item><item><title>A Proposal for @ethereumproject Provisions, Contracts, and Packages</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-03-06-introducing-ethereum-package-manager/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-03-06-introducing-ethereum-package-manager/</guid><description>Lately on my &amp;ldquo;regular&amp;rdquo; blog I have been doing a decent amount of writing about virtual automatic contracts. It has been fun to think through the possibilities of virtual automatic contracts and how those could really work in developing countries.
Background and Introduction Earlier this week I had the distinct pleasure of attending the Ethereum meetup in Amsterdam to learn more about how virtual automatic contracts (or as they call them smart contracts) work within the Ethereum blockchain.</description></item></channel></rss>