<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/</link><description>A Site About Resilience and Authoritarianism</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</managingEditor><webMaster>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</webMaster><copyright>All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/somaliland/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>On the Sovereignty of CryptoCurrencies -- What Bitcoin can Learn from Somaliland</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-08-14-bitcoin-somaliland/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-08-14-bitcoin-somaliland/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently a video was made: &amp;ldquo;The Declaration of Bitcoin's Independence&amp;rdquo;. Here's the video.&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XQqZ9b0S0BY" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>For those of you not involved with the, all in all, rather small cryptocurrency community the people in that video are some of the bigger names within the community. The village elders if you will. Not sure the village actually chose them, but elders tend to be self appointed anyway &amp;ndash; at least at first.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My friend and business partner, Preston, provided his response in &lt;a href="http://prestonbyrne.com/2014/08/14/tory-2/">this fine article&lt;/a>. I take an analogous, but distinct, view from Preston's.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="anarchists-go-experience-anarchy-or-shut-up">Anarchists: Go Experience Anarchy, Or Shut Up&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>One of the overarching points of the video is that Bitcoin is somehow sovereign, which I assume means a system unto itself. And I'm not simply picking out one word from many and obsessing about it. That is the entire point of a &amp;ldquo;Declaration of Independence&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; for a group to declare that it is no longer beholden to a prior sovereign and is now beholden to a different sovereign.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But who is the sovereign in which these individuals of common purpose are beholden to? Who knows.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I'm a relative outsider to this whole cryptocurrency thing. Sure, I'm trying to &lt;a href="https://erisindustries.com">build a business&lt;/a> which will utilize some of the technology underpinning cryptocurrencies. However, I am by no means a believer that a few cryptographic hashes and a fancy database somehow changes any of the real human dynamics which scientists, artists, philosophers, and the like have been pondering for a couple millennia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As an outsider, it is (anthropologically) interesting to watch a bunch of (predominantly) white (predominantly) Americans (and Canadians) purport to claim that an interesting payment protocol will solve world peace, governmental overreach, and all the other ills of modernity. The idea that somehow because there are cryptographic hashes and p2p communications protocol that those will suddenly shift the paradigm of modernity and that we can reach a point where governments are unnecessary is&amp;hellip; I'm not sure what it is actually.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I've lived in anarchy. I know what it looks like when governance systems collapse. I have felt how easy elite capture becomes in such situations. I have tasted hyper inflation. I challenge anyone who identifies as an anarchist to actually go to Somalia &amp;ndash; or another area where governance systems have collapsed for a significant amount of time. Spend some time there. Talk to people about their lives. Understand what the hell you're talking about.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Whatever the participants&amp;rsquo; individual motives are I cannot speak to, I suspect that many would identify more with libertarian thinking than pure anarchical thinking. For those that do have anarchical tendencies, please see above. For those that have libertarian thinking, please see below.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="lesson-1-declaring-independence-is-an-emotional-exercise-building-a-system-is-a-rational-exercise">Lesson 1: Declaring Independence is an Emotional Exercise; Building a System is a Rational Exercise&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In 1991 the elites of the Somalilanders &amp;ldquo;freedom&amp;rdquo; movement (it wasn't about freedom really, it was about capturing the state in the name of the Somalilanders) were forced by a bunch of emotional people to declare their independence from Somalia. Many at the time, and many today, question whether this heated, emotional, reaction was the correct decision. Nonetheless, it happened.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As most Democracy and Governance, Conflict Studies, and Crisis Situation scholars and practitioners understand declaring independence is the easy bit. Pretty words on paper (or in a video) don't mean anything in reality. They are simply those &amp;ndash; pretty words. They can inspire, sure, but beyond that they mean little.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the case of Somaliland it took about 13 years after the Declaration of Independence to have a really functional Constitution and the state building is still going on &amp;ndash; and likely will be for another two generations. It took a massively important leader with a real commitment to building a functional system who fought tooth and nail to build a constitution which was both responsive to constituent concerns while also setting the framework for a functional system. It took scholars, and discussion, and compromise, and &lt;em>work&lt;/em> to get there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The question I have for those who participated in this video is this: are you actually interested in doing the work necessary to craft a system? Only time will tell.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="lesson-2-if-you-want-to-sit-at-the-adults-table-act-like-adults">Lesson 2: If You Want to Sit At The Adults&amp;rsquo; Table Act Like Adults&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>During my time in Somaliland I said the above more times than I could count. Mostly in response to idiotic stuff whatever Minister or other person of purported power who was sitting in some vaunted chair did. It would drive me crazy that Somalilanders in positions of power would drone on about how they were a &amp;ldquo;real state&amp;rdquo; but how they continued to fail to perform the most basic of governance functions. You can't have it both ways I would tell my friends. Either you need to do the work, make the sacrifices, and be your own state, or else you just need to shut up. More times than I currently care to count, I would watch the Somaliland government act as a rebel organization acts and then go on BBC Somali asking why the world wasn't treating them like a state. Most of the time the reason the &amp;ldquo;world&amp;rdquo; wasn't treating them like a state was because they weren't acting as a state acts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I view the cryptocommunity through a similar lens. It talks &amp;ndash; &lt;strong>at nauseum&lt;/strong> &amp;ndash; about how it &lt;em>deserves&lt;/em> to be taken seriously. Really? Why? What has it done to &lt;em>deserve&lt;/em> being taken seriously? Certainly there is some very interesting technology that has been built. And that technology should be taken seriously. As technology.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But Bitcoiners, and the cryptocommunity more generally, should not somehow be free from the normal rules which apply. If those inside the cryptocommunity want cryptocurrencies to be treated &lt;em>as&lt;/em> currency, then they must abide by the &lt;em>normal&lt;/em> rules which attend to handling money.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These rules &lt;em>are&lt;/em> onerous, precisely because businesses which deal with folks&amp;rsquo; money are, well, dealing with folks&amp;rsquo; money. I do not understand why cryptocurrencies businesses should somehow get a bye as to providing proper safeguards, as has been agreed in the relevant states are necessary.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="lesson-3-real-systems-empower-professionals-and-root-out-scammers">Lesson 3: Real Systems Empower Professionals and Root Out Scammers&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When I was in Hargeisa some of the more interesting people I hung out with were folks who were trying to set up a governmental quality assurance system. There were a lot of problems that needed to be tackled, but foremost on the minds of these scientists (some of who had been trained locally some of whom had been trained abroad) was the difficulty of ensuring that medicines were proper. There was (and likely still is) a huge problem of knock-off drugs, mislabeled drugs, and the like. These scientists were trying to tackle this. Because it was putting the health of community members in jeopardy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I enjoyed my time with these scientists and doers precisely because they saw a collective problem and were trying to do something about it &amp;ndash; despite the odds. The odds being that big importers who supported big actors within the government make more money off fake drugs than real ones. The odds being that quality assurance of medicines is not one of aid's current hot topics (and therefore there was no aid money to support their activities). The odds being that of all the problems in Hargeisa this was not the one that was on the tip of folks&amp;rsquo; minds &amp;ndash; except for when those folks had sick kids. Despite those odds, these guys were trying to do something to protect folks. And that was awesome from my perspective. They are a &lt;strong>long&lt;/strong> way from solving this issue, but they are trying.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What is the cryptocommunity doing about rooting out scammers? There are, indeed, some efforts. And I hope that they continue, because the cryptocommunity has a huge scammers problem that needs to be addressed in a fundamental way. It isn't likely to happen with a technological solution; it is much more likely to happen via legal or social mechanisms. But so far we've only seen a few of these take place.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Time will tell how this all plays out. Indeed, most of this is about the community more generally than a response to the specifics of that video. I think there is some very interesting technology which bitcoin has brought to people's attention. It would be a shame if that technology was overshadowed by people projecting their issues and complaints with bigger systemic issues on it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Micro-States; Pirates; Terrorists; The London Conference: What a Fascinating Time for Watchers of Somalis</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-01-30-micro-states-pirates-terrorists-the-london-conference-what-a-fascinating-time-for-watchers-of-somalis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-01-30-micro-states-pirates-terrorists-the-london-conference-what-a-fascinating-time-for-watchers-of-somalis/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/burningmax/2987516225/">&lt;img src="http://blog.caseykuhlman.com/assets/images/2012/2987516225_11e2cef572.jpg" alt="somali-days by burningmax @ flickr" tit="somali-days by burningmax @ flickr" />&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For almost four years now I’ve been a careful observer of Somali politicians. For three of those years I was paid to try to be their lawyer. To provide them expert international legal assistance tied to a deep network full of some of the finest international practitioners and thinkers in the world. But they rarely, if ever, wanted that help. So largely I invented work, I went into meetings and had a product to sell. &lt;em>I can’t buy you new computers, but I how about I help you write that legal framework that Parliament has required you to do&lt;/em>?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve spent a lot of time with Somali politicians, and I also spend a lot of time with other people who spend a lot of their time with Somali politicians. This is an expat’s life when you live in a pretty small town. I reference Hargeisa, a town of, oh, 500,00 to 1M people depending on who’s estimating as a small town.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And that it truly is. This is one of the most amazing things when you really get to know an African town. To learn how inter-connected things are is fascinating. This is what makes me do something foolish like invest everything I have into starting a law firm in a country which has very little (if any) law. Judges routinely dismiss cases with little to no justification. Parliamentarians make no estimates, and rarely even discuss, what the effects of this law will be in the next month, much less the next year – so legislation (a lot of it quite decent) is routinely ignored.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yet things work. I don’t believe in libertarianism – much to my father’s chagrin – it is incredibly unjust and inefficient. But I can say the Somalis are teaching me how to respect it, and how to work within its boundaries. I know a little but more importantly I truly care deeply about this place. I have spent more time in this place than I had in any one place since I was in college. I have joined, in many ways, the ranks of the diaspora (only the opposite way that that term is used).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a long time, when I first arrived, it seemed like no one really got what the hell was happening down here. See Nairobi is a long way away. And after the 2008 Hargeisa bombings, when pretty much all of the expats left the connections between Hargeisa and Nairobi were even more tenuous. So a disconnect really felt like it developed. Luckily, over the course of the previous year it has &lt;em>felt&lt;/em> like “Nairobi” is starting to get it. I don’t agree with everything I’m hearing coming out of the high level cluster meetings and typical other rumor mill stuff, but I must say that I agree with a lot of it (see, e.g., &lt;a href="http://blogs.fco.gov.uk/mattbaugh/2012/01/1a7/london-conference-on-somalia-building-momentum/" title="London Conference, Building Momentum">this initiative&lt;/a> by the UK’s government).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I did not think that a harder military strategy off the coast would reduce piracy. I really felt that a tribunal in Somaliland along with a huge police building effort in Puntland was the best possible shot at fixing things (basically pirate DDR is what needs to happen); I still feel this needs to happen, but the military situation seems to be putting a recent damper on the number of attacks. So they may be right, they may be wrong, but at least they aren’t &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/zA7LWR" title="Somali Pirates Seize 80% Fewer Ships as Early Strikes Work‎">dead wrong&lt;/a>. Not the way they were dead wrong in the early nighties when everyone that knew anything about Somalia would tell you how clearly wrong some of the actions were.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nairobi (by which I mean the big money and big – even if distant – powers), seems to be starting to understand two things: there has to be some element of external assistance to stabilize the situation, BUT the Somalis want to have assurances that this isn’t an invasion or their territorial fires start overheating. To do that largely means staying the hell out of the politics BUT also helping to create the conditions of stability long enough for the Somalis to figure out how they will be represented and what the terms are – which can often take months or years – even where you have a majority clan conferences these things take lots of time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most Somali analysts are quick to point out that the reason the South cannot seem to fix itself is that the Italians castrated the clan leader system. The problem has been for a long time that no one had the moral authority – among the Southern clans – to stand up to the gangsters that kept hijacking clan resources, state resources, international resources. They just continued to gobble them up like locusts and when they reached an end to their resources they just started gobbling each other. From the early warlord phase into the ICU takeover this is what continued happening.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But a couple of other things were happening also beneath the surface of that. For twenty years there seems to have been an identity crisis within much of the Somali community. This identity, just like lots of things in our lives, runs to the safest place it can find when it is threatened. For most Somalis that is somewhere around one or two or three or four or five clans below the major clan level. It varies by the individual and their experience where this safe place is. One thing I can say for sure, that for most people I’ve met in four years Northerners, Southerners, Easterners and Westerners, for the vast vast percentage of these people that place is no where even close to the pan-Somali level. This is and will for a long time remain the invalidity in the argument that the pan-Somali movement was a viable option without a dictator.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even after twenty years Somaliland politicians bicker nearly continuously; lack of trust within Somaliland is rife. The same can be said, only the distrust rises as you go clockwise around the circle.This deep distrust is deep seated in Somali lore going back to way before the mad mullah. By the time you get to Isaaq’s grandsons, they were already fighting with each other. I don’t like all my cousins, but I certainly know I’m not ready to fight with them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Luckily the Somalilanders – at the end and often despite this distrust – they make it work. Things haven’t fallen apart here and actually are going pretty well. It has taken a long time to solidify the post-conflict gains and to begin the development phase of their state building, but it is going. And, perhaps more importantly, it is going at a Somali pace. Somaliland really did have to retract after it separated from the South into basically a federated microstate solution. Sure there was a central government created at the Burco conference. But the amount of power and influence of that government was marginal. One cannot compare the power that Silanyo has with the power that Tuur had. The central government was present, but it has taken almost two decades of steady work before anyone gives it any mind about being anything other than a minor inconvenience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is another incredibly fascinating thing about being here now, this is the point where the Somaliland Government is really figuring itself and really trying to exert some will.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This gets us to the microstate solution. In my view, it should be endorsed as it is probably the best viable option currently. Some of the donors seem to be realizing that – as reflected in much of the language coming from the UK as well as the US’s two-track policy shift. In my opinion, the donors need to throttle back the incentives for state capture. When the mandate for the TFG ends UNDP needs to have the political courage to stop paying Parliamentarian salaries, and other than emergency aid the rest of the money flowing into the South needs to end. Then the donors need to let the Somalis work from their grassroots (microstate) levels up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Equal with this the Somalis have to take ownership. They really have to stop blaming &lt;em>all&lt;/em> of their problems on the international community and take ownership for their own mistakes. I can fully accept many Somalis gripes about the prior actions of external actors. And I fully understand their paranoia about external interventions in their problems. But equally they have to trust a bit more. And they have to take a lot more ownership. This is, at its most elemental, a Somali problem, and they have to be the ones to figure the solutions out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am cautiously optimistic about London Conference. A lot of the right things appear to being said. We will see what will happen but if the donors really wanted to get to the roots of the problems, they need to just shut up and they need to hold their next conference in a place which is neutral &lt;em>enough&lt;/em> to get all of the important-to-Somalis people under a great big, giant ass tree and then they need to not show up and to not pay. And then let them stay there until they figure it out. It will take a hell of a long time, but it will get done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It has taken the fine work of a lot of Somalis and Westerners for the awareness to be sufficiently raised as to why we’re here and what the hell can we do about it. I must say for the first time in a while I’m cautiously optimistic about all of the Somali region.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more perspective on the London Conference here are a few articles I thought highly incisive, particularly from the Somaliland view point: &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/zh7Zcm" title="Somaliland and the London Conference on Somalia">Article 1&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/z1OXHx" title="Six Elements for Success of Somali Conference in UK">Article 2&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On The Somali Famine: A Thought Collage</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-07-30-somali-famine-collage/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-07-30-somali-famine-collage/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/oxfameastafrica/5974209957/in/photostream/" title="Original via Oxffam East Africa @ Flickr">&lt;img src="http://www.flickr.com/photos/oxfameastafrica/5974209957/in/photostream/" alt="New arrivals wait to get processed original via Oxfam East Africa @ Flickr" title="Original via Oxffam East Africa @ Flickr">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>The original photo is &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/oxfameastafrica/5974209957/in/photostream/" title="Original via Oxffam East Africa @ Flickr">here&lt;/a>, my alteration is &lt;a href="http://blog.caseykuhlman.com/wp-content/blogs.dir/4/files/2011/07/5974209957_75f686bf8b_o-e1312029321201.jpg" title="My alteration">here&lt;/a>. If I had to title the alteration, I would call it An Homage to Motherhood&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This post is a bit random in nature, but it is a compilation of some sources and commentary and thought. So think of it as more of a collage than a strict narrative. Much of this was originally posted on &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/nunfsy" title="Original Post">Google &lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="thought-1-early-warning-systems-worked">Thought 1: Early Warning Systems Worked&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We’ve known this was coming for well over six months. According to &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/r1eFZk">here&lt;/a>, it has been well known since November 2010 which seems about right to me. Those that are paid to do handle these things were trying their best (more on that in a minute) to address the situation but were unable to deliver the food aid at that time. There’s little to suggest that anything has changed in the interim and delivery of the aid will somehow be magically easier.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Up here in Somaliland we were taking bucket showers as early as March of this year. Although it does take a while to get to the point where there is a certified famine (due to a strict criteria to certify a disaster/drought as a famine), all of the early warning systems worked. The rains ended up coming for Somaliland, but they did not come (until a couple of weeks ago, and way too late for the livestock and vegetables) for the South. Yet in Somaliland the Government took a lot of steps to ease the suffering of the pastoralists and farmers in their territory.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Amaryta Sen is famous for saying that all famines are avoidable failures of governments. Somaliland’s government passed that test. Ministers were out escorting water tankers into the country-side, TV shows on water conservation were aired on national television (not that Somalis need these lessons, but anyway), and mostly it was a local re-distribution effort rather than an international aid effort.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is an impossible hypothetical what would have happened if the rains had not come to Somaliland. Yet, I suspect that the efforts would have been decently well-thought out and executed as a community. All of it would have been led by Somalis with the international community playing a supporting role, as it should be.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="thought-2-extent-of-suffering">Thought 2: Extent of Suffering&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The famine is confined to two regions of very Southern Somalia which are sparsely populated to begin with. Although millions are at risk, it isn’t millions that are actually suffering. This isn’t meant to minimize the suffering of those that are suffering, it is simply to bring some perspective. I’m not cynical, how can you be when you look at pictures like &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/qYLsnF" title="mourning at the grave of a 3 y/o">this&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Coincidentally, these are the same areas where al-Shabaab has a very strong control over the population. One picture that has certainly caught my eye is of a Shabaab soldier with rows and rows of squatting women behind him looking distraught. The photographer obviously focused on the warrior, but the women in the background are the stars of the shot for me. It is a soberingly iconic reminder of what is really going on. See the picture &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/q5CAfm" title="shabaab soldier and women">here&lt;/a>, and look close.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shabaab has been playing both sides of this issue. First they banned nearly every aid agency from working in their zones. This was a long time ago, and ironically enough when I’ve been in Nairobi talking to people who work in the South they were telling me that the (non-Somali) agencies which were allowed to continue working were faith-based organizations like &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/nhch7c">World Vision&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/r07JSt">ADRA&lt;/a>. Mostly these organizations were headed by one or at most two Kenyans and largely they were left alone to do their work, except for one young aid worker I heard about who was killed by Shabaab for proselytizing. We may feel bad for the man’s family, but it was a bit of &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/n2KAxP">Darwinism&lt;/a> at work if you ask me.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="thought-3-aid-agencydysfunctionalism--restrictions">Thought 3: Aid Agency Dysfunctionalism &amp;amp; Restrictions&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>WFP-Somalia is, for those of us that have been in/worked on Somalia for more than 30 seconds, about the &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/oomANF">most&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/n58Y82">dysfunctional&lt;/a>&lt;a href="http://wsl.so/oqX8Y5"> organization&lt;/a>. I have serious doubts that the increases in aid will end up as food in bellies – except for (maybe) those that are working in Daadab where it is a bit more straight-forward to deliver and where there is some semblance of oversight. Also there are fundamental structural problems with the way aid agencies (including NGOs and UN organs) are built and work. See &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/p7M6aZ">here&lt;/a> for a great discussion of this (but rather technical if you’re not into the biz of aid/development). The summary:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In summary, a major reason why aid agency presence has not translated into reduced vulnerability to, for example, famine, is due to aid agencies not being geared to do just that:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Aid agencies do not build their programs around context, but are influenced by donor interest, assumptions, internal capacity and their own models of approach.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Aid agencies don’t have resources that can be quickly tasked from one mode of operation (development) to another (emergency response).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Aid agencies’ internal measuring systems do not hold them accountable to how well they reduce the risk of a disaster happening, only on how well they acheive project deliverables.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>And aid agencies own internal systems and staffing do not allow a seamless transition from a long-term development presence to an emergency response.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Yes, the international community has made many mistakes. But I do not believe that it is the role of the international community to lead at times like this. I strongly believe that the role of the international community is to support local efforts with materiale, technical assistance, logistics expertise, and funding. I am disheartened by the increasing frequency of calls for an intervention on the level of the 92/93 intervention which burst the New World Order bubble and ushered in a decade of UN futility as the world’s largest NGO body of political discourse.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even though it is true that the international community, US, UK, Italy, etc. are definitely not without fault, I’m terribly tired of the narrative which places the entirety of the blame on these external parties. An example is here, where there is an entire, well written &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/quvuzF">post&lt;/a> by an educated Somali without the smallest hint of acceptance for any responsibility by the Somali community for what is happening (other than a few “criminals”). Here’s the crux of his argument.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If we had had foresight and acted upon it; if the Marines had disarmed the warlords; if the U.N. Security Council had issued arrest warrants for the warlords early on, stopping them from prolonging the failure of the state; if the Security Council had dealt with the warlords — who had denied starving millions access to food — speedily and decisively, in the same way it dealt with the genocidal regimes in Serbia, Rwanda, Sierra Leone and Sudan, then al-Qaeda would not have established a secure base from which to plan terrorist attacks. Our country would not have been hamstrung by the enormity of our problem, nor would it have become the world’s worst humanitarian disaster.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>A friend on G asked me a good question:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I would be interested if anybody knows some more details on the reason Al-Shabab has refused to let the aid organisations in. I mean, no matter what they publicly say, I am sure they feel the pressure of famine too. So why is it not possible to find some kind of middle ground? Are the NGOs reluctant to give up control over food deliveries? If yes, is that justified? &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/p3m5eU" title="Peter Dorrie on Google Plus">~Peter Dorrie&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>My answer was that that’s part of it. Another big part of it is donor restrictions on supporting terrorist organizations. It is difficult to say with any certainty what Shabaab’s position is as they are terribly decentralized and non-uniform. Their position isn’t terribly rational but it is basically isolationist (like N.Korea, Taliban, Myanmar, etc.). They came to power on an anti-invaders platform and largely have kept to that meme throughout. On top of their irrationalities on banning bras, samosas, music, and anything that is fun, the group is funadamentally more nationalistic than it is Islamist (which is why I have always questioned the depth of their linkages with an Arab-led organization like Al-Qaeda).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are other things in play. According to &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/rpMQUy">this&lt;/a> article which examines this in a bit more detail.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The first point I would make is that al Shabab is minimizing the crisis because, as many observers and experts are saying, the movement itself likely made the famine worse. Famines often (always?) result not only from failed rains or population growth, but also government policies, especially denial and inaction. . . . Every indication points to the conclusion that al Shabab not only fit into this regional trend [of refusing to recognize or limiting acknowledgement of the extent of a drought/famine because it highlights the ruling organization's shortcomings or racism], but was – because of its limited resources, its preoccupation with the civil war, and its ideology – a particularly bad offender.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My second thought is that when looking at al Shabab’s hostility to outsiders, it is worthwhile to try to understand the movement’s thinking from the inside. . . . The movement is made up mostly of young men (its name, after all, is Arabic for “the youth”), many of whom were children, or were not even born yet, when the Somali state collapsed in 1991. They have only known war and instability. They have seen weak would-be central governments come and go, they have seen clan rivalry tear at the social and political fabric of the country, and they have seen a parade of external actors, some of whom, like Ethiopia when it occupied Somalia from late 2006 to early 2009, carried out massive violence. Growing up in that environment would brutalize many people and make them deeply suspicious of outsiders.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But the famine strikes directly at the relationship between al Shabab and its constituents. The movement is taking a huge risk if it tries to solve this problem through violence and denial. Al Shabab controls territory, and so it must have some local support – support that is likely based in large part on al Shabab’s ability to offer some security and stability after years of fighting. Allowing the famine to go unchecked could destroy whatever local legitimacy al Shabab possesses, potentially resulting in infighting, fragmentation, rebellions, or desertions. From this perspective, it is not difficult to see why al Shabab originally decided to re-admit external aid agencies. And yet it now seems that paranoia and suspicion of outsiders are winning out in the leadership’s thinking.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>For an aid worker’s perception of this see &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/r9qxK6">this&lt;/a> great article by &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/pUP9XF">@morealtitude&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>An invitation from al Shabbab central command may sound like a good enough reason to think aid workers would be safe re-entering south-central, but in fact it isn’t. Like many insurgency groups, al Shabbab is as much a network of affiliated warlords as it is a hierarchical paramilitary organization. Fighters on the ground- the ones with guns, grenades and IEDs- will align themselves first with their local commander, and only after that with al Shabbab central. Then there’s the assumption that the message is even getting down to those field grunts and their captains. Or the notion that some 16-year-old with an AKM, who’s never been to school but has spent the last ten years being told that westerners are pillaging his country and deserve to die, will pay any attention to some recent order from someone he’s never heard, when he sees an NGO Land Cruiser drive past.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="thought-4-the-role-of-somalis">Thought 4: The Role of Somalis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Through all that I’ve read, I am most heartened by the diaspora involvement. Pull up &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/oIgTvU">#feedsomalia&lt;/a> and you’ll see lots of activity. New, caring diaspora members are increasing their networks and ability to influence. This is a long-term positive.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While the immediate causes of the crisis have been the drought and insecurity in the south, there is something more fundamental at play here. &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/rdLcUg">This&lt;/a> article digs a bit beyond the boilerplate rhetoric.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Drought is not a new environmental condition for much of Africa but a recurring one. The semi-arid Horn of Africa and the entire Sahelian region — running just south of the Sahara Desert across the continent — have long experienced erratic rainfall. While climate change may be exacerbating rainfall variability, traditional livelihoods in the region are adaptable to deal with situations when rainfall is not dependable. . . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Traditionally, herders ranged widely across the landscape in search of better pasture, focusing on areas as meteorological conditions dictated. The approach worked because, unlike fenced-in pastures in North America, it was incredibly flexible and adapted to variable rainfall. As farming has expanded, including in some instances to large-scale commercial farms, the routes of herders have become more concentrated and more vulnerable to drought. [Note, the conflict between the pastoralists and agriculturalists is one of the many, many causes of insecurity in the south.] . . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just as death from exposure is not an inherent result of a cold winter, famine is not a natural consequence of drought. Simply put, the structure of human society often determines who is affected and to what degree.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Fundamentally, the core of the problem is a breakdown of the social redistribution networks which are a basis of Somali culture (see Somaliland’s reaction described above). The diaspora &lt;em>should&lt;/em> be taking the lead, as they are much closer to the realities of the situation than the US Representative for Somalia (we don’t have an ambassador any longer) is to the situation. The more Somali community leaders take charge, accept the situation, and work towards a solution – the faster the entire situation (meaning more than the famine which is temporary) will stabilize and improve.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more on the diaspora’s efforts, see &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/n5pN4r">here&lt;/a> (among other &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/oIgTvU">places&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="thought-6-starvation-porn">Thought 6: Starvation Porn&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://wsl.so/prWxac">Poverty/Starvation Porn&lt;/a> is very real and am happy that it is being talked about outside of the echo chamber of the “aid bloggers/tweeters” (for lack of a better label). There have been some great &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/om4GAY">articles&lt;/a> which have challenged the ethics of this type of coverage, which have come out of the situation. Here’s his punch-line:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Because it’s a cycle. African governments know that drought is coming and they don’t prepare. Foreign charities working there talk about long-term plans to help people become self-sufficient but they’ve been failing to achieve them for 20 years. It’s as much about politics and war and poor economic policies as it is about no rain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m no expert but I know that much. I also know it’s wrong that every few years we’re faced with an “emergency” that could have been prevented, that aid groups must frantically try to raise money to respond to, that journalists need to find emaciated babies at death’s door and film and photograph and write about them before the world gives a damn.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>While there &lt;em>is some&lt;/em> value in showing the extent of suffering, it definitely skews the situation. While that is great marketing for aid organizations, as most of us who have worked in the developing world intuitively understand increases in aid flows do not necessarily end up as food in bellies or kids’ butts on school benches. As Haiti and Japan have shown there is an absorptive capacity formula to disaster relief whereby increases in aid can end up resulting in more rotten food or spoiled medicines rather than where it was intended. As &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/njzSQL">this&lt;/a> post from a former World Vision worker puts it, “Poverty is not an image, or a statistic; poverty has a face, a name and a story.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, most aid workers are quick to admit that there is a dualism to poverty porn as am sure they are quite happy with what they get in their bank account at the end of the month (and largely it is money that is well deserved as this is very hard work). But it is not easy to see what you’re working on cheapened by skewed coverage. Some of the ads for help, in particular the one on the Tumblr dashboard (can’t upload screenshot for some reason but at least the kids in the photo are smiling).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An aid worker / blogger who I have lots of respect for has put it this way in &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/p7M6aZ">this article&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Articles are starting to look like a fill-the-blanks template that the reporters are all sharing around: Quote some stats about the famine; talk about the complicating factor of al Shabbab making life difficult in Somalia; drop in some pithy quotes about the fact that short-term aid is repetitive and doesn’t solve the underlying problems (always with a nod to the fact that, well, of course it saves lives now); then end on the dark yet hopeful twist that while aid agencies clearly don’t have it right, clearly what’s needed is ‘long-term solutions’. Yeah, cool, thanks. . . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But what I’m really ratty about is not that what the media are saying is wrong &lt;em>per se&lt;/em>. My problem is, they’re making noise but missing the point. . . . [Point 1] By rabbiting on about long-term solutions (I’m sorry, what solutions did you suggest, exactly?), they make it sound like nobody’s ever come up with that idea before. . . . Point two is, these solutions aren’t simple in the real-world.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="thought-7-what-can-be-done--what-can-you-do">Thought 7: What Can Be Done / What Can You Do&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Military intervention is about the worst solution human minds could conjure. History should be a lesson here. Somalis are phenomenal at skewing international interventions intended to help as invasions of their sovereignty. And in general Somalis are pretty duplicitous as to outsiders.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Second worst idea to me is trying to deliver via trucks and ground workers within the Shabaab zones. I fundamentally disagree that the US Gov should “work with Shabaab” as &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/r1eFZk">this&lt;/a> article by Richard Dowden of the Royal African Society argues. This is a golden opportunity for the Somalis to see the results of their acquiescence to Shabaab’s presence. The easiest thing one can learn from Somali history is that when they’re sick of you they’ll find a way to overthrow you. When the communities within the Shabaab zones get sick of them they will kick them out of those communities and I know if I was living in these communities I would certainly be pretty circumspect about Shabaab. Of course no one wants to stay “starve them out” as that is cruel and inhumane treatment, but delivery within Shabaab’s areas I am 64.8% sure will end in a worse situation than never going in. As &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/pUP9XF">@morealtitude&lt;/a> put it &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/r9qxK6">here&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Letting aid workers in solves many problems for al Shabbab. It demonstrates to its own people that it’s taking steps to solve the problem. It helps slow the outflux of refugees. It brings in resources that bolster the population- which may be appropriated by fighters at times, or the effects may be indirect, such as more money in the economy that supports fighters’ families which in turn supports them. And, if aid agencies don’t do the right thing by al Shabbab, it gives them fresh ammunition in the polarizing of its people against the west.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Not increasing aid at all within Somalia is the best possible solution in my mind. The best option within Somalia is to stay out of the diaspora’s way with respect to their remittance flows into Somalia so people can purchase from local markets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was talking the other day with a few friends who work in this area. They told me that the real heart-break is that after people have trekked to the refugee camps in Kenya and Ethiopia they are finding that the food isn’t there. In these refugee camps there is a host government who is not impeding the delivery of aid and there is a relatively well-trekked cow-path for the logisticians to follow. Increasing the flows to these areas is a relatively straight-forward process and will ease one of the main problems while staying away from the quagmire.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next best options are to work through Somali NGOs and increase the flows that they are delivering, continue and maybe increase the &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/r7VE6P">air drops&lt;/a> (although these have to be terribly costly from a utilitarian point of view, and finally increase more traditional types of delivery within Mogadishu which the TFG / AMISOM troop relatively control.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to give here are some organizations (in the order I would give to them if I had disposable income and wasn’t already fully invested in Somalis):&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://wsl.so/qdaZLT">MSF&lt;/a> (Doctors without Borders who provide extensive medical care in the refugee camps)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://wsl.so/rgGS3S">Save the Children&lt;/a> (who have been working in the camps since the beginning)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://wsl.so/ojJQ0R">OXFAM-AUS&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/qCEFxc">OXFAM-UK&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/n7LClH">OXFAM-US&lt;/a> (Who also provides water and other services in the camps)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://wsl.so/pfIBe4">IRC&lt;/a> (Who provides a number of services within the refugee camps)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On Colonies, the AU &amp;amp; Borders: Somaliland&amp;#8217;s Recognition Journey</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-07-24-on-colonies-and-borders/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-07-24-on-colonies-and-borders/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This is the second installment in a series which is parsing through Somaliland’s journey towards recognition. The first post in the series, the introduction is available &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/entry/somalilands-recognition-journey" title="What Does it Mean to be Independent: Somaliland’s Recognition Journey">here&lt;/a>. One of the legal criteria for statehood is established borders. There is a serious and very well, although often, hidden question as to where Somaliland’s borders are. In this post I try to parse this a bit mainly from the perspective of international law, but also from the political perspective as well.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My friend, and fellow Somaliland voyeur, Rudie made some very interesting and important points in the comments to my previous point. One of which was:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The AU for instance has a declared policy that colonial borders will be the norm for independence. I think this was to prevent states splitting up in small tribal entities. That would create chaos due to the haphazard way in which colonial borders were drawn with no respect for tribal territories, dividing tribes between countries.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>But before I get to that point of policy, let me put on my lawyer hat for a second (which looks amazing like a &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/compleatang">cowboy hat&lt;/a> when you live in an anarchical state).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-international-criteria-for-statehood">The International Criteria for Statehood&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There are clearly defined baseline criteria for a state to be considered a state under international law. The first is a definable population; the second is a definable territory; the third is a government; and the fourth is the capacity to enter relations with other states.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Three of these criteria were first stated in the book, Allgemeine Staatslehre (General Theory of the State), published in 1900 by Georg Jellinek  which would put them in the classification of international law of “opinions of reknowned jurists” (which is the layman’s term, it has an official term from the Vienna Convention but I’m too lazy to look it up). This is a law classification and can easily be trumped or changed by higher classifications of international law which conflict with the opinions. However, as with much of international law (and indeed, with law in general) the opinions of jurists form and shape the “real” (known to lawyers as “positive”) law.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, what happened was later, in 1933, a regional treaty was passed which took into account the three criteria which were originally stated by Jellinek. was the &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/pjgrt0">Montevideo Convention on the Rights and Duties of States&lt;/a>, which was a treaty concluded by the Organization of American States. Since that time, these four baseline criteria have become so well understood and highly utilized that they have allegedly become fully integrated into international law and adopted by most of the world’s states. Article 1 of that convention state the four criteria listed above.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="montevideo-criteria-2definableterritory">Montevideo Criteria #2: Definable territory.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I must say, when I was doing some quick background research for this post that I learned something. The criteria for borders is less stringent than I originally thought. At least legally speaking. What the International Court of Justice (the World’s Supreme Court for matters such as these), requires is that there be a core territory (see North Sea Case, p. 32, para. 46). If there is a region of the territory which is disputed that is not a hindrance to statehood (see German Gas v. Poland, 5 A.D. 11 at 15). At least legally speaking.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I keep saying, “at least legally speaking” for a reason. Here’s the bottom line, just because a geographic area meets the criteria for statehood, does not mean that recognition is automatic. Why? Politics. Politics and law are very often intertwined (for they are two sides of the same coin). There is likely no major sector of law where politics are more intertwined than they are with international law. And even within international law, there is perhaps no norm where politics and law are &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/nBwhVz">more intertwined&lt;/a> than when it comes to recognition.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="politics-of-recognition">Politics of Recognition&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="politics-lens-1-the-african-unions-declaration-of-respect-for-colonial-borders">Politics Lens #1: The African Union’s Declaration of Respect for Colonial Borders&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In the 1960′s the US wasn’t the only territory worried about domino’s falling. The rapidly gaining independence African states were also worried about this. For those who may not fully understand African politics, let me simplify most African states are arbitrary maps on lines which were negotiated far from the ground itself. Largely there are two effect to this: (1) people who identify in very different ways have been haphazardly lumped together for no logical reason other than they traditionally resided near one another, and (2) people who identify in very similar ways have often been separated by international borders which they were given no part in making.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These are not small problems. They are still causing many, many problems throughout the continent. No matter the problems, the AU made a declaration long ago which basically froze the borders the way they were at the end of the colonial period. Why? Hard to say completely, but I suspect it was a devil you know v. devil you don’t know situation. At the end of the day there was a slippery slope argument that the politicians had to quelch. If one tribe, clan, or nation was given its independence within the colonial borders, the massive number of self-identifying entities within Africa would have demanded similar treatment and chaos would have ensued. Or so goes the theory.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a long time the AU has tightly held this norm. South Sudan challenges this norm directly as it is the first state within Africa which very clearly violates this.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="politics-lens-2-outsourcing-decisions-to-the-african-union">Politics Lens #2: Outsourcing Decisions to the African Union&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Quite a while ago now, both the US and the UK, publicly stated that they would follow the AU’s lead when it came to Somaliland. Before I came here I thought this was a good thing. It represented to me, at that time, that the US and the UK were forcing the AU to act like a grown up regional organization and would allow it to take the diplomatic lead on this issue. Publicly at least, I have seen no retraction as to this policy – as applied to the Somaliland situation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="facts-on-the-ground">Facts on the Ground&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="factual-lens-1-borders-from-the-somaliland-perspective">Factual Lens #1: Borders from the Somaliland Perspective&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Somalilanders feel very strongly that they meet the Montevideo Criteria #2 without violating the AU’s declaration of respect for colonial borders. Remember Somaliland was a sovereign nation for five days in 1960 (ironically enough, the first state to recognize them during that era was Israel). So Somalilanders say, we have defined borders. And they are the borders of the Somaliland Colony (or Protectorate, which Rudie challenged me on and I haven’t yet had a chance to dig up the answer from my history books here at the office). Case shut.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="factual-lens-2-borders-from-the-puntland-perspective">Factual Lens #2: Borders from the Puntland Perspective&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I don’t really know if there is a legal basis to Puntland’s argument, but Puntland does claim the far eastern regions of Somaliland as belonging to it. The border (as Somalilanders see it) does indeed run straight through the middle of a major Somali clan’s traditional homeland, so Puntland’s argument makes sense from a socio-cultural perspective, but I am not sure what their legal basis is. This divergence of opinion is the source of border scuffles which ebb and flow still.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This disputed region, according to the ICJ, does not hinder Somaliland’s statehood quest. At least legally. I suspect, it is a very real world hindrance. Why? One word. Eritrea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eritrea’s “break-away” from Ethiopia in the early 1990′s was not dissimilar to what Somaliland needs to accomplish. It was a unification that went awry and the break-away state wanted to reinstate its borders upon independence. The problem was that no one really knew where the border was and Ethiopia and Eritrea ended up fighting a semi-protracted war over the region which required the international community to come in, clean it up, and keep the peace.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, the borders are very likely a very real thing in the minds of diplomats sitting at desks in Nairobi and Addis writing their home governments analysis memos about Somaliland’s recognition.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Currently, the Somaliland army does occupy almost the entirety of the territory. It doesn’t really control it, but it’s there and it’s doing the best it can with what little resources it has. The problem isn’t really from the Somaliland-Puntland perspective as much as it is from the perspective of the local people. Many of whom put up Puntland flags in their houses and claim to “not know Somaliland.” Somaliland has literally bent over backwards, giving portions of the governance sector way out of per capita proportions to clans from the East. It has attempted, when it can, to sink money into the East. It is actively encouraging development and aid agencies not only to work in the “triangle” but to also work further east. At the end of the day, the area we’re talking about would make Deadwood look like modern Stockholm in comparison. It is L A W L E S S. See &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/oYVYij">here&lt;/a> for news from this week about what happens in this area.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although I have heard Somalilanders often claim that if recognition comes to Somaliland that the eastern clans would “come around” and support Somaliland. Behind close doors, in the majlises that I visit and sit with Somalilanders, most readily admit that it isn’t that simple. The eastern clans have traditionally been among the rules of Somalis overall. One of their major clans has a long a history of being politicians as the Isaaqs (Somaliland’s far-majority clan) have of being traders and business people. Another of their major clans was the clan of the former dictator, Siad Barre. So it isn’t quite a simple matter for them to subservient themselves to the Isaaq. Puntland (where the same clans which are in eastern Somaliland completely occupy), if it were to become a sovereign nation, would be in an awful position resource-wise. They have &lt;em>very&lt;/em> little resources to speak of. The areas they claim in Somaliland are said to be decent (if not great) grazing areas and are said to have a decent amount of minerals including perhaps hydrocarbon deposits. So it isn’t a simple matter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was talking with a friend on Thursday about this issue and basically we could agree that the area is likely more trouble than it is worth. So I posited why doesn’t the President just cede the area to Puntland and let them deal with the problems. After it left my mouth I realized instantly why Somaliland can never do that: they would then be rewriting the colonial borders.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is where the South Sudan precedent may be of assistance to Somaliland. If the AU either restricts or abolishes its declaration of respect for colonial borders, or at a minimum creates some exceptions, then Somaliland could potentially allow the area to go to Puntland and still argue that it meets the criteria for statehood. That is incredibly far-fetched I know, but it could be an option at least.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Up next: population&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What Does it Mean to be Independent: Somaliland&amp;#8217;s Recognition Journey</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-07-20-somalilands-recognition-journey/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-07-20-somalilands-recognition-journey/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://wsl.so/pxvnYK">&lt;img src="http://wsl.so/pxvnYK" alt="A Bright Spot in a Dreary Neighborhood">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After having been in Somaliland, one of the world’s most advanced unrecognized countries, for well over three years I have thought much about what it means to be a state, to have your independence, to maintain your sovereignty and many related issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In short, Somaliland’s history breaks down like this. Somaliland (now) was known before as British Somaliland and as any astute reader may be able to understand from the glaring connotations it was a British colony. What is now the rest of Somalia (known together as Puntland and South-Central for those of us who work on and/or live in the territory of the former Republic of Somalia) was at the same time known as Italian Somaliland. In 1960 when independence movements were sweeping the world (in the US we just called them the civil rights movements, in Africa they were “real” independence movements), Both of the former colonies received their independence within 5 days of each other in the summer of 1960. British Somaliland was a stand-alone entity for five days, afterward it formed a union with the former Italian colony based upon the notion that all five of the Somali areas (modern-day Djibouti, eastern Ethiopia, Somaliland, the former Italian colony, and the North-Eastern part of Kenya) would unite to form a republic for the Somali people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Things didn’t end up turning out as the Somali elites at the time had hoped. The French did not give up Djibouti until much later. Ethiopia and Kenya were worried about their hetergenous populaces and if they allowed the Somalis to break away each of the tribes or nations within their countries would demand similar treatment. The US wasn’t the only one in the 1960′s worried about Domino Effects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Northerners (formerly British Somalilanders, who currently identify as Somalilanders), though leading the push for unification with the South were mismatched and could not compete for their pro rata places throughout the elite of Somali society. They ended up being dominated in almost every facets of country-wide politics by (to them) outsiders and they were not given the opportunity to participate properly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a long series of events the Northerners formed a rebel group in the mid- / late-1980s (depending on how you classify “formed”) which was called the Somali National Movement. It was dominated by Northern elites, but its stated purpose was to overthrow the dictator of the time, Siad Barre. Again things did not turn out as the elites expected. The populace of the Northern tribes, after the SNM drove Siad’s forces (mostly) out of their region demanded that SNM “reinstate” the independence which the Northerners had gained when the British lowered their flags. The SNM leadership, reliant upon cash from the diaspora and the support of the local people for the continuation of their campaign against Siad, had no choice and complied with the demands of the people and “reinstate” their independence (alternatively known locally as “retract the unity with the south” or “declared independence”). That was 1991.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since 1991, Somalilanders have done an amazing amount. They have developed a tri-partite governance system based upon a US model of independent executive with a bicameral legislature. They have a flag, currency, a national anthem, customs officials, defined borders, national monuments, and every other outward hallmark of a state.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But yet they have not been recognized as an independent, sovereign state by any entity in the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Meanwhile, &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/pxvnYK">South Sudan&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/rrYYLM">Libyan rebels&lt;/a> are being recognized by states and international organizations all over the world. Which begs the question why has this bastion of democracy and stability in an area much better known for pirates, terrorists, war lords, and downed helicopters not been given the diplomatic support of the “international community”?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Those fresh off the planes to Egal International Airport in Hargeisa will often ask that question to their drivers, fixers, or staff directly. And they answers they receive vary from Nile politics, to Jewish conspiracies, to cynical disenfranchisement. My own thoughts differ from all of those theories.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First the Libyan rebels situation is different, as explained in the link referenced above. This consortium of disparate groups is not trying to separate and form a new, unique republic but is trying to take over the entire country and overthrow a dictator (not dissimilar to the SNM’s original mission). The recognition given by the US, UK, French, and other big players in world politics is simply a recognition that they are the valid governing coalition for the entire geographical area and have the right to speak on behalf of the entire Libyan people. This shift from Qaddafi regime to the rebel regime is not terribly different than the diplomatic maneuverings which happened when Obama took over from Bush. Legally speaking at least. So that is a very different situation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The South Sudan situation is much closer to the Somaliland situation, but it also has one very important difference. South Sudan fought a long, protracted war against the Bashir regime which resulted in a 2005 peace agreement. This peace agreement between the rebels now forming the basis of the South Sudan government and the Bashir regime allowed for the South to have a referendum vote on independence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is a substantial difference than the unilateral declaration by Somaliland of the “reinstatement” of its independence, at least diplomatically. Somaliland has yet to negotiate with the internationally recognized government down in Mogadishu the terms of its separation. Partially this is due to the animosity between the two. Partially this is due to the fact that no single entity has been in Mogadishu for very long with a sufficient amount of political power for Somaliland to be able to have anyone legitimate on the other side of such a bargaining table.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While the Transitional Federal Government has made great strides towards stability recently, they still only occupy half of their capital city and outside of that have very little ability to impose their will. So therein lies the crux of the problem for Somalilanders. They are steadily building their own country, and have an entire generation who know only Somaliland and nothing about the Republic of Somaliland, meanwhile their appeals to the international community have fallen on deaf ears and they have no one in Mogadishu that for the foreseeable future they will be able to negotiate with the terms of their separation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are an incredible amount of layers to this onion and in future posts I hope to have the time to peel this back a bit further, but for tonight this will have to suffice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why I Started Watershed Legal Services: My Journey from Expat Aid Worker to Expat Entrepreneur</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-04-23-why-i-started-watershed/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-04-23-why-i-started-watershed/</guid><description>&lt;p>a[![Ninja Law Firm via SolYoung @ flickr][2]][2]
Ninja Law Firm via SolYoung @ flickr&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I read an interesting article yesterday from a man who I referenced in my previous post as one of my favorite development bloggers: Owen Barder. Owen has joined a DC based development think-tank called Center for Global Development and in his [good-bye to Ethiopia post][2] he had an interesting thing to say about aid. He claims, and I heartily support, that development is much broader than simply aid, it is about trade policy, climate policy, monetary policy (which he didn’t actually mention), and numerous other policies which the developed world implements and in the globalized economy has massive effects in the developing world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/entry/why-i-started-watershed/4928948235_9882789b97">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/entry/why-i-started-watershed/4928948235_9882789b97&lt;/a>
[2]: &lt;a href="http://www.owen.org/blog/4540">http://www.owen.org/blog/4540&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The article returned my thoughts to something which I have pondered off and on for the eight months since we have opened the doors on &lt;a href="http://watershedlegal.com">Watershed Legal Services&lt;/a>, my small law firm in this corner of the Horn of Africa.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are an assortment of varied and divergently relevant reasons why I invested my time and money in this entity. It is a hodge-podge, a kaleidoscope which changes its predominant colors over time. For one, I wanted to get off the NGO train, to stop skimming the surface of places and to dig into a country. To plant roots. For another, my marriage wasn’t going to thrive in an environment where we were constantly moving as my wife is also a professional and the chances of two professionals finding professionally satisfying positions in a new country every two or three years was daunting at best. And I simply fell in love with Somalis and Somaliland – despite (or perhaps because of) its craziness, its madness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Those are mainly all personal reasons, but there were also some professional reasons which I have considered at length. Rightly or wrongly I was tired of a culture of giving. Now that is not to say that I have stopped giving, indeed I cannot count the number of pro bono hours that our small firm has performed in our short life. I am not tired of giving, I am tired of the expectation that I am here to give – full stop. I am tired of a culture where nothing will happen without a body with money external to the state saying yes we will  fund that. These are backwards to how I see the world. I have no problems with giving a man a fish. But when there are so many fish givers in a place that the giving of a fish becomes an expectation then I think we have reached a point where things should be reevaluated. It isn’t development, it isn’t sustainable, and something has to give. This is why I was excited to start a for-profit law firm, this is why we don’t chase projects in the same way that NGOs do, this is why we haven’t taken outside funding from foundations or other organizations who have shown willingness to assist organizations such as Watershed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Law is not something that can be given. It is, at its core, a conversation between power centers. This conversation ebbs and flows over time. It changes and must change in order to have life and to enable its success. While it is a conversation which can often be informed by actors abroad, if it is not a conversation within the society in which it is being imposed, it will never be successful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me put some meat on that paragraph. What I see from the other side of the table now that I have switched from a legal reform NGO to a practitioner within the country is a tangled mess of laws which will never be implemented here. I see laws built by consultants from other countries who have never bothered to learn the legal structures of this country and bring their own governance proclivities with them. The simple fact of a Kenyan consultant coming to Somaliland to write a law brings big troubles because until recently Kenya was a fundamentally British parliamentary system. Those types of governments operate in a fundamentally different way than governments on a different part of the spectrum. Somaliland, in contradistinction, is built upon an American model. You cannot simply take ideas of how the conversations between power centers works in one system and transplant them whole sale into a different system. Yes, there are often analogies, but not always. American notions of the separation of power and the reasons that America has been able to make an independent executive work requires a method of thought which differs in so many ways. It is like comparing how you talk to your close friends over a cup of coffee sitting on their couch to how you would talk to a new business associate. You talk fundamentally different because the social modes which develop around each of those situations is vastly different. The same is true about law.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So really it boils down to the fact that I wanted to help Somaliland develop its own way of conversing. I want to stop consultants coming from other countries dropping off finished laws and running away. I want to assist parliament and the government to learn how to converse with each other in a legal sense. I want to give young, sharp lawyers a chance to move beyond a simple contract for an NGO where they will never be pushed where they will stagnate and never have the chance to have the feeling of a bit of hard work pushed out the door and the ultimate relaxation and joy which follows.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That, my friends, is why I do what I do. That, my friends, is why I’m more professionally satisfied in these recent months than I’ve ever been in my life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>For Business or for Pleasure: Which is Aid?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-04-18-for-business-or-for-pleasure-which-is-aid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-04-18-for-business-or-for-pleasure-which-is-aid/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748704425804576220524034207558.html">&lt;img src="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748704425804576220524034207558.html" alt="Cropped version of Wisconsin: Open for business. Closed for people. by BlueRobot @ flickr">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This week two interesting articles (to me) have been published and they have given me the push to return to commenting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The articles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first was an &lt;a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748704425804576220524034207558.html">Op-Ed&lt;/a> that was recently published by a publication which is not exactly known for its do-gooder tendencies, the WSJ. It was written by a man I know of, but surprisingly have never run into in the very small expat community we have here in Hargeisa, Jonathon Starr. It was a rage against the machine of the aid industrial complex, something that I can generally get behind. There were parts of the article I agreed with and parts which I disagreed with. Jonathon attacks aid, which is his right – even though I would argue he is an outsider. I am unimpressed by some his more self-righteousness (I took no salary and expect my staff to do the same). He also makes the general broad-side attack of an industry that is very much fodder for an Op-Ed but lacks the detail and bite of a genuine argument which make me think and reflect. The basic gist of the article is that aid is fundamentally flawed because the lack of a profit motive therein causes inefficiencies in its delivery.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="http://talesfromethehood.com/2011/04/18/big-business/">second&lt;/a> was a response to Jonathon’s piece by one of my favorite aid-bloggers, J, who maintains the &lt;a href="http://http://talesfromethehood.com/">Tales from the Hood&lt;/a> blog (as well as the uber hilarious &lt;a href="http://stuffexpataidworkerslike.com">Stuff Expat Aid Workers Like&lt;/a>). J does not have the nicest take on what Jonathon originally wrote. He attacks Jonathon as an outsider who never learned about aid (a meme that he often comes back to and one in which I only partially buy). But more to the point, he defends aid by saying that it should not be run as a business.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-thoughts">The thoughts.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I would enjoy a response from Jonathon to J.  But in the event (a phrase I am increasingly enjoying), I think that if a discussion were to develop they may be arguing past each other. I have a decent understanding of what Jonathon is doing here. It is a small town, and even smaller where the expats are concerned; as with all small towns, we’re in each other’s business to the point of dysfunction. What he is doing is not really what I would classify as aid work. That is to say, it isn’t NGO work as I would classify such. I would call it non-profit work. I make this distinction because Jonathon isn’t really struggling with the same things that most people I know who are EAWs struggle with. It is a subtle distinction, running a program focussed on opening schools and opening a school, but it is a distinction nonetheless. I should clarify this more but it is getting late and I’m lazy. Let us leave it at this: the scale, the tensions, the accounting, the partners – all of these are very different. That aside, Jonathon is clearly an intelligent man and whether he lacks or possesses epistemic authority as an insider to back his argument he originally crafted it and I would hope that he is willing to engage, defend, respond, and converse.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think they both could agree on one point, and it is a point which &lt;a href="http://owenabroad.com">Owen Barder&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://http://www.oxfamblogs.org/fp2p/">Duncan Green&lt;/a> have made eloquently. Owen has made it numerous times, and &lt;a href="http://www.owen.org/blog/4018">here&lt;/a> is one example. I cannot seem to find Duncan’s, but I remember he has written at least one very good piece on it. The upshot of their argument is that aid is fundamentally lacking feedback mechanisms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This, it seems to me, is what Jonathon was originally trying to say. He rightly identifies one of the major problems with aid (its lack of feedback), but he misplaces the meat of his argument by equivocating (wrongly I think) a profit motive with feedback. Yes, in some businesses the bottom line is one of the feedback mechanisms to show whether there is uptake of the goods or services. But the key is not the presence or absence of a profit motive, the key is the presence of ANY feedback loop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J rightly defends some of the current state of aid affairs by saying that indeed aid is not business and some efforts to make it more business-like would be misplaced. Such a reformation would in many instances leave out the real points of aid which is delivery of services to under-serviced sectors – sectors which the profit driven world has, for whatever reason, missed. That would be precisely contrary to what the aid world should be doing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Learning from different sectors is one thing. When I was a Marine, I knew others who got the opportunity to go be seconded to a big company or to the stock exchange for a year or so. They brought back with them their lessons learned and they improved some things within the Corps. And that was fine. That is simply organizational learning. But the reformation which Jonathon proposes is quite a different thing. I fail to see where the presence of a profit motive would truly affect the delivery of NGO services. I see for-profit clinics and schools all around me during my drive to work every day. And I also see tons of kids unable to afford those schools therefore playing in the streets at school time and old ladies too sick to walk to the clinic and unable to afford the clinics anyway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The profit motive is not what is wrong with aid. What is wrong with aid is that it has built into itself neither feedback loops nor accountability. I do not know of a single industry more isolated or insular than aid. There are those inside the echo chambers of twitter and blogs and they are each trying their best to improve the accountability and the feedback mechanisms, but the bottom line is that aid is an industry which is out of site and out of mind for everyone who is not an insider. And what incentive to any of the insiders have to change things other than simple altruism which is never a very powerful motivator? If aid fundamentally changed and if aid accomplished its mission many of the insiders would be out of jobs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And so the cycles spin and people (like J) scream how aid needs professionals in order for it to be delivered correctly. While I do not quibble with what he is saying, I think that outsiders need to engage more. I appreciate the courage which Jonathon displayed in making his original argument. The more outsiders disrupt, the more insiders disrupt, the more improvements we will hopefully see.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are lots of spaces to fill. There are spaces which aid (at least of the international, relatively big-money variety) deserves to be, where it can properly fit and prosper. There are spaces where locally oriented non-profits deserve to be, where they can properly fit and prosper. And there are spaces where businesses should be. If each continues to share lessons learned and if there continues to be a good conversation between the many camps and factions then hopefully what we are all searching for, a reasonable chance for those we wee around us, will come ever closer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But let us not turn our comparisons of apples and oranges into app-ange juice because even though I have never drank that I’m not sure it would be delicious.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Decoding the Somali Mind: A Guide for Expats (Anecdotal, Not Definitive Version): Responsibility</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-18-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-responsibility/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-18-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-responsibility/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This is a new series containing a few stories which have stood out in my time here in Somaliland and have helped me to understand a bit more a culture that in many ways is very different from my own, but in many ways is not. This series explores those differences.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I generally prefer to point out the similarities between disparate people.  I enjoy very much the common humanity aspects about my life.  But I equally enjoy learning about the differences.  This post contains more of the latter than the former.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m American and we are taught from a young age that a major part of being an American means that you are individualistic.  Our pop culture and education system celebrate individuality and the human against the odds above many other cultural memes.  Most of the people that have immigrated to America over the years have come to chase something that was related to individual efforts.  Those of us who descend from those who immigrated we have it both from nature and from nurture.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Somalilanders are taught precisely the opposite.   They celebrate communal victories above individual victories in their poetry and dramas and songs.  They rely on communal networks for insurance when things get tough.  Collective responsibility is bred into them as deeply as individual responsibility has been bred into me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Two months ago my Ethiopian watchman stole an SUV that I was borrowing from a friend and he drove it so fast (likely enjoying his own sense of individuality and freedom of the road – something that isn’t a big leap for me to empathize with) that when he had to swerve to hit someone he hit a bump and jumped the SUV, and I mean jumped it, on top of other cars.  Two other cars that were sitting in a used car dealership beside the road.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I was told about it I was pretty crushed because I knew instantly that I would have to pay for the damage.  Even though he had stolen from me.  Even though his job description involved neither driving nor speeding.  Even though I had not the slightest to do with the situation.  Because that is the way that things work.  Everyone is responsible for everyone else.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If the Ethiopian kid had been Somali and the employer was not responsible then the clan would provide the necessary insurance.  If I as the employer had been Somali and I was unable to cover the costs then my clan would have been called upon to provide the insurance.   But neither of us fit into that system.  I paid.  I had no other choice.  I could reason through very easily that in my system I wasn’t liable.  But I wasn’t living in my system.  I gain the consequences of the system but not the benefits.  I guess that is life though and how many minorities throughout history have had that exact thought?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another thing that is fairly prevalent is that senior Somalis working for organizations get held personally liable for all of the actions or non-actions of the organization.  My number two with my old NGO recently had his power shut off because of a dispute between the power company the organization signed a services contract with and the party responsible for paying the final two months electricity bill.  Sure his name isn’t on the invoices, but his name is there in the computer as the responsible party.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This can be very annoying when you are held responsible for the actions of another that you “normally” would not have to be responsible for.  But when you understand the system and you understand that there &lt;em>is&lt;/em> a system, although maybe facially foreign.  Then you can at least navigate it.  But if you’re new to Somalis these are key because how you treat your staff and the pressures that especially your senior staff will face need to be understood.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I&amp;#8217;m Supposed to Write on Water, but I Don&amp;#8217;t Have Any&amp;#8230;</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-15-supposed-write-water-any/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-15-supposed-write-water-any/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today the Interweb Gods have deemed is World Blog about water day.  Or likely more accurately, the brilliant &lt;a href="http://blogactionday.change.org/">change.org&lt;/a> marketers have deemed today as world blog about water:Day.  I haven’t read every post I have seen come across my various Twitter wires, but the ones I’ve read talk about the need for us to have water.  Seems pretty self-evident and so the rhetoric can turn into a polemic rather quickly.  I thought about writing a love post to water, but then I realized that I’m annoyed at water.  We fell out with each other a couple of weeks ago, which by the way was the last time water came through my pipes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The water system in Hargeisa is over stretched, under maintained, now badly managed network, under funded cluster of an organization.  It makes money so the government doesn’t want to privatize it.  And that is likely the right move considering the power system is privatized and is a mess.  It is all the rage to claim that the private sector is going to save Africa, and I while I believe that I’m not a complete free marketer.  The private sector can be just as lazy and dumb as a public sector can be.  The presence of competition does not necessitate innovation and good economic behavior in and of itself.  But that is a different story and before I go down that road, let me tell you about my pipe problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The pipes that supply Hargeisa were buried about an 1 deep all willy nilly throughout the place.  Whenever you go off of the main roads it is inevitable that you’ll have to drive over one.  That isn’t a structural economic problem.  That has little to do with Ministerial efficiency or World Bank proclamations.  It is just stupid and lazy workmanship.  It doesn’t have anything to do with a depressed education system or beleaguered healthcare system.  it is just stupid and lazy workmanship.  Nothing more, nothing less.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And because these pipes were not buried deep enough, and because I live near a bus station, the pipes that come to my house often are broken by buses running over them.  And then we have to pay for a plumber to come fix them.  The Water Agency this time even refused to drive a plumber up here even after we agreed to pay for the plumber.  And then after we brought the plumber up here to our sector of Hargeisa, the guy wanted $20, TWENTY DOLLARS, to do the fifteen minutes of work it would require to cut a new pipe, tap it, and tighten it onto the new pipe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I told the guy to f-off.  He laughed, I rolled my eyes, he said ten, I agreed.  And then he fixed the pipe.  But since that time no water has come through the pipes.  I don’t think they’re broken as we can usually tell.  In the morning when we drive to work if the water has come and the pipe is broken it just pools uselessly in the muck at the main intersection of the bus station.  In a desert country with small water resources no one seems to give an F about this water just sitting there.  But that hasn’t happened in the past week or ten days since we paid the plumber to fix the water.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why is that the case?  Because I live near a hotel.  You know the kind, one of the few places in town known to cater to expats.  They are all in one shape or form the same.  But the guy who owns the hotel pays the guy who controls the water in our sector a little bit more each month and so the water guy reroutes almost all of the water to the hotel.  The old Hargeisa water manager was a friend of ours and when we told him our hypothesis in this regard he investigated, found it to be true, fought tooth and nail (I heard directly many of the conversations between him and the sector manager who is below him) for us, and still was only moderately successful in getting us water.  Since he was sacked for unknown reasons which had nothing to do with his competence but basically boiled down to the other dude supported the government than won the recent election and had to be rewarded somehow, since that time we have gotten water through the pipes on only a couple of occasions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So water and I have seemingly broken up.  And that is not cool with me.  It isn’t cool in a way that  has nothing to do with what any policymaker or bureaucrat or large NGO marketing department wants me to think.  It isn’t cool and it has nothing to do with funding levels (throwing more money at the sector isn’t going to get the pipes buried deeper, repaired faster, or micro-managed more equitably), bold statements, or glossy web sites.  It isn’t cool and much of it comes down to stupidity and laziness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Excuse me, I gotta run, the dude that drives the donkey cart with the ex-oil drum on the back is here to deliver my water.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On Going Local: Finding Your Happy Place</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-12-local-finding-happy-place/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-12-local-finding-happy-place/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>On Going Local is a new (short) series that I’ll be running which will attempt to look at my life from an objective perspective as I transition from and NGO worker into an entrepreneur here in the developing world.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve been here in Somaliland now for around two and a half years now.  It has been a wonderful time, and I’ve enjoyed every minute of it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are many aspects of Somali / Somaliland society &amp;amp; culture that I have found it easy to adjust too.  But there are a few things which have been difficult.  Not the least of which is the six day work week.  Being an Islamic country, we take Friday off.  But that most people take off.  Going from a two day weekend to a one day weekend with shorter days throughout the six was a big adjustment and I’m not sure that I will ever fully adjust to it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, this is about space.  Physical space.  Like most development workers I lived for a long time in a &lt;a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/caseykuhlman/SomalilandCompound02" title="Gorgorka Luxury Estates">gigantic house&lt;/a> shared among an assortment of other expatriates, cleaners, cooks, guards, and staff.  It can be a fantastically good time having all the excitement of different activities, smells, and languages around you.  For a little while…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a time, though, it becomes stifling.  For one thing, you are never “off duty.”  At any time of the day or night someone may come and knock on your door.  Someone’s family member is sick and they need money; someone’s mobile phone was stolen and they need money; the guards caught two people making out in a dark corner behind the house; all sound tracked to random gunshots due to land disputes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most development or aid workers I know always like to say it’s not a job, it’s a lifestyle.  And that is all well and good, but it isn’t a lifestyle I was very interested in.  Sure you can try to set boundaries, but you don’t want to incentivize the people working with you to not tell you what is happening.   That can lead to all kinds of problems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This balance is incredibly difficult to achieve between having some personal space (when the standard living situation is tenement and shared, college-esque, except we’re not college age anymore) and being “open.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have recently moved out of that mansion into what would be normal to me.  Luckily enough it is also what would be normal to a middle-class Somali.  Instead of ten bedrooms (some of which were office space), I now have three.  Instead of having to walk 15 minutes to get to the kitchen, it now takes me 15 seconds.  I don’t have to worry about staff all of the time as I only have someone who comes to clean for me a few days a week &amp;amp; when I’m at the office.  It is safer this way, as you are a target when you live in a mansion.  You can do what you like without having to worry about being disturbed.  You can metaphorically unpack your bags.  You can find normality in an otherwise frantic existence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The place I’m living now actually feels like a home rather than a dorm.  And that is fantastic.  I love my old roommates dearly, but it is so nice to have something that is “yours.”  And when my wife comes down next year for a bit, my life will be complete!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Decoding the Somali Mind: A Guide for Expats (Anecdotal, Not Definitive Version): Wants v. Needs</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-28-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-v/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-28-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-v/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This is a new series containing a few stories which have stood out in my time here in Somaliland and have helped me to understand a bit more a culture that in many ways is very different from my own, but in many ways is not. This series explores those differences.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![want need syrup by thebrianmeyer @ flickr][2]][2]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every development worker I’ve ever met, and I can say with confidence, without exception, hates the following phrase with a passion: “What we &lt;em>really&lt;/em> need is….”  Hearing that phrase pretty much ruins your entire day.  Usually, but not always, it is accompanied by a veiled threat of what will happen if the particular worker does not comply.  Well, that happens when one is dealing with governmental clients.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a preliminary (and because despite my non-traditional path I am still a trained lawyer), let me define what I’m talking about when I say “wants” and “needs.”  I would define (for the purposes of this piece only, &lt;em>see supra&lt;/em>) “needs” as those things which are required to perform a given task, whereas I would define “wants” as those things which are not required but would be beneficial to accomplish a given task.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do I “need” internet to survive? No.   Do I “need” internet to do my job? Yes (reasons for this answer will be detailed in a forthcoming post).  I say this almost flippantly, but in any culture it is incredibly easy to conflate these concepts and trying to differentiate between the two will depend largely upon an individual’s perspective.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Especially when it comes to legislative action, determining whether a mechanism or a “thing” is needed or wanted is incredibly difficult to determine with accuracy.  One of the arts of political action is convincing others of one’s perspective as to whether something is a needed requirement or a wanted luxury.  This is one of  the many reasons why so many politicians are trained lawyers – as we get paid to use words to twist concepts to convince individuals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yet, when it comes to Somali society figuring out such a differential is complicated by the Somali language.  In Somali, to say “I want X” one would say “X waan doonayaa,” whereas to say “I need X” one would say “X waan doonayaa.”  The root of the verb (“doon”) means both of the concepts expressed in the English words “want” and “need.”  It isn’t a far leap to see that this makes it even more difficult to differentiate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first time I was running a workshop here in Hargeisa talking to legislators about the differences in these concepts my translator was struggling and I was having a hard time understanding why it was difficult to pose the question to the participants.  At the break I pulled my translator aside and tried to figure out why he was having such trouble getting across what I was trying to say.  He was also extremely frustrated but didn’t say much other than he would do his best.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Months later, when I was learning Somali, it became clear to me that the difficulty my translator had experienced much earlier was a function of the Somali language.  After I had learned a modicum of Somali than I changed some of the curriculum of the workshop from wants and needs to requirements and luxuries.  After that it was much easier for my translator to get the preliminary concepts across so that the participants could have a good discussion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of my favorite all time stories during my years here in Somaliland falls (loosely) under this concept of wants v. needs.  In October, 2008, there were three suicide bombs detonated in different places here in Hargeisa: the Ethiopian Embassy, the UNDP compound, and the Presidential mansion.  After these bombings there were probably four of us expatriates who stuck around while everyone else ran away to Nairobi.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My team and I worked day and night for the two weeks after the bombings preparing a series of documents to help the government and parliament understand the legal mechanisms for reacting to terrorism that have been emplaced under (1) international law; and (2) national laws within the region.  The government told me very early on that they were looking to emplace something like the Somaliland Patriot Act and so we had done tons of research on the topic for the government.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We broke up the delivery of the work product among the different affected clients: namely the Ministry of Interior, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, and the Ministry of Justice.  I was in with the Minister of Justice briefing him on the current problems that they would have if they wanted to prosecute suspected terrorists under their current penal code.  I had included in my briefing a bunch on due process as well as the international human rights mechanisms, which had been imputed into the Somaliland Constitution, that currently limited their ability to move forward with prosecutions prior to further legislative action.  About 2/3d’s of the way through my presentation the Vice Minister of Justice barged into the briefing and sat down.  He waited for about thirty seconds before he turned to me and said the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This is all well and good, but what Somaliland really *needs *is you to call up the CIA and brief them on what is happening here.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Seriously, Mr. Vice Minister, do you really think that I have the CIA’s number on my speed dial?  My sarcastic side said.  For once, I controlled that and tried my best to explain in a temperate tone that I had no contacts with the CIA and that even if I did they wouldn’t listen to me.  I caught the Minister’s eyes rolling slightly while the Vice Minister was on his tirade after my response so I knew I was on OK ground and I just moved along with my briefing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After we finished, and we were leaving the Vice Minister (who I had never spoken to once prior to this exchange) walked out to our vehicle with us.  He told me that he knew exactly who I was and that he was going to hold me personally liable for informing the CIA of what was happening here in Somaliland.  I assured him in the most even tones I could conjure at that moment that there was nothing I could do for him on this issue and that he should use the Minister of Foreign Affairs rather than some external NGO worker.  He was never convinced.  And I wasn’t convinced that he was mentally stable enough to be a Vice Minister.  I left completely flabbergasted.  To this day, there is no Somaliland Patriot Act.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Understanding the Somaliland Elections (2 of 3): The Contenders</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-26-understanding-somaliland-elections-2-3-contenders/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-26-understanding-somaliland-elections-2-3-contenders/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Today Somaliland is holding its Presidential elections. To understand the significance of this event, one must understand the road that it has taken the Somalilanders to get to this point. This election has been delayed for over two years. This entry contains a small background on the three men on the ballot.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.ucidparty.com/">&lt;img src="http://www.ucidparty.com/" alt="UCID Chairman Faisal Ali Warabe via Sallaxleynews @ flickr">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="contender-a-faisal-ali-warabe-chairman-ucid-party">Contender A: Faisal Ali “Warabe” Chairman UCID Party&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Faisal and his &lt;a href="http://www.ucidparty.com/">UCID party&lt;/a> have long been seen as the also rans in Somaliland politics.  But UCID seems to have found some resonance in its argument this term and seems to have a growing cadre of supporters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Name:  Faisal Ali “Warabe.” **“Warabe” means hyena in Somali.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Clan: Ciidagaale.&lt;/strong> The Ciidagale are a small-ish (but not a minority) clan within the Somaliland clans.  They are a subclan of the Isaaq who are the majority clan within Somaliland.  The Ciidagaale have a kinship-alliance with one of the major clans within Somaliland politics of the past ten years: the Habar Yunis.  This kinship-alliance is called the Galhajis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Ciidagaale see themselves as the linkage between the major Isaaq subclans from the west of Somaliland (namely the Habar Awal kinship-alliance between the Issa Muse and Sa’ad Muse) and those in the east of Somaliland (namely their “brethren” from the Galhajis as well as the Habar Jaclo).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These two items (their relatively small size and their geographical position between the major players) have long given the Ciidagaale an outsized view of themselves.  They have always played with the big boys, indeed for hundreds of years before and during British colonialism their sultan was one of  the most powerful in all of the northern Somali regions.  They claim that they ruled Somaliland for 500 years, but it is a bit more complicated than that.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="strengths">Strengths:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Not one of the two major players&lt;/strong>.  This underdog position has allowed UCID to campaign nearly without the hassles that the other two “major” parties have had to cope with.  Most of the shots which UDUB and KULMIYE fire across one another’s bows (including claims and counterclaims of terrorist affiliation) are irrelevant to UCID.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Relatively free from the baggage of the SNM / Siad Barre conflict.&lt;/strong> Most Somaliland youth don’t really understand the SNM conflict except in a historical context.  To them this was something that happened before and it does not have the viscerality that it likely had in the prior Presidential elections.  Claims and counterclaims between UDUB and KULMIYE as to whether the prevalence of old SNM fighters who “liberated” Somaliland are waning as a relevant point within Somaliland politics as the years pass.  UCID, who is seen as largely free of this baggage, is in a good position to capitalize on this by pulling in those who see membership in SNM as a hindrance rather than a selling point.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Intellectual vigor.&lt;/strong> The team that Faisal has assembled within the UCID network contains some of the better intellectuals around Somaliland.  This is recognized as a positive by most people that I’ve talked to. UCID seems to have an energy that the other two parties do not have.  Although, this positioning, which is populist in nature, has likely not brought the finances into the campaign coffers required to deal with contingencies after the voting.  They have been very effective at targeting two major centers of the Somaliland electorate: women voters and younger voters.  Most of the rallies held by UCID have seen a larger proportion of woman than any of  the other two parties (from my limited perspective at least).  This definitely will set UCID up for long term success, even if they fail to win this election.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="weaknesses">Weaknesses:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Not one of the major players.&lt;/strong> UCID’s outsider status is also their major weakness.  They have a difficult time capitalizing on the winds which blow through the Somaliland deserts because it is difficult for many to visualize their party in power.  They have difficulty dominating any news cycles or forging forward with their own spin on a given situation.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Wishy-Washy.&lt;/strong> Faisal is seen as wishy-washy by the Somaliland electorate.  I must say that while I understand where they are coming from, I think personally much of this comes from Faisal’s position in between the other two major players.  He is forced into a difficult position where he is required to mediate likely more than he would prefer due to his “third party” status.  This centrist positioning comes across as wishy-washy.  It is unfortunate.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.xisbigaudub.com/">&lt;img src="http://www.xisbigaudub.com/" alt="UDUB Chairman and Incumbent President of Somaliland, Dahir Kahin Riyale via Swiatoslaw Wojtkowiak @ flickr">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="contender-b-dahir-kahin-riyale-chairman-udub-party-incumbent-president">Contender B: Dahir Kahin Riyale, Chairman UDUB Party, Incumbent President&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Riyale and his &lt;a href="http://www.xisbigaudub.com/">UDUB party&lt;/a> have been in power, more or less, since Somaliland declared its independence from Mogadishu and handed over power to a civilian government in the early 1990′s.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Name: Dahir Kahin Riyale.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Clan: Gaadabursi.&lt;/strong> The Gaadabursi are a western clan within Somaliland.  They are probably the largest non-Isaaq clan within Somaliland.  There are some other larger non-Isaaq clans, but the majority of these clans are located outside of Somaliland.  Many feel that having a non-Isaaq President has been beneficial to help keep the Isaaq from imploding and fighting with one another during the years of instability of the 2000′s.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many other Isaaq’s feel that having a non-Isaaq President has given too much power to minority clans within Somaliland.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="strengths-1">Strengths:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Incumbent.&lt;/strong> Let’s be honest.  This is Africa.  The incumbent has numerous advantages that any incumbent would normally have, but also those that may not be available to non-African incumbents.  Already possessing the state gives access to finances that are not available to others within the country.  As Gettleman pointed out in yesterday’s &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/06/26/world/africa/26somaliland.html?hp">piece&lt;/a> for the New York Times, sometimes the voting isn’t what matters, but what happens afterward.  For the afterwards, being the incumbent is a distinct advantage.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Experience.&lt;/strong> Many Somalilanders will endlessly debate whether the Riyale administration has done enough on the development front to get a new chance to run the country.  That said, most Somalilanders will concede that as far as experience governing the current team assembled by Riyale cannot be matched.  Although there are many former Ministers and government officials within KULMIYE’s team, and although UCID brings a lot of intellectual firepower to their team, pure raw experience seems to still be having a decent amount of resonance with those I speak to here in Hargeisa.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>**Continuity. **If Riyale were to stay there would be some continuity to the governing system.  Riyale has proffered two arguments in his favor.  The first is similar to the argument Rove was making in 2004, don’t change horses in the middle of the war.  The Riyale administration has made a big deal out of the current and impending conflict with al-Shabaab operatives that continue to hound Somaliland.  They have argued that they have the right team to tackle this problem.  The second argument has no analogy in American politics, but it is essentially: “we’re already fat, they are skinny, who will really take less from the state coffers.”  For a while this seemed to carry a good amount of weight with the electorate, but has largely been sidelined over the weeks leading up to the election.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="weaknesses-1">Weaknesses:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Background &amp;amp; Baggage.&lt;/strong> Riyale is a former intelligence officer for Siad Barre.  He was not aligned with the SNM, and he sometimes has had to distinguish aside these two arguments.  His response has oscillated between the extremes of hiring lots of SNM veterans and by trying to marginalize the SNM veterans.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>**Engagement Level. **Many question Riyale’s engagement within Somaliland.  Since his wife mostly lives in Paris with their children rather than in Somaliland, lots of voters that I have spoken with have wondered how much Riyale genuinely cares about Somaliland.  He has had to simultaneously deflect attacks that ironically have sought to portray his administration as (1) autocratic, and (2) blind.  While I have seen the evidence pointed to by opposition members in this regard, it is Africa and there will always be some conflating of a Presidential seat vested in institutions with a Kingdom vested in the personality.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.kulmiye.com/">&lt;img src="http://www.kulmiye.com/" alt="Kulmiye Chairman, Ahmed Mohamed Mohamud &amp;ldquo;Silanyo&amp;rdquo; via Berberanews.com @ flickr">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="contender-c-ahmed-mohamed-mohamud-silanyo-chairman-of-the-kulmiye-party">Contender C: Ahmed Mohamed Mohamud “Silanyo” Chairman of the Kulmiye Party&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Silanyo and his &lt;a href="http://www.kulmiye.com/">Kulmiye party&lt;/a> are largely seen as the primary rivals for the Presidency against Riyale. In the last Presidential election Silanyo lost to Riyale by 80 votes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Name: Ahmed Mohamed Mohmoud “Silanyo”&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Clan: Habar Jaclo.&lt;/strong> The Habar Jaclo are one of the largest Isaaq sub-clans in Somaliland.  They traditionally have occupied the farthest east of the Somaliland Isaaq clans, from Burco all the way to Ceerigavo and almost to Las Anood.  This is significant for two reasons.  First, Burco has traditionally felt second-city syndrome to Hargeisa since the British colonial time.  Second, as one of the largest subclans of the majority clan, Habar Jaclo can appeal to parts of the Isaaq electorate that none of the other candidates can due to their majority (semi-majority) status.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many of the Habar Jaclo feel that this is their time, that they have waited as the other major Isaaq clans have had opportunities within the governance framework that they have not had access to (which is a bit of gamesmanship but that is beside the point for how they feel).  They are a tough clan and have shown little hesitation in the past to fight for what they feel they deserve.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="strengths-2">Strengths:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Effective usage of Obama Change Mantra.&lt;/strong> Kulmiye has been exceedingly effective at hijacking the change mantra.  This is hilarious to me, as most of the team within Kulmiye are retreads from prior administrations – either from the SNM times or the post-SNM UDUB days.  However, they have convinced a large portion of the population that they will be the most effective vehicle for change.  This has allowed them to leverage growing discontentment with the current state of Somaliland as a factor in their favor – although many of them were involved in setting the preconditions or implementation of many of the policies they now argue against.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Post-Clanism.&lt;/strong> Another ironic, but effective, political tactic that has been used by the Kulmiye team is to preach post-clanism.  This is also ironic as many Somalilanders feel that among the three parties, Kulmiye is by far the most tied to various clan networks.  I have  no opinion as I’ve never met many of the Kulmiye officials, but certainly they have had that reputation for a long time.   The simple fact that most Habar Jaclo feel that this is their time and that Silanyo, being Habar Jaclo, is their vehicle for political success argues against the post-clanism rhetoric which has been effectively utilized by Kulmiye.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Crowd-sourcing&lt;/strong>.  Kulmiye, among the three parties, has probably had the greatest ability to leverage populism embedded in African big-crowd politics.  They have very energized supporters, especially among the middle-aged former SNM fighters who see their old colonels and central party members as those now wearing suits and up for Ministerial positions and other positions if Kulmiye were to win.   They also have been very effective at energizing supporters among the youth.  Those that have not gone with UCID have largely gone with Kulmiye.  Lastly, Kulmiye seems to understand the power of a crowd and routinely buses in large amounts of supporters before their rallies in order to create a scene which has an undeniable magnetic effect in the Somali world-view.  All of these show an understanding of political process, but I still have seen little evidence that their policies will be effectively implemented.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="weaknesses-2">Weaknesses:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Baggage&lt;/strong>.  As with Riyale, Silanyo comes with his own (very large) baggage.  As the oldest of the three men, and a long-time politician within Somali/Somaliland circles, Silanyo has a long and well-known history.  Silanyo was one of the driving forces behind the formation, training, and equipping of SNM.  However, he was ousted as Chairman soon before SNM’s reentry into Somaliland.  Many claim that this ousting was due to Silanyo cutting a last minute deal with Siad for SNM not to attack Somalia and for the Isaaq to be given more autonomy.  I have no opinion on the truthiness of this claim, however it is a widely disseminated rumor and has made many Somalilanders I’ve talked to question Silanyo’s patriotism and his willingness to make a difficult decision.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Retreads&lt;/strong>.  Much of Silanyo’s team has been there before.  Many were leaders among the SNM and / or the post-SNM UDUB administrations of Egal and Riyale.  In many voters’ eyes this is seen as a negative.  Many within this team are felt to be hardliners that may fight before negotiating.  Whether this is true or not, it is certainly the feeling among a percentage of the Somaliland electorate.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Understanding the Somaliland Elections (3 of 3): The Arguments</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-26-understanding-somaliland-elections-3-3-arguments/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-26-understanding-somaliland-elections-3-3-arguments/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Today Somaliland is holding its Presidential elections. To understand the significance of this event, one must understand the road that it has taken the Somalilanders to get to this point. This election has been delayed for over two years. This entry contains a small background on the arguments that have been given by three men on the ballot.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.garoweonline.com/artman2/publish/Opinion_20/Somaliland_KULMIYE_Formidable_Opposition_Party_or_Troublous_Rebel_Group.shtml">&lt;img src="http://www.garoweonline.com/artman2/publish/Opinion_20/Somaliland_KULMIYE_Formidable_Opposition_Party_or_Troublous_Rebel_Group.shtml" alt="Kulmiye colours by CharlesFred @ flickr">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After discussing some of the background and the personas involved in the election, in this final installment I would like to discuss the arguments that have been raised by each of the three parties.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These are not that complex, so if they seem as if I’ve shortened innumerable hours of speeches by politicians into slogans blithely, let me respond that it is without blitheness and really all I’ve done is distilled the hours of speeches into their core by taking out all of the repetitive words and colorful adjectives which are used by the protagonists with the microphones.  I’ve also tried my best to take out the facial inaccuracies that I see within their arguments, such as &lt;a href="http://www.garoweonline.com/artman2/publish/Opinion_20/Somaliland_KULMIYE_Formidable_Opposition_Party_or_Troublous_Rebel_Group.shtml">this particular article&lt;/a> (from the Kulmiye camp).&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-you-should-vote-for-udub-udub-version">Why You Should Vote &lt;em>For&lt;/em> UDUB (UDUB Version).&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>“We have kept the peace &amp;amp; development will come.”&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-you-should-vote-against-kulmiye-udub-version">Why You Should Vote *Against *Kulmiye (UDUB Version).&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>“They are terrorists.”&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-you-should-vote-for-kulmiye-kulmiye-version">Why You Should Vote &lt;em>For&lt;/em> Kulmiye (Kulmiye Version).&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>“We need change!”&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-you-should-vote-against-udub-kulmiye-version">Why You Should Vote *Against *UDUB (Kulmiye Version).&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>“They are terrorists, and have done nothing for the country.”&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-you-should-vote-for-ucid-ucid-version">Why You Should Vote *For *UCID (UCID Version).&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>“We are the real change.  Here is what we will do for you [insert long list of unobtainables here].”&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-you-should-vote-against-ucid-udub-kulmiye-version">Why You Should Vote *Against *UCID (UDUB Kulmiye Version).&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>[blank] No one seems to make this argument. But when it is made, it goes: “They are terrorists.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Understanding the Somaliland Elections (1 of 3): Background</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-25-understanding-somaliland-elections-1-3-background/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-25-understanding-somaliland-elections-1-3-background/</guid><description>&lt;p>[![Somaliland Victory Monument by Somaliland247 @flickr][2]][2]
Somaliland Victory Monument by Somaliland247 @flickr&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today Somaliland is holding its Presidential elections.  To understand the significance of this event, one must understand the road that it has taken the Somalilanders to get to this point.  This election has been delayed for over two years.  This entry contains a small background on that time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Presidential elections were originally scheduled for August, 2008.  In April 2008, the Council of Elders – Somaliland’s upper house of Parliament (the Guurti) – extended the term of the President until April 6, 2009.  In April 2008, the NEC released a press statement indicating that the elections would take place as originally scheduled and that the Guurti did not have the authority to unilaterally delay the timeline for the elections as the original timeline had been agreed to by all political parties and the House of Representatives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a result of mounting tensions, the President agreed to meet with the leaders of the two opposition parties to negotiate a solution. The negotiations among the parties continued for approximately six weeks, when the three political parties and the NEC held a press conference and ceremony to sign the agreement which appeared to have formally resolved the election dispute. The main points of the agreement were that the presidential election would be held before the President’s term expires on April 6, 2009. The NEC originally scheduled the election to be held on March 29, 2009.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On September 23, 2008, NEC announced that it was accepting applications for temporary workers to administer the voter registration program.  Potential applicants were to attend screening interviews at NEC’s office in Hargeisa, Somaliland.  Several hundred applicants gathered outside the office and an adjacent hotel.  The gathering began to grow agitated upon learning that only several dozen positions would be available.  The police attempted to disperse an increasingly tense situation by firing several gunshots into the air.  Two days later NEC continued the screening process without further incident.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On August 24-26, 2008, a dispute arose within the main opposition party, Kulmiye, over the rules of procedure for electing the party’s candidates for President during the Kulmiye party conference.  Before the conference began several candidates had emerged to oppose the current party chairman and previous Kulmiye Presidential candidate, Ahmed “Silanyo” Mahmoud Mohamed.   These challengers withdrew prior to the party conference in apparent recognition of their slim chances to defeat the incumbent party chairman.  Kulmiye reconciled its differences sometime in the middle of October.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The National Election Commission (NEC) conducted a voter awareness-raising drive during the first week of October, 2008 prior to beginning the actual registration process.  In the midst of this, there was a dispute within the NEC, with four members voting to oust the Chairman of the NEC.  It was never clear what the dispute was centered on, but a settlement was worked out soon thereafter to retain the present NEC Chairman in a meeting between the NEC and the three political parties.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The voter registration process began in the northern port city of Berbera on October 14 and concluded there on October 21.  After Berbera, the voter registration teams moved to Borama and Gabiley for registration of the regions west of Hargeisa.  Hargeisa region, the largest region, was originally scheduled to register voters starting October 28 through to November 3, 2009.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On October 29, 2008, three explosions occurred in Hargeisa.  All three were the result of vehicle suicide bombs.  A group named al-Shabaab claimed credit for the bombings.  Al-Shabaab is a group that claims to have linkages with al Qaeda and has been waging an insurgency in South-Central Somalia for many years.  Although they were known to have operatives in Somaliland throughout their history, this was the first time they acted in such a large-scale and sophisticated fashion.  The Somaliland government quickly and efficiently rooted out many of the remnants of al-Shabaab’s network within Somaliland and brought into custody individuals who have some level of suspected involvement.  More importantly perhaps, the Somaliland citizenry unequivocally rejected al-Shabaab, and many moderate Islamic Clerics spoke out against the attacks and expressed solidarity with the victims and with the Somaliland government.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Somaliland national security apparatus continued to maintain a high state of alert against information relating to ongoing threats.  Specifically, Somaliland officials have reportedly received and responded to numerous pieces of information at various times regarding imminent threats of attack or infiltrations by members of al-Shabaab’s network.  While no such attacks transpired after the initial wave of bombs, throughout this time there was a heightened threat environment and the Somaliland government appeared to be taking all available measures within its capacity to pursue these threats.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Due to the Hargeisa bombings there were a few delays in the registration process for the regions that were originally scheduled to follow Hargeisa region.  The first delay was due to the actual bombings.  The second delay was for staff training as the expatriates supporting the registration effort with information technology services were recalled by their companies and the local Somaliland staff had to be trained.  As a result, voter registration began on December 1 in Hargeisa.  Following the Hargeisa region, the NEC moved towards the eastern regions where it continued with the voter registration process.  The registration teams first went to Burao, the capital of the Togdheer region, followed shortly thereafter in the Sanaag region on December 30, 2008, and then concluded in Sool region.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Somaliland government officials describe the voter registration process as an overwhelming success.  Over 1 million people were registered, according to Somaliland officials, with many Somalilanders presently residing in Bossasso, Puntland reportedly even returning across the border just to register.  Previous population estimates of Somaliland were about 3.5 million, with roughly 30% of that population, or 1.3 million, estimated to be of eligible voting age.  Therefore, the figure of over 1 million voters registered seems close to legitimate. The NEC announced on January 12, 2009 that it had successfully completed the first phase of the voter registration process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As expected, the leaders of both the UDUB and UCID parties were nominated as the Presidential candidate for their respective party in the spring of 2009.  The ruling party, UDUB, nominated the incumbent President as its party’s nominee for the upcoming Presidential election.  The weaker of the two opposition parties, UCID, nominated its chairman, Faisal Ali Warabe, to be its party’s nominee for the upcoming Presidential election.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In February, NEC replaced its chairman.  The preceding chairman resigned on February 2, 2009 from his chairmanship but remained a commissioner.  The new chairman, Mr. Jama Mohamed, entered his position soon thereafter.  On February 23, 2009 NEC announced that it would not be able to hold the elections on the prior agreed date of March 29, 2009.  NEC stated that because of the high number of multiple registrants it would not be able to complete the verification of its database in time.  NEC used computerized software alongside digitized fingerprints and facial photos to identify persons who had registered multiple times.  The complicated computer algorithm that was used to “purge” the database of multiple registrants required outside consultants and extensive computing power – both of which took some time for NEC to acquire.  Additionally, there was a political dispute over the analysis of multiple registrants.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the time when NEC announced that it would not be able to make the March 29 election date, it had yet to complete the identification of multiple registrants.  Following NEC’s announcement that it would be unable to meet the March 29 election date, Kulmiye announced that it would not acknowledge the legitimacy of the current government beyond its allotted mandate – which was set to expire on April 6, 2009.  Kulmiye announced that it would only accept a unified caretaker regime from April 6 until the election was complete.  UDUB, the ruling party, refused to accept any government of unification.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Both parties finally compromised by sending the decision to the Guurti.  After an intense political battle, the Guurti announced on March 28, 2009 that it was extending the President’s mandate another six months, which in turn, extended UDUB’s ability to legally rule Somaliland until October 6, 2009.  Soon thereafter, in the first week of April, NEC announced that it would hold the election on September 27, 2009.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During the first week of April, Kulmiye announced that despite its earlier call to submit the extension of the Presidential mandate to the Guurti, the eventual decision by the Guurti was unconstitutional.  Kulmiye continued to claim that it would not accept UDUB’s legality to rule Somaliland after April 6, 2009.  The party made many claims during this period that it would resort to violence which never came to fruition.  On May 27, 2009 all three of the political parties finally accepted the decision of the mediation committee that the extension of the incumbent’s term by the Guurti, was constitutionally valid and that the election could be held on September 27, 2009.  The leaders of the three parties signed a memorandum of agreement enshrining their current desire to hold the election on that date.  One of the major reasons for the numerous delays was the continued technical difficulties in analyzing the database of registered voters and purging those who registered more than once.  Sometime around the 10th of June, this issue was thought finalized.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Running parallel to the political haggling over the Presidential elections was another battle over control of the Guurti.  On two occasions, first in the middle of February and second at the end of March, 2009 the Guurti brought forward motions to oust the current chairman of the Guurti, Suliman Mahmoud Adan.  Both challenges to the chairman were attributed to his perceived political allegiance to the chairman of Kulmiye, Silanyo.  On both occasions the opposition to the chairman was not able to acquire the quorum of two-thirds of the Guurti constitutionally required to unseat a sitting chairman.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The NEC had its own internal problems during the summer of 2009.  Two of the Commissioners were accused of corruption sometime around June 12 and were sacked by the NEC Chairman about a week later.  Since both of the sacked Commissioners had been appointed by the House of Representatives, that House was vested with the task of replacing them.  Rather than replacing the Commissioners at this late date in the election process, the House decided sometime around the 23rd of June to send the Commissioners back to NEC, despite the corruption allegation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The political gamesmanship between the Government and opposition parties, the Parliament, the National Election Commission (NEC), and the international donors escalated towards the end of July, again jeopardizing the prospects for the election on the scheduled date.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The implementing international NGO, InterPeace, supporting the election process in Somaliland was determined to resolve the technical difficulties associated with the voter registration database and released the final voter registration list to the NEC by July 27.  On July 28 the international donors, providing support to both InterPeace and the presidential elections, announced that the voter list had been released to the NEC on July 27 as agreed, and alleged that the NEC was holding up the process by not releasing the list to the political parties and the general public.  Later that same day, the NEC responded with an announcement that the voter list submitted to them had not resolved the ongoing technical difficulties and was therefore invalid.  The NEC announced further that the election would be conducted on the scheduled date, but without utilizing the voter registration list.  The donors responded with another press announcement that they would withdraw support for the election if the voter registration list was discarded by the NEC.  Meanwhile, the chairmen of both houses of parliament, along with the opposition parties, backed the international donors and announced that the election must only be conducted using the voter registration list.  However, the NEC and Somaliland Government held firm that the election would be conducted without the voter registration list, even going so far as to deport some of InterPeace’s international staff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Throughout August of 2009, the political parties and the National Election Commission (NEC) remained at loggerheads over the decision about whether to hold the election without the voter registration database.  Toward the end of the month, the President decided that the election would take place without the voter list.  This decision inflamed the opposition parties and operated as a catalyst for many relationships to fracture.  The first fissure was between the three parties.  August 3 was the date established by NEC for the political parties to begin campaigning.  On that day, the two opposition parties announced that they would boycott the election if the President continued to maintain his intransigence regarding the voter list.  Meanwhile, the ruling party held rallies for their candidate.  The following day the opposition parties announced, via their MPs, that they would seek the impeachment of the incumbent President.  They cited the Presidential intent to hold the election without the voter list and other unconstitutional actions by the President as their reason.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The drama between the political parties and the President was acted out on two stages.  The first stage was between the Presidential candidates, who participated in numerous mediation committee meetings to resolve their differences regarding whether or not the voter registration list was to be used.  The second stage was between the President and opposition MPs.  On August 15, the Parliament passed a decree allowing the elections to continue as planned without using the list, despite arguments that doing so would be contrary to the Voter Registration Act.  The back and forth between the opposition and ruling parties culminated in at the end of August with an assassination attempt on the Speaker of the House of Representatives by one of the MPs. The Speaker escaped into a prepositioned rally of anti-government supporters.  Following this, pro-government MPs sought the removal of the Speaker.  Meanwhile, anti-government MPs continued to seek the impeachment of the President.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition to the tensions within the Parliament, numerous other tensions were operating within Somaliland over the course of August.  The President and NEC found themselves in a battle with many external actors over the timing and conduct of the election.  On August 20, the Ethiopian Minister of State for Foreign Affairs arrived in Hargeisa in an effort to mediate the differences among the parties on these two issues.  He proved to be unsuccessful in his efforts.  After the Minister departed, a delegation from the African Union arrived in Hargeisa with a similar mission.  Finally, on August 29th, a British diplomat from the UK’s embassy in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia arrived.  All of these missions were unsuccessful and there was no agreement or clarity with regards to the timing and conduct of the Presidential election at the time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In early September, the National Election Commission (NEC) announced that they would be unable to conduct the elections as scheduled on September 27, 2009.  They did not announce a new timetable for when they would be able to conduct the elections.   Toward the end of September, 2009, the President’s mandate was expiring and all of the issues surrounding the election remain unsolved.  On the morning of the day the election was supposed to take place the Guurti finally was able to broker a deal.  The Guurti extended the President’s term indefinitely, but required him to hold the elections in good faith as soon as feasible.  The pro-government supporters agreed to drop their insistence on removing the Speaker of the House, while the anti-government supporters agreed to drop their impeachment motion against the President.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During the first week of October, the seven Commissioners from the National Election Commission (NEC) resigned under domestic and international pressure.  The second and third weeks of October saw seven new Commissioners nominated by the various stakeholders in the process.  Although there was a significant amount of political discourse on the selection of the new NEC, the prior animosity between the various political factions was largely absent from the process.  On October 21, the President forwarded the list of the new Commissioners to the House of Representatives.  On October 24, the House approved the list.  They were sworn in the following week.  The turnover from the old Commissioners to the new Commissioners took place during the first weeks of November.  The new NEC began their work and meetings during November.  They spent a significant portion of the month in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia meeting with donors and participating in training seminars.  NEC returned to Hargeisa from their meetings abroad during the latter part of December.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The NEC came under pressure throughout the early part of 2010 to fix a date for the elections.  The new NEC shied away from media attention and focused itself in the practicalities of conducting elections.  The legal mandate of the 2007 Voter Registration Act placed the NEC in difficult position, as it was required to use the database, but the database it inherited from the previous NEC was largely unusable.  Subsequently, Interpeace sent technicians to try to recover the data that is either lost or in the wrong form.  This effort was largely successful, and the NEC was able to publish the voter list for the political parties in late March without incident.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The NEC spent most of February planning polling station locations and resolving the final technical issues with the voter registration database.  Around the 25th of February information was leaked to the press that the NEC would not be ready to hold the presidential election until the end of the year and that they would distribute new voter registration cards in each region to voters who had not registered twice.  The news was not met with much tension in Hargeisa.  However, later in the quarter different information circulated that the election would take place in June or July of 2010.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Guurti experienced more turmoil during the early part of 2010.  The Chairman of the House left Somaliland in December and went to the United Kingdom for routine medical treatment.  While the Chairman was away, motions were brought before the House to change the by-laws to reduce the current super-majority required to oust a sitting chairman to a simple majority.  Many members of the House felt that this was a first step toward deposing the current Chairman, and members quickly began taking sides on the issue.  When the Chairman returned on January 12, 2010, he immediately began working to resolve the conflict.  In late January, the Deputy Chairman, who was widely seen as the heir apparent to the Chairman’s post if he was ousted, announced his resignation.  This again caused polarization in the House, with numerous back and forth accusations and rebuttals from both camps[[LB4]][2] [[CSK5]][3] .  After more political mediation, the Deputy Chairman retracted his resignation and was reinstated by the plenary chamber of the House.  Both camps agreed to keep the bylaws as they were.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[2]: /Users/Casey/Documents/CSK, ESQ/PILPG/Somaliland/PILPG Somaliland Final Report CK Draft 06.14.10.doc#_msocom_4
[3]: /Users/Casey/Documents/CSK, ESQ/PILPG/Somaliland/PILPG Somaliland Final Report CK Draft 06.14.10.doc#_msocom_5&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Early in April, 2010 the Chairman of the Ghanaian National Election Commission visited and assisted the Somaliland National Election Commission (NEC) in the various preparations necessary for the election.  On April 29 the NEC held a press conference where they confirmed that they would be ready to hold the election in June, 2010.  NEC has prepared all of the polling stations, ordered and accepted the delivery of the ballot boxes, and has delivered the approved and finalized voter registration cards to the electorate.  In May, 2010 the NEC announced that the Presidential elections would take place on June 26, 2010.  The campaigns for the elections began without significant tension on June 5, 2010 and have continued without any significant disruption up to the time of this report.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Decoding the Somali Mind: A Guide for Expats (Anecdotal, Not Definitive Version): Introduction</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-21-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-21-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This is a new series containing a few stories which have stood out in my time here in Somaliland and have helped me to understand a bit more a culture that in many ways is very different from my own, but in many ways is now. This series explores those differences.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![BraiNut 1.0 via sath.es @flickr][2]][2]
via sath.es @flickr&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have lived &amp;amp; worked with Somalis here in Somaliland for over two years now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have, like many expats before me, sat in rooms on the floor with rugs underneath us cushions behind our backs, mauis’s (skirts) on sporting wife-beaters drinking the sweetest teas one has ever drank and (as my wife likes to say) sticking green leaves up our noses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Equally I have sat many nights, like many expats before me, on a veranda, a glass of wine in hand, cool breezes of Hargeisa swirling around, dressed in jeans and semi-glamorous (but always purposively casual) shirts, some ipod attached to portable speakers, listening to music that is on the verge of being hip back home and talking about the deep cultural differences between us and those that fill our daily lives (our clients, our friends, our colleagues, people we meet around).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have had a steady turnover in Hargeisa of expatriates lately.  And over that time there seems to be an increasing amount of tension between the expatriates and the Somalilanders.  I am not sure exactly why this seems to be happening (because this is Somaliland it is spoken of in metaphors and resides fully in the subtextual zone), but it has become increasingly tangible to me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the course of the past year there has been this tit-for-tat between the powerful voices for the expatriates and the powerful voices for the Somalilanders.  The problem is that those of us who aren’t given powerful voices become batted around as the game is played by others.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Something happened to me recently which I would like to use (again cloaked in metaphor and subtext, because this is how to communicate in Somaliland) as a tuusaale (example).  One of my best expat friends here in Hargeisa (who is a development worker) recently had some professional dealings with one of my best Somali friends (who is a mid-level government employee).  Due to forces above and beyond either’s control the dealings did not turn out well and both became frustrated by the situation (for very different reasons but that is beside the point).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a while I was caught in the middle of everything but the biggest problem was that I was getting completely different stories as to what happened from either “side” (so to say).  There was so little alignment between the stories that for a while I wondered if these were two completely different situations involving different people completely.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Later I started to piece it together, to connect the people that were being referenced by one story with how I organize those relationships when I’m talking to the other side, to connect the things that I knew were more important to one side with those that had little emphasis in the other’s side of the story.  I don’t know much about mediation, but I was trying to see these events through each side’s cultural lens and come to some sort of objective understanding of what likely transpired.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was only after spending literally hours trying to dig through and cross-check and re-examine and then start all over again that I was able to ferret out what may have actually happened.  And only after that did I realize that the actualities of the situation were out of the control of either party.  That happens in development work and it is one of the occupational hazards of this work.  However, the relational aspects of the situation were very much aggravated by the cultural differences between the parties.  It is this part – the cultural misunderstandings and their attendant relational aspects which causes (in my mind) undue hardships in development work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is why I wanted to write a few words over the course of the next little while trying to tell a few stories that have taught me a ton about humanity and culture (and which is which).  A few stories which I think of and use when I’m trying to analyze things through a foreign cultural lens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If I had to pick one of the most intellectually satisfying aspects of working here in Somaliland, it has been the opportunity to dig deep into a culture and a way of thinking and seeing the world that is very different than my own.  Each of the cultural differences, while stark at times, belies evidence of our common humanity.  Every time I become frustrated with the cultural differences then something will happen to me which will reinforce the common humanity which is always there.  The tenderness of a father’s reprimand, or a shared joke, or an extraordinarily kind act.  These things accompany each and every one of the cultural differences.  So I hope to share a few of these stories along the way as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What Does Gerstle Mean Pro-People Development?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-05-27-gerstle-pro-people-development/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-05-27-gerstle-pro-people-development/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://humanrights.change.org/blog?author_id=351">&lt;img src="http://humanrights.change.org/blog?author_id=351" alt="Double rainbows from my roof">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://humanrights.change.org/blog?author_id=351">David Gerstle&lt;/a>, who writes for &lt;a href="http://change.org">@change&lt;/a>, among others is fastly becoming one of my favorite journalists commenting on Somalia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have my quibbles with some of the things he says, but mainly it is a difference of assumption rather than philosophy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This week he wrote a post talking about the ineffectual nature of the stream of “governments”  that have “ruled” Somalia since Siad Barre was thrown from power by a queer arrangement of circumstances and bad decisions.  (Yes, if we were discussing this over a beer I would have used finger quotes around those words.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gerstle’s argument is that Somalia has lacked a visionary unifier that was able to convince a wide-swath of the Somali community to band together.  This is true.  There has been no one.  Likely there will never be one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In history no one has been able to rule Somalis by consent.  Either it is by force or there is controlled anarchy.  And this controlled anarchy is likely to continue into the foreseeable future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here in Somaliland there was a group that was able to achieve some of what Gerstle is arguing for, but for a long calculus of reasons that I’m too bored with to go into here and now they were focussed on unifying the people and clans of Somaliland rather than the entirety of the Somali people.  Unfortunately for Somaliland and the rest this group of pragmatic visionaries is dead and no one has stepped up and been able to sell a vision to the Somalilanders of where Somaliland is going and why it should go in that direction.  But where is Somaliland now after the death of the original visionaries?  There is a crazy stew of controlled anarchy spiced up with a bit of controlling top-down authoritarianism just to make the stew interesting and unexpected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even though there is a lack of current visionaries, there is no lack of vision which is discussed and debated at nauseum while no one seems to take any steps in any direction – even those directions where everyone agrees.  Yet, despite these challenges, everywhere I look I see hope around me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A young generation is coming up with only knowledge of Somaliland.  They are educated and passionate about unification.  They have links with diaspora who are helping to curb the clanistic tendencies which the older generation feels deeper than the young.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Largely, Somalis and Americans have lots in common.  Especially when you are able to have a philosophical discussion about the role of government in people’s lives.  They are deeply distrustful of the government and very private sector focussed.  They are comedic, warm (after they know you), and pragmatic.  I see so much in common between the problems that Somaliland is facing and the problems that America is facing.  Every day I see the frustrations of people here and read about the frustrations of my friends and family back home.  Although the scale is different, the problems largely stem from the same source: a feeling of distrust in one’s government which should be there to help.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is a difficult proposition to project what will happen in Somalia or Somaliland.  The problem, as I see it, with the international approaches so far along with the local approaches, is that it is difficult to reconcile the philosophical desires of most Somalis with the history that they have faced in the modern era of authoritarian rule.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Simply put authoritarian rule will not work long term in Somalia.  Maybe it will work in more deferential cultures, but Somali culture is about as far from deferential as I’ve every experienced.  Someone, I do not doubt, will come along with a vision of how to reconcile these notions and will actually put into practice the tenants of the Somaliland Constitution which was built quite well as a decentralized structure with dissipated power very similar to the US governance model.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Such a visionary, powered by the continued education of most Somalilanders will be the double rainbow which will allow Somaliland to turn the corner.  It will not happen simply by a visionary telling the country what it has to do.  Somalis will rarely accept such orders.  But someone will come along – eventually, inshallah – that will be able to convince people of his or her vision of how to reconcile the dissonance between the historical predicates of Somalia and the cultural desires for decentralized power.  When this unselfish visionary comes along the world should ilaalayaa because these people that I have grown to love will be a powerful force.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>