<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>somaliland on underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/somaliland/</link><description>Recent content in somaliland on underWater desert Blogging</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/somaliland/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>On the Sovereignty of CryptoCurrencies -- What Bitcoin can Learn from Somaliland</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-08-14-bitcoin-somaliland/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-08-14-bitcoin-somaliland/</guid><description>Anarchy isn't great. People are not immune to the system. These are things which adding a nice payment protocol and some interesting cryptographic hashes does not change.</description></item><item><title>Micro-States; Pirates; Terrorists; The London Conference: What a Fascinating Time for Watchers of Somalis</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-01-30-micro-states-pirates-terrorists-the-london-conference-what-a-fascinating-time-for-watchers-of-somalis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-01-30-micro-states-pirates-terrorists-the-london-conference-what-a-fascinating-time-for-watchers-of-somalis/</guid><description>For almost four years now I’ve been a careful observer of Somali politicians. For three of those years I was paid to try to be their lawyer. To provide them expert international legal assistance tied to a deep network full of some of the finest international practitioners and thinkers in the world. But they rarely, if ever, wanted that help. So largely I invented work, I went into meetings and had a product to sell. &lt;em>I can’t buy you new computers, but I how about I help you write that legal framework that Parliament has required you to do&lt;/em>?</description></item><item><title>On The Somali Famine: A Thought Collage</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-07-30-somali-famine-collage/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-07-30-somali-famine-collage/</guid><description>This post is a compilation of sources, commentary and thought. It is a collage on the famine in the South of Somalia, the media storm which is surrounding it, and possible things to do.</description></item><item><title>On Colonies, the AU &amp;amp; Borders: Somaliland&amp;#8217;s Recognition Journey</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-07-24-on-colonies-and-borders/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-07-24-on-colonies-and-borders/</guid><description>One of the legal criteria for statehood is established borders. There is a serious and very well, although often, hidden question as to where Somaliland's borders are. In this post I try to parse this a bit mainly from the perspective of international law, but also from the political perspective as well.</description></item><item><title>What Does it Mean to be Independent: Somaliland&amp;#8217;s Recognition Journey</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-07-20-somalilands-recognition-journey/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-07-20-somalilands-recognition-journey/</guid><description>After having been in Somaliland, one of the world's most advanced unrecognized countries, for well over three years I have thought much about what it means to be a state, to have your independence, to maintain your sovereignty and many related issues. In this post, I try to parse the differences between Somaliland, South Sudan and the Libyan Rebels.</description></item><item><title>Why I Started Watershed Legal Services: My Journey from Expat Aid Worker to Expat Entrepreneur</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-04-23-why-i-started-watershed/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-04-23-why-i-started-watershed/</guid><description>I felt the need to justify (perhaps mostly to myself) why I have started what to many are a fantastically crazy journey of starting a socially-conscious law firm in a very undeveloped country. Here's why I made that decision.</description></item><item><title>For Business or for Pleasure: Which is Aid?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-04-18-for-business-or-for-pleasure-which-is-aid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-04-18-for-business-or-for-pleasure-which-is-aid/</guid><description>Two articles were published this week on opposite sides of an interesting debate, what is the role of profit in the deployment of development services? I think that they both slightly miss the mark and here's why&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Decoding the Somali Mind: A Guide for Expats (Anecdotal, Not Definitive Version): Responsibility</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-18-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-responsibility/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-18-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-responsibility/</guid><description>This is a new series containing a few stories which have stood out in my time here in Somaliland and have helped me to understand a bit more a culture that in many ways is very different from my own, but in many ways is not. This series explores those differences. This entry is about relationships in Somaliland.</description></item><item><title>I&amp;#8217;m Supposed to Write on Water, but I Don&amp;#8217;t Have Any&amp;#8230;</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-15-supposed-write-water-any/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-15-supposed-write-water-any/</guid><description>Today the Interweb Gods have deemed is World Blog about water day. Or likely more accurately, the brilliant charity:Water marketers have deemed today as world blog about water:Day. I haven't read every post I have seen come across my various Twitter wires, but the ones I've read talk about the need for us to have water. Seems pretty self-evident and so the rhetoric can turn into a polemic rather quickly. I thought about writing a love post to water, but then I realized that I'm annoyed at water.</description></item><item><title>On Going Local: Finding Your Happy Place</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-12-local-finding-happy-place/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-12-local-finding-happy-place/</guid><description>On Going Local is a new (short) series that I’ll be running which will attempt to look at my life from an objective perspective as I transition from and NGO worker into an entrepreneur here in the developing world. This post is about finding some personal space.</description></item><item><title>Decoding the Somali Mind: A Guide for Expats (Anecdotal, Not Definitive Version): Wants v. Needs</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-28-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-v/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-28-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-v/</guid><description>This is a new series containing a few stories which have stood out in my time here in Somaliland and have helped me to understand a bit more a culture that in many ways is very different from my own, but in many ways is not. This series explores those differences. This entry is about relationships in Somaliland.</description></item><item><title>Understanding the Somaliland Elections (2 of 3): The Contenders</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-26-understanding-somaliland-elections-2-3-contenders/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-26-understanding-somaliland-elections-2-3-contenders/</guid><description>Today Somaliland is holding its Presidential elections. To understand the significance of this event, one must understand the road that it has taken the Somalilanders to get to this point. This election has been delayed for over two years. This entry contains a small background on the three men on the ballot.</description></item><item><title>Understanding the Somaliland Elections (3 of 3): The Arguments</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-26-understanding-somaliland-elections-3-3-arguments/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-26-understanding-somaliland-elections-3-3-arguments/</guid><description>Today Somaliland is holding its Presidential elections. To understand the significance of this event, one must understand the road that it has taken the Somalilanders to get to this point. This election has been delayed for over two years. This entry contains a small background on the arguments that have been given by three men on the ballot.</description></item><item><title>Understanding the Somaliland Elections (1 of 3): Background</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-25-understanding-somaliland-elections-1-3-background/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-25-understanding-somaliland-elections-1-3-background/</guid><description>Today Somaliland is holding its Presidential elections. To understand the significance of this event, one must understand the road that it has taken the Somalilanders to get to this point. This election has been delayed for over two years. This entry contains a small background on that time.</description></item><item><title>Decoding the Somali Mind: A Guide for Expats (Anecdotal, Not Definitive Version): Introduction</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-21-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-21-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version/</guid><description>A new series from underWater desert Blogging which attempts to bridge some distinct cultural differences via a storytelling format. This is the introduction entry.</description></item><item><title>What Does Gerstle Mean Pro-People Development?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-05-27-gerstle-pro-people-development/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-05-27-gerstle-pro-people-development/</guid><description>It is a difficult proposition to project what will happen in Somalia or Somaliland. The problem, as I see it, with the international approaches so far along with the local approaches, is that it is difficult to reconcile the philosophical desires of most Somalis with the history that they have faced in the modern era of authoritarian rule. But someone will come along - eventually, inshallah - that will be able to convince people of his or her vision of how to reconcile the dissonance between the historical predicates of Somalia and the cultural desires for decentralized power. When this unselfish visionary comes along the world should ilaalayaa because these people that I have grown to love will be a powerful force.</description></item></channel></rss>