<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ethereum on underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/ethereum/</link><description>Recent content in ethereum on underWater desert Blogging</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Casey Kuhlman</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/ethereum/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Iterating over the Traditional - Legal Approaches to Smart Contract Development</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-04-09-notes-from-my-ethereum-talk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-04-09-notes-from-my-ethereum-talk/</guid><description>Audio Talk is Here Introduction ![slide 1]({{ site.url }}{{ site.root }}{{ site.images_dir }}/{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; }}/ethereum-talk-slides-1.png)
Who am I? My name is Casey Kuhlman and I'm an American lawyer. Currently, I'm running a small law firm with our headquarters in Somalia. In particular, we work mainly in the north of Somalia which is a self-declared independent state of Somaliland. I've been in Somaliland for coming up on six years now and my practice has a wide focus on law building, corporate governance work, compliance work, and corporate transactions.</description></item><item><title>A Proposal for @ethereumproject Provisions, Contracts, and Packages</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-03-06-introducing-ethereum-package-manager/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-03-06-introducing-ethereum-package-manager/</guid><description>Lately on my &amp;ldquo;regular&amp;rdquo; blog I have been doing a decent amount of writing about virtual automatic contracts. It has been fun to think through the possibilities of virtual automatic contracts and how those could really work in developing countries.
Background and Introduction Earlier this week I had the distinct pleasure of attending the Ethereum meetup in Amsterdam to learn more about how virtual automatic contracts (or as they call them smart contracts) work within the Ethereum blockchain.</description></item><item><title>How I Would Structure Automatic Virtual Contracts</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-02-17-structuring-automatic-virtual-contracts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-02-17-structuring-automatic-virtual-contracts/</guid><description>Automatic contracts have been occupying a great deal of my free mental energies for the past few weeks since I first learned that there are platforms in the works that will allow for such things to happen. My thoughts on this are quite nascent, as is the technology, but here are my early observations.
Introduction Automatic virtual contracts are, essentially, small computer scripts which are linked to virtual currency wallets. The basic idea is that a financial transaction and the terms and conditions governing the transaction collapse into a singular instrument &amp;ndash; or script.</description></item></channel></rss>