<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/</link><description>A Site About Resilience and Authoritarianism</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</managingEditor><webMaster>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</webMaster><copyright>All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Day in My Life: Somaliland Edition</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-01-29-day-in-life-somaliland/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-01-29-day-in-life-somaliland/</guid><description>&lt;p>The other day, my dad asked me to write a short piece about what my daily life is like in Somaliland. I usually refrain from such things, but I think it is a good opportunity to show how &lt;em>normal&lt;/em> everything is here. With a few caveats.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![Office Guest Suite][2]][2]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I generally awake between 9 and 10. Although this is late for a work day, if you read to the end you’ll see why. Mostly everyone else is out of the office in the morning either in court or meetings or taking care of personal errands. This is great for me, since I’m a slow waker so I like the peacefulness in the mornings as it lets me wake at a reasonable pace. In many ways the afternoons and mornings are sort of flipped around from life in the US. Things start slowly here for almost everyone. Although I used to have my own house that I rented, these days I’m spending less long stretches in Hargeisa and so we have built a sleeping room here at the office for me to use when I’m here and for the team to use after a late night working when I’m not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![][3]][3]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a freezing cold shower that although painful is effective at getting your juices flowing, I head into our office. I share and office with Hassan, my Vice President, but he is rarely there in the mornings. I like to begin my day with a cup of coffee and some news, as many others do. Here that comes in a flask of Ethiopian coffee my watchman brings from our close Ethiopian tin shack shop and accompanied by my scans of my Google Reader (using Feedly’s skin), Twitter, Facebook, and Tumblr feeds. I generally do a more or less quick scan in the mornings. I read a few smaller articles from my feeds, but I just generally skim the headlines and then mark the longer articles that seem interesting for my Readability queue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After I’m finished with the news, I then usually begin working on whatever lies in front of me. I usually try to start the working day with the mundane admin tasks that don’t require as much thought as my client work. About 12:30 or 1:00 I’ll realize that I’m hungry and ask my watchman to go bring my lunch. We have a hotel about two blocks away that serves a decently nice chicken sandwich and edible fries (which is my typical lunch order). When I reach a stopping point in my work then I take a small break and migrate into our chewing room. This usually involves several trips to get all of the waste baskets in the office, rearrange the cushions in the room, make sure the tea cups and ashtrays are brought in, and also that all my accoutrement is ready.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![Chewing Session][4]][4]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I like to eat in the relaxation of the sitting room while listening to either some music or a podcast. The rest of the gang usually arrives somewhere between 2 and 3. Our majlis is almost always open to people if they are interested in coming to chat with us. The only times we ask people not to come are when we have a meeting planned. On a typical afternoon, we’ll have 7 to 10 people with us for varying lengths of time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![My Chewing Position][5]][5]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chewing sessions are interesting. You make an effort to prepare your spot so everything you’ll need for the next 6 to 12 hours is within your reach. You make sure that your water, your tea, your soft drinks, your fake beer, your chat, your phone, your computer (and cord), your wallet, keys, everything is just around you. At our office, we developed a habit of using our wastebaskets as small tables for our laptops. It works fantastically as the laptop doesn’t overhead and when you’re sitting on the floor it is at a really good height so your back does not get jarred. Also it is quite easy to move when you are changing the way that you sit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chewing sessions generally start quite festive and then steadily deteriorate into quietness. Everyone usually is chatting at the beginning, or reading some news, or checking their facebook. Then after everyone is more or less settled in they begin work. In many offices, not only ours, the real work takes place at chewing sessions. Although many expats in Hargeisa are very much against qat (for admittedly valid reasons) the argument that it makes people lazy I simply don’t buy. For me, it focuses me and I actually work quite well when I’ve had a normal dosage of qat. The high you get from qat, if one can even call it a high, is very subtle and take a long time to settle in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some people join us but do not have work that day so they will chat or listen to Somali songs or watch TV depending on their moods. The rest of us either put on headphones or we just listen as we are working. It is not unlike a co-working space.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The great thing about a chewing session is that when you need a break or if you have a question you just ask or you just visit with people. If something comes on the news people will generally discuss. If there had been a big political incident earlier that day it will get analyzed in detail. And sometimes people will just work or chat on facebook. It is a very relaxed environment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Usually people leave between 9 and 10. At this point in the night, I’m usually getting my best work done and so I will often stay going until about 2 or 3 when I snoozily saunter to the sleeping room. Then the cycle starts all over again. So that’s a typical Somaliland day. With a few pictures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![Chewing Session 2][6]][6]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On Transparency &amp;amp; Openness in Organizational Behavior</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-27-transparency-openness-organizational-behavior/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-27-transparency-openness-organizational-behavior/</guid><description>&lt;p>I run a law firm in Somaliland, or what National Geographic’s map section probably calls Somalia (northern section).  I have been a technophile for a long time; indeed, as long as I can remember I’ve had a computer and used it extensively.  To me at least, many of my “mentors” for creating an organization are companies which are currently operating in the technology sector rather than in the legal sector.  These tech companies seem to have organizational philosophies that excite me.  Although one can never know for sure without having a deeper glimpse inside the company than what they allow one to glimpse from the outside, many of these companies give customers and potential customers an opportunity to view them deeper than we have likely ever seen before for corporate behavior.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is a huge part of me which appreciates this from a consumer point of view.  It makes it easier to do your task management when you “feel” as if you “like” the program you are using and even better when you feel as if you “know” something about those who made it, where they are trying to go with it, etc.  It enables a feeling of community and communal interest even though I’m here in Somaliland and they may be thousands of miles away.  This interactivity is powerful when applied to corporate behavior as it allows companies to leverage the increased loyalty and interactivity found in small community-based businesses with the scales of economy found in large MNC’s.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many times being open is more efficient than being closed.  It is also quite efficient to tag and publish your links in a way that allows your team and your community to see them.  I mean everyone will keep current with news, analysis, etc. within their sector.  Pushing those links into the semi-public team spaces and public community spaces with the click of one button.  Why not?  At the end of the day it saves you more time than having to break these tasks of media consumption, team discussion, and marketing into individual blocks.  Crowdsourcing is another great example of openness’s links to efficiency.  See &lt;a href="http://weijiblog.com/2010/10/62-diaspora-and-kickstarter/">this&lt;/a> great entry from the &lt;a href="http://weijiblog.com/">weijiblog&lt;/a> as an example of what I’m talking about.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All this is well and good.  But there are a few tensions which any organization must be aware of.  These areas should pull you back from a 100% open business if they apply to your situation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="confidentiality--duh">Confidentiality – Duh&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The most obvious tension with openness that we, and other professional services companies, face is that of client confidentiality.  As lawyers we have to put in an extremely rigid firewall between the reception area and the back area of our online presence.  Discussing what we are working on today is a no-go if it is anything whatsoever to do with client activity.  Sure I use &lt;a href="http://foursquare.com/compleatang">foursquare&lt;/a> and many times it check-in when I’m making sales calls.  But I never do it when I’m having a client meeting.  Sure I blog, tweet, etc.  But never about client matters.  Ancillary to client matters is even a personal no-go area.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Each individual professional organization and each professional within that organization will be subjected to their own specific confidentiality requirements.  Many lawyers get around these by blogging anonymously but still revealing many confidential facts of a case simply by hiding in plain sight and not mentioning names.  While this may work for them, I have personally chosen a different path.  I prefer to blog publicly using my real given name and simply not put into the public space those things which I’m required (and would anyway even if I wasn’t required) to maintain as confidential.  I see the value in the humor of some blogs I read by public defenders or other practitioners.  But I would never write one.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="areas-of-strategic-advantage">Areas of Strategic Advantage&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The less obvious tension with openness is that of commodification of those areas where your organization has a distinct strategic advantage.  This is something which I struggle with more.  Operating where we operate and having the research base which we have built and having the connections which we have has taken a lot of time and a lot of work.  It isn’t the easiest place to live and it certainly isn’t the easiest place to operate.  But nevertheless, we are making it work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a strategic advantage for our firm.  We are well connected abroad and locally.  We have a deeper understanding that probably any organization in the world as to the current state of the Somaliland legal system.  So there is a huge tension for me when it comes to this area.  On the one hand, I truly believe that laws should be published by the governments which pass them.  This information needs to be public and freely available to all those who may be subjected to its provisions.  But the reality is that the Somaliland government has not done this.  We do have all of the applicable laws, but we have had to find many of them.  Some we even had to pay some money to acquire.  So when a lawyer from abroad emails to ask about this law or that law and if we can send it to them I struggle to find the proper answer.  While we are building our firm we need to leverage each of the strategic advantages which we have   Maybe later, when we’re more established and our cash flow is more stable then we can relax and open up a few of the strategic advantages – especially in the area of information vis a vis analysis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is a danger here also which is that if you begin with the habits of holding your cards closer than you optimally may that that habit will become a policy rather than the habit of the beginning organization.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But for now, and for us, it is unlikely that I’m going to give you those things which I have worked very hard to achieve.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Annotated Reading: So THAT is Why I Don&amp;#8217;t Fit In</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-04-annotated-reading-fit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-04-annotated-reading-fit/</guid><description>&lt;p>This week I read a fascinating article which was written by a former high-level DFID individual named Rosalind Eyben.  The title of the piece is, “Hiding Relations: The Irony of ‘Effective Aid.’” It can be found in its entirety [here][2].
[2]: &lt;a href="http://www.oxfamblogs.org/fp2p/wp-content/uploads/ejdr201010a1.pdf">http://www.oxfamblogs.org/fp2p/wp-content/uploads/ejdr201010a1.pdf&lt;/a>
This article spoke to me in a way that not many pieces have recently.  Perhaps it is my transition from an aid receiving NGO worker to the other side of the coin as a private sector social entrepreneur, and the conjunction of the transition with my reading of the article.  Or maybe I am trying to continue to understand a world and a profession which on the surface seems straight-forward (go to Somalia &amp;amp; help) but underneath is complicated, political, and stifles lots of creativity for no reason.
There are many varied reasons for the underlying complications.  Some of the reasons come from other annotated readings that I have put up in the past.  Some of the reasons come from the complications of running world-wide operations with thousands, if not millions of associated partners – not to mentions the hundreds of millions of people involved in the entire operation from politicians, to top-level administrators, to top-level NGO workers, to country-level NGO workers, all the way to the purported beneficiaries of a project.  So, in short, this is a complicated undertaking and requires people who understand complexity theory (an annotated reading which is in the works) and who understand relationships.
The main gist of the piece is that aid should value the relationships which are developed between a recipient population and those individuals mandated with the delivery of the project.  I have always felt that this work requires a complex understanding of the context in which the project is undertaken, and I have always valued the relationships which I have built along the way.  Indeed, the value which I place on those relations is one of the driving forces for my new ventures (see [here][3] and [here][4]).  While I have placed value, as an individual human, on these relationships, I always had this odd feeling whenever I would talk to others within my organization or in donor communities that this was some sort of a remote control SimCity game that had less to do with human beings and more to do with numbers and metrics which never had any application at least in my specific context here in S’land.
[3]: &lt;a href="http://watershedlegal.com">http://watershedlegal.com&lt;/a>
[4]: &lt;a href="http://watershedfarms.net">http://watershedfarms.net&lt;/a>
That said, I have always been impressed when meeting face-to-face with those in my old organization and in the donor community.  On many levels they are bright, well-intentioned individuals.  So I could never quite put my finger on this divergence.  This piece has filled in many of the gaps for me.  So without further introduction, here is the piece.
[![][6]][6]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=394">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=394&lt;/a>
[![][7]][7]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=395">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=395&lt;/a>
[![][8]][8]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=396">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=396&lt;/a>
[![][9]][9]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=397">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=397&lt;/a>
[![][10]][10]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=398">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=398&lt;/a>
[![][11]][11]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=399">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=399&lt;/a>
[![][12]][12]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=400">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=400&lt;/a>
[![][13]][13]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=401">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=401&lt;/a>
[![][14]][14]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=402">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=402&lt;/a>
[![][15]][15]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=403">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=403&lt;/a>
[![][16]][16]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=404">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=404&lt;/a>
[![][17]][17]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=405">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=405&lt;/a>
[![][18]][18]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=406">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=406&lt;/a>
[![][19]][19]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=407">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=407&lt;/a>
[![][20]][20]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=408">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=408&lt;/a>
[![][21]][21]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=409">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=409&lt;/a>
~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Uncle will Teach your Face Off</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-04-21-my-uncle-will-teach-your-face-off/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-04-21-my-uncle-will-teach-your-face-off/</guid><description>&lt;p>[]&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/neioaD7ibPU&amp;amp;hl=en" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">1&lt;/a>
~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Navy Teaches Old Missiles New Tricks</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-21-navy-teaches-old-missiles-new-tricks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-21-navy-teaches-old-missiles-new-tricks/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m not sure why, but this whole deal fascinates me.  The Navy re-programmed its intercept missiles (which were built to intercept anti-ship missiles launched from Russian planes in the event of full scale war against the Soviets) to take out satellites in space.  Maybe it is my love of Spies Like Us, but if it only took the Navy three weeks to perform the software calibration on these things then that means that it either wasn’t that complicated or that they had been working on it for much longer than they are releasing.  My theory is that it isn’t that complicated, because satellites should be easier to track and know where they are in 3-Ds then missiles launched.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Link: &lt;a href="http://blog.foreignpolicy.com/node/8212" title="Navy teaches old missiles new tricks | FP Passport">Navy teaches old missiles new tricks | FP Passport&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>leaving&amp;#8230;on a jet plane</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-10-05-leaving-on-a-jet-plane/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-10-05-leaving-on-a-jet-plane/</guid><description>&lt;p>in case you had not heard or i have been negligent in letting you know, i will be heading to sierra leone next semester to work with &lt;a href="http://www.sc-sl.org/">the special court for sierra leone&lt;/a>. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>it looks like i’ll be working on either pre-trial stuff, trial work (assisting not arguing, obviously) or post-trial appellate level work.  at this point we are not sure and it will depend upon the dynamics of the situation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i will be getting credit for my work there so there are no problems with my ability to graduate on time, and most importantly I’M GOING TO SIERRA LEONE.  i’ll be abroad from january until june.  i’m not sure what will be happening for the summer, we’ll just have to see.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>what does the court do:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>        The Special Court for Sierra&lt;br>
        Leone was set up jointly by the Government of Sierra Leone and the&lt;br>
        United Nations. It is mandated to try those who bear the greatest&lt;br>
        responsibility for serious violations of international humanitarian law&lt;br>
        and Sierra Leonean law committed in the territory of Sierra Leone since&lt;br>
        30 November 1996.&lt;br>
       &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Currently,&lt;br>
eleven persons associated with all three of the country’s former&lt;br>
warring factions stand indicted by the Special Court. They are charged&lt;br>
with war crimes, crimes against humanity, and other serious violations&lt;br>
of international humanitarian law. Specifically, the charges include&lt;br>
murder, rape, extermination, acts of terror, enslavement, looting and&lt;br>
burning, sexual slavery, conscription of children into an armed force,&lt;br>
and attacks on United Nations peacekeepers and humanitarian workers,&lt;br>
among others. Indictments against two other persons were withdrawn in&lt;br>
December 2003 due to the deaths of the accused.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>that is what they do.  needless to say, i’m quite stoked about the opportunity to make a god damn difference.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>wolf v. deer</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-23-wolf-v-deer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-23-wolf-v-deer/</guid><description>&lt;p>i’ve been busy.  but i’ve meant to write this story for a while.  last week when i was in the woods i saw the coolest thing i’ve ever seen in the backcountry and maybe the coolest thing i’ve seen — ever!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i was on an early morning hike to the top of this mountain.  the first part of the hike i could tell was about three or four miles of a fairly even, though uphill, approach to the mountain part.  it was shaded by many varietals of nice evergreens that i did not know what their latin or american or aboretal names were.  douglas firs?  pine bark fingerlings?  beetle upchuck prostitutes?  i never know these things.  i never have.  although one of the things that i did resolve was to become a better naturalist.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>that is all beside the point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>so i was walking on this approach with just me and my camelback containing my sketchbook, a pen, an apple and some water.  it was completely peaceful as i was nearing the end of the timbered approach.  it was late enough that the birds were not as active as they had been nearer the beginning of the hike.  it was still early enough that the bugs were not out in the few meadows that i had passed through.  all in all quiet and beautiful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i was walking along and heard a CRACK up ahead.  i was a bit startled at first, but then i realized that the brook that i was walking beside contained a waterfall just ahead of me.  i heard the distinct waterfall noise after the crack.  i discounted the crack as the waterfall carrying a stick down it and breaking it.  i’ve seen it happen; water is an amazingly powerful substance (the floods in the NE prove that, inter alia!).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i took about three more steps before i heard another, louder CRACK.  i looked up.  this confirmed that it must be an animal moving around.  this did not really bother me.  already on the trip i had seen elk, deer, foxes, bears and other, smaller rodents and marmots.  i saw a deer running parallel to my direction.  &lt;em>that’s cool.  a deer is running.&lt;/em>  i thought.  but then i wondered what he/she was running to/from.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>it was probably just spooked by something&lt;/em>, i was still too far away to have been the instrument of the spooking.  so it wasn’t me, but i didn’t put things together quickly enough.  i walked two or three more steps before i could see the full flank of the deer running.  before i had only caught a glimpse of it before it had gone behind some foliage. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>then i saw a flash of gray.  i was not really sure what it was going on so i just stood statutesquely. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>the gray and the deer were both running and then they turned and started running down the trail TOWARDS ME.  they came around the corner of the trail and down the straightaway towards me.  the corner was about 20 yards away and there it was, a gray WOLF and a deer.  the wolf was snarling. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>now i know that it was a wolf because there have been some releases in this part of colorado within the past five years as they try to capitalize on the popularity that was created by the repopulation efforts that happened up by cam in jackson a while ago.  plus i could see the fucking thing.  its face was a wolf’s face.  it was not a fox.  it was not a dog. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>he looked mean as he ran.  there was the snarling and the full force of its momentum as it came careening down the fucking trail, RIGHT AT ME.  i was not scared.  i was petrified, but not out of fear.  out of concern.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>see the wolf was being chased by the deer.  i’m not fucking around.  the deer was chasing the wolf.  it was the craziest, most disney-worthy scene.  bambi’s mama had her head low as she ran chasing that wolf.  there was a cacophonous shattering of my peace and i couldn’t really make out all the noises but it sounded like the deer was grunting.  i’m not sure if i was hearing things, or merely not able to separate all the sounds that were going on.  there was lots of crashing and thrashing and grunting and snarling.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>so these two animals were both obviously scared out of their minds.  this is what i was thinking about as they came running towards me.  i did not want to move and startle them further.  maybe they would form an unholy alliance and attack me together, the wolf turning my calfs into roast beef for bambi’s herbivorous conversion while the deer grunted and head butted my chest into tender loin shanks for the wolf to breakfast upon.  so i continued to stand there with my nueroses rock-solid in order to minimize my inpact upon the situation. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>plus i like to leave no trace when i’m in the backcountry.  the trace i’d like to leave the least is some of my body parts on the trail or in the form of wolf scat. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>when they were within twenty feet of me the wolf took a hard right turn.  his swift ninety degree turn was a big quick for the deer that was chasing him, but bambi’s mom made the turn quick enough.  i continued to stand still while they started to do large laps and circles around me. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>for no less than two minutes, one-hundred and twenty seconds, i stood there in full rapture of nature’s embracing of irony.  i did not really know what to do.  wolves are pack animals.  so did the gray phantom of jack london fame have mates (victorian version) or mates (aussie version) around that were up on the woods surrounding me, waiting for me to make my move.  but if these repopulations were just isolated animals or couples than it is likely that there would not be another around and that this guy was on his own.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>in either case i had to wait, at a minimum, until they left my immediate vicinity.  when they did and they were doing laps on the other side of the creek, i started stepping out of there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>running would be a bad idea, obviously.  maybe the wolf would abandon its hunger for bambi and suddenly acquire a hunger for casey.  running would only incite his BIOS to chase and chomp.  but i wanted to get out of the area nonetheless for assorted reasons that are likely to be self-evident based upon the above discourse, so i walked quickly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i finished the rest of the approach without incident and began to walk up the main part of the mountain.  it was not a technical climb, it was merely a hike.  most of it was littered with high altitude grasses and flowers of the eidelwies variety.   i refrained from performing julie andrews impersonations. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>the top part of the mountain was very shaley.  lots of them were very loosely forming the top of the mountain.  the view was one of the most incredible i’ve seen in colorado or anywhere else.  the sky was a deep blue, there were at least twelve high mountain lakes that i could see.  there were four rivers that i could see.  i could see higher mountains from steamboat springs (i think) to vail (i’m pretty sure) along the corridor where the road runs between the two.  there were flowers and rocks and grasses.  a few minutes before topping out i saw a few mountain goats doing there thing.  they were like mine, a family of four.  although it is hard to imagine my father lithely jumping tenuous rocks as if they were our living room mexican tiles firmly grouted into a cement floor, but you can only stretch the metaphors so far.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i signed the summit log and started to head back down.  i wanted to find a shelter from the biting wind to stop and eat my apple.  before i had a chance i heard some howls.  i was positive that they were wolf howls.  they definitely were not coyotes, i know what those sound like from when those fucking rodents used to get too close to our shit when i lived in the stumps.  foxes don’t really make noises.  i guess they could have been wild dogs, but those are not really prevalent in colorado.  so i’m quite certain that there had been a pack. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>i began to fantasize that the howls were rebukes for the wolf that i had seen earlier was a young warrior who was out on walkabout and to prove his manhood and be deemed a warrior of the pack he had to bring back a bambi, or a casey, and the howls were not howls of joys for the iniation rites had become complete and now it was a festive afternoon in the woods.  i thought that the howls were darker than that.  eventually the wolf must have failed and was returning.  the rest of the pack was less worried about not being able to eat as they were in the failure of the young man.  now what were they to do with him?  put him with the squaws to boil water and grind meal, i decided.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>the rest of the day went by quickly, except for on the descent when i passed near the place i was sure to perform the julie andrews renditions that i had avoided singing from the mountaintops.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>end of the week</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-21-end-of-the-week/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-21-end-of-the-week/</guid><description>&lt;p>i will have something for your consumption after the weekend.  am off tomorrow for the woods.  i am writing (pen and paper) much of what i’ve worked on so far.  i think that i like what i’ve produced so far.  i’ll have it up for your consumption if you wish after the weekend.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>audi 500.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>girl scouts</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-02-14-girl-scouts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-02-14-girl-scouts/</guid><description>&lt;p>mom,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i’m kind of pissed at you.  all those years growing up.  all those tables in front of wal-mart.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>how in the hell did we miss out on thin mints.  they’re so good.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>mock trial</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-01-21-mock-trial/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-01-21-mock-trial/</guid><description>&lt;p>so this weekend past we did our mock trial competition.  yale did phenomenally well.  she made it past the preliminaries and is now in the final four (she and her partner found out today). &lt;/p>
&lt;p>team korea (my team) didn’t champion the effort to the extent that their girlfriends did.  i was really pissed about it for a while.  much of that came from the inherrent pressure that is always present, pushing upon my insides from my outsides.  but once i got past this i really started to unpack the dissappointment i realized that much of my dissappointment was because when i didn’t know the procedural possibilities i felt handcuffed. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>see, we knew the arguments to make, i did fine in torts.  but i didn’t know how to make them.  i cannot just pick up a manual and learn something.  i need to be empowered by seeing something happen in front of me. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>so i have decided to run to run the thing next year. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>the major thing that i want to change is to push the preliminaries back a week.  it was pretty harsh to have it the first weekend when we got back, a weekend we all wanted to enjoy.  but during that first weekend back i would put on a seminar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>the optional seminar will empower people like me to really dig deep.  by giving them the tools that they didn’t have before it will allow them to make some really good arguments. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>i’m planning to run the seminar the way i’ve learned to teach people.  edip style.  explain, demonstrate, immitate, practice.  start with some classes on (how to question, speculation, hearsay, entering evidence, decorum essentials, opens/closes, tactical/strategy basics), followed by part of trial that we would demonstrate for them.  then i’d break the students into small groups and let the 1l’s coach them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>this will empower people like me that know the arguments to make but get a little handicapped because they don’t know how to make it.  it will also level the playing field.  many of the people who advanced (reference yale) had parents that were lawyers or had mock trial experience.  that i’m not as much worried about.  the main thing that i thought was disparate was the level of coaching that some people recieved after the first trial and were so much better during the second one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>if you can move the coaching up front i think that people will get much more out of it.  i have a lot yet to work on this.  more to come.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>first chances</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-01-14-first-chances/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-01-14-first-chances/</guid><description>&lt;p>today will be my first chance to litigate.  we’ll see how mock trial goes&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>in the time of snow patrols I was a monkey</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-01-13-in-the-time-of-snow-patrols-i-was-a-monkey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-01-13-in-the-time-of-snow-patrols-i-was-a-monkey/</guid><description>&lt;p>so returning wasn’t nearly as difficult as i thought it would be.  i just hopped in the car and left my paradices.  i might have purposefully made some subconscious hedge by going to jackson first and then leaving the west.  easing my way out of the hot tub by sitting on the side with only your feet in before you race into the house over the snow littered deck….?  not sure. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>only thing is that this week has been vicious.  luckily i when i was called on i was prepared the the guy she called on before me is an idiot so i turned out looking stellar and she didn’t really press me too hard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>in other news, i’ve been thinking a lot about how we all throttle our lives.  many of my friends, the younger ones anyway, don’t really know what is going on with this.  all they have ever known is school where you’re always on, always moving, always going going going.  but it has been a long time for me personally since i was in such an environment (obviously before last august).  i’m not sure how i feel about it.  for one thing it definitely makes the time go by quickly.  this is a post for another chapter, but i thing that my fear of losing out on things lines up here well to create my abject hatred of routines, cause you don’t see things in the same way.  but back to the point, the quickly thing is helpful when you’re not engaged in the most desirous of experiences.  i guess there is something to be said.  maybe not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>mock trial competition preliminaries are this weekend.  grades come out on tuesday.  we’ll just see!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>homer</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-10-19-homer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-10-19-homer/</guid><description>&lt;p>go home puppies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>dreamin&amp;#8217;</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-09-20-dreamin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-09-20-dreamin/</guid><description>&lt;p>last night i had this extremely lucid dream where one of my eyebrows was gone and the other was super bushy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>think that it means that i’m betraying my fair and balanced-ness and putting too much time into one area of my life.  the unfortunate thing is that isn’t going to change for many many years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>sometimes i’ll be in class or reading and have this really weird sensation creep through and past me, surreal visions of oak and courtrooms and i think i’m going to be doing this? &lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Old Men Rule?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-09-04-old-men-rule/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-09-04-old-men-rule/</guid><description>&lt;p>Rule #2 is Old Men Rule.  I have a shirt that says as much on it.  Yes, in those words.  I gaurantee you’ve seen it.  There is an interesting duality when I where it to school those as most people now know that I’m older than them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rule #3 is Work Smarter not Harder.  In that vein I give you a reply to another email.  A friend asked me what I thought about the distinct age difference between myself and those I now find myself surrounded by.  I give you that question below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And now in celebration of my 29th Birthday:  A Treatise on Age&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I am conflicted in my thoughts on the age issue.  Considering the&lt;br>
backdrop of life in general and this especially being a competition (no&lt;br>
matter how many times the professors try to mantra into me that vandy&lt;br>
is a &amp;ldquo;collegial atmosphere,&amp;rdquo; its still a fucking competition…..) I&lt;br>
think that it is mostly to my &amp;ldquo;advantage,&amp;rdquo; although there are a few&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;disadvantages.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My view of much of my class is fairly close to what I expected:  greek,&lt;br>
business or poli sci majors, straight from college, clicky, etc.  In&lt;br>
the two weeks we’ve been together now I have watched the stratification&lt;br>
of this formerly nebulous mixture o people into their respective&lt;br>
pieces, or more appropriately how they have viewed themselves&lt;br>
throughout their undergraduate experience.  This is a carryover for&lt;br>
these people, a mere continuation.  I can tell it by the way they talk&lt;br>
about drinking by the away messages they leave on their AIM accounts by&lt;br>
the ease which they flow around the building with their computer bags&lt;br>
yanking at their trapezious muscles. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are a few exceptions to the rules, those that are not greek,&lt;br>
those with interesting majore, those that took the vaunted one year&lt;br>
off, but by and large these exceptions are only in one category and&lt;br>
those that exhibit these exceptions fall into line on the other&lt;br>
categories. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are a few others.  I know of two with masters (one that has his&lt;br>
MFA in creative writing and with whom I have had many chats), and one&lt;br>
other guy who is older than me.  He is married with a couple of kids,&lt;br>
etc. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then there is me.  I’m not yet sure how I fit into the social spectrum,&lt;br>
cream or juice?  I, frankly, do not care.  I’m equally nice and equally&lt;br>
ass-holic to most people which stems from the fact that I feel that I&lt;br>
have much less vested in the social aspect of this school scenario.&lt;br>
I’ve been in the real world, I know what it is like to spend entire&lt;br>
months only talking to one or two people, none of that ever bothered&lt;br>
me.  But many of these people do not know that freedom and so they tie&lt;br>
much of their identity up in the social dynamics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This vestiture creates some interesting things.  Firstly, I think it&lt;br>
creates in many a fear of &amp;ldquo;being called on&amp;rdquo; by the professors.  In the&lt;br>
socratic method professors will pick out a student and then stick with&lt;br>
them for a while asking question after question, hopefully breaking off&lt;br>
the outside skin of the onion and distilling the truth out of the&lt;br>
specificity of the case…..specificity to generality is the law school&lt;br>
mantra (mixing of metaphors was on purpose).  But this method is&lt;br>
generally frightening to many people b/c their brainpower will be laid&lt;br>
out there for all their social comrades to see if they’re an idiot or&lt;br>
surprisingly mentally adroit.  Secondly, I think it creates a dynamic&lt;br>
similar to high school.  We are around the same people, in the same&lt;br>
building, all the time.  What I mean by the high school simile (which&lt;br>
is far from unique) is merely the constancy of display.  You can’t blow&lt;br>
up at someone without the rest of the class finding out about it&lt;br>
quickly and then they will all look at you, look at you in class, look&lt;br>
at you in the halls on the way to the lockers, look at you in the cafe&lt;br>
during lunch, look at you in the library after class when much of our&lt;br>
compatriots are in the same large room with big tables that always&lt;br>
makes me think that I’m in the study hall from Dead Poet’s Society and&lt;br>
that cranky teacher is going to come in at any moment and make me turn&lt;br>
off my iPod and study harder.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So the rest of them are very vested.  I’m not.  I don’t give a flying&lt;br>
rat fuck about any of that stuff.  I’m here to spend $60k a year to&lt;br>
learn stuff, and I’ll learn it well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The life experience aspect of it all is the other advantage that I&lt;br>
hold, the only one that really matters (I think) besides the &amp;ldquo;not&lt;br>
caring about what people think of me&amp;rdquo; advantage.  In classes where you&lt;br>
are nearly required to have a perspective on the world and you can only&lt;br>
conceptually create one it builds an idealist when a realist would do.&lt;br>
These are all advantages and I won’t belabor the point, even though it&lt;br>
is a valid one.  I understand business in a way they don’t.  I&lt;br>
understand politics in a way they don’t.  I understand foreign&lt;br>
relations, and constitutional powers and the mind of evil people in a&lt;br>
way they don’t.  But none of that matters now.  Right now we’ve all&lt;br>
been thrown blindfolded, tied up, and dowsed in K-Y into the pool and&lt;br>
are merely trying to get our bearings without the lube making our eyes&lt;br>
sting.  We’ll just have to see how this all pans out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main disadvantage is the being used to the school deal and the&lt;br>
knowing how to study deals…..&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Happy Birthday to me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reasons</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-09-03-reasons/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-09-03-reasons/</guid><description>&lt;p>A friend asked me why I’m here.  This was the best I could come up with:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I DID decide to come to law school for an assundry of reasons.  I don’t&lt;br>
ever see myself becoming one of &amp;ldquo;those&amp;rdquo; lawyers to whom you refer.&lt;br>
That has never been my style, I like to save my fights for something I&lt;br>
care about, not things that don’t really matter.  One of the very few&lt;br>
things that I think that I’ve learned in life is the difference&lt;br>
therein, what matters and what doesn’t matter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But back to my reasons.  They are many, but they basically came down to&lt;br>
a failure to finalize the next deal and give myself some assurances&lt;br>
that the writing career was going to launch for real.  When I found&lt;br>
that out then it was still not an easy choice.  For a long time I&lt;br>
thought that coming here and doing this was a complete compromise of a&lt;br>
value system that I had steadily developed over my two year repose in&lt;br>
bum land.  Arguably creating a value system while you are bumming is&lt;br>
not really a sane thing to do b/c it would inherently serve merely to&lt;br>
propagate that lifestyle.  That conceded, I think I constructed it&lt;br>
fairly lucidly.  And I believed in it, but I came here&lt;br>
notwithstanding. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have realized over the course of the last two weeks that I am not&lt;br>
violating that value system by being here.  I am probably still within&lt;br>
that bounds of that value system.  I had been so focused on law&lt;br>
school=debt=need for financial assurances=selling out to the firm&lt;br>
lifestyle=doing stuff that I don’t want to do and living in a place I&lt;br>
don’t want to live.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My epiphany has come in regards to the end of the chain of logic.  It&lt;br>
doesn’t necessarily follow that I will have to do stuff that I don’t&lt;br>
want to do, in fact if I play my cards correctly there are a lot of&lt;br>
really tool things that you can do.  And plus, NYC isn’t Aspen but I’ve&lt;br>
always wanted to live there just like I have always wanted to live on&lt;br>
vacation.  So in fact they are the same thing (the environments) they&lt;br>
just embrace different aspects of my complicated desire spectrum.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Whatever.  The point is that I really felt like a fucking failure when&lt;br>
I came here, like a sellout, but now I’m realizing that I’m certainly&lt;br>
not a failure and as long as I don’t sellout I’m not a sellout. &lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>So for whatever it is worth there it is.  I have some blogging to do this weekend.  There are some things and thoughts to share, we’ll get around to this thing Yet.  Don’t fret.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>into or out of the mist</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-08-24-into-or-out-of-the-mist/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-08-24-into-or-out-of-the-mist/</guid><description>&lt;p>i’m unsure of where this blog entry will go.  i know that i want it to go somewhere &amp;ldquo;somewhere great&amp;rdquo; [in a patronizing voice].  but i’m not sure where that great will be.  i guess that could be a metaphor for my life.  for my desires towards women, for my desires towards fulfillment, for my desires, for my life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>when did i become so unsure of myself?  i have always had direction, drive, determination, focus, goals and all that zig zigler shit.  and now?  now i cannot even understand what the fuck i’m doing spending $150k on an education that i only want to marginally (at best) use.  i like it, don’t get me wrong.  it is challenging and collegial and academic and all that crap, but is it correct.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>for the first time in over 10 days i actually had some time.  whether i’ve been moving or settling or entering into new social interactions (meeting new people, yaddy yadda) or figuring out the class load or remembering how to study, or whatever.  i’ve been fucking rush rush rush for the past while.  that more so than the fact that i’m here is what is really compromising the value system that i had established for myself over two years of claiming to be an artist.  but what was really lacking was time.  time to think, time to analyze, time to examine, time to be.  i haven’t looked deeply at anything other than what the fuck this dude means when he says &amp;ldquo;stare decisis is crap and i say that stare principiis should reign supreme&amp;rdquo; for whatever that is worth. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>today i finished my work up while at school and came home and worked out and then had some time before eric and i were to run to dinner and i just sat on the couch (laid) and thought and listened to some music and just was.  i had a moment of reconciliation where i realized that this is just like anything else.  it isn’t different, it may be new, but it is the fucking same.  i need to treat it the same.  i need to stop looking at the face value of my experience and remember what i have learned over the course of these past years since i returned from combat.  i have to analyze what the fuck is important in the manner.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>today i realized that i was thinking exactly what the teacher was wanting me to think.  like a fish hooked on the lip being drug to the left and then to the right.  i could fight, but i was still at her mercy.  but it is the one class, the one and only true intellectual endeavor which i will experience this year.  i cannot let myself do that.  i have to think either faster or slower than she wants be to think.  i have to go anti-ocsillitory she keeps us running back and forth back and forth and i need that to end for me.  i need to rage against the machine, at least in that class. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>i expressed these sentiments to a few people in between that class and another and they looked at me like i was courtney love exiting church in a long ann taylor dress.  nevertheless that is how it has to be.  i have to think more, act less, be more efficient.  but more than all of that i just have to be who i am, and not who any of these professors want me to become.  &amp;ldquo;we’re here to teach you to think like a lawyer&amp;rdquo; is OK except for when i don’t want to think like a lawyer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>but will that be inevitable?  i’m unsure.  what will i be LIKE at the end of this process.  we’ll all have to find that out together.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>