<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/</link><description>A Site About Resilience and Authoritarianism</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</managingEditor><webMaster>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</webMaster><copyright>All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Day in My Life: Somaliland Edition</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-01-29-day-in-life-somaliland/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-01-29-day-in-life-somaliland/</guid><description>&lt;p>The other day, my dad asked me to write a short piece about what my daily life is like in Somaliland. I usually refrain from such things, but I think it is a good opportunity to show how &lt;em>normal&lt;/em> everything is here. With a few caveats.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![Office Guest Suite][2]][2]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I generally awake between 9 and 10. Although this is late for a work day, if you read to the end you’ll see why. Mostly everyone else is out of the office in the morning either in court or meetings or taking care of personal errands. This is great for me, since I’m a slow waker so I like the peacefulness in the mornings as it lets me wake at a reasonable pace. In many ways the afternoons and mornings are sort of flipped around from life in the US. Things start slowly here for almost everyone. Although I used to have my own house that I rented, these days I’m spending less long stretches in Hargeisa and so we have built a sleeping room here at the office for me to use when I’m here and for the team to use after a late night working when I’m not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![][3]][3]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a freezing cold shower that although painful is effective at getting your juices flowing, I head into our office. I share and office with Hassan, my Vice President, but he is rarely there in the mornings. I like to begin my day with a cup of coffee and some news, as many others do. Here that comes in a flask of Ethiopian coffee my watchman brings from our close Ethiopian tin shack shop and accompanied by my scans of my Google Reader (using Feedly’s skin), Twitter, Facebook, and Tumblr feeds. I generally do a more or less quick scan in the mornings. I read a few smaller articles from my feeds, but I just generally skim the headlines and then mark the longer articles that seem interesting for my Readability queue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After I’m finished with the news, I then usually begin working on whatever lies in front of me. I usually try to start the working day with the mundane admin tasks that don’t require as much thought as my client work. About 12:30 or 1:00 I’ll realize that I’m hungry and ask my watchman to go bring my lunch. We have a hotel about two blocks away that serves a decently nice chicken sandwich and edible fries (which is my typical lunch order). When I reach a stopping point in my work then I take a small break and migrate into our chewing room. This usually involves several trips to get all of the waste baskets in the office, rearrange the cushions in the room, make sure the tea cups and ashtrays are brought in, and also that all my accoutrement is ready.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![Chewing Session][4]][4]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I like to eat in the relaxation of the sitting room while listening to either some music or a podcast. The rest of the gang usually arrives somewhere between 2 and 3. Our majlis is almost always open to people if they are interested in coming to chat with us. The only times we ask people not to come are when we have a meeting planned. On a typical afternoon, we’ll have 7 to 10 people with us for varying lengths of time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![My Chewing Position][5]][5]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chewing sessions are interesting. You make an effort to prepare your spot so everything you’ll need for the next 6 to 12 hours is within your reach. You make sure that your water, your tea, your soft drinks, your fake beer, your chat, your phone, your computer (and cord), your wallet, keys, everything is just around you. At our office, we developed a habit of using our wastebaskets as small tables for our laptops. It works fantastically as the laptop doesn’t overhead and when you’re sitting on the floor it is at a really good height so your back does not get jarred. Also it is quite easy to move when you are changing the way that you sit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chewing sessions generally start quite festive and then steadily deteriorate into quietness. Everyone usually is chatting at the beginning, or reading some news, or checking their facebook. Then after everyone is more or less settled in they begin work. In many offices, not only ours, the real work takes place at chewing sessions. Although many expats in Hargeisa are very much against qat (for admittedly valid reasons) the argument that it makes people lazy I simply don’t buy. For me, it focuses me and I actually work quite well when I’ve had a normal dosage of qat. The high you get from qat, if one can even call it a high, is very subtle and take a long time to settle in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some people join us but do not have work that day so they will chat or listen to Somali songs or watch TV depending on their moods. The rest of us either put on headphones or we just listen as we are working. It is not unlike a co-working space.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The great thing about a chewing session is that when you need a break or if you have a question you just ask or you just visit with people. If something comes on the news people will generally discuss. If there had been a big political incident earlier that day it will get analyzed in detail. And sometimes people will just work or chat on facebook. It is a very relaxed environment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Usually people leave between 9 and 10. At this point in the night, I’m usually getting my best work done and so I will often stay going until about 2 or 3 when I snoozily saunter to the sleeping room. Then the cycle starts all over again. So that’s a typical Somaliland day. With a few pictures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![Chewing Session 2][6]][6]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On Transparency &amp;amp; Openness in Organizational Behavior</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-27-transparency-openness-organizational-behavior/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-27-transparency-openness-organizational-behavior/</guid><description>&lt;p>I run a law firm in Somaliland, or what National Geographic’s map section probably calls Somalia (northern section).  I have been a technophile for a long time; indeed, as long as I can remember I’ve had a computer and used it extensively.  To me at least, many of my “mentors” for creating an organization are companies which are currently operating in the technology sector rather than in the legal sector.  These tech companies seem to have organizational philosophies that excite me.  Although one can never know for sure without having a deeper glimpse inside the company than what they allow one to glimpse from the outside, many of these companies give customers and potential customers an opportunity to view them deeper than we have likely ever seen before for corporate behavior.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is a huge part of me which appreciates this from a consumer point of view.  It makes it easier to do your task management when you “feel” as if you “like” the program you are using and even better when you feel as if you “know” something about those who made it, where they are trying to go with it, etc.  It enables a feeling of community and communal interest even though I’m here in Somaliland and they may be thousands of miles away.  This interactivity is powerful when applied to corporate behavior as it allows companies to leverage the increased loyalty and interactivity found in small community-based businesses with the scales of economy found in large MNC’s.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many times being open is more efficient than being closed.  It is also quite efficient to tag and publish your links in a way that allows your team and your community to see them.  I mean everyone will keep current with news, analysis, etc. within their sector.  Pushing those links into the semi-public team spaces and public community spaces with the click of one button.  Why not?  At the end of the day it saves you more time than having to break these tasks of media consumption, team discussion, and marketing into individual blocks.  Crowdsourcing is another great example of openness’s links to efficiency.  See &lt;a href="http://weijiblog.com/2010/10/62-diaspora-and-kickstarter/">this&lt;/a> great entry from the &lt;a href="http://weijiblog.com/">weijiblog&lt;/a> as an example of what I’m talking about.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All this is well and good.  But there are a few tensions which any organization must be aware of.  These areas should pull you back from a 100% open business if they apply to your situation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="confidentiality--duh">Confidentiality – Duh&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The most obvious tension with openness that we, and other professional services companies, face is that of client confidentiality.  As lawyers we have to put in an extremely rigid firewall between the reception area and the back area of our online presence.  Discussing what we are working on today is a no-go if it is anything whatsoever to do with client activity.  Sure I use &lt;a href="http://foursquare.com/compleatang">foursquare&lt;/a> and many times it check-in when I’m making sales calls.  But I never do it when I’m having a client meeting.  Sure I blog, tweet, etc.  But never about client matters.  Ancillary to client matters is even a personal no-go area.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Each individual professional organization and each professional within that organization will be subjected to their own specific confidentiality requirements.  Many lawyers get around these by blogging anonymously but still revealing many confidential facts of a case simply by hiding in plain sight and not mentioning names.  While this may work for them, I have personally chosen a different path.  I prefer to blog publicly using my real given name and simply not put into the public space those things which I’m required (and would anyway even if I wasn’t required) to maintain as confidential.  I see the value in the humor of some blogs I read by public defenders or other practitioners.  But I would never write one.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="areas-of-strategic-advantage">Areas of Strategic Advantage&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The less obvious tension with openness is that of commodification of those areas where your organization has a distinct strategic advantage.  This is something which I struggle with more.  Operating where we operate and having the research base which we have built and having the connections which we have has taken a lot of time and a lot of work.  It isn’t the easiest place to live and it certainly isn’t the easiest place to operate.  But nevertheless, we are making it work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a strategic advantage for our firm.  We are well connected abroad and locally.  We have a deeper understanding that probably any organization in the world as to the current state of the Somaliland legal system.  So there is a huge tension for me when it comes to this area.  On the one hand, I truly believe that laws should be published by the governments which pass them.  This information needs to be public and freely available to all those who may be subjected to its provisions.  But the reality is that the Somaliland government has not done this.  We do have all of the applicable laws, but we have had to find many of them.  Some we even had to pay some money to acquire.  So when a lawyer from abroad emails to ask about this law or that law and if we can send it to them I struggle to find the proper answer.  While we are building our firm we need to leverage each of the strategic advantages which we have   Maybe later, when we’re more established and our cash flow is more stable then we can relax and open up a few of the strategic advantages – especially in the area of information vis a vis analysis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is a danger here also which is that if you begin with the habits of holding your cards closer than you optimally may that that habit will become a policy rather than the habit of the beginning organization.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But for now, and for us, it is unlikely that I’m going to give you those things which I have worked very hard to achieve.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Annotated Reading: So THAT is Why I Don&amp;#8217;t Fit In</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-04-annotated-reading-fit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-04-annotated-reading-fit/</guid><description>&lt;p>This week I read a fascinating article which was written by a former high-level DFID individual named Rosalind Eyben.  The title of the piece is, “Hiding Relations: The Irony of ‘Effective Aid.’” It can be found in its entirety [here][2].
[2]: &lt;a href="http://www.oxfamblogs.org/fp2p/wp-content/uploads/ejdr201010a1.pdf">http://www.oxfamblogs.org/fp2p/wp-content/uploads/ejdr201010a1.pdf&lt;/a>
This article spoke to me in a way that not many pieces have recently.  Perhaps it is my transition from an aid receiving NGO worker to the other side of the coin as a private sector social entrepreneur, and the conjunction of the transition with my reading of the article.  Or maybe I am trying to continue to understand a world and a profession which on the surface seems straight-forward (go to Somalia &amp;amp; help) but underneath is complicated, political, and stifles lots of creativity for no reason.
There are many varied reasons for the underlying complications.  Some of the reasons come from other annotated readings that I have put up in the past.  Some of the reasons come from the complications of running world-wide operations with thousands, if not millions of associated partners – not to mentions the hundreds of millions of people involved in the entire operation from politicians, to top-level administrators, to top-level NGO workers, to country-level NGO workers, all the way to the purported beneficiaries of a project.  So, in short, this is a complicated undertaking and requires people who understand complexity theory (an annotated reading which is in the works) and who understand relationships.
The main gist of the piece is that aid should value the relationships which are developed between a recipient population and those individuals mandated with the delivery of the project.  I have always felt that this work requires a complex understanding of the context in which the project is undertaken, and I have always valued the relationships which I have built along the way.  Indeed, the value which I place on those relations is one of the driving forces for my new ventures (see [here][3] and [here][4]).  While I have placed value, as an individual human, on these relationships, I always had this odd feeling whenever I would talk to others within my organization or in donor communities that this was some sort of a remote control SimCity game that had less to do with human beings and more to do with numbers and metrics which never had any application at least in my specific context here in S’land.
[3]: &lt;a href="http://watershedlegal.com">http://watershedlegal.com&lt;/a>
[4]: &lt;a href="http://watershedfarms.net">http://watershedfarms.net&lt;/a>
That said, I have always been impressed when meeting face-to-face with those in my old organization and in the donor community.  On many levels they are bright, well-intentioned individuals.  So I could never quite put my finger on this divergence.  This piece has filled in many of the gaps for me.  So without further introduction, here is the piece.
[![][6]][6]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=394">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=394&lt;/a>
[![][7]][7]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=395">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=395&lt;/a>
[![][8]][8]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=396">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=396&lt;/a>
[![][9]][9]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=397">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=397&lt;/a>
[![][10]][10]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=398">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=398&lt;/a>
[![][11]][11]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=399">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=399&lt;/a>
[![][12]][12]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=400">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=400&lt;/a>
[![][13]][13]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=401">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=401&lt;/a>
[![][14]][14]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=402">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=402&lt;/a>
[![][15]][15]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=403">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=403&lt;/a>
[![][16]][16]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=404">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=404&lt;/a>
[![][17]][17]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=405">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=405&lt;/a>
[![][18]][18]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=406">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=406&lt;/a>
[![][19]][19]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=407">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=407&lt;/a>
[![][20]][20]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=408">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=408&lt;/a>
[![][21]][21]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=409">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=409&lt;/a>
~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>