<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>learning on underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/learning/</link><description>Recent content in learning on underWater desert Blogging</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Casey Kuhlman</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Day in My Life: Somaliland Edition</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2012-01-29-day-in-life-somaliland/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2012-01-29-day-in-life-somaliland/</guid><description>The other day, my dad asked me to write a short piece about what my daily life is like in Somaliland. I usually refrain from such things, but I think it is a good opportunity to show how normal everything is here. With a few caveats.
[![Office Guest Suite][2]][2]
I generally awake between 9 and 10. Although this is late for a work day, if you read to the end you’ll see why.</description></item><item><title>On Transparency &amp;amp; Openness in Organizational Behavior</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-10-27-transparency-openness-organizational-behavior/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-10-27-transparency-openness-organizational-behavior/</guid><description>![She left the Door open via h.koppdelaney @ flickr]({{ site.url }}{{ site.root }}{{ site.images_dir }}/{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; }}/3746675779_ec501685a1.jpg)
I run a law firm in Somaliland, or what National Geographic’s map section probably calls Somalia (northern section). I have been a technophile for a long time; indeed, as long as I can remember I’ve had a computer and used it extensively. To me at least, many of my “mentors” for creating an organization are companies which are currently operating in the technology sector rather than in the legal sector.</description></item><item><title>Annotated Reading: So THAT is Why I Don&amp;#8217;t Fit In</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-06-04-annotated-reading-fit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-06-04-annotated-reading-fit/</guid><description>![Day 123 Screw the imaginary!]({{ site.url }}{{ site.root }}{{ site.images_dir }}/{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; }}/4655741915_c398dfcd7f.jpg) via mariebledeebles @ flickr This week I read a fascinating article which was written by a former high-level DFID individual named Rosalind Eyben. The title of the piece is, “Hiding Relations: The Irony of ‘Effective Aid.’” It can be found in its entirety [here][2]. [2]: http://www.oxfamblogs.org/fp2p/wp-content/uploads/ejdr201010a1.pdf This article spoke to me in a way that not many pieces have recently.</description></item><item><title>My Uncle will Teach your Face Off</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-04-21-my-uncle-will-teach-your-face-off/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-04-21-my-uncle-will-teach-your-face-off/</guid><description>[]1 ~ # ~</description></item><item><title>Navy Teaches Old Missiles New Tricks</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-02-21-navy-teaches-old-missiles-new-tricks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-02-21-navy-teaches-old-missiles-new-tricks/</guid><description>I’m not sure why, but this whole deal fascinates me. The Navy re-programmed its intercept missiles (which were built to intercept anti-ship missiles launched from Russian planes in the event of full scale war against the Soviets) to take out satellites in space. Maybe it is my love of Spies Like Us, but if it only took the Navy three weeks to perform the software calibration on these things then that means that it either wasn’t that complicated or that they had been working on it for much longer than they are releasing.</description></item><item><title>leaving&amp;#8230;on a jet plane</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-10-05-leaving-on-a-jet-plane/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-10-05-leaving-on-a-jet-plane/</guid><description>in case you had not heard or i have been negligent in letting you know, i will be heading to sierra leone next semester to work with the special court for sierra leone. it looks like i’ll be working on either pre-trial stuff, trial work (assisting not arguing, obviously) or post-trial appellate level work. at this point we are not sure and it will depend upon the dynamics of the situation.</description></item><item><title>wolf v. deer</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-06-23-wolf-v-deer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-06-23-wolf-v-deer/</guid><description>i’ve been busy. but i’ve meant to write this story for a while. last week when i was in the woods i saw the coolest thing i’ve ever seen in the backcountry and maybe the coolest thing i’ve seen — ever!
i was on an early morning hike to the top of this mountain. the first part of the hike i could tell was about three or four miles of a fairly even, though uphill, approach to the mountain part.</description></item><item><title>end of the week</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-06-21-end-of-the-week/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-06-21-end-of-the-week/</guid><description>i will have something for your consumption after the weekend. am off tomorrow for the woods. i am writing (pen and paper) much of what i’ve worked on so far. i think that i like what i’ve produced so far. i’ll have it up for your consumption if you wish after the weekend.
audi 500.
~ # ~</description></item><item><title>girl scouts</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-02-14-girl-scouts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-02-14-girl-scouts/</guid><description>mom,
i’m kind of pissed at you. all those years growing up. all those tables in front of wal-mart.
how in the hell did we miss out on thin mints. they’re so good.
~ # ~</description></item><item><title>mock trial</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-01-21-mock-trial/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-01-21-mock-trial/</guid><description>so this weekend past we did our mock trial competition. yale did phenomenally well. she made it past the preliminaries and is now in the final four (she and her partner found out today). team korea (my team) didn’t champion the effort to the extent that their girlfriends did. i was really pissed about it for a while. much of that came from the inherrent pressure that is always present, pushing upon my insides from my outsides.</description></item><item><title>first chances</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-01-14-first-chances/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-01-14-first-chances/</guid><description>today will be my first chance to litigate. we’ll see how mock trial goes
~ # ~</description></item><item><title>in the time of snow patrols I was a monkey</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-01-13-in-the-time-of-snow-patrols-i-was-a-monkey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-01-13-in-the-time-of-snow-patrols-i-was-a-monkey/</guid><description>so returning wasn’t nearly as difficult as i thought it would be. i just hopped in the car and left my paradices. i might have purposefully made some subconscious hedge by going to jackson first and then leaving the west. easing my way out of the hot tub by sitting on the side with only your feet in before you race into the house over the snow littered deck….? not sure.</description></item><item><title>homer</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-10-19-homer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-10-19-homer/</guid><description>go home puppies.
~ # ~</description></item><item><title>dreamin&amp;#8217;</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-09-20-dreamin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-09-20-dreamin/</guid><description>last night i had this extremely lucid dream where one of my eyebrows was gone and the other was super bushy.
think that it means that i’m betraying my fair and balanced-ness and putting too much time into one area of my life. the unfortunate thing is that isn’t going to change for many many years.
sometimes i’ll be in class or reading and have this really weird sensation creep through and past me, surreal visions of oak and courtrooms and i think i’m going to be doing this?</description></item><item><title>Old Men Rule?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-09-04-old-men-rule/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-09-04-old-men-rule/</guid><description>Rule #2 is Old Men Rule. I have a shirt that says as much on it. Yes, in those words. I gaurantee you’ve seen it. There is an interesting duality when I where it to school those as most people now know that I’m older than them.
Rule #3 is Work Smarter not Harder. In that vein I give you a reply to another email. A friend asked me what I thought about the distinct age difference between myself and those I now find myself surrounded by.</description></item><item><title>Reasons</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-09-03-reasons/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-09-03-reasons/</guid><description>A friend asked me why I’m here. This was the best I could come up with:
I DID decide to come to law school for an assundry of reasons. I don’t
ever see myself becoming one of &amp;ldquo;those&amp;rdquo; lawyers to whom you refer.
That has never been my style, I like to save my fights for something I
care about, not things that don’t really matter. One of the very few</description></item><item><title>into or out of the mist</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-08-24-into-or-out-of-the-mist/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-08-24-into-or-out-of-the-mist/</guid><description>i’m unsure of where this blog entry will go. i know that i want it to go somewhere &amp;ldquo;somewhere great&amp;rdquo; [in a patronizing voice]. but i’m not sure where that great will be. i guess that could be a metaphor for my life. for my desires towards women, for my desires towards fulfillment, for my desires, for my life.
when did i become so unsure of myself? i have always had direction, drive, determination, focus, goals and all that zig zigler shit.</description></item></channel></rss>