<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>otherwise on underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/otherwise/</link><description>Recent content in otherwise on underWater desert Blogging</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/otherwise/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Book Inscription</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012-02-03-book-inscription/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012-02-03-book-inscription/</guid><description>Here’s to the embarkation on a great journey. Here’s to a massive flop or a spectacular success. Here’s to nothing in between. Here’s to risk. Here’s to reward. Here’s to taking a chance. Here’s to never being satisfied with what is. Here’s to questioning. Here’s to listening. Here’s to excellence. Here’s to professionalism. Here’s to helping everywhere we can in every way we can to everyone we can. Here’s to solving problems. Here’s to trust in unwavering allies. And most of all. Here’s doing our best to impact in those we touch in some small way that truly speaking tomorrow is going to be a better day.</description></item><item><title>Decoding the Somali Mind: A Guide for Expats (Anecdotal, Not Definitive Version): Responsibility</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010-10-18-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-responsibility/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010-10-18-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-responsibility/</guid><description>This is a new series containing a few stories which have stood out in my time here in Somaliland and have helped me to understand a bit more a culture that in many ways is very different from my own, but in many ways is not. This series explores those differences. This entry is about relationships in Somaliland.</description></item><item><title>What I Do Before Work</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010-10-15-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010-10-15-work/</guid><description>My morning workflow. Generally I do the following two things before I shower and get ready. With my coffee pot in hand, I usually begin with a news sweep followed by responding to shorter messages that came in while I was sleeping. The specifics are in the post.</description></item><item><title>Decoding the Somali Mind: A Guide for Expats (Anecdotal, Not Definitive Version): Wants v. Needs</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010-06-28-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-v/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010-06-28-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-v/</guid><description>This is a new series containing a few stories which have stood out in my time here in Somaliland and have helped me to understand a bit more a culture that in many ways is very different from my own, but in many ways is not. This series explores those differences. This entry is about relationships in Somaliland.</description></item><item><title>Decoding the Somali Mind: A Guide for Expats (Anecdotal, Not Definitive Version): Introduction</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010-06-21-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010-06-21-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version/</guid><description>A new series from underWater desert Blogging which attempts to bridge some distinct cultural differences via a storytelling format. This is the introduction entry.</description></item><item><title>Happy Dad&amp;#8217;s Day!</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010-06-20-happy-dads-day/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010-06-20-happy-dads-day/</guid><description>I sit here in my house in Hargeisa and reflect upon the fact that I'm missing yet another holiday far away from my father and trying to justify why to myself, the only thing that makes sense is to put on some of my dad's favorite songs.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010-02-11-15/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010-02-11-15/</guid><description>Beaker Twitter = Hilarity. HT – Frank</description></item><item><title>Piling it On.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008-06-13-piling-it-on/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008-06-13-piling-it-on/</guid><description>Consider me another addition!  From [Ben Smith][1]:</description></item><item><title>Bo Videos</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007-06-12-bo-videos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007-06-12-bo-videos/</guid><description>These are some videos we shot while upcountry in SL.</description></item><item><title>one more reason</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006-06-12-one-more-reason/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006-06-12-one-more-reason/</guid><description>i’m forgetting another salient reason:  i’d have to shave my face and head.  and i look too good in long hair to do that again.  ever.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005-08-05-251/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005-08-05-251/</guid><description>am reading kundera for the first time.  it is outlandish.  i’m learning so fucking much.  and i don’t even know czech to read it in the original.  am going to reread this flipping thing as soon as i finish it b/c there is too much here.  there are two basic things that i’m learning from him.  first, how to weave a narrative outside of time.  this thing is like a tarratino flick in that he likes to tell the story along certain lines other than a linear (based on time) slide.  there is organization here and i haven’t quite figured it out.  it isn’t completely, merely, just thematical separation, although there is an element of that.  it isn’t just isolated on one character out of the four in this particular section, b/c how can you tell the story of one without another.  and that is the point.  there is the essence of perspective, and i’m not completely unconvinced that he isn’t using each section to change perspective, but not exclusively, in other words he is not limiting himself to that.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005-07-21-252/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005-07-21-252/</guid><description>am i on a treadmill or actually road running.  cannot tell.  hopefully will know something soon</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005-07-20-253/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005-07-20-253/</guid><description>went and saw the young dubliners tonight at the little club in town.  the open band was called the saucy monkeys.  or something of the sort.  they were two artsy chicks with acoustic guitars.  for some reason i was reminded of the two chicas who opened for bush in 94 when i saw them with eric in orlando.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005-07-18-254/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005-07-18-254/</guid><description>the following things happened during my evening hike today:  i was startled by a fairly large brown bear when i rounded the corner and there he/she was 15 yards from me.  luckily she/he sauntered off.  i gave blood to the mosquito blood bank of the roaring fork valley….don’t they know i’ve been given the anthrax and small pox vaccinations and cannot give blood for another five years.  i startled a beaver and he made a pop sound with his tail and for a while i couldn’t figure out what had happened until i saw his dam and his house, which were directly in front of me the entire time.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005-04-07-255/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005-04-07-255/</guid><description>does anyone else wonder what happens when you actually blast one of the ipod’s?  does it show up at your doorstep in a couple of days with a &amp;lsquo;thanks for playing our carnival game&amp;rsquo; note on the inside of the cubic apple box?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005-04-05-256/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005-04-05-256/</guid><description>the pope passing on is significant.  i wonder how much of that significance will be lost on the seventh-day adventist church because of its complete anti-catholicism stance.  or will it perhaps spawn a thought process, one of reevaluation of that stance.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005-03-29-257/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005-03-29-257/</guid><description>i feel sated. a snake on a warm spring afternoon curled on a sandstone deposit, belly full of mouse, jaw reattached, water near, people and mongeese far.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005-03-26-258/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005-03-26-258/</guid><description>today i shall bew bland and newsy b/c i’m too warped to be funny and too jaded to be artsy.  i feel like complete shit today for no real reason.  last night was a our big, the ski season’s almost over fuckers party.  as per my usual i got on the near side of trashed, just coherent enough to convince many others that i’m not trashed and just trashed enough to through out my ensemble of social conditionings, self-loathings and general wallflowerness.  then i went home with a woman.  nothing happened, as half-way home i realized what the fuck, over? and ended up sleeping in the guest bed, on top of the covers, still in my gorilla suit.  but alas, everyone saw me leave with her.  now don’t get me wrong, she isn’t an unattractive woman, but i had quite the reputation brewing up here and now i’m wondering if that isn’t just a little bit altered.  had i had one less vodka drink i think everything would have been OK as i would have come to my WTF, mate epiphany a few minutes earlier and wouldn’t have left with her.  but whatever, i don’t really really care.  plus i think that my boss lady friend is seeing someone else, a friend of mine, on the sly.  that is another aspect to my feeling like shit today.  stir in a teaspoon of good ole’ hungover and you got yourself quite a dish of crap.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005-03-24-259/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005-03-24-259/</guid><description>impressions of an evening in aspen.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005-03-20-260/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005-03-20-260/</guid><description>is no artistic output better than bad artistic output?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005-03-06-261/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005-03-06-261/</guid><description>it is saturday night and i’m typing and enjoying wine and then going to sit down with my book for the rest of the evening.  damn i’m boring!</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005-03-04-262/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005-03-04-262/</guid><description>i think that in the past i’ve been very patronizing towards hot chocolate and have made a conscious decision to rethink my position on the substance.  maybe it should be legalized afterall.  what do you think?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005-03-03-263/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005-03-03-263/</guid><description>i am quite tired and sore this evening.  not sure what i’m sore from, probably life beating me about my head and neck relentlessly without me really giving a damn and just taking it lick by fucking lick.  and i’m not talking about the tongue against ice cream cone kind either.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005-03-01-264/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005-03-01-264/</guid><description>WARNING:  this shit is VERY graphic and ENTIRELY conjecture.  just painting a picture of one way it could have gone down.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005-02-23-265/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005-02-23-265/</guid><description>Now, I must do this justice, and to do that I need to back up.  First, some background. His name is Hunter S. Thompson, if you don’t know that name, google him.  I find some odd parallel’s in my living in the same town with the counterculture icon when he dies and with Eric’s story of his friend farting next to Allen Ginsberg’s coffin during some candlelit vigil to the old beat-en poet.  Fast-forwarding and keeping my vile flatulence under control I paint the background of the piece before revealing the subject.  He died two nights ago now, shot himself in the head with a .45.  The rumors around town vary, but the prevailing story is he was old and dying and he just sped up the process.  Many have discounted my first thought that it was  drunken accident by the posterboy for &amp;lsquo;alcoholics among us.&amp;rsquo;  His &amp;lsquo;compound&amp;rsquo; [paragraphical insert: he didn't have a house, the local's tend to pay him some sort of weird homage among the castles that litter the countryside up in the extremely posh neighborhood where he lives, he doesn't have a simple house like Michael Douglas or Prince Bandar, but a fortified compound&amp;hellip;.I guess that is how you can standout in a place like Assssspen.] was two doors down from where my landlord lives.  We stop the story there merely to rewind a bit, because I don’t think you know this part of the story.  I rent a townhouse in a small &amp;lsquo;suburb&amp;rsquo; of the spotlight in the valley that is aspen from a lady who is the personal assistant to some bigwig Aspen-ite.  She was married before and currently a widow and her late-hubby was some 18 trillion-th generational Aspen-ite.  So she is very ingrained with the local history of the place.  Well she is in this odd relationship that after months of observation I cannot commit to any sort of vague or clear categorization–with my roommate.  To summarize, I live with the &amp;lsquo;boyfriend,&amp;rsquo; becuase she is still the personal assistant and as the bigwig grows older and more senile she must spend more time up there near him.  So she has a guest house beside the castle, nothing special in this fucked up world.  Her house is a few acres away from the compound.  The first time I went up to her house to sign my lease I was jolted into some flashbacks when the windows of her house rumbled and the floor of her elevated treated hardwood flooring shook under my dirty new balance shoes.  When I got up from my involuntary temporary fetal position she told me not to worry that it was just Hunter blowing dynamite which was much worse than the naval flare guns or the simple handguns and shotguns.  Me being the Assssspen virgin I wondered aloud, Hunter who?  She told me HST, and I thought, oh, that freak.  Well, I put that memory away on some unused shelf beside the time in gradeschool when Justin Birmele and I were filling out some form and he said &amp;lsquo;sex, yes please,&amp;rsquo; in response to the &amp;lsquo;male or female&amp;rsquo; response we were supposed to give–until the last few days.  I was speaking with my terribly off roommate about HST tonight and how I had grabbed a few of the Aspen Daily New’s to send to a few lucky friends and then he responded in his burnt-out-smoked-as-much-hash-as-cheech way that he had something to show me.  The he dug for a while and came to my room, a rare occurance and asked if I wanted to read the greatest HST shit ever.  I said, why not, I don’t have anything going on, being between books and waiting on many things to happen before Jim will take our next proposal to the street even though it is close to finished.  Then matt, the roommate, brought out these rolled up things that his &amp;lsquo;girlfriend&amp;rsquo; my landlord had gotten many years ago, 1970 in fact.  That year HST was going to run for sheriff and to bolster his campaign and also to promote his personal racket and other things he and a local artist, thomas benton, made these &amp;lsquo;newspapers.&amp;rsquo;  I am not sure how many of them were done, but the following excerpt was taken from the June 30, 1970 edition, Wallpapers No. 2.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005-01-14-266/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005-01-14-266/</guid><description>i spent the entire day cuddling with myself and reveling in the peacefulness.  odd roommate has been conspicuously absent for the past few days and i have barely ventured outside for more than a solitary walk to convince myself that the sun puts out vitamins that i needed to or could actually soak in through all my layers as i walked around in the teen-something degree air and tried to maintain breathing through a stuffed up nose that was pierced by the freezing cold air.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004-12-04-267/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004-12-04-267/</guid><description>i’m sore.  and i don’t mean butt-hurt, even though my butt does hurt.  well, the ass muscles hurt.  i’ve been riding hard for the past two days, and i don’t mean the ladies–the snow baby.  the riding skills are coming back faster than i imagined that they would.  i was jumping natural kickers both in the groomers and in the trees.  i was taking the bumps and the trees without pausing.  i even jammed a few rails.  i was screaming faster than i think i’ve ever ridden. the snow here is really really hard and fast, but you can go fast b/c you know that it isn’t going to ice on you and have your board slip out from you as long as you are riding correctly.  that i something that i’ve had to learn how to do again, ride correctly.  the bottom line is that i haven’t made a complete ass out of myself.  excellent–in my best crazy scientist voice.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004-11-22-268/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004-11-22-268/</guid><description>i feel like i have come almost full circle, let me explain.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004-11-13-269/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004-11-13-269/</guid><description>i feel refreshed.  i feel wierd in fact, because there has been some odd vindication that has came at the same time as an odd amount of conflict.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004-11-08-270/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004-11-08-270/</guid><description>five days later i make my next entry.  this time it is from the boulder public library where i’ve been camped out for a bit and pretending i’m back in college and doing something productive with my time.  i think that i’ve found where i want to live.  boulder has the quadfecta as i’ve deemed it of:  climbing, kayaking, ski, community.  those are the four things that i’ve looking for in places to live.  there are lots of other smaller things, but generally they come with the above four.  this town is beautiful, near the mountians, has decent weather, nice people, a great art scene, bouldering within walking distance, skiing an hour away, kayaking through town, ice climbing an hour and a half, more trad and sport routes within 15 minutes of the town than i could probably do in a lifetime.  coffeeshops with great art, funky music and weird people.  it is just fantastic here.  the college is loud and rambunctious and there is just a great vibe in the town.  everyone works out, i’ve seen like 2 fat people in my two days here so far.  it is fantastic.  well i’ll get off boulder’s crank now i’ve done enough!</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004-11-02-271/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004-11-02-271/</guid><description>well i’m reading all these things about how the vote has begun. so, in a sign of things to come:  i have lost a toe nail.  and it isn’t one of the small ones, it is the big one on my left foot.  on a hike about four weeks ago i stubbed it terribly bad while i was running down the insanely steep hill and trying to avoid both the rocks and the cacti.  the past two fall seasons i have used that technique to hone my quick feet skills in hopes that it’ll help me on the snow covered mountains. it didn’t really help me that i can pinpoint last year, but i stuck to the technique this year…dumby me, huh?  well, i stubbed my big toe and my middle toe pretty badly and they were f-ed up pretty badly.  so i did the ole’ technique that i’ve seen doc’s use (which BTW joe told me afterthefact was the correct one to use) of heating up a safety pin with a lighter until it was glowing hot and then burning through my toenail until there was a small hole in it.  well after four or five tries i finally burned completely through the nail on the big toe and when i pulled it out that last time five gallons of fluid came pouring out from underneath.  luckily i had at papertowel handy to sop much of it up.  then i burned through my middle toenail in one elegant fell swoop.  and that one was taken care of too.  well i had been anxious about the toenails for a couple of weeks and then randomly the big one fell off two nights ago.  the entire f-ing thing.  i’ve lost toenails before but they were on the smaller nails.  this one is the big one baby. and that is crazy.  so i feel concerned b/c the only other person that i’ve known that has lost a big toenail has been dave and he’s had about 19 different ingrown toenails since then.  so that cannot be good.  but i’m living with a nailless big toe.  it looks odd, because the skin is still there thinking that there is a nail, but there isn’t.  i had all kinds of scabbing and such on the skin that i steadily picked off, but every time i touched the skin where the nail used to be it sent shivers down my spine like fingernails on the proverbial blackboard.  but whatever, i’m growing used to it now.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004-10-31-272/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004-10-31-272/</guid><description>decisions decisions decisions.  i guess that i have made my bed and now i’ll revel in it.  i put in the applications at aspen and heard back from the chica there yesterday.  she seemed anxious to interview me, i’m sure i can talk my way into the job.  i was already planning to leave on friday to get there for vail’s job fair on saturday.  now i suspect that i’ll leave here as soon as i close the loops on two different things.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004-10-24-273/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004-10-24-273/</guid><description>i think that something interesting to study would be the history of companionship.  at what points in history have people really desired true companionship and partnership out of their significant others?  the victorians and all that flowery poetry shit that they wrote were supposed to be significant steps in the history of love.  however, i wonder if it was love like we would call it.  whenever i read any of elizabeth barrett browning or any of her contemporaries it seems that it is only infatuation.  it doesn’t seem deep seated; just surface-al.  then the sixties were all about free love.  they probably made up a lot of grounds on the front of sexual equality but it was such an open society that i wonder sometimes how much they valued the individual.  many of the communes were probably against the individual.  without the individual then there can be no love of someone specific.  you could love a group of people but you could love someone specifically i would suggest.  i guess that was good for the polygamous types.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004-10-08-274/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004-10-08-274/</guid><description>tonight’s thematique du jour is loneliness for two reasons.  firstly because i think that i’m essentially a completely lonely person, even when surrounded by people.  secondly, and more presently, because i watched parts (most) of about schmidt.  that movie is basically a film students study in the emotion.  at least that is my take on the piece.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004-10-04-275/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004-10-04-275/</guid><description>the one thing that i’ve learned as i ease into the hottub of the blogging culture is that late sunday night is the time for the big ‘weekend recap.’   so let me see, what did i do this weekend.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004-09-30-276/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004-09-30-276/</guid><description>&amp;lsquo;chasing amy&amp;rsquo; is on tonite.  i’m watching my past.  i’m amused by the scene where they throw darts.  i also like jason lee’s character, it’s one of the internally truest characters in movie-dom.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004-09-26-277/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004-09-26-277/</guid><description>just back from the getty for the afternoon.  went down the hill to my friend’s house for the first night.  actually was one of my ex’s.  she’s fairly intense, and likes it that way so she plays it up.  we drank wine on her porch while i sweated in my jeans and too long of sleeve shirt because its been cold up here and my dumb ass was relishing the cold enough that i dressed for it when i shouldn’t have.</description></item></channel></rss>