<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/</link><description>A Site About Resilience and Authoritarianism</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</managingEditor><webMaster>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</webMaster><copyright>All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/otherwise/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Book Inscription</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-02-03-book-inscription/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-02-03-book-inscription/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here’s to the embarkation on a great journey. Here’s to a massive flop or a spectacular success. Here’s to nothing in between. Here’s to risk. Here’s to reward. Here’s to taking a chance. Here’s to never being satisfied with what is. Here’s to questioning. Here’s to listening. Here’s to excellence. Here’s to professionalism. Here’s to helping everywhere we can in every way we can to everyone we can. Here’s to solving problems. Here’s to trust in unwavering allies. And most of all. Here’s doing our best to impact in those we touch in some small way that truly speaking tomorrow is going to be a better day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Decoding the Somali Mind: A Guide for Expats (Anecdotal, Not Definitive Version): Responsibility</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-18-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-responsibility/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-18-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-responsibility/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This is a new series containing a few stories which have stood out in my time here in Somaliland and have helped me to understand a bit more a culture that in many ways is very different from my own, but in many ways is not. This series explores those differences.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I generally prefer to point out the similarities between disparate people.  I enjoy very much the common humanity aspects about my life.  But I equally enjoy learning about the differences.  This post contains more of the latter than the former.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m American and we are taught from a young age that a major part of being an American means that you are individualistic.  Our pop culture and education system celebrate individuality and the human against the odds above many other cultural memes.  Most of the people that have immigrated to America over the years have come to chase something that was related to individual efforts.  Those of us who descend from those who immigrated we have it both from nature and from nurture.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Somalilanders are taught precisely the opposite.   They celebrate communal victories above individual victories in their poetry and dramas and songs.  They rely on communal networks for insurance when things get tough.  Collective responsibility is bred into them as deeply as individual responsibility has been bred into me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Two months ago my Ethiopian watchman stole an SUV that I was borrowing from a friend and he drove it so fast (likely enjoying his own sense of individuality and freedom of the road – something that isn’t a big leap for me to empathize with) that when he had to swerve to hit someone he hit a bump and jumped the SUV, and I mean jumped it, on top of other cars.  Two other cars that were sitting in a used car dealership beside the road.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I was told about it I was pretty crushed because I knew instantly that I would have to pay for the damage.  Even though he had stolen from me.  Even though his job description involved neither driving nor speeding.  Even though I had not the slightest to do with the situation.  Because that is the way that things work.  Everyone is responsible for everyone else.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If the Ethiopian kid had been Somali and the employer was not responsible then the clan would provide the necessary insurance.  If I as the employer had been Somali and I was unable to cover the costs then my clan would have been called upon to provide the insurance.   But neither of us fit into that system.  I paid.  I had no other choice.  I could reason through very easily that in my system I wasn’t liable.  But I wasn’t living in my system.  I gain the consequences of the system but not the benefits.  I guess that is life though and how many minorities throughout history have had that exact thought?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another thing that is fairly prevalent is that senior Somalis working for organizations get held personally liable for all of the actions or non-actions of the organization.  My number two with my old NGO recently had his power shut off because of a dispute between the power company the organization signed a services contract with and the party responsible for paying the final two months electricity bill.  Sure his name isn’t on the invoices, but his name is there in the computer as the responsible party.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This can be very annoying when you are held responsible for the actions of another that you “normally” would not have to be responsible for.  But when you understand the system and you understand that there &lt;em>is&lt;/em> a system, although maybe facially foreign.  Then you can at least navigate it.  But if you’re new to Somalis these are key because how you treat your staff and the pressures that especially your senior staff will face need to be understood.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What I Do Before Work</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-15-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-15-work/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://millensonthemove.blogspot.com/">&lt;img src="http://millensonthemove.blogspot.com/" alt="Coffee &amp; Newspapers">&lt;/a>
Photo via cafemama @ flickr&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the longest while, I’ve been obsessed with time management &amp;amp; efficiency.   In college my good friend &lt;a href="http://millensonthemove.blogspot.com/">Dave&lt;/a>, who was running the orientation program for our ROTC that year, asked me to give a class on time management.  It was one of the most enjoyable topics I’ve ever lectured on.   We were incoming seniors and we were talking to incoming freshmen.  At the time I was listening to lots of Zig Zigler.  I remember my tips included always carrying around a small notebook with you and writing down to dos, things you liked in the day, etc.  I don’t remember the rest of my sage-like wisdom.  That would have been the summer of 1998.  Now I just use my mobile to take notes rather than the pen and paper method.  The rest is below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I always have idealized those people who would rise early and have five or six newspapers read before they went to work.  Yet, everyone knows I am far from a morning person.  But, still, I try to emulate those people in my own way.  I’ve used RSS readers in one form or another for probably six or seven years.  It is a fantastic technology which allows me to get tabs on the content from numerous sites without having to wait for those sites to load, scan the pages, figure out what I have and have not read, read the content I’m interested in, and then do something with that information.   For a long time I used FeedDemon.  Eventually he integrated Google Reader sync into FeedDemon and I switched all my subscriptions over to Reader.  After that it was a short leep to &lt;a href="http://feedly.com">feedly&lt;/a>, which I currently use exclusively.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is how RSS works.  When a site publishes content (new articles, etc.) it pushes that content out to the RSS feed.  The feed reader then pulls in that content and only that content.  Google Reader acts as the feed reader, and pulls in all of the content.  Feedly, on the other hand is simply and overlay for the Reader interface.  All of this allows me to keep tabs on tons of sites while only having to visit one site.  Living in a country with low bandwidth this is a lifesaver.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="reading-content">Reading Content&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Generally I begin by scanning all of the headlines and excerpts on each of the category pages that I have built into feedly/reader.  These are like the sections of the newspaper – more or less.  Either I read the content directly as I’m working through the content and pages, or if I’ve slept late I save the articles for later.  When I’ve finished the category, I mark it as read and move on to the next one.  It usually takes about 15 minutes to scan everything, a bit more time if I read some of the content on the initial sweep.  Feedly has a great interface for reading content.  I have begun hating all of the extraneous stuff that people put on sites (thus the subtle redesign my site and my company’s &lt;a href="http://watershedlegal.com">site&lt;/a> – which is ongoing).  I find the latest tweets of the site, all of the follow options, all of the related content, etc. to be annoying.  First it distracts from the content – which is the reason I’m on the site to begin with.  Second it takes bandwidth – usually lots of bandwidth and java crunching – to load all of that stuff.  Feedly is ultra-fast on my slow machine when I use my Chrome, so it is great for reading content.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Saving articles for later is fantastic with &lt;a href="http://instapaper.com">Instapaper&lt;/a>.  It is a very light-weight site which is really open and integrates well with both my phone and my laptop.  While I’m working through my feedly if I am late or not interested in the time with the article but know I will be later, I simply push the Instapaper icon in feedly and it is saved.  During the day if I’m waiting on something generally I will use my phone to scan my twitter feeds and my reader articles that have come in, when I find something interesting it takes three button pushes to save the article onto Instapaper (I use &lt;a href="http://mobileways.de/gravity">Gravity&lt;/a> on my Nokia E72, and is integrated with my facebook, twitter, reader, and foursquare accounts).  During the day if I see something good either on twitter or just while generally being around it takes one click to save on Instapaper (I used &lt;a href="https://chrome.google.com/extensions/detail/kbmipnjdeifmobkhgogdnomkihhgojep">Shareaholic&lt;/a> extension for &lt;a href="http://chrome.google.com">Chrome&lt;/a>).  There are tons of ways to “save for later” and I have tried many of them, but I generally try to keep one basket for everything.  Instapaper shines with long form articles as it will clip the text only – another lifesaver for my low-bandwidth constraints.  I especially like the using the &lt;a href="https://chrome.google.com/extensions/detail/ppelffpjgkifjfgnbaaldcehkpajlmbc">iReader&lt;/a> extension for Chrome which blows everything up and is perfect when you want to sit back on focus on the text of an article without all of the clutter that is on most sites.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="after-reading-content">After Reading Content&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>One of the first things I think about after reading a good piece of content is I want to share it.  As I’m working my way through my feedly generally I use the save for later feature that feedly has (which is integrated with your reader save for later) as my saving queue.  I find it more efficient to just push one button and move along keeping my focus on the next piece of content, rather than getting distracted by figuring out the intended share audience for the content.  Sometimes, it is clear to me that what I want to do with the article and feedly is great for that as it has most of the integrations for sharing that I need.  Also if I want to save the article in (see below) I can just push the Evernote button and voila.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After I have read the content usually I want to do something with that content – either save it as a reference for later or share it.  As my reference basket I have tried different options also, but at this point I use only &lt;a href="http://evernote.com">Evernote&lt;/a>.  It has nice integration, although it is not as widely integrated as Instapaper is.  It has its own extension for Chrome, but I find that it was superfluous when I was already using the Shareaholic extension.  Both the Evernote extension and Shareaholic were pulling up the same interface, so there was no point in using them both.  Evernote has a desktop app, but my laptop is old and doesn’t have much RAM so mainly I use the web app in Chrome as it is lighter.  Evernote allows you to organize articles using the best scenario (for me): both categories and tagging.  Some others delicious, digg, instapaper, use only one of the two organizing methods, but I prefer Evernote’s dual-nature for referencing articles.  I also use Evernote as my current notepad to remember random crap – although it doesn’t have a Symbian app that will be cured when I am able to grab an Android phone.  The last thing I like about Evernote is that it allows you to share your notebooks, which we use for our company.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sharing, sharing, sharing.  Blah, blah, blah.  Here’s how I do it, at any rate.  I mainly use &lt;a href="http://hootsuite.com">Hootsuite&lt;/a> to monitor all of my networks.  My only current gripe about Hootsuite is that they have not yet integrated with Buzz.  Hootsuite generally does everything well.  What I tend to do after I’ve read everything in my feedly that I want to read, is I go to my saved items in feedly and then work through them.  Generally I will press the tweet button in feedly and that will shorten the URL (using bit.ly not Hootsuite’s proprietary shortener, ow.ly) and grab the title of the article.  Then I’ll copy that over to my Hootsuite, where I can share the article with different networks by simply selecting the ones that I want.  Different networks have different social mores for sharing content, so I generally have a small think about what the intended audience for the sharing is.  I monitor three twitter accounts, my facebook, two facebook pages, and my linked in on Hootsuite.  Each of those have different profiles so I try to figure out who I want the content to go to.  If it is only one of the audiences that rather than using Hootsuite I will just share the article directly from feedly.  The other feature I use a lot on Hootsuite is the scheduling feature.  Since I’m seven hours ahead of East Coast time in the US, and many of my friends are there, I generally delay some of my sharing to the afternoon my time, which is the morning their time.  Also because I do my news sweep mostly in the morning, I want to space that content sharing out over the day rather than flooding my feeds only in the morning.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Decoding the Somali Mind: A Guide for Expats (Anecdotal, Not Definitive Version): Wants v. Needs</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-28-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-v/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-28-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-v/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This is a new series containing a few stories which have stood out in my time here in Somaliland and have helped me to understand a bit more a culture that in many ways is very different from my own, but in many ways is not. This series explores those differences.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![want need syrup by thebrianmeyer @ flickr][2]][2]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every development worker I’ve ever met, and I can say with confidence, without exception, hates the following phrase with a passion: “What we &lt;em>really&lt;/em> need is….”  Hearing that phrase pretty much ruins your entire day.  Usually, but not always, it is accompanied by a veiled threat of what will happen if the particular worker does not comply.  Well, that happens when one is dealing with governmental clients.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a preliminary (and because despite my non-traditional path I am still a trained lawyer), let me define what I’m talking about when I say “wants” and “needs.”  I would define (for the purposes of this piece only, &lt;em>see supra&lt;/em>) “needs” as those things which are required to perform a given task, whereas I would define “wants” as those things which are not required but would be beneficial to accomplish a given task.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do I “need” internet to survive? No.   Do I “need” internet to do my job? Yes (reasons for this answer will be detailed in a forthcoming post).  I say this almost flippantly, but in any culture it is incredibly easy to conflate these concepts and trying to differentiate between the two will depend largely upon an individual’s perspective.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Especially when it comes to legislative action, determining whether a mechanism or a “thing” is needed or wanted is incredibly difficult to determine with accuracy.  One of the arts of political action is convincing others of one’s perspective as to whether something is a needed requirement or a wanted luxury.  This is one of  the many reasons why so many politicians are trained lawyers – as we get paid to use words to twist concepts to convince individuals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yet, when it comes to Somali society figuring out such a differential is complicated by the Somali language.  In Somali, to say “I want X” one would say “X waan doonayaa,” whereas to say “I need X” one would say “X waan doonayaa.”  The root of the verb (“doon”) means both of the concepts expressed in the English words “want” and “need.”  It isn’t a far leap to see that this makes it even more difficult to differentiate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first time I was running a workshop here in Hargeisa talking to legislators about the differences in these concepts my translator was struggling and I was having a hard time understanding why it was difficult to pose the question to the participants.  At the break I pulled my translator aside and tried to figure out why he was having such trouble getting across what I was trying to say.  He was also extremely frustrated but didn’t say much other than he would do his best.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Months later, when I was learning Somali, it became clear to me that the difficulty my translator had experienced much earlier was a function of the Somali language.  After I had learned a modicum of Somali than I changed some of the curriculum of the workshop from wants and needs to requirements and luxuries.  After that it was much easier for my translator to get the preliminary concepts across so that the participants could have a good discussion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of my favorite all time stories during my years here in Somaliland falls (loosely) under this concept of wants v. needs.  In October, 2008, there were three suicide bombs detonated in different places here in Hargeisa: the Ethiopian Embassy, the UNDP compound, and the Presidential mansion.  After these bombings there were probably four of us expatriates who stuck around while everyone else ran away to Nairobi.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My team and I worked day and night for the two weeks after the bombings preparing a series of documents to help the government and parliament understand the legal mechanisms for reacting to terrorism that have been emplaced under (1) international law; and (2) national laws within the region.  The government told me very early on that they were looking to emplace something like the Somaliland Patriot Act and so we had done tons of research on the topic for the government.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We broke up the delivery of the work product among the different affected clients: namely the Ministry of Interior, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, and the Ministry of Justice.  I was in with the Minister of Justice briefing him on the current problems that they would have if they wanted to prosecute suspected terrorists under their current penal code.  I had included in my briefing a bunch on due process as well as the international human rights mechanisms, which had been imputed into the Somaliland Constitution, that currently limited their ability to move forward with prosecutions prior to further legislative action.  About 2/3d’s of the way through my presentation the Vice Minister of Justice barged into the briefing and sat down.  He waited for about thirty seconds before he turned to me and said the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This is all well and good, but what Somaliland really *needs *is you to call up the CIA and brief them on what is happening here.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Seriously, Mr. Vice Minister, do you really think that I have the CIA’s number on my speed dial?  My sarcastic side said.  For once, I controlled that and tried my best to explain in a temperate tone that I had no contacts with the CIA and that even if I did they wouldn’t listen to me.  I caught the Minister’s eyes rolling slightly while the Vice Minister was on his tirade after my response so I knew I was on OK ground and I just moved along with my briefing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After we finished, and we were leaving the Vice Minister (who I had never spoken to once prior to this exchange) walked out to our vehicle with us.  He told me that he knew exactly who I was and that he was going to hold me personally liable for informing the CIA of what was happening here in Somaliland.  I assured him in the most even tones I could conjure at that moment that there was nothing I could do for him on this issue and that he should use the Minister of Foreign Affairs rather than some external NGO worker.  He was never convinced.  And I wasn’t convinced that he was mentally stable enough to be a Vice Minister.  I left completely flabbergasted.  To this day, there is no Somaliland Patriot Act.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Decoding the Somali Mind: A Guide for Expats (Anecdotal, Not Definitive Version): Introduction</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-21-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-21-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This is a new series containing a few stories which have stood out in my time here in Somaliland and have helped me to understand a bit more a culture that in many ways is very different from my own, but in many ways is now. This series explores those differences.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![BraiNut 1.0 via sath.es @flickr][2]][2]
via sath.es @flickr&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have lived &amp;amp; worked with Somalis here in Somaliland for over two years now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have, like many expats before me, sat in rooms on the floor with rugs underneath us cushions behind our backs, mauis’s (skirts) on sporting wife-beaters drinking the sweetest teas one has ever drank and (as my wife likes to say) sticking green leaves up our noses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Equally I have sat many nights, like many expats before me, on a veranda, a glass of wine in hand, cool breezes of Hargeisa swirling around, dressed in jeans and semi-glamorous (but always purposively casual) shirts, some ipod attached to portable speakers, listening to music that is on the verge of being hip back home and talking about the deep cultural differences between us and those that fill our daily lives (our clients, our friends, our colleagues, people we meet around).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have had a steady turnover in Hargeisa of expatriates lately.  And over that time there seems to be an increasing amount of tension between the expatriates and the Somalilanders.  I am not sure exactly why this seems to be happening (because this is Somaliland it is spoken of in metaphors and resides fully in the subtextual zone), but it has become increasingly tangible to me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the course of the past year there has been this tit-for-tat between the powerful voices for the expatriates and the powerful voices for the Somalilanders.  The problem is that those of us who aren’t given powerful voices become batted around as the game is played by others.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Something happened to me recently which I would like to use (again cloaked in metaphor and subtext, because this is how to communicate in Somaliland) as a tuusaale (example).  One of my best expat friends here in Hargeisa (who is a development worker) recently had some professional dealings with one of my best Somali friends (who is a mid-level government employee).  Due to forces above and beyond either’s control the dealings did not turn out well and both became frustrated by the situation (for very different reasons but that is beside the point).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a while I was caught in the middle of everything but the biggest problem was that I was getting completely different stories as to what happened from either “side” (so to say).  There was so little alignment between the stories that for a while I wondered if these were two completely different situations involving different people completely.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Later I started to piece it together, to connect the people that were being referenced by one story with how I organize those relationships when I’m talking to the other side, to connect the things that I knew were more important to one side with those that had little emphasis in the other’s side of the story.  I don’t know much about mediation, but I was trying to see these events through each side’s cultural lens and come to some sort of objective understanding of what likely transpired.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was only after spending literally hours trying to dig through and cross-check and re-examine and then start all over again that I was able to ferret out what may have actually happened.  And only after that did I realize that the actualities of the situation were out of the control of either party.  That happens in development work and it is one of the occupational hazards of this work.  However, the relational aspects of the situation were very much aggravated by the cultural differences between the parties.  It is this part – the cultural misunderstandings and their attendant relational aspects which causes (in my mind) undue hardships in development work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is why I wanted to write a few words over the course of the next little while trying to tell a few stories that have taught me a ton about humanity and culture (and which is which).  A few stories which I think of and use when I’m trying to analyze things through a foreign cultural lens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If I had to pick one of the most intellectually satisfying aspects of working here in Somaliland, it has been the opportunity to dig deep into a culture and a way of thinking and seeing the world that is very different than my own.  Each of the cultural differences, while stark at times, belies evidence of our common humanity.  Every time I become frustrated with the cultural differences then something will happen to me which will reinforce the common humanity which is always there.  The tenderness of a father’s reprimand, or a shared joke, or an extraordinarily kind act.  These things accompany each and every one of the cultural differences.  So I hope to share a few of these stories along the way as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Happy Dad&amp;#8217;s Day!</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-20-happy-dads-day/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-20-happy-dads-day/</guid><description>&lt;p>[![Happy Father's Day in advance to someone who may be mature enough to have children by age 62][2]][2]It is actually quite crazy to think that when my father was the age in which I currently find myself he had two sons (one 12 and one 9), and was on his third (or fourth?) house.  I, on the other hand, am childless, and property-less!  Although I must say very happily married.  So as I sit here in my house in Hargeisa and reflect upon the fact that I’m missing yet another holiday far away from my father and trying to justify why to myself, the only thing that makes sense is to put on some of my dad’s favorite songs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://www.someecards.com/card/3071">http://www.someecards.com/card/3071&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With such a soundtrack for successful blogging, I would like to thank my dad for (via nature &amp;amp; nurture) imbuing in me a curiosity and an open-mindedness about the world that have led me along the crazy path I’ve lived so far.  And although it has driven us apart geographically (as Ballad of Billy the Kid comes on) and forced me to miss some of these days in person, I’m there with you in spirit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I love you dad.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-11-15/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-11-15/</guid><description>&lt;p>Beaker Twitter = Hilarity. HT – Frank&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>