<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/</link><description>A Site About Resilience and Authoritarianism</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</managingEditor><webMaster>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</webMaster><copyright>All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/otherwise/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Book Inscription</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-02-03-book-inscription/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-02-03-book-inscription/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here’s to the embarkation on a great journey. Here’s to a massive flop or a spectacular success. Here’s to nothing in between. Here’s to risk. Here’s to reward. Here’s to taking a chance. Here’s to never being satisfied with what is. Here’s to questioning. Here’s to listening. Here’s to excellence. Here’s to professionalism. Here’s to helping everywhere we can in every way we can to everyone we can. Here’s to solving problems. Here’s to trust in unwavering allies. And most of all. Here’s doing our best to impact in those we touch in some small way that truly speaking tomorrow is going to be a better day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Decoding the Somali Mind: A Guide for Expats (Anecdotal, Not Definitive Version): Responsibility</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-18-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-responsibility/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-18-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-responsibility/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This is a new series containing a few stories which have stood out in my time here in Somaliland and have helped me to understand a bit more a culture that in many ways is very different from my own, but in many ways is not. This series explores those differences.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I generally prefer to point out the similarities between disparate people.  I enjoy very much the common humanity aspects about my life.  But I equally enjoy learning about the differences.  This post contains more of the latter than the former.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m American and we are taught from a young age that a major part of being an American means that you are individualistic.  Our pop culture and education system celebrate individuality and the human against the odds above many other cultural memes.  Most of the people that have immigrated to America over the years have come to chase something that was related to individual efforts.  Those of us who descend from those who immigrated we have it both from nature and from nurture.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Somalilanders are taught precisely the opposite.   They celebrate communal victories above individual victories in their poetry and dramas and songs.  They rely on communal networks for insurance when things get tough.  Collective responsibility is bred into them as deeply as individual responsibility has been bred into me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Two months ago my Ethiopian watchman stole an SUV that I was borrowing from a friend and he drove it so fast (likely enjoying his own sense of individuality and freedom of the road – something that isn’t a big leap for me to empathize with) that when he had to swerve to hit someone he hit a bump and jumped the SUV, and I mean jumped it, on top of other cars.  Two other cars that were sitting in a used car dealership beside the road.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I was told about it I was pretty crushed because I knew instantly that I would have to pay for the damage.  Even though he had stolen from me.  Even though his job description involved neither driving nor speeding.  Even though I had not the slightest to do with the situation.  Because that is the way that things work.  Everyone is responsible for everyone else.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If the Ethiopian kid had been Somali and the employer was not responsible then the clan would provide the necessary insurance.  If I as the employer had been Somali and I was unable to cover the costs then my clan would have been called upon to provide the insurance.   But neither of us fit into that system.  I paid.  I had no other choice.  I could reason through very easily that in my system I wasn’t liable.  But I wasn’t living in my system.  I gain the consequences of the system but not the benefits.  I guess that is life though and how many minorities throughout history have had that exact thought?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another thing that is fairly prevalent is that senior Somalis working for organizations get held personally liable for all of the actions or non-actions of the organization.  My number two with my old NGO recently had his power shut off because of a dispute between the power company the organization signed a services contract with and the party responsible for paying the final two months electricity bill.  Sure his name isn’t on the invoices, but his name is there in the computer as the responsible party.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This can be very annoying when you are held responsible for the actions of another that you “normally” would not have to be responsible for.  But when you understand the system and you understand that there &lt;em>is&lt;/em> a system, although maybe facially foreign.  Then you can at least navigate it.  But if you’re new to Somalis these are key because how you treat your staff and the pressures that especially your senior staff will face need to be understood.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What I Do Before Work</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-15-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-15-work/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://millensonthemove.blogspot.com/">&lt;img src="http://millensonthemove.blogspot.com/" alt="Coffee &amp; Newspapers">&lt;/a>
Photo via cafemama @ flickr&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the longest while, I’ve been obsessed with time management &amp;amp; efficiency.   In college my good friend &lt;a href="http://millensonthemove.blogspot.com/">Dave&lt;/a>, who was running the orientation program for our ROTC that year, asked me to give a class on time management.  It was one of the most enjoyable topics I’ve ever lectured on.   We were incoming seniors and we were talking to incoming freshmen.  At the time I was listening to lots of Zig Zigler.  I remember my tips included always carrying around a small notebook with you and writing down to dos, things you liked in the day, etc.  I don’t remember the rest of my sage-like wisdom.  That would have been the summer of 1998.  Now I just use my mobile to take notes rather than the pen and paper method.  The rest is below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I always have idealized those people who would rise early and have five or six newspapers read before they went to work.  Yet, everyone knows I am far from a morning person.  But, still, I try to emulate those people in my own way.  I’ve used RSS readers in one form or another for probably six or seven years.  It is a fantastic technology which allows me to get tabs on the content from numerous sites without having to wait for those sites to load, scan the pages, figure out what I have and have not read, read the content I’m interested in, and then do something with that information.   For a long time I used FeedDemon.  Eventually he integrated Google Reader sync into FeedDemon and I switched all my subscriptions over to Reader.  After that it was a short leep to &lt;a href="http://feedly.com">feedly&lt;/a>, which I currently use exclusively.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is how RSS works.  When a site publishes content (new articles, etc.) it pushes that content out to the RSS feed.  The feed reader then pulls in that content and only that content.  Google Reader acts as the feed reader, and pulls in all of the content.  Feedly, on the other hand is simply and overlay for the Reader interface.  All of this allows me to keep tabs on tons of sites while only having to visit one site.  Living in a country with low bandwidth this is a lifesaver.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="reading-content">Reading Content&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Generally I begin by scanning all of the headlines and excerpts on each of the category pages that I have built into feedly/reader.  These are like the sections of the newspaper – more or less.  Either I read the content directly as I’m working through the content and pages, or if I’ve slept late I save the articles for later.  When I’ve finished the category, I mark it as read and move on to the next one.  It usually takes about 15 minutes to scan everything, a bit more time if I read some of the content on the initial sweep.  Feedly has a great interface for reading content.  I have begun hating all of the extraneous stuff that people put on sites (thus the subtle redesign my site and my company’s &lt;a href="http://watershedlegal.com">site&lt;/a> – which is ongoing).  I find the latest tweets of the site, all of the follow options, all of the related content, etc. to be annoying.  First it distracts from the content – which is the reason I’m on the site to begin with.  Second it takes bandwidth – usually lots of bandwidth and java crunching – to load all of that stuff.  Feedly is ultra-fast on my slow machine when I use my Chrome, so it is great for reading content.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Saving articles for later is fantastic with &lt;a href="http://instapaper.com">Instapaper&lt;/a>.  It is a very light-weight site which is really open and integrates well with both my phone and my laptop.  While I’m working through my feedly if I am late or not interested in the time with the article but know I will be later, I simply push the Instapaper icon in feedly and it is saved.  During the day if I’m waiting on something generally I will use my phone to scan my twitter feeds and my reader articles that have come in, when I find something interesting it takes three button pushes to save the article onto Instapaper (I use &lt;a href="http://mobileways.de/gravity">Gravity&lt;/a> on my Nokia E72, and is integrated with my facebook, twitter, reader, and foursquare accounts).  During the day if I see something good either on twitter or just while generally being around it takes one click to save on Instapaper (I used &lt;a href="https://chrome.google.com/extensions/detail/kbmipnjdeifmobkhgogdnomkihhgojep">Shareaholic&lt;/a> extension for &lt;a href="http://chrome.google.com">Chrome&lt;/a>).  There are tons of ways to “save for later” and I have tried many of them, but I generally try to keep one basket for everything.  Instapaper shines with long form articles as it will clip the text only – another lifesaver for my low-bandwidth constraints.  I especially like the using the &lt;a href="https://chrome.google.com/extensions/detail/ppelffpjgkifjfgnbaaldcehkpajlmbc">iReader&lt;/a> extension for Chrome which blows everything up and is perfect when you want to sit back on focus on the text of an article without all of the clutter that is on most sites.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="after-reading-content">After Reading Content&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>One of the first things I think about after reading a good piece of content is I want to share it.  As I’m working my way through my feedly generally I use the save for later feature that feedly has (which is integrated with your reader save for later) as my saving queue.  I find it more efficient to just push one button and move along keeping my focus on the next piece of content, rather than getting distracted by figuring out the intended share audience for the content.  Sometimes, it is clear to me that what I want to do with the article and feedly is great for that as it has most of the integrations for sharing that I need.  Also if I want to save the article in (see below) I can just push the Evernote button and voila.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After I have read the content usually I want to do something with that content – either save it as a reference for later or share it.  As my reference basket I have tried different options also, but at this point I use only &lt;a href="http://evernote.com">Evernote&lt;/a>.  It has nice integration, although it is not as widely integrated as Instapaper is.  It has its own extension for Chrome, but I find that it was superfluous when I was already using the Shareaholic extension.  Both the Evernote extension and Shareaholic were pulling up the same interface, so there was no point in using them both.  Evernote has a desktop app, but my laptop is old and doesn’t have much RAM so mainly I use the web app in Chrome as it is lighter.  Evernote allows you to organize articles using the best scenario (for me): both categories and tagging.  Some others delicious, digg, instapaper, use only one of the two organizing methods, but I prefer Evernote’s dual-nature for referencing articles.  I also use Evernote as my current notepad to remember random crap – although it doesn’t have a Symbian app that will be cured when I am able to grab an Android phone.  The last thing I like about Evernote is that it allows you to share your notebooks, which we use for our company.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sharing, sharing, sharing.  Blah, blah, blah.  Here’s how I do it, at any rate.  I mainly use &lt;a href="http://hootsuite.com">Hootsuite&lt;/a> to monitor all of my networks.  My only current gripe about Hootsuite is that they have not yet integrated with Buzz.  Hootsuite generally does everything well.  What I tend to do after I’ve read everything in my feedly that I want to read, is I go to my saved items in feedly and then work through them.  Generally I will press the tweet button in feedly and that will shorten the URL (using bit.ly not Hootsuite’s proprietary shortener, ow.ly) and grab the title of the article.  Then I’ll copy that over to my Hootsuite, where I can share the article with different networks by simply selecting the ones that I want.  Different networks have different social mores for sharing content, so I generally have a small think about what the intended audience for the sharing is.  I monitor three twitter accounts, my facebook, two facebook pages, and my linked in on Hootsuite.  Each of those have different profiles so I try to figure out who I want the content to go to.  If it is only one of the audiences that rather than using Hootsuite I will just share the article directly from feedly.  The other feature I use a lot on Hootsuite is the scheduling feature.  Since I’m seven hours ahead of East Coast time in the US, and many of my friends are there, I generally delay some of my sharing to the afternoon my time, which is the morning their time.  Also because I do my news sweep mostly in the morning, I want to space that content sharing out over the day rather than flooding my feeds only in the morning.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Decoding the Somali Mind: A Guide for Expats (Anecdotal, Not Definitive Version): Wants v. Needs</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-28-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-v/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-28-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-v/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This is a new series containing a few stories which have stood out in my time here in Somaliland and have helped me to understand a bit more a culture that in many ways is very different from my own, but in many ways is not. This series explores those differences.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![want need syrup by thebrianmeyer @ flickr][2]][2]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every development worker I’ve ever met, and I can say with confidence, without exception, hates the following phrase with a passion: “What we &lt;em>really&lt;/em> need is….”  Hearing that phrase pretty much ruins your entire day.  Usually, but not always, it is accompanied by a veiled threat of what will happen if the particular worker does not comply.  Well, that happens when one is dealing with governmental clients.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a preliminary (and because despite my non-traditional path I am still a trained lawyer), let me define what I’m talking about when I say “wants” and “needs.”  I would define (for the purposes of this piece only, &lt;em>see supra&lt;/em>) “needs” as those things which are required to perform a given task, whereas I would define “wants” as those things which are not required but would be beneficial to accomplish a given task.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do I “need” internet to survive? No.   Do I “need” internet to do my job? Yes (reasons for this answer will be detailed in a forthcoming post).  I say this almost flippantly, but in any culture it is incredibly easy to conflate these concepts and trying to differentiate between the two will depend largely upon an individual’s perspective.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Especially when it comes to legislative action, determining whether a mechanism or a “thing” is needed or wanted is incredibly difficult to determine with accuracy.  One of the arts of political action is convincing others of one’s perspective as to whether something is a needed requirement or a wanted luxury.  This is one of  the many reasons why so many politicians are trained lawyers – as we get paid to use words to twist concepts to convince individuals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yet, when it comes to Somali society figuring out such a differential is complicated by the Somali language.  In Somali, to say “I want X” one would say “X waan doonayaa,” whereas to say “I need X” one would say “X waan doonayaa.”  The root of the verb (“doon”) means both of the concepts expressed in the English words “want” and “need.”  It isn’t a far leap to see that this makes it even more difficult to differentiate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first time I was running a workshop here in Hargeisa talking to legislators about the differences in these concepts my translator was struggling and I was having a hard time understanding why it was difficult to pose the question to the participants.  At the break I pulled my translator aside and tried to figure out why he was having such trouble getting across what I was trying to say.  He was also extremely frustrated but didn’t say much other than he would do his best.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Months later, when I was learning Somali, it became clear to me that the difficulty my translator had experienced much earlier was a function of the Somali language.  After I had learned a modicum of Somali than I changed some of the curriculum of the workshop from wants and needs to requirements and luxuries.  After that it was much easier for my translator to get the preliminary concepts across so that the participants could have a good discussion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of my favorite all time stories during my years here in Somaliland falls (loosely) under this concept of wants v. needs.  In October, 2008, there were three suicide bombs detonated in different places here in Hargeisa: the Ethiopian Embassy, the UNDP compound, and the Presidential mansion.  After these bombings there were probably four of us expatriates who stuck around while everyone else ran away to Nairobi.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My team and I worked day and night for the two weeks after the bombings preparing a series of documents to help the government and parliament understand the legal mechanisms for reacting to terrorism that have been emplaced under (1) international law; and (2) national laws within the region.  The government told me very early on that they were looking to emplace something like the Somaliland Patriot Act and so we had done tons of research on the topic for the government.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We broke up the delivery of the work product among the different affected clients: namely the Ministry of Interior, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, and the Ministry of Justice.  I was in with the Minister of Justice briefing him on the current problems that they would have if they wanted to prosecute suspected terrorists under their current penal code.  I had included in my briefing a bunch on due process as well as the international human rights mechanisms, which had been imputed into the Somaliland Constitution, that currently limited their ability to move forward with prosecutions prior to further legislative action.  About 2/3d’s of the way through my presentation the Vice Minister of Justice barged into the briefing and sat down.  He waited for about thirty seconds before he turned to me and said the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This is all well and good, but what Somaliland really *needs *is you to call up the CIA and brief them on what is happening here.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Seriously, Mr. Vice Minister, do you really think that I have the CIA’s number on my speed dial?  My sarcastic side said.  For once, I controlled that and tried my best to explain in a temperate tone that I had no contacts with the CIA and that even if I did they wouldn’t listen to me.  I caught the Minister’s eyes rolling slightly while the Vice Minister was on his tirade after my response so I knew I was on OK ground and I just moved along with my briefing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After we finished, and we were leaving the Vice Minister (who I had never spoken to once prior to this exchange) walked out to our vehicle with us.  He told me that he knew exactly who I was and that he was going to hold me personally liable for informing the CIA of what was happening here in Somaliland.  I assured him in the most even tones I could conjure at that moment that there was nothing I could do for him on this issue and that he should use the Minister of Foreign Affairs rather than some external NGO worker.  He was never convinced.  And I wasn’t convinced that he was mentally stable enough to be a Vice Minister.  I left completely flabbergasted.  To this day, there is no Somaliland Patriot Act.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Decoding the Somali Mind: A Guide for Expats (Anecdotal, Not Definitive Version): Introduction</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-21-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-21-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This is a new series containing a few stories which have stood out in my time here in Somaliland and have helped me to understand a bit more a culture that in many ways is very different from my own, but in many ways is now. This series explores those differences.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![BraiNut 1.0 via sath.es @flickr][2]][2]
via sath.es @flickr&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have lived &amp;amp; worked with Somalis here in Somaliland for over two years now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have, like many expats before me, sat in rooms on the floor with rugs underneath us cushions behind our backs, mauis’s (skirts) on sporting wife-beaters drinking the sweetest teas one has ever drank and (as my wife likes to say) sticking green leaves up our noses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Equally I have sat many nights, like many expats before me, on a veranda, a glass of wine in hand, cool breezes of Hargeisa swirling around, dressed in jeans and semi-glamorous (but always purposively casual) shirts, some ipod attached to portable speakers, listening to music that is on the verge of being hip back home and talking about the deep cultural differences between us and those that fill our daily lives (our clients, our friends, our colleagues, people we meet around).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have had a steady turnover in Hargeisa of expatriates lately.  And over that time there seems to be an increasing amount of tension between the expatriates and the Somalilanders.  I am not sure exactly why this seems to be happening (because this is Somaliland it is spoken of in metaphors and resides fully in the subtextual zone), but it has become increasingly tangible to me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the course of the past year there has been this tit-for-tat between the powerful voices for the expatriates and the powerful voices for the Somalilanders.  The problem is that those of us who aren’t given powerful voices become batted around as the game is played by others.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Something happened to me recently which I would like to use (again cloaked in metaphor and subtext, because this is how to communicate in Somaliland) as a tuusaale (example).  One of my best expat friends here in Hargeisa (who is a development worker) recently had some professional dealings with one of my best Somali friends (who is a mid-level government employee).  Due to forces above and beyond either’s control the dealings did not turn out well and both became frustrated by the situation (for very different reasons but that is beside the point).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a while I was caught in the middle of everything but the biggest problem was that I was getting completely different stories as to what happened from either “side” (so to say).  There was so little alignment between the stories that for a while I wondered if these were two completely different situations involving different people completely.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Later I started to piece it together, to connect the people that were being referenced by one story with how I organize those relationships when I’m talking to the other side, to connect the things that I knew were more important to one side with those that had little emphasis in the other’s side of the story.  I don’t know much about mediation, but I was trying to see these events through each side’s cultural lens and come to some sort of objective understanding of what likely transpired.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was only after spending literally hours trying to dig through and cross-check and re-examine and then start all over again that I was able to ferret out what may have actually happened.  And only after that did I realize that the actualities of the situation were out of the control of either party.  That happens in development work and it is one of the occupational hazards of this work.  However, the relational aspects of the situation were very much aggravated by the cultural differences between the parties.  It is this part – the cultural misunderstandings and their attendant relational aspects which causes (in my mind) undue hardships in development work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is why I wanted to write a few words over the course of the next little while trying to tell a few stories that have taught me a ton about humanity and culture (and which is which).  A few stories which I think of and use when I’m trying to analyze things through a foreign cultural lens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If I had to pick one of the most intellectually satisfying aspects of working here in Somaliland, it has been the opportunity to dig deep into a culture and a way of thinking and seeing the world that is very different than my own.  Each of the cultural differences, while stark at times, belies evidence of our common humanity.  Every time I become frustrated with the cultural differences then something will happen to me which will reinforce the common humanity which is always there.  The tenderness of a father’s reprimand, or a shared joke, or an extraordinarily kind act.  These things accompany each and every one of the cultural differences.  So I hope to share a few of these stories along the way as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Happy Dad&amp;#8217;s Day!</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-20-happy-dads-day/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-20-happy-dads-day/</guid><description>&lt;p>[![Happy Father's Day in advance to someone who may be mature enough to have children by age 62][2]][2]It is actually quite crazy to think that when my father was the age in which I currently find myself he had two sons (one 12 and one 9), and was on his third (or fourth?) house.  I, on the other hand, am childless, and property-less!  Although I must say very happily married.  So as I sit here in my house in Hargeisa and reflect upon the fact that I’m missing yet another holiday far away from my father and trying to justify why to myself, the only thing that makes sense is to put on some of my dad’s favorite songs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://www.someecards.com/card/3071">http://www.someecards.com/card/3071&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With such a soundtrack for successful blogging, I would like to thank my dad for (via nature &amp;amp; nurture) imbuing in me a curiosity and an open-mindedness about the world that have led me along the crazy path I’ve lived so far.  And although it has driven us apart geographically (as Ballad of Billy the Kid comes on) and forced me to miss some of these days in person, I’m there with you in spirit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I love you dad.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-11-15/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-11-15/</guid><description>&lt;p>Beaker Twitter = Hilarity. HT – Frank&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Piling it On.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-13-piling-it-on/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-13-piling-it-on/</guid><description>&lt;p>Consider me another addition!  From &lt;a href="http://www.politico.com/blogs/bensmith/0608/Fighting_smears_gaming_Google.html">Ben Smith&lt;/a>: &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wired's Thomas Goetz emails to make a great point about Obama's big &lt;a href="http://www.fightthesmears.com">FightTheSmears.com&lt;/a> rollout today:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>By putting their own website out there front-and-center, and then getting&lt;br>
everybody to link to it (starting with all the media covering the launch of the&lt;br>
site), the result will be to drive fightthesmears.com towards the top of a&lt;br>
Google search on, say, &amp;ldquo;obama muslim&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;michelle obama whitey.&amp;rdquo; Ideally, if&lt;br>
enough of the pro-Obama network links to fightthesmears.com, it'll drive the&lt;br>
sites that peddle in the rumor-mongering, which are now the first results on&lt;br>
said searches, off the top of the results list. Ideal long term result: any&lt;br>
curious low-information voter who eventually bothers to google these pesky&lt;br>
rumors will immediately be led to the debunking rather than the rumor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My&lt;br>
take: Did the Obama campaign create fightthesmears.com to game Google? If so,&lt;br>
they're even more net-savvy than folks give them credit for.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Indeed, Obama already had a protype of this page connected to his &lt;a href="http://factcheck.barackobama.com">Fact Check &lt;/a>site, and even bought &lt;a href="http://www.politico.com/blogs/bensmith/0108/An_antirumor_Google_ad.html">Google&lt;br>
ads&lt;/a> linking it. But this wave of publicity will probably push the new site&lt;br>
to the top of Google to stay.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bo Videos</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-06-12-bo-videos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-06-12-bo-videos/</guid><description>&lt;p>These are some videos we shot while upcountry in SL.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/underwater/files/bo_008driving_on_the_highway.mov">driving on the highway.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/underwater/files/bo_015_center_of_bo_people_here_are_much_more_relaxed.mov">standing in the center of bo. people here are much more relaxed.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/underwater/files/bo_018_short_thru_bo.mov">driving thru bo.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/underwater/files/bo_029_was_this_bridge_destroyed_during_the_war.mov">standing on a bridge conversing.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/underwater/files/bo_074_is_he_stupid.mov">taking the piss.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/underwater/files/bo_078_sketchy_bridge.mov">driving across an extremely sketchy bridge.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/underwater/files/bo_089_at_least_we_didnt_have_to_eat_balls.mov">at least we didn’t have to eat each other’s balls.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/underwater/files/bo_093_i_think_they_like_white_people_up_here.mov">i think they like white people up here.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/underwater/files/bo_094_grass_tunnel.mov">grass tunnel.&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>one more reason</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-12-one-more-reason/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-12-one-more-reason/</guid><description>&lt;p>i’m forgetting another salient reason:  i’d have to shave my face and head.  and i look too good in long hair to do that again.  ever. &lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-08-05-251/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-08-05-251/</guid><description>&lt;p>am reading kundera for the first time.  it is outlandish.  i’m learning so fucking much.  and i don’t even know czech to read it in the original.  am going to reread this flipping thing as soon as i finish it b/c there is too much here.  there are two basic things that i’m learning from him.  first, how to weave a narrative outside of time.  this thing is like a tarratino flick in that he likes to tell the story along certain lines other than a linear (based on time) slide.  there is organization here and i haven’t quite figured it out.  it isn’t completely, merely, just thematical separation, although there is an element of that.  it isn’t just isolated on one character out of the four in this particular section, b/c how can you tell the story of one without another.  and that is the point.  there is the essence of perspective, and i’m not completely unconvinced that he isn’t using each section to change perspective, but not exclusively, in other words he is not limiting himself to that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>the second thing that i’m learning is the integration of pop cultural reference.  although his pop cultural references aren’t allusions to vh1 shows, or US magazine articles, they are more like beethoven and nietzche (sorry about the germanic nature, blame him not me).  so i guess that it is more like literate references rather than pop cultural.  but he does these things to develop the theme, but not to develop the theme for him.  i have been working on this and thinking upon it more.  if you were to point to this movie quote, or say that this was like a bruce springsteen song (courtesy hornby) or whatnot…is that a copout.  i think it can be if you do it poorly.  however it can add a lot of color and depth to your characters if done correctly.  the bad thing about purely pop icons is that you would date your manuscript pretty distinctly.  if you were to step out a concentric ring from purely pop to somewhat enduring then you would not date it so much and more readers would have the opportunity to truly embrace what the hell you mean by &amp;ldquo;dropping names like change on a sunny day.&amp;rdquo; (as eric dsaid when he was drunk the other night. i’m not sure what he meant)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>in the real world still waiting on the word on the next manuscript.  my editor likes it and they have circled it around SMP.  they were going to bring it up in production meeting to talk about whether they want it or not.  i am pretty confident, especially based upon our publicists comment to the assistant publisher (Senior VP), &amp;ldquo;I don’t care if it sucks, I can sell the fucking thing.&amp;rdquo;  So maybe i’ll know today, maybe i’ll know tomorrow, maybe i’ll know next week, maybe i’ll know in september.  Who knows.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Am back east, in NC (winston-salem) visiting best ole friend.  have put 2200 miles on my car over the last week, have visited one cousin, one brother, one college friend, one college, one elementary friend, one law school, and now one best friend.  if no word comes tomorrow on the deal i will be signing a nashville lease on monday and then will spend the rest of the week moving in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>this shit is getting tight.  and i don’t mean TI-EGHT.  i mean flippin’ close&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-07-21-252/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-07-21-252/</guid><description>&lt;p>am i on a treadmill or actually road running.  cannot tell.  hopefully will know something soon&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-07-20-253/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-07-20-253/</guid><description>&lt;p>went and saw the young dubliners tonight at the little club in town.  the open band was called the saucy monkeys.  or something of the sort.  they were two artsy chicks with acoustic guitars.  for some reason i was reminded of the two chicas who opened for bush in 94 when i saw them with eric in orlando.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>yougn dubliners were &amp;ldquo;celtish rock&amp;rdquo; which i wasn’t so sure about…but it really was riverdance meets pop rock, including a fiddler who looked like the midnight oil dude, a bassist who looked exactly how henry rollins would look if he let his vanity go and got semi-fat and a lead guitarist who reminded me of the lead guitarist from frank black and the catholics who in turn reminds me of david bowie, but the guy from the &amp;ldquo;dubs&amp;rdquo; didn’t remind me of bowie at all.  the lead singer’s voice was pretty smooth and their hooks were catchy.  they got all the whiteys out on the dance floor shaking their feet around, patty style.  there were a ton of beautiful people there…i know….welcome to aspen right?  but one in particular who had tons of curly red hair and a really pristine face.  maybe it was becuase i was at an irish concert that i was so taken by her.  anyway i went with my friend who was jetlagged and really tired and we left early and i didn’t talk to the red haired girl even though she was tossing me looks now and again.  but, whatever….that is my MO right?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-07-18-254/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-07-18-254/</guid><description>&lt;p>the following things happened during my evening hike today:  i was startled by a fairly large brown bear when i rounded the corner and there he/she was 15 yards from me.  luckily she/he sauntered off.  i gave blood to the mosquito blood bank of the roaring fork valley….don’t they know i’ve been given the anthrax and small pox vaccinations and cannot give blood for another five years.  i startled a beaver and he made a pop sound with his tail and for a while i couldn’t figure out what had happened until i saw his dam and his house, which were directly in front of me the entire time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>and i almost hit bambi’s mom on the drive home.  eventful, beautiful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>watched school of rock again tonight because i’d been singing led zeppelin to myself most of the hike, when i wasn’t day dreaming.  and face it, we all need our jack black fix from time to time. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-04-07-255/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-04-07-255/</guid><description>&lt;p>does anyone else wonder what happens when you actually blast one of the ipod’s?  does it show up at your doorstep in a couple of days with a &amp;ldquo;thanks for playing our carnival game&amp;rdquo; note on the inside of the cubic apple box?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>on my way to dinner i saw a shirt that amused me, simply as i do not understand it.  it was one of those white t-shirts with the collar and cuffs at the sleeves in some muted gray color.  the shirt in block letters said: TONGUE SHIRT. one word to each line.  i don’t understand. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>tongue shirt?  won’t even conjecture an answer.  so i’m back from my ten year reunion and i suppose that i should reflect on the major event for posterity sake.  except that i didn’t really think it was that major.  it just was there, another event in my life.  i wonder if the lack of tv and movies in my life is allowing me to separate myself from what pop culture tells me is significant and allowing to pass my own judgements?  probably not.  it is probably just that i felt it was a relaxed happening with some people i hadn’t seen before.  i suppose that there have been times in my life in between graduation and now when i would have been &amp;ldquo;out to prove all those fuckers wrong&amp;rdquo; about me.  but those times have passed.  it was odd that they inherently proved themselves wrong without any posturing on my part. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>this is the most tangible way the war changed me.  i don’t need it, any of it.  i’ve already done that and now i just get to live my life. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>sure, i’m still an egotistical bastard, but less so than i have been.  there is much i have left to do, more that i have left to learn, but less that i have left to prove.  in the hollywood sports flick parlance, i left it all out there on the field and i can just look back fondly and say i did the job that i did and now i can look forward. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>its probably all drivel, i realize.  less than a week left of snow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-04-05-256/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-04-05-256/</guid><description>&lt;p>the pope passing on is significant.  i wonder how much of that significance will be lost on the seventh-day adventist church because of its complete anti-catholicism stance.  or will it perhaps spawn a thought process, one of reevaluation of that stance. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>if we are not constantly, vehemently justifying our existence would people still subscribe to the dogma?  i think that is the crux of the matter for some of the more learned leaders of my (former?) church.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>we have two pastors in our class:  bron and louis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>all is protected from here on out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-03-29-257/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-03-29-257/</guid><description>&lt;p>i feel sated. a snake on a warm spring afternoon curled on a sandstone deposit, belly full of mouse, jaw reattached, water near, people and mongeese far.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>have finalized summer plans, spring plans and other assorted plans.  will be diving into jamaica for 4/20 even though i’m not a pothead and don’t intend to become one.  its just an anthropological experiment, like so much of the rest of my life.  extended out my lease here through august. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>the train keeps turning its wheels.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-03-26-258/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-03-26-258/</guid><description>&lt;p>today i shall bew bland and newsy b/c i’m too warped to be funny and too jaded to be artsy.  i feel like complete shit today for no real reason.  last night was a our big, the ski season’s almost over fuckers party.  as per my usual i got on the near side of trashed, just coherent enough to convince many others that i’m not trashed and just trashed enough to through out my ensemble of social conditionings, self-loathings and general wallflowerness.  then i went home with a woman.  nothing happened, as half-way home i realized what the fuck, over? and ended up sleeping in the guest bed, on top of the covers, still in my gorilla suit.  but alas, everyone saw me leave with her.  now don’t get me wrong, she isn’t an unattractive woman, but i had quite the reputation brewing up here and now i’m wondering if that isn’t just a little bit altered.  had i had one less vodka drink i think everything would have been OK as i would have come to my WTF, mate epiphany a few minutes earlier and wouldn’t have left with her.  but whatever, i don’t really really care.  plus i think that my boss lady friend is seeing someone else, a friend of mine, on the sly.  that is another aspect to my feeling like shit today.  stir in a teaspoon of good ole’ hungover and you got yourself quite a dish of crap.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>have finally sketched out the summary for what will be the final runthrough of the shield proposal.  if he doesn’t accept this one then i surrender.  this is original and scary and good and fuck him if he doesn’t see that.  i think he will, but i’m just laying down the law. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>at least i have decided to stay for the summer, have decided to accept the hiking guide job and have decided to stay in this apartment.  that feels good, and the only real decision i have to make now is whether or not i’ll be here the last week of august or in nashville.  am thinking that it will be nashville unless some very specific and grand things happen to make me stay.  although what those could be, even with my &amp;ldquo;specific&amp;rdquo; word choice, i only semi-know.  i know what things could complicate a decision, but i’m not sure what would complicate it to the point of tipping the scales in a direction that my logic has not leaned it towards already.  as if that makes sense…?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>took a long walk and sat by the river.  it is engorged today from all the snow we’ve been having followed closely by warm temperatures.  haven’t ridden my snowboard in two days, must do that tomorrow.  now i’m drivelling and you have stopped caring.  good-bye&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-03-24-259/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-03-24-259/</guid><description>&lt;p>impressions of an evening in aspen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>clothes too poor in room of quadrillionaires.sushi left out too long.white wine somehow too crisp.is this a date or am i a seat filler.snow.headlights.crowds like the sand in the middle of the antique watch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>youngster.hipster.mullato.piano.hands upright.were those wrists slapped by an old lady with a ruler.noise pierces through cacophony that i’m unable to locate.ensembles are like cocktail parties.wallflower with my wine, against the wall.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>old crew.easy.at ease.peaceful in their existence.stage lights reflecting off the guitarists cufflinks directly into my eyes.contrasting hands of two bassists, one sinewy, one porky.largest elf i’ve ever seen onto stage, sits behind piano, shoulderless, on heroin.heroine.everyone bites their lip in their own way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>jazz, the balance of existence within a void.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-03-20-260/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-03-20-260/</guid><description>&lt;p>is no artistic output better than bad artistic output?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>do you have to be drugged to appreciate drug induced art?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>cameron was down, again, this weekend, for the night and was telling me a funny story.  he want to his public library up there in jackson (wy) to see a fiddler who seems to be a performance poet of some kind.  apparently the guy is from alaska and he tells stories, plays irish jigs on his fiddle and weaves wilderness poetry in the cracks.  all is well at this point we are very interested, right?  he has a cabin up in nome, ak and spends much time up there in a state of mental oneness with himself.  still OK right? &lt;/p>
&lt;p>well the crowd seemed to be excited about him, they were an ecclectic mix of high school students there for extra credit, families there for ANYTHING different to keep the kids enthralled for &amp;ldquo;a few minutes, a few minutes, a few minutes of SIIIIIILEnce&amp;rdquo; (paul westerburg), old couples and cam his sister and best friend in the crowd.  his comment on the crowd was they were the only three people among the ten’s that were crowding the small space that were under thirty-five and not forced to be there by some outside force.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>then the guy took the stage, burnt as cheech in 1978 after a hard day’s filming.  he told half of his stories before interrupting himself with some fiddling that would meander (always a medley becuase he could not decide on one song) for a few bars before asking a rhetoric or non-rhetoric question to the audience.  from time to time he would stop dead in his tracks and examine the drop ceiling tiles, i wonder if he was counting the holes in them or merely wondering in his stoned mind how they got up there.  at one point he stopped dead during an irish influence song based on a famous song everyone should know, but only loosely so you may not recognize it as this famous song and since he had titled the song texas you could just know it as texas from heretofore, and told the crowd that there was some &amp;ldquo;really good listening going one right now…&amp;rdquo; either that or he was just so out there that they were concentrating too hard to figure out his synopsial-crossings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>the unfortunate part, according to cam, was that his poetry was pretty good and his delivery, at least of the poetry, was quite good.  it seems unfortunate that it got drowned out by the cacophony of the other madnesses. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>it appears that i will not be joining jack on the national book and appearances tour.  i’m more than a little pissed and upset about the situation.  what i don’t want to happen is for a wedge to be driven between him and i.  i’m not sure if that isn’t going to become an inevitability (maybe i need more negatives in there), hopefully it work itself out, who knows.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-03-06-261/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-03-06-261/</guid><description>&lt;p>it is saturday night and i’m typing and enjoying wine and then going to sit down with my book for the rest of the evening.  damn i’m boring!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>last night i had a quasi-date with the guat_princess.  (as a side note i have decided the best thing about blogging is that i get to give real people fake names and pretend that i’m in sex in the city).  i’ll ruin it for all of you:  the act banished any interest that i had.  it was at dinner when it hit me.  during the movie (lame i know, but it was what she wanted to do.) there was much incidental contact.  i didn’t do what i’ve done too many times in the past and act upon it.  i just didn’t care.  so we went to the worst mexican restaurant ever afterwards.  i knew better than to go since it was horrible when big perm and i went, but again i bowed under the wind of her pressure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>we were speaking of cats for some odd, random reason and it was when she hit me.  she is exactly like a siamese cat: strinking and unobtainable.  i can’t really read her or figure her out, and i’ve stopped trying.  the enigma isn’t going to draw me further in, i refuse to let it. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>exit stage left one marginal interest, enter stage right another.  we’ll see how that goes tomorrow (or the next day, or monday, or tuesday….that’s how i roll). &lt;/p>
&lt;p>the culinary interest of the evening is regarding tater tots: they make me happy.  think that i’ll take a bath.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-03-04-262/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-03-04-262/</guid><description>&lt;p>i think that in the past i’ve been very patronizing towards hot chocolate and have made a conscious decision to rethink my position on the substance.  maybe it should be legalized afterall.  what do you think? &lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-03-03-263/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-03-03-263/</guid><description>&lt;p>i am quite tired and sore this evening.  not sure what i’m sore from, probably life beating me about my head and neck relentlessly without me really giving a damn and just taking it lick by fucking lick.  and i’m not talking about the tongue against ice cream cone kind either.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i also think that it is stupid people week and have been loudly blinking that out of my flourescent mouth.  i swear to god i’ve gotten the stupidest fucking people all week wasting my time.  i mean, it isn’t like i’ve been terribly busy, i’ve just been sitting there when not dealing with the stupid people.  but i’d much rather sit there than deal with morons.  rule number one or not, they tire me and make me sore.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>finished koopman’s book this week and almost done with 100 years….been a while huh?  well fuck you, i read slowly.  in regards to koop’s mss:  it is a decent account.  i don’t think that his sales will come close to ours, but it was still really good to relive things through another’s eyes.  jack didn’t seem concerned about him not corraborating our story, however, i was.  turned out that the only discrepancies i found were so minor that many copy editor’s wouldn’t have caught them.  the problem for his book is that he was an embedded reporter with a miltiary unit in iraq.  big flipping deal napoleon.  there are only a ga-gillion of thos books floating around and the big publishers with the big advertising budgets and big pull with BN and amazon already have their embedded reporter goes to iraq book.  his two-bit publisher just won’t be able to make things happen like the rolling stone dude’s guys (HarperCollins, I think) were about to.  And thus his book sold well.  that said, i liked it–a lot.  almost better than ours.  the thing that was terribly touching was that he included many of the emails that he received while he was with us.  it was very poignant to me seeing the other side, a side that i have been hidden from for some reason.  when you are there and in it you know the dangers that you’re taking, when you’re back here and watching and waiting your mind fears the worst.  like my craziness with marine_gurl a while ago….damn thoughts, why wont’ they just go away.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>law school you ask?  what the hell is he bringing that up for?  don’t know, just thought i’d share a bit of foreshadowing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>lastly, we’re back to the drawing board for the forth time on the shield proposal, not a biggy, guess i look at the other attempts as workouts.  at some point we’ll actually get into the game on this one, i suspect.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>have fun and smile, i am.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~  # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-03-01-264/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-03-01-264/</guid><description>&lt;p>WARNING:  this shit is VERY graphic and ENTIRELY conjecture.  just painting a picture of one way it could have gone down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>so it seems to me that i may be reading too much into the HST death.  it seems that no one cares.  am i the only one?  and i dont’ even really care, what I do care about is the social phenomenon the pop counter-culter icon itself. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>i actually don’t really give a damn that some old man put a .45 into his mouth, cocked it up towards the top of his head, took in one final, fatalistic and resigned deep nose-breath, sighed it out slowly, thought, &amp;ldquo;damn i’m wasted&amp;rdquo; and pulled the trigger straight back, all after he had previously played with the semi-automatic handgun for a number of hours while he sipped whiskey (or gorged on it depending on your alcoholism perspective) and free-based coke off some old metal spoon he had been using for just that purpose for over 20 years.  finally when his siatica acted up one too many times the old fucker said, that’s it and picked up the hand gun that he had been twirling and caressing with his fingertips on the side table.  the sound of the gun being pulled off the table and then checked to make sure it was loaded.  the sound of the slide going home on a full chamber and giving one final, audible resolute, detestable click were the only sounds in the room.  after one last gu8lp of his favorite whiskey and teh inevitable temporary paralysis that accompanies drinking any hard liquor neat, which as we all know is followed by the bitter beer face.  but probably not for this veteran, he had stifled that face many years ago in some masculine escapade where he determined he was more man than any of the other fuckers at the woody creek tavern and he wasn’t going to give in to them and their bitter beer faces, no matter how good or bad the whiskey, his reaction was always the same, simple zen realization that the hard liquor was trickling down his throat and going to further intocicate him.  that was it.  the gun was cool on his lips and semi-comforting at first and in his completely obliterated baseline state he didn’t even really care about that or the fact that his siatica was really hurting.  the liquor was literally eating him from the liver out and he didn’t give a fuck becuase it had been with him too long and there was no way you were going to talk him out of his bottle now.  the only way to end this thing was in one blaze of glory and since he wasn’t a terribly courageous man he would just cower and take his own life–Papa H style.  The tip of the gun pointed toward the roof and then exploded with fire and small bits of metal and one large piece of lead.  the fire created a presser that his closed lips could not contain and it then exploded out of his mouth as the bullet was careering through his sinuses towards the middle of his brain.  HST wasn’t fucking around he knew exactly what he was going to do.  he wouldn’t have fucked it up.  the large caliber bullet had fragmented somewhere between his brain and sinuses and the pressure that was leading the bullet had already cracked his skull when the fragments pushed half of his scalp off his head and onto the ceiling.  that was it.  his legacy was complete. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>it was the only way that it could end for the comet from another time.  other than being an icon his relavancy, although surely needed, was called into question on many questions by others and surely by himself.  all he ever wanted to do was to raise hell and to push his personal agenda.  so fuck that mother fucker.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i guess i really only care becuase it is something to care about.  there isn’t much else that i can get passionate about in this town right now since my sights have been moved elsewhere.  so that’s it!  told you it was graphic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-02-23-265/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-02-23-265/</guid><description>&lt;p>Now, I must do this justice, and to do that I need to back up.  First, some background. His name is Hunter S. Thompson, if you don’t know that name, google him.  I find some odd parallel’s in my living in the same town with the counterculture icon when he dies and with Eric’s story of his friend farting next to Allen Ginsberg’s coffin during some candlelit vigil to the old beat-en poet.  Fast-forwarding and keeping my vile flatulence under control I paint the background of the piece before revealing the subject.  He died two nights ago now, shot himself in the head with a .45.  The rumors around town vary, but the prevailing story is he was old and dying and he just sped up the process.  Many have discounted my first thought that it was  drunken accident by the posterboy for &amp;ldquo;alcoholics among us.&amp;rdquo;  His &amp;ldquo;compound&amp;rdquo; [paragraphical insert: he didn't have a house, the local's tend to pay him some sort of weird homage among the castles that litter the countryside up in the extremely posh neighborhood where he lives, he doesn't have a simple house like Michael Douglas or Prince Bandar, but a fortified compound&amp;hellip;.I guess that is how you can standout in a place like Assssspen.] was two doors down from where my landlord lives.  We stop the story there merely to rewind a bit, because I don’t think you know this part of the story.  I rent a townhouse in a small &amp;ldquo;suburb&amp;rdquo; of the spotlight in the valley that is aspen from a lady who is the personal assistant to some bigwig Aspen-ite.  She was married before and currently a widow and her late-hubby was some 18 trillion-th generational Aspen-ite.  So she is very ingrained with the local history of the place.  Well she is in this odd relationship that after months of observation I cannot commit to any sort of vague or clear categorization–with my roommate.  To summarize, I live with the &amp;ldquo;boyfriend,&amp;rdquo; becuase she is still the personal assistant and as the bigwig grows older and more senile she must spend more time up there near him.  So she has a guest house beside the castle, nothing special in this fucked up world.  Her house is a few acres away from the compound.  The first time I went up to her house to sign my lease I was jolted into some flashbacks when the windows of her house rumbled and the floor of her elevated treated hardwood flooring shook under my dirty new balance shoes.  When I got up from my involuntary temporary fetal position she told me not to worry that it was just Hunter blowing dynamite which was much worse than the naval flare guns or the simple handguns and shotguns.  Me being the Assssspen virgin I wondered aloud, Hunter who?  She told me HST, and I thought, oh, that freak.  Well, I put that memory away on some unused shelf beside the time in gradeschool when Justin Birmele and I were filling out some form and he said &amp;ldquo;sex, yes please,&amp;rdquo; in response to the &amp;ldquo;male or female&amp;rdquo; response we were supposed to give–until the last few days.  I was speaking with my terribly off roommate about HST tonight and how I had grabbed a few of the Aspen Daily New’s to send to a few lucky friends and then he responded in his burnt-out-smoked-as-much-hash-as-cheech way that he had something to show me.  The he dug for a while and came to my room, a rare occurance and asked if I wanted to read the greatest HST shit ever.  I said, why not, I don’t have anything going on, being between books and waiting on many things to happen before Jim will take our next proposal to the street even though it is close to finished.  Then matt, the roommate, brought out these rolled up things that his &amp;ldquo;girlfriend&amp;rdquo; my landlord had gotten many years ago, 1970 in fact.  That year HST was going to run for sheriff and to bolster his campaign and also to promote his personal racket and other things he and a local artist, thomas benton, made these &amp;ldquo;newspapers.&amp;rdquo;  I am not sure how many of them were done, but the following excerpt was taken from the June 30, 1970 edition, Wallpapers No. 2. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>I guess some of you could see my sending this through some tiny clear wires that light passes through and eventually it will pop up on your screens as some sore of endorsement of HST’s lifestyle or his belief system.  That isn’t the case, I’m simply sharing a piece of history with you.  enjoy it or don’t, your choice:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>*from the class of ’58…EPITAPH…to the class of ‘70&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The following article – or Commencement Address – has a strange history.  It was originally written in 1958, by Milton Mayer, and published that year in The Christian Century – where it was noticed by a young writer at &lt;em>Time&lt;/em> magazine.  He added an introduction of his own and sent it up the tube to the ME’s office, where it was rejected out of hand.  &lt;em>Time&lt;/em> was still pruning its “upbeat” image in’58; the package was still super-slick, with no room at all for depressing things like this.  I was working there at the time –supposedly learning “The Business” –and in my role as trainee/copyboy/hired-punk-of-all-trades, I often found myself delivering rejected articles back to the writers.  Usually I read them enroute, and in this case I decided to make a xerox copy of the reject before letting it go….if for no other reason than that it was very weird thing to find floating around in the editorial mill at &lt;em>Time.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The writer, Jack Skow, was not surprised when I brought the manuscript back to him.  We talked for a while about &lt;em>Time&lt;/em>, writing and the whorish hazards of a scene we were both just getting into 00 and we assured each other, very firmly, that no journalist with any self0respect could work very long for *Time, *and that we would both be gone very shortly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That night, after work, I went back to my apartment and dropped my copy of Skow’s doomed article in a trunk, where it spent the next 12 years.  I was living, that winter, in a freak-slum just off the Columbia University campus at 113th and Broadway.  &lt;em>Time&lt;/em> was paying my tuition, presumably on the theory that sooner or later I would “settle down” and become a useful cog-wheel in the Luce empire.  I was a nice arrangement – for me, at least – but my clearest memory of that era is a night in the West End Bar when Jack K made his first appearance on national TV.  On The Road was just out, and the West End was jammed with a wild hell-broth of student-types who cheered crazily at everything K said.  His words hardly mattered.  He was a “beatnik,” whatever that meant, and so were we.  K was speaking for all of us; he was a young Columbia refugee who ran amok and still made it big, on his own terms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That was the night, I think, when I decided to quite my job at* Time* and get into full-time craziness.  The first year was heavy, but by 1960 with JFK in the White House it was suddenly not so bad to be a misfit.  Kennedy found them useful, and his taste set the style; by the end of ’63 exmisfits had accumulated such vast leverage on all fronts that even now – seven evil years later and despite relentless weeding by the best hired pros in the game – the American Establishment is still riddled with very competent Kennedy-style misfits.  Nixon has never understood them, and John Mitchell never will.  They are a strange breed – cynical as old pawnbrokers, yet haunted losers, still waiting…not liking themselves too well and sometimes feeling half-dead, or maybe just half-alive; and usually about half-corrupt, in the shadow-memory of things un-done and un-tried….&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thinking along these lines the other night I found myself rooting through an old trunk, looking for my Xerox copy of Milton Mayer’s 1958 commencement address.  It was there, along with Skow’s original Time-style introduction:&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="the-corrupt-and-the-dead">&lt;em>The Corrupt and the Dead&lt;/em>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>“To a generation that sometimes calls itself Beat came a message from the generation that is old enough to know what a moral beating modern man gives himself, In the Christian Century, middle-aged (49) Author Milton Mayer (The Revolution in Education) writes a dour document address to the class of ‘58”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“If my own history and the history of the race is instructive, this commencement is for nearly every last one of you the commencement of disintegration.  You have lived 20 years in a deplorable society.  You have lived sheltered lives, but you have had no one to shelter you from your parents and teachers.  Your parents have done what they could to adjust you to the deplorable society to which they have successfully adjusted themselves.  When they said you were improving, they meant that you were getting to be like them.  When they said they hoped you would keep out of trouble, they meant that you should not do anything that they wouldn’t do.  But some of the things that they wouldn’t do should have been done.  The condition of society is the proof of their criminal negligence.  Your teachers are no better.  They have done as they were told, and in a deplorable society there are some things that men are told to do that no men should do. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Like your teachers and your parents before you, you will be told to do bad things in order to hold your job.  In college you may have quite the campus daily or defied the old fraternity on principle.  It will be harder to quite the metropolitan daily or defy the Old Country on principle; it will be easier to forget the principle.  You will have wives (at least one apiece) and children to maintain.  You will have a home and mortgage to enlarge.  And neighbors who are having their children’s teeth straightened.  Your dentist’s bills alone will corrupt you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“You protest my melancholy prediction, but the Great Actuarial Table is against you.  Twenty-five years from now, nine out of ten of you (or all ten) will tolerate an existence which, if you could foresee it now, you would call intolerable.  You won’t even know that you are corrupt.  You will have friends who praise in you the characteristics you have in common with them.  And if, some sudden night, you go berserk and bawl out that life is a sell, they will put you to bed with the assurance that you will be all right in the morning.  And you will be.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Twenty-five years from now you will celebrate your 20th wedding anniversary.  Because you love your wife – still more if you don’t – you will want to celebrate it in style.  You will reserve a window table for two at the choicest restaurant in town, and the champagne bucket will be at the table when you arrive.  AS your eye travels down the menu it will be distracted by something outside the window, which will prove to be a hungry man.  Do you know what you will do then, 25 years from now? You will call the maitre-d’ and tell him to have the drapes pulled, and he will tell the waiter, and he will tell the bus boy, who will do it.  Thirsty, and a little nervous still, you will sip your glass, forgetting to toast your wife, and resume your study of the menu.  And then for the first time you will see, in fine italic print at the bottom, the words, ‘the Management reserves the right to refuse service to anyone.’  And then you will know (for you will be an educated man) that you are sitting in a Jim Crow restaurant.  What will you do?  You will stay at the table and order your dinner and eat it.  You will have been measured for corruption and found to fit.  I do not doubt that I would have raised the flag at Iwo Jima, rather than let it drop in public.  But I was the man who took his wife to dinner at the Jim Crow restaurant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“I don’t mean that you won’t continue to have good impulses.  You will.  From time to time, as the vestige of your springtime idealism stirs you, you will want to do the right thing.  But you will have to put off doing it until you have buried your father, and then your mother, your brother, your children, and your grandchildren.  You may life to be very old, but you will not outlive the last descendant for whose sake you will suppress your good impulses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“I would not steal another man’s watch unless my children were starving, and my children would never be starving.  Nor will yours’ the reason is that you will have been corrupted.  Your corruption will save you from having to decide whether to steal another man’s watch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Other, more agreeable commencement orators have warned you of life’s pitfalls.  I tell you that you are marked for them.  I believe you will not escape them because I see nothing in your environment that has prepared you even to recognize them.  You were divinely endowed to know right and to do right, and you have before you, in the tradition of your country and of human history, the vision to help you if you will turn to it.  But the dictates of your society, of any society, will not serve you.  They are the dictates that corrupted your parents and your teachers.  If Socrates did not know where virtue came from — and he didn’t – neither do I.  He pursued it earlier and harder than anyone else and concluded that it was the gift of God.  In despair of your parents and your society, of your teachers and your studies, of your neighbors and your friends, and above all of your fallen nature and the Old Adam in you, I bespeak for you the gift of God.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>postscript&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>            Now, 12 years later, that late-1950’s world that Mayer was talking about seems a million miles away.  Jack K is dead, at the age of 52, and so is Eisenhower.  Jack Skow quite &lt;em>Time&lt;/em> right on schedule, and went to work for the &lt;em>Saturday Evening Post&lt;/em>.  He got married and had a few children, and when the &lt;em>Post&lt;/em> folded he went to free-lancing.  The last time I saw his byline was in &lt;em>Playboy&lt;/em> at the time.  They assigned me to write about Jean-Claude Killy’s new lifestyle – which I did, but they refused to print it.  And &lt;em>Time&lt;/em> larded the irony by quoting me to the effect that *Playboy *is “a conspiracy of anemic masturbators.”  That was accurate, but &lt;em>Time&lt;/em> couldn’t handle the rest of that quote – which appeared, for good or ill, in &lt;em>Scanlan’s Monthly.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>            But at this point – and in this context 00 the quote hardly matters.  Neither Skow nor I understood, back then, what Mayer was really saying.  There was no way to know, without going to the well, and even now I can’t be sure Mayer was right.  But I’d like to talk to Jack Skow about it, and probably I will sometime soon.  Or maybe not; some things are better left alone, or at least left quietly.  My own history, since then, would twist the nerves of any hiring agent or corporate personnel director like the man who originally signed me on for Time, Inc.  He told me I would “do well,” and no doubt he told Skow the same thing.  Jack K never worked for &lt;em>Time&lt;/em>, but he was a football hero at Columbia – and that knowledge must surely put a lump in the throats of all the good folk around the fountain in St. Petersburg.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>            As for Mayer’s “dour document,” well…my own advice, on the basis of experiences, is to read it once, quickly, then stuff it in a trunk and read it again about 10 years later.  It comes on very slow, and some of the lines are dated…but I think its still worth reading, even though &lt;em>Time&lt;/em> wouldn’t print it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>                                                                – Hunter S. Thompson&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-01-14-266/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-01-14-266/</guid><description>&lt;p>i spent the entire day cuddling with myself and reveling in the peacefulness.  odd roommate has been conspicuously absent for the past few days and i have barely ventured outside for more than a solitary walk to convince myself that the sun puts out vitamins that i needed to or could actually soak in through all my layers as i walked around in the teen-something degree air and tried to maintain breathing through a stuffed up nose that was pierced by the freezing cold air. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>have been reading &amp;ldquo;one hundred years of solitude&amp;rdquo; which i have slowly come to realize is a massive undertaking in which garcia marquez has attempted to comment on the entire history of the human race and i have taken to internally calling it the &amp;ldquo;brief history of time, latin american version.&amp;rdquo; &lt;/p>
&lt;p>have been playing massive amounts of jazz from my gaudy collection that has become unruly unless i listen to some as-yet-un-heard tune-age. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>the reading and jazz seem to be at odds with each other.  the reading has rekindled the sense of adventure.  that fire has been stoked by the fact that i have not left this place in two months.  i haven’t driven for more than 15 minutes.  i haven’t left the 30 square mile radius.  i have not been outside one of the three towns i’ve been habitating.  the fact that marquez speaks of places i know nothing about not to mention the quest for adventure beginning to mount as a major theme in the book have both made me go &amp;ldquo;ummm.&amp;rdquo;  the jazz is pulling me the other way.  it always make me think of calm sunday mornings reading the new york times over a steaming mug of coffee while it plays quietly or not so quietly in the background.  walking around in a hugh heffner robe onto the balcony and looking out over some scenic view and thinking, damn that’s nice.  it makes me long for some sort of a life that i am not sure if i even want, but the picture is there in my head and some sort of desire is attached to it.  always has been.  the dream of settlign here in aspen plays off of that becuase this is the type of place where you really can do something like that.  if you only have enough money to support those muses.  it is so cyclical with me the nomadic desires rise and fall and rise and fall and i can feel them rising right now.  in one hand it is a copout that makes me not want to participate fully in life NOW becuase i’m always looking to get out of this and move somewhere new.  i think that it has become some sort of a coping mechanism on some level.  but whatever it is there and there is no sense trying to fight it.  the only real compromise or satisifaction would be found in having a home of one’s own and traveling from there.  but there are so many drawbacks to that as well.  what if it isn’t in a good place, what if you cannot stand where you are, what, what, what, why. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>i’m just a bucket of indecision.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-12-04-267/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-12-04-267/</guid><description>&lt;p>i’m sore.  and i don’t mean butt-hurt, even though my butt does hurt.  well, the ass muscles hurt.  i’ve been riding hard for the past two days, and i don’t mean the ladies–the snow baby.  the riding skills are coming back faster than i imagined that they would.  i was jumping natural kickers both in the groomers and in the trees.  i was taking the bumps and the trees without pausing.  i even jammed a few rails.  i was screaming faster than i think i’ve ever ridden. the snow here is really really hard and fast, but you can go fast b/c you know that it isn’t going to ice on you and have your board slip out from you as long as you are riding correctly.  that i something that i’ve had to learn how to do again, ride correctly.  the bottom line is that i haven’t made a complete ass out of myself.  excellent–in my best crazy scientist voice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>speaking of crazy scientists, tonight 20/20 had on the guy who runs BALCO, the steroid factory.  or at least the one that has gotten all the press.  he was an interesting guy, mainly b/c of how unrepentant he was.  he portrayed illegal drug usage to be on an epidemic proportions.  that does not surprise me.  the few things that did surprise me, though, was the lack of finger pointing directed at football and at basketball.  football received one very small segment that was directed at romanousky (who strikes me as an ass anyway) and that was it.  the majority of the program was involved with sprinters.  with the remainder going to baseball.  i think that viewers were much more interested and connected with the baseball segments as people don’t really internalize T&amp;amp;F unless you are into it.  the normal majority of people probably routed for marion jones during the olympics, forgot about her for four years, were reminded of who the hell she was and went, oh yeah i rooted for her before.  there is not following of the olypmic sports in this country like there is of: baseball, basketball and football.  not a unique comment. however, i was interested to see that football came away almost completely clean and of course the stereotype is for that sport to be the most prone to steroid and performance enhancing potions.  i am not as surprised to see basketball, which has its own problems and could ill afford to have this pile one, not get pointed towards.  it is a sport that is much more skill related and a lot less pure performance related.  unless you are defending against shaq in the low post you don’t have a terrible need to become much stronger.  anyone can be fast on a breakaway, but you still have to dribble the ball on the breakaway.  so i could see why some may take EPO which is an endurance drug (clear throat, pause, Kobe) but other than that i just don’t see the need.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>my xmas cd’s are finished burning.  yeah i can have theme music for the car now.  four cd’s worth.  god bless i-tunes.  now i just need a bigger harddrive and an ipod so i can really work on my music collection! &lt;/p>
&lt;p>on a lift today i was struck by the pack resemblance that all the duders maintain.  for those of you that don’t know what a duder is, watch the XGames for those are duders and the heros of the rest of the duders.  baggy pants with long poofy jackets.  beenies and goggles like the rest of us, but they maintain them at precarious angles where the rest of us like to keep them at straight angles to the world.  they talk with an advanced vocabulary.  that is the only way to describe it, b/c the rest of the world has no clue what the f they are saying!  i never noticed before how terribly rare it is to see them by their lonesome.  there is either a complete lack or an infestation.  they are just pack animals.  herd animals.  they like to keep the air of superiority even if they aren’t that good and it is helped by the twin tip skiers who have wakes the size of slalom water skiers consisting of snow that will blind, pelt and annoy any outsider who tries to get too close to the pack.  i also realized today, well, remembered in fact, how much hotter a chick in twin tips is in comparison to a chick on a snowboard.  for some reason chicks on snowboards just aren’t that hot to me any more.  what the F am i getting that old?  damn life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>rode the lift with this guy who was 82 today.  he was awesome.  and old.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>enjoy life b/c what the hell else can you do with it!!!!  all from assssspen for now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-11-22-268/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-11-22-268/</guid><description>&lt;p>i feel like i have come almost full circle, let me explain. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>i had reached a point of something this summer that was unlike anything i had ever reached before.  i am not sure whether that was a zen state of living or just the ability to thoughtfully live in the present.  whatever title you choose to give to it i was there.  i wasn’t working, but i was constantly working.  i was living like i hadn’t lived before.  although i had taken the spill off the rock and the whole head thing i was past that to a point.  i wasn’t able to lead climb but i was able to climb again.  i was running rivers, i was wakeboarding.  but all of those i think were secondary.  really what i was doing was reading and working.  it didn’t seem like that to my goal driven mother, but that is what was happening.  it was all internalized and no one but me was able to see it.  i didn’t have some sort of a strange glow about me like i had just had sex (which was not happening on a daily basis at least) or that i had just been baptized into some evangelical cult.  it was on some levels deeper than that and probably on some levels shallower. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>what was happening was i was changing the way my mind was working.  i was observing things deeper.  i always could read people and decypher what their likely motivations for this or that were.  but suddenly i realized that i was able to internalize their story in a way that i hadn’t before.  maybe i was just beginning to fancy myself as a writer, or maybe i was slowly becoming one.  as i was living the life on the rocks in the river or in panera things were becoming crystallized to me.  i was able to look at colors and realize that they were there.  i was slowing down.  i told brian once about this and he replied with the quote from happy gilmore:  welcome to my world gramma.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>and then that was shattered.  or i should rephrase it properly, i allowed it be shattered.  i had the fling with marine_gurl that i will always wonder about.  why did i let myself do that?  was i a search for belonging or was it living how i wanted to live or was it more vindictive than that?  did i want to prove to her that she had made the wrong decision those years ago when she dumped me.  and not becuase i regretted my current life, but that i was still angry for all the hurt she threw at me?  i remain unsure of the answers to those questions, and they aren’t the point of this post.  the point is that i was taken out of that zen state of everything and nothingness.  or to use an existential reference i was taken out of my transcendence and into immanence.  (or do i have those backwords, i guess it doesn’t matter)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>what happened was this, i returned to my familiar goal oriented way of thinking.  and since i wasn’t achieving anything i allowed myself to daydream of when i would have achieved these stated goals, and i don’t even remember what they may have been.  i became unhappy and unsettled for a long period of time.  i guess that is it.  after sitting here for five minutes trying to figure out what the next sentence is, i guess that there isn’t one.  that is the bottom line.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>but now things are different.  i wonder if it is the environment, the relationships (or lack of), or just mindset.  like i’ve said too many times in this post, i don’t really know.  but i feel that i’m slowly returning to that place.  of course i will always daydream, but i am not letting myself be driven by those daydreams, they are pleasant places to visit but i’m not sure that i truly expect for them to become a reality.  is that giving up or living inside of the real?  i’m not sure, i guess much of the answer to that question would depend on what you are dreaming of and the plausibility of that dream.  most of mine are implausible and that is what makes them dreams.  i think that is fundamentally different than what the famous successful people proclaim from podiums at self-help seminars:  follow your dreams and all that.  i think that those kinds of dreams are different.  of course i have those too, and frankly i’m living that.  i’m following that advice, and i’m not sure where it is leading, and i’m not sure that it matters. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>i could be in law school right now.  close to my family and safe in vanderbilt where i would have a built in community of friends between my peers and eric’s already established community.  but here i am, moving (again) to a place where i knew no one simply becuase i wanted to ski.  i am writing everyday and not sure that i’m getting better but at least am getting smoother.  and that is that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>in my mind this post boils down to this:  i guess that i am following my dreams, but for once the correct ones, the obtainables that i will have to work for, but not the unobtainables that fall into my lap. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>and that is what i feel terribly good about.  i feel like some fucking switch in my mind has been turned back on, and now i’m feeling my way towards a safe well-lit place that i had glimpsed before but never really touched.  let’s see if i can get there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-11-13-269/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-11-13-269/</guid><description>&lt;p>i feel refreshed.  i feel wierd in fact, because there has been some odd vindication that has came at the same time as an odd amount of conflict.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>first there was the major conflict, and that one was internal.  i left 29 palms about 10 days ago thinking that i would have resolution on the aspen job quickly.  either she would offer me the job or she would tell me to pack sand.  at least that was how it was in the movie that i was playing over and over again in my head with various endings and middles.  so i drive to aspen and i interview with her.  the lady is really nice as is everyone around the mountain.  a few things happen (which would add color here, but alas, i cannot remember) that spark my imagination to take over.  &amp;ldquo;oh, they are omen’s that i shall be here for the winter, wasn’t that nice of the powers that be to do that for me….thank you powers that be.&amp;rdquo;  and so it goes.  after what i thought was a pretty good interview (and it turns out a great interview, but not good enough, too much foreshadowing, i don’t know) i ask her when she will make her decision.  &amp;ldquo;monday.&amp;rdquo;  &amp;ldquo;monday? holy cow that is a while.&amp;rdquo;  is my thought response.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK no big deal, i have not been to colorado since i’ve realized that it is OK to develop opinions of your own outside of groupthink, aka since i graduated high school.  so i decide to roll down to boulder.  prior internet research had revealed a hostel down there where i can get a private room for something on the order of 30 a night.  easy peesy i think.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>so i roll to boulder and the town is remarkable.  yaddy yadda.  i liked it yaddy yadda. well then i wait all day on monday and then most of the morning on tuesday.  i’m feeling really displaced and really poor and really just blah.  finally the chica calls me and says, well i chose someone that was more familiar with aspen ski schools and whatnot, but would you be interested in this other job.  i thought what the hey.  so i jump in the car and start heading back out towards the mountains.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>luckily about the time that i arrive in glenwood springs, the major turnoff from the interstate and one of the few places along the &amp;ldquo;I-70 corridor&amp;rdquo; where you have excellent cell coverage, this lady calls me.  we talk for not very long and she offers me the job, taking phone calls from tara reid’s personal assistant when she wants lift tix and ski skool lessons.  fine, easy job i think, plus i think that is a chick’s job so there should be a high percentage of ladies around, even if they are married they’ll wanna hook me up with their single friends.  so i accept their offer.  and i head down to snowmass and shake their hands and get my paperwork and all, finally heading to the aspen hostel where it is a few dollars more expensive but equally blase. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>sitting on my bed, cell in hand i break out the papers and start calling people.  i call about 15 people and three get back to me.  one is a weirdo that wanted approximately a million dollars to move into his campy altar to all the is kitsch and ugly, the second was an old lady whose first words out of her mouth were how i was to keep the room spotless and make my bed everyday and keep the showerwalls scrubbed and finally the third lady seemed nice, but i couldn’t see the place until the following morning.  so after about the 17th night in a row of fitfull, stressed sleep i wake up and come visit the third place. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>it is actually a sane place, internet, good cell reception, furnished with nice furniture, a TV, heat, and not too expensive, it met all my criteria in that order and i was pleased so i signed the lease on the spot and gave her my money and felt good about myself.  went to my orientation, got my ski pass and moved in and got a post office box and a bank account and generally became settled over the course of today and the previous two.  i feel more settled now than since i left 29 palms the first time. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>running parrallel to this has been an emotional rollercoaster that i refuse to ride with regards to the writing.  shooter is now almost finished, we have 21 of 27 chapters completed and next week we should finish the rest and have everything into charlie and hopefully approved so we can look at the check sometime in the middle of december.  jack has been courting the head of publicity who we found out was charlie’s boss big time.  it turns out that he has lots of power in the company and we let the dog slip out about our project and he got totally jazzed about it.  apparently along a similar timeline jim let slip to charlie about our project too.  so both of them know about it.  according to jim that could work for us, but it could also work against us because it is possible that they wouldn’t want to make a move until they saw sales results on shooter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>well today was the apex of all of this, and if i ws less tired and drained i could do a much better job with the narrative and really have built up the suspense, but sucks to be you the reader, because i’m just going to cut to the chase.  jim loved our project.  he thinks that it is sellable, he thinks that we can do this for a living, he thinks that we are going to make money, and decent money too.  he liked our writing style and our characters.  what he didnt’ like was the plot premise of our book, he didn’t like it being historical fiction and he didn’t like the lack of a &amp;ldquo;face to the villian.&amp;rdquo;  but the plot wasn’t the important thing to me it was the writing style and the characters that we developed.  we can plug those characters now into a different scene without a problem.  so now we are back to work hardcore on shield and we are both jazzed and charged about the project.  we’ll see where it goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-11-08-270/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-11-08-270/</guid><description>&lt;p>five days later i make my next entry.  this time it is from the boulder public library where i’ve been camped out for a bit and pretending i’m back in college and doing something productive with my time.  i think that i’ve found where i want to live.  boulder has the quadfecta as i’ve deemed it of:  climbing, kayaking, ski, community.  those are the four things that i’ve looking for in places to live.  there are lots of other smaller things, but generally they come with the above four.  this town is beautiful, near the mountians, has decent weather, nice people, a great art scene, bouldering within walking distance, skiing an hour away, kayaking through town, ice climbing an hour and a half, more trad and sport routes within 15 minutes of the town than i could probably do in a lifetime.  coffeeshops with great art, funky music and weird people.  it is just fantastic here.  the college is loud and rambunctious and there is just a great vibe in the town.  everyone works out, i’ve seen like 2 fat people in my two days here so far.  it is fantastic.  well i’ll get off boulder’s crank now i’ve done enough! &lt;/p>
&lt;p>but to get here in the form that would really be acceptable it’ll take a little while.  at least through the winter.  i could must stay here, find a job and a room somewhere and settle down.  i don’t think that is how i’d like to roll it.  i think that i’d really like to settle here, with my stuff, in an apartment, yaddy yadda.  but that will take money which i don’t have and time which i do have.  they will have to coincede and have not yet. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>the good thing about visiting this town is that i feel like i’m coming to grips with the picture of how my life will be if the writing thing can actually happen.  i’ve retained a good grasp of what lawyer casey would be like:  vandy, nyc, suburbia.  but i have had too many pictures of what writer casey would look like.  i think that this would be it.  boulder-writer-casey.  i like the thought.  just like always it seems i’m in a holding pattern.  hopefully jim will get back to us this week with some news and i can start planning on writing or law-ing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i have to wait till monday to find out about the aspen job.  i went by breck and i like the scene there, but it is a long, convuluted process getting a job at the vail resorts and i don’t think that i’m going to fuck with it.  so like so many other times in my life all my eggs are in one basket:  aspen.  if marge calls me tomorrow and says no then back east for mamo’s birthday.  if she calls and tells me yeah then off to aspen and searching for tix to dave’s wedding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i guess that is about it.  i’m leaving the library now to walk a mile or so to the rocks and fall off of them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-11-02-271/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-11-02-271/</guid><description>&lt;p>well i’m reading all these things about how the vote has begun. so, in a sign of things to come:  i have lost a toe nail.  and it isn’t one of the small ones, it is the big one on my left foot.  on a hike about four weeks ago i stubbed it terribly bad while i was running down the insanely steep hill and trying to avoid both the rocks and the cacti.  the past two fall seasons i have used that technique to hone my quick feet skills in hopes that it’ll help me on the snow covered mountains. it didn’t really help me that i can pinpoint last year, but i stuck to the technique this year…dumby me, huh?  well, i stubbed my big toe and my middle toe pretty badly and they were f-ed up pretty badly.  so i did the ole’ technique that i’ve seen doc’s use (which BTW joe told me afterthefact was the correct one to use) of heating up a safety pin with a lighter until it was glowing hot and then burning through my toenail until there was a small hole in it.  well after four or five tries i finally burned completely through the nail on the big toe and when i pulled it out that last time five gallons of fluid came pouring out from underneath.  luckily i had at papertowel handy to sop much of it up.  then i burned through my middle toenail in one elegant fell swoop.  and that one was taken care of too.  well i had been anxious about the toenails for a couple of weeks and then randomly the big one fell off two nights ago.  the entire f-ing thing.  i’ve lost toenails before but they were on the smaller nails.  this one is the big one baby. and that is crazy.  so i feel concerned b/c the only other person that i’ve known that has lost a big toenail has been dave and he’s had about 19 different ingrown toenails since then.  so that cannot be good.  but i’m living with a nailless big toe.  it looks odd, because the skin is still there thinking that there is a nail, but there isn’t.  i had all kinds of scabbing and such on the skin that i steadily picked off, but every time i touched the skin where the nail used to be it sent shivers down my spine like fingernails on the proverbial blackboard.  but whatever, i’m growing used to it now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>my two predictions for the election tomorrow are this:  number one: there will be the largest turnout ever.  number two: there will not be the major problems that everyone is claiming there will be and there will actually be a clear winner.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>it seems that whenever the press proclaims that something will be a major problem it never ends up turning out thusly.  like the old &amp;ldquo;sunscreen&amp;rdquo; song. the real troubles in your life are things that hit you on some idle tuesday.  and worrying is like trying to solve an algebra problem by chewing bubblegum.  classic!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>preliminary results on the novel proposals were received from jim, the agent, today:  Damn, you Marines don’t do anything half-assed. This is good stuff! And lots of it, too. I’ve read about half of LIBERTY’S SHIELD in this office this morning and will finish and report this week if I can steal enough reading time from my family. Jim. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>i think that is good.  we’ll find out. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>well i’m drunk enough now in celebration and in my standard wine drinking formula that i’ll go to bed now and revel in the fact that my agent actually liked something that i wrote and then i’ll get up tomorrow, hope that my van sells quickly and hope that i can talk the aspen chick into giving me a job on friday when i interview with her.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>enjoy!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-10-31-272/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-10-31-272/</guid><description>&lt;p>decisions decisions decisions.  i guess that i have made my bed and now i’ll revel in it.  i put in the applications at aspen and heard back from the chica there yesterday.  she seemed anxious to interview me, i’m sure i can talk my way into the job.  i was already planning to leave on friday to get there for vail’s job fair on saturday.  now i suspect that i’ll leave here as soon as i close the loops on two different things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>the first is to wait until the rack comes in the mail.  i broke down and ordered it even though i didn’t want to spend the moola.  i had to have something to carry the boards and my bouldering pad on.  it’ll just make everything easier. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>the second is to finally sell the van.  i lowered the prices through the floor on ebay and have been getting some good bites even though i’m only a day into the auction which will end on wednesday.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>so worst case scenario i’ll be able to leave on thursday now for an interview on friday.  best case scenario the van sells early on buy it now and the rack gets here as scheduled on tuesday.  then i could leave on wednesday for a thursday interview. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>i suspect that this is one of those things where the earlier the better my chances of getting a job are.  aspen looks very kool, dwarfing the cool quotient of mammoth.  they are having the X games there.  they have two different concert series that roll through town.  there are 100 bars and restaurants and coffee shops.  there are four mountains to ride/ski.  so many aspects make it a good decision.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>of course i don’t have the job, but my ego tells me that i will. and i feel really good about the aspen decision if it comes to fruitition.  we’ll see.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>shooter has gone to D&amp;amp;A even though the rewrites are not complete.  we should be getting the money on that before thanksgiving.  jim has the two proposals we’ve worked up now.  he gets back from san diego on sunday so we should get some feedback this week.  lots happening.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>we’re watching the world’s biggest outdoor cocktail party and i just saw the funniest commercial.  a cow decked out in flippers and floaties and a pool skirt jumped off this diving board at a bar-b-q and drowned out the burgers.  then there was a cow draped in a sign, &amp;ldquo;eat mor chikin.&amp;rdquo;  which, of course, is the chik-fil-a motto.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>f-ing hi-larry-ous. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>keep on keepin’ on….we’ll see how things go.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>watched two movies this week:  huckabees and friday night lights.  i want to speak on huckabees, maybe later, maybe not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-10-24-273/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-10-24-273/</guid><description>&lt;p>i think that something interesting to study would be the history of companionship.  at what points in history have people really desired true companionship and partnership out of their significant others?  the victorians and all that flowery poetry shit that they wrote were supposed to be significant steps in the history of love.  however, i wonder if it was love like we would call it.  whenever i read any of elizabeth barrett browning or any of her contemporaries it seems that it is only infatuation.  it doesn’t seem deep seated; just surface-al.  then the sixties were all about free love.  they probably made up a lot of grounds on the front of sexual equality but it was such an open society that i wonder sometimes how much they valued the individual.  many of the communes were probably against the individual.  without the individual then there can be no love of someone specific.  you could love a group of people but you could love someone specifically i would suggest.  i guess that was good for the polygamous types. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>now?  now, i think that overall society is more involved with trying to get ahead then they are with sharing things.  i think that my generation will have a much lower divorce rate than the baby boomers had, and we will probably be the first generation since the 1900′s to have a lower divorce rate then our parents.  however sometimes i wonder how fulfilling the relationships are.  many people are spending so much time in pursuit of objects that i wonder how much of the world they are enjoying.  now that seems a bit off the point, but it isn’t.  there is the quality of life issue at stake.  if you aren’t happy in your own life then you may not be able to find happiness in your partner.  maybe your partner is where you will find your happiness, all is wrong with the world outside your arms, or something to that effect.  i doubt that though.  yes having a companion to come home to after a bad day is nice and a massage after a hard workout will feel good.  but the massage isn’t going to get you in shape.  that you have to do on your own.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>which leads to the second topic, individual freedom.  the personification of it has come in various times but is most prevalent as the Cowboy of the American West.  the really interesting thing would be to compare the two.  when in history has companionship been valued and when has individuality been valued and is there any correlaries.  i don’t know what the answer to that question would be.  by no means am i a historian, yet if i had lots of time and resources and maybe that phone booth from Bill and Ted’s then i think that it would be interesting to find out some of the things that i’ve posed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>or not.  have a good time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-10-08-274/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-10-08-274/</guid><description>&lt;p>tonight’s thematique du jour is loneliness for two reasons.  firstly because i think that i’m essentially a completely lonely person, even when surrounded by people.  secondly, and more presently, because i watched parts (most) of about schmidt.  that movie is basically a film students study in the emotion.  at least that is my take on the piece.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>and so now, as the digital cable electronic channel blares extremely quietly i will discourse on the subject.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i think that america, as a culture has a very interesting relationship with the emotion.  most of us came as emigrants from cultures that were much more communal than this one is.  that is the background and the source of the &amp;ldquo;loathing&amp;rdquo; of loneliness and the neccessity of companionship and belonging. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>there is a flip to this, however.  those that had the balls (give or take for the women readers) to come over here were essentially either independent loners who were wired for self-sufficiency or they were already attached.  but both arenas maintained a romantic fascination with the &amp;ldquo;lone cowboy of the american west&amp;rdquo; or the many iterations that have followed in various forms, but all basically revolving around the same themes of:  choosing to be alone, not having to be, survivalist under duress, and blah blah blah.  mostly its macho shit and i wonder what a female’s perspective on the subject would be. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>that is hard to achieve b/c most of the women’s opinions whom i respect rarely find themselves unattached.  except for one…..&lt;/p>
&lt;p>and there is the completely unavoidable topic and rhetorically answerable question that was posed at the beginning of this horribly not-eloquent speech.  am i lonely?  gasp.  mutter amongst yourselves.  is he really not so self-sufficient as he always tells others that he is?  how could it be?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>yeah, its true you fuckers.  i’m stuck in the fucking desert sleeping on a fucking couch and every fucking day is the same.  i mean we’re getting tons of work done, and it is valuable and rewarding shit, but other than to jack or his two wonderfully sweet girls i say like seven words to people.  shit.  what the hell?  i hate the fucking desert.  but what are you gonna do.  part of me wants to be the starving artist who thinks that success will taste that much sweeter when achieved, but there is an equally large part of me that is saying:  flee, we’ll go somewhere and make some money and find the partner in crime that we’ve only had at fleeting moments in my life.  often for a weekend at the time and rarely longer glimpsed then that, at least not since college.  hell, that was five years ago. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>but then i say, stop being a martyr you drunk fuck and just plod on with your life.  it isn’t like i’m going to be here forever.  soon enough we should have some sort of feedback on shooter which will be my initial gauge as to whether my desired career will really pan out or not.  the second, and frankly more important, gauge will come soon thereafter when we go to jefe with the proposal for the second manuscript.  the one for the first novel.  jack remains steadfast in his outward confidence regarding the project.  i’m not so much.  i like it and i think we’ll produce a quality product, but that doesn’t mean jack shit in the big scheme of things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>there is this rising question, however, that do i need to have THIS novel to succeed?  with the money that i got from shooter, could i finance a MFA degree, learn some new shit and venture further with my own shit.  it is a hard row to plod, much harder than getting my JD and the gaurantee that would come with that career choice.  all that is just conjecture, frankly. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>i’m committed to this project until it becomes a complete non-player.  and then we’ll have to reevaluate.  until that point i’m stuck trying to produce the best project that i can.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>crystal method is on the channel now.  it was the first electronic concert i ever went to, with first)luv after we were broken up at the house of bluz in chi-town, home of the fucked up cubbies…..it was a great show.  my favorite song off the album is on here:  track four…..&lt;/p>
&lt;p>late’s all.  have a good weekend.  hopefully i’ll have some more movement on my career yaddy yadda after the weekend.  maybe i just need to get away and do something physical like climb a fucking mountain.  what’s wrong with me?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>my link of the day idea has fizzled as i knew it would.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-10-04-275/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-10-04-275/</guid><description>&lt;p>the one thing that i’ve learned as i ease into the hottub of the blogging culture is that late sunday night is the time for the big ‘weekend recap.’   so let me see, what did i do this weekend.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>not a fucking thing!  i worked the entire weekend and when i wasn’t arguing over sentence structure or the connotations of one word versus another and the stylistic derivations of this character’s &amp;ldquo;written pattern of speech&amp;rdquo; versus anothers or some other idiotic equivalent i was curled on my corner of jack’s comfy couch staring blankly at some television that was either a movie or sports or the food network.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>the food network has been fascinating me again and i have no idea why.  i don’t even like many of the personalities of the cultish-pseudo-celebrities on there.  but i guess i like what i learn there more than i would like if i was watching animal planet, discovery or the travel channel.  if i see one more thing on the guide about the fucking secrets of vegas i’ll puke.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i have done absolutely zilch to enliven my life or extend the powers of my brain beyond this room.  but tomorrow as my internally imposed deadline to stop the duldrums that are still lingering over marinegurl quasi-dumping me again, and without a viable reason, again.  i had orginally set the date because i thought that was when i was going to start with the new job.  now i know that isn’t going to happen and maybe that is for the best.  there is much work to be done and this way i’ll have time to do that. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>as long as i stop waiting for something to happen and just embrace the current status of my existence i think that much of my current disillusionment with the entire world and, oh by the way, the fucking desert of my present world will melt.  that and making my ass pay for all the sitting around and eating chocolate i’ve been doing! &lt;/p>
&lt;p>got sucked into a war novel that is pretty good.  WEB Griffin.  he can write dialogue ok, but i have yet to even see how he writes action.  he lacks color and i don’t he writes so little outside of the characters that i’m not sure i can fully embrace his style, but i understand what he’s trying to do.  it has been important to jack that i read him because i think it is the book that jack is envisioning us writing.  it seems a bit weak to me on many points where we are strong, mainly the personal touches and feels of what is going on.  what does a trigger feel like on your finger, what does your eye actually do when its behind a scope.  how do you make decisions, what factors do you consider, what factors enter your mind but not the decision making process.  that is all well and good, but now we have to go out there and actually do it! &lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-09-30-276/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-09-30-276/</guid><description>&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;chasing amy&amp;rdquo; is on tonite.  i’m watching my past.  i’m amused by the scene where they throw darts.  i also like jason lee’s character, it’s one of the internally truest characters in movie-dom.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>why do people always lie when answering the question:  how are you?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>news of the day:  jimmy swaggart told some people that if a guy ever looked at him weird he’d kill them.  reminds me of when i was drunk in LA soon after the war and i told these chick’s i’d &amp;ldquo;fucking kill them.&amp;rdquo;  i don’t even, to this day, have a clue what set me off. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>my current consumption rate is equalling out at about a bottle and a third of wine a night.  that’s a lot of grapes.  but, nevertheless, we’re getting some good work done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>no final answer on the USMC job yet.  homeboy that is in charge of setting things up for me is pissing me off becuase I called his ass on tuesday and still haven’t heard back from him, that’s two days worth of return phone call time.  maybe he’s on leave….&lt;/p>
&lt;p>heard back a tiny bit on SHOOTER today, from the assistant editor and he liked it a lot.  we’ll see though in another week or so when the actual editor gives it a read.  just want to get it done so we can move on to other projects mentally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>guess that’s it!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-09-26-277/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2004/2004-09-26-277/</guid><description>&lt;p>just back from the getty for the afternoon.  went down the hill to my friend’s house for the first night.  actually was one of my ex’s.  she’s fairly intense, and likes it that way so she plays it up.  we drank wine on her porch while i sweated in my jeans and too long of sleeve shirt because its been cold up here and my dumb ass was relishing the cold enough that i dressed for it when i shouldn’t have. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>any, i gave her the low down on marinegurl and what the hell was up/happened with regards to her.  also broke down some other stuff for her. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>saturday i went to getty.  will write more about that later.  while down there glitterbrain told me about this sight.  figured i’d try it out.  more later tonight, good football game one now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>link of the day:  photoblog:  &lt;a href="http://www.wideangle.ca/">http://www.wideangle.ca&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>