<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>otherwise on underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/otherwise/</link><description>Recent content in otherwise on underWater desert Blogging</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Casey Kuhlman</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/otherwise/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Book Inscription</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2012-02-03-book-inscription/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2012-02-03-book-inscription/</guid><description>Here’s to the embarkation on a great journey. Here’s to a massive flop or a spectacular success. Here’s to nothing in between. Here’s to risk. Here’s to reward. Here’s to taking a chance. Here’s to never being satisfied with what is. Here’s to questioning. Here’s to listening. Here’s to excellence. Here’s to professionalism. Here’s to helping everywhere we can in every way we can to everyone we can. Here’s to solving problems.</description></item><item><title>Decoding the Somali Mind: A Guide for Expats (Anecdotal, Not Definitive Version): Responsibility</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-10-18-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-responsibility/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-10-18-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-responsibility/</guid><description>This is a new series containing a few stories which have stood out in my time here in Somaliland and have helped me to understand a bit more a culture that in many ways is very different from my own, but in many ways is not. This series explores those differences.
![Responsibility via PaDumBumPsh @ flickr]({{ site.url }}{{ site.root }}{{ site.images_dir }}/{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; }}/4586821590_6000f395c6.jpg)
I generally prefer to point out the similarities between disparate people.</description></item><item><title>What I Do Before Work</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-10-15-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-10-15-work/</guid><description>Photo via cafemama @ flickr
For the longest while, I’ve been obsessed with time management &amp;amp; efficiency. In college my good friend Dave, who was running the orientation program for our ROTC that year, asked me to give a class on time management. It was one of the most enjoyable topics I’ve ever lectured on. We were incoming seniors and we were talking to incoming freshmen. At the time I was listening to lots of Zig Zigler.</description></item><item><title>Decoding the Somali Mind: A Guide for Expats (Anecdotal, Not Definitive Version): Wants v. Needs</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-06-28-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-v/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-06-28-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-v/</guid><description>This is a new series containing a few stories which have stood out in my time here in Somaliland and have helped me to understand a bit more a culture that in many ways is very different from my own, but in many ways is not. This series explores those differences.
[![want need syrup by thebrianmeyer @ flickr][2]][2]
Every development worker I’ve ever met, and I can say with confidence, without exception, hates the following phrase with a passion: “What we really need is….</description></item><item><title>Decoding the Somali Mind: A Guide for Expats (Anecdotal, Not Definitive Version): Introduction</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-06-21-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-06-21-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version/</guid><description>This is a new series containing a few stories which have stood out in my time here in Somaliland and have helped me to understand a bit more a culture that in many ways is very different from my own, but in many ways is now. This series explores those differences.
[![BraiNut 1.0 via sath.es @flickr][2]][2] via sath.es @flickr
I have lived &amp;amp; worked with Somalis here in Somaliland for over two years now.</description></item><item><title>Happy Dad&amp;#8217;s Day!</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-06-20-happy-dads-day/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-06-20-happy-dads-day/</guid><description>[![Happy Father's Day in advance to someone who may be mature enough to have children by age 62][2]][2]It is actually quite crazy to think that when my father was the age in which I currently find myself he had two sons (one 12 and one 9), and was on his third (or fourth?) house. I, on the other hand, am childless, and property-less! Although I must say very happily married. So as I sit here in my house in Hargeisa and reflect upon the fact that I’m missing yet another holiday far away from my father and trying to justify why to myself, the only thing that makes sense is to put on some of my dad’s favorite songs.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-02-11-15/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-02-11-15/</guid><description>Beaker Twitter = Hilarity. HT – Frank</description></item><item><title>Piling it On.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-06-13-piling-it-on/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-06-13-piling-it-on/</guid><description>Consider me another addition! From Ben Smith: Wired's Thomas Goetz emails to make a great point about Obama's big FightTheSmears.com rollout today:
By putting their own website out there front-and-center, and then getting
everybody to link to it (starting with all the media covering the launch of the
site), the result will be to drive fightthesmears.com towards the top of a
Google search on, say, &amp;ldquo;obama muslim&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;michelle obama whitey.</description></item><item><title>Bo Videos</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-06-12-bo-videos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-06-12-bo-videos/</guid><description>These are some videos we shot while upcountry in SL.
driving on the highway.
standing in the center of bo. people here are much more relaxed.
driving thru bo.
standing on a bridge conversing.
taking the piss.
driving across an extremely sketchy bridge.
at least we didn’t have to eat each other’s balls.
i think they like white people up here.
grass tunnel.</description></item><item><title>one more reason</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-06-12-one-more-reason/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-06-12-one-more-reason/</guid><description>i’m forgetting another salient reason: i’d have to shave my face and head. and i look too good in long hair to do that again. ever. </description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-08-05-251/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-08-05-251/</guid><description>am reading kundera for the first time. it is outlandish. i’m learning so fucking much. and i don’t even know czech to read it in the original. am going to reread this flipping thing as soon as i finish it b/c there is too much here. there are two basic things that i’m learning from him. first, how to weave a narrative outside of time. this thing is like a tarratino flick in that he likes to tell the story along certain lines other than a linear (based on time) slide.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-07-21-252/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-07-21-252/</guid><description>am i on a treadmill or actually road running. cannot tell. hopefully will know something soon
~ # ~</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-07-20-253/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-07-20-253/</guid><description>went and saw the young dubliners tonight at the little club in town. the open band was called the saucy monkeys. or something of the sort. they were two artsy chicks with acoustic guitars. for some reason i was reminded of the two chicas who opened for bush in 94 when i saw them with eric in orlando.
yougn dubliners were &amp;ldquo;celtish rock&amp;rdquo; which i wasn’t so sure about…but it really was riverdance meets pop rock, including a fiddler who looked like the midnight oil dude, a bassist who looked exactly how henry rollins would look if he let his vanity go and got semi-fat and a lead guitarist who reminded me of the lead guitarist from frank black and the catholics who in turn reminds me of david bowie, but the guy from the &amp;ldquo;dubs&amp;rdquo; didn’t remind me of bowie at all.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-07-18-254/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-07-18-254/</guid><description>the following things happened during my evening hike today: i was startled by a fairly large brown bear when i rounded the corner and there he/she was 15 yards from me. luckily she/he sauntered off. i gave blood to the mosquito blood bank of the roaring fork valley….don’t they know i’ve been given the anthrax and small pox vaccinations and cannot give blood for another five years. i startled a beaver and he made a pop sound with his tail and for a while i couldn’t figure out what had happened until i saw his dam and his house, which were directly in front of me the entire time.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-04-07-255/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-04-07-255/</guid><description>does anyone else wonder what happens when you actually blast one of the ipod’s? does it show up at your doorstep in a couple of days with a &amp;ldquo;thanks for playing our carnival game&amp;rdquo; note on the inside of the cubic apple box?
on my way to dinner i saw a shirt that amused me, simply as i do not understand it. it was one of those white t-shirts with the collar and cuffs at the sleeves in some muted gray color.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-04-05-256/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-04-05-256/</guid><description>the pope passing on is significant. i wonder how much of that significance will be lost on the seventh-day adventist church because of its complete anti-catholicism stance. or will it perhaps spawn a thought process, one of reevaluation of that stance. if we are not constantly, vehemently justifying our existence would people still subscribe to the dogma? i think that is the crux of the matter for some of the more learned leaders of my (former?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-03-29-257/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-03-29-257/</guid><description>i feel sated. a snake on a warm spring afternoon curled on a sandstone deposit, belly full of mouse, jaw reattached, water near, people and mongeese far.
have finalized summer plans, spring plans and other assorted plans. will be diving into jamaica for 4/20 even though i’m not a pothead and don’t intend to become one. its just an anthropological experiment, like so much of the rest of my life. extended out my lease here through august.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-03-26-258/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-03-26-258/</guid><description>today i shall bew bland and newsy b/c i’m too warped to be funny and too jaded to be artsy. i feel like complete shit today for no real reason. last night was a our big, the ski season’s almost over fuckers party. as per my usual i got on the near side of trashed, just coherent enough to convince many others that i’m not trashed and just trashed enough to through out my ensemble of social conditionings, self-loathings and general wallflowerness.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-03-24-259/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-03-24-259/</guid><description>impressions of an evening in aspen.
clothes too poor in room of quadrillionaires.sushi left out too long.white wine somehow too crisp.is this a date or am i a seat filler.snow.headlights.crowds like the sand in the middle of the antique watch.
youngster.hipster.mullato.piano.hands upright.were those wrists slapped by an old lady with a ruler.noise pierces through cacophony that i’m unable to locate.ensembles are like cocktail parties.wallflower with my wine, against the wall.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-03-20-260/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-03-20-260/</guid><description>is no artistic output better than bad artistic output?
do you have to be drugged to appreciate drug induced art?
cameron was down, again, this weekend, for the night and was telling me a funny story. he want to his public library up there in jackson (wy) to see a fiddler who seems to be a performance poet of some kind. apparently the guy is from alaska and he tells stories, plays irish jigs on his fiddle and weaves wilderness poetry in the cracks.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-03-06-261/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-03-06-261/</guid><description>it is saturday night and i’m typing and enjoying wine and then going to sit down with my book for the rest of the evening. damn i’m boring!
last night i had a quasi-date with the guat_princess. (as a side note i have decided the best thing about blogging is that i get to give real people fake names and pretend that i’m in sex in the city). i’ll ruin it for all of you: the act banished any interest that i had.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-03-04-262/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-03-04-262/</guid><description>i think that in the past i’ve been very patronizing towards hot chocolate and have made a conscious decision to rethink my position on the substance. maybe it should be legalized afterall. what do you think? ~ # ~</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-03-03-263/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-03-03-263/</guid><description>i am quite tired and sore this evening. not sure what i’m sore from, probably life beating me about my head and neck relentlessly without me really giving a damn and just taking it lick by fucking lick. and i’m not talking about the tongue against ice cream cone kind either.
i also think that it is stupid people week and have been loudly blinking that out of my flourescent mouth.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-03-01-264/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-03-01-264/</guid><description>WARNING: this shit is VERY graphic and ENTIRELY conjecture. just painting a picture of one way it could have gone down.
so it seems to me that i may be reading too much into the HST death. it seems that no one cares. am i the only one? and i dont’ even really care, what I do care about is the social phenomenon the pop counter-culter icon itself. i actually don’t really give a damn that some old man put a .</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-02-23-265/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-02-23-265/</guid><description>Now, I must do this justice, and to do that I need to back up. First, some background. His name is Hunter S. Thompson, if you don’t know that name, google him. I find some odd parallel’s in my living in the same town with the counterculture icon when he dies and with Eric’s story of his friend farting next to Allen Ginsberg’s coffin during some candlelit vigil to the old beat-en poet.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-01-14-266/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-01-14-266/</guid><description>i spent the entire day cuddling with myself and reveling in the peacefulness. odd roommate has been conspicuously absent for the past few days and i have barely ventured outside for more than a solitary walk to convince myself that the sun puts out vitamins that i needed to or could actually soak in through all my layers as i walked around in the teen-something degree air and tried to maintain breathing through a stuffed up nose that was pierced by the freezing cold air.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2004-12-04-267/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2004-12-04-267/</guid><description>i’m sore. and i don’t mean butt-hurt, even though my butt does hurt. well, the ass muscles hurt. i’ve been riding hard for the past two days, and i don’t mean the ladies–the snow baby. the riding skills are coming back faster than i imagined that they would. i was jumping natural kickers both in the groomers and in the trees. i was taking the bumps and the trees without pausing.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2004-11-22-268/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2004-11-22-268/</guid><description>i feel like i have come almost full circle, let me explain. i had reached a point of something this summer that was unlike anything i had ever reached before. i am not sure whether that was a zen state of living or just the ability to thoughtfully live in the present. whatever title you choose to give to it i was there. i wasn’t working, but i was constantly working.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2004-11-13-269/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2004-11-13-269/</guid><description>i feel refreshed. i feel wierd in fact, because there has been some odd vindication that has came at the same time as an odd amount of conflict.
first there was the major conflict, and that one was internal. i left 29 palms about 10 days ago thinking that i would have resolution on the aspen job quickly. either she would offer me the job or she would tell me to pack sand.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2004-11-08-270/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2004-11-08-270/</guid><description>five days later i make my next entry. this time it is from the boulder public library where i’ve been camped out for a bit and pretending i’m back in college and doing something productive with my time. i think that i’ve found where i want to live. boulder has the quadfecta as i’ve deemed it of: climbing, kayaking, ski, community. those are the four things that i’ve looking for in places to live.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2004-11-02-271/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2004-11-02-271/</guid><description>well i’m reading all these things about how the vote has begun. so, in a sign of things to come: i have lost a toe nail. and it isn’t one of the small ones, it is the big one on my left foot. on a hike about four weeks ago i stubbed it terribly bad while i was running down the insanely steep hill and trying to avoid both the rocks and the cacti.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2004-10-31-272/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2004-10-31-272/</guid><description>decisions decisions decisions. i guess that i have made my bed and now i’ll revel in it. i put in the applications at aspen and heard back from the chica there yesterday. she seemed anxious to interview me, i’m sure i can talk my way into the job. i was already planning to leave on friday to get there for vail’s job fair on saturday. now i suspect that i’ll leave here as soon as i close the loops on two different things.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2004-10-24-273/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2004-10-24-273/</guid><description>i think that something interesting to study would be the history of companionship. at what points in history have people really desired true companionship and partnership out of their significant others? the victorians and all that flowery poetry shit that they wrote were supposed to be significant steps in the history of love. however, i wonder if it was love like we would call it. whenever i read any of elizabeth barrett browning or any of her contemporaries it seems that it is only infatuation.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2004-10-08-274/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2004-10-08-274/</guid><description>tonight’s thematique du jour is loneliness for two reasons. firstly because i think that i’m essentially a completely lonely person, even when surrounded by people. secondly, and more presently, because i watched parts (most) of about schmidt. that movie is basically a film students study in the emotion. at least that is my take on the piece.
and so now, as the digital cable electronic channel blares extremely quietly i will discourse on the subject.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2004-10-04-275/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2004-10-04-275/</guid><description>the one thing that i’ve learned as i ease into the hottub of the blogging culture is that late sunday night is the time for the big ‘weekend recap.’ so let me see, what did i do this weekend.
not a fucking thing! i worked the entire weekend and when i wasn’t arguing over sentence structure or the connotations of one word versus another and the stylistic derivations of this character’s &amp;ldquo;written pattern of speech&amp;rdquo; versus anothers or some other idiotic equivalent i was curled on my corner of jack’s comfy couch staring blankly at some television that was either a movie or sports or the food network.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2004-09-30-276/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2004-09-30-276/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;chasing amy&amp;rdquo; is on tonite. i’m watching my past. i’m amused by the scene where they throw darts. i also like jason lee’s character, it’s one of the internally truest characters in movie-dom.
why do people always lie when answering the question: how are you?
news of the day: jimmy swaggart told some people that if a guy ever looked at him weird he’d kill them. reminds me of when i was drunk in LA soon after the war and i told these chick’s i’d &amp;ldquo;fucking kill them.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2004-09-26-277/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2004-09-26-277/</guid><description>just back from the getty for the afternoon. went down the hill to my friend’s house for the first night. actually was one of my ex’s. she’s fairly intense, and likes it that way so she plays it up. we drank wine on her porch while i sweated in my jeans and too long of sleeve shirt because its been cold up here and my dumb ass was relishing the cold enough that i dressed for it when i shouldn’t have.</description></item></channel></rss>