<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/</link><description>A Site About Resilience and Authoritarianism</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</managingEditor><webMaster>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</webMaster><copyright>All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/sci-tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Video of Real Life Minority Report</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-16-video-of-real-life-minority-report/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-16-video-of-real-life-minority-report/</guid><description>&lt;p>I think my hands would sweat in those gloves and probably my arms would get tired from fighting with the computers.  What do you think?  I like the ominous music though!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://vimeo.com/2229299">g-speak overview 1828121108&lt;/a> from &lt;a href="http://vimeo.com/user922585">john underkoffler&lt;/a> on &lt;a href="http://vimeo.com">Vimeo&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sick Around the World, and Random Settled Thoughts.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-05-27-sick-around-the-world-and-random-settled-thoughts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-05-27-sick-around-the-world-and-random-settled-thoughts/</guid><description>&lt;p>In case you missed it, I've posted the first YouTube link to the very excellent PBS Frontline special &amp;ldquo;Sick Around the World.&amp;rdquo;  A Washington Post reporter went to six industrialized nations and asked how they've been able to ensure universal healthcare at a much lower cost than the US has been able to figure out. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now that I'm here in S-land am becoming addicted to web content.  Frontline has all of their documentaries up.  Another great site I've found is: &lt;a href="http://freedocumentaries.org">http://freedocumentaries.org&lt;/a> which has tons of documentaries available for downloading.  Not sure the quality as I've been downloading other things, but will get to some of these documentaries soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In other news, am hoping to become the gardener of H-town.  A new found friend, a Kenyan guy who works for an iNGO is also looking for a house.  If we do get a house, I'm planning to plant some veggies and some herbs.  Now, if only I could get my stereo across, purchase a cheap projector to watch TV on the wall, get a faster VSAT connection and find some CHEESE, I'll be set. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Have been listen to lots of hip hop lately.  Kanye is really f-ing good.  Not sure why it took me so long to get into him. &lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>