<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>governance on underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/governance/</link><description>Recent content in governance on underWater desert Blogging</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/governance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Spectrum of Public to Private Service Delivery</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-01-24-spectrum-service-delivery/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-01-24-spectrum-service-delivery/</guid><description>Let's stop thinking in binary terms about the delivery of services. There is a spectrum from purely public (government driven) to purely private (corporate driven) delivery of services. When we think about this as a spectrum rather than a binary situation, my opinion is that political debates about the delivery of services gets a lot easier and we focus on providing solutions rather than zero sum arguments which no one can ever win.</description></item><item><title>What Does Gerstle Mean Pro-People Development?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-05-27-gerstle-pro-people-development/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-05-27-gerstle-pro-people-development/</guid><description>It is a difficult proposition to project what will happen in Somalia or Somaliland. The problem, as I see it, with the international approaches so far along with the local approaches, is that it is difficult to reconcile the philosophical desires of most Somalis with the history that they have faced in the modern era of authoritarian rule. But someone will come along - eventually, inshallah - that will be able to convince people of his or her vision of how to reconcile the dissonance between the historical predicates of Somalia and the cultural desires for decentralized power. When this unselfish visionary comes along the world should ilaalayaa because these people that I have grown to love will be a powerful force.</description></item></channel></rss>