<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>governance on underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/governance/</link><description>Recent content in governance on underWater desert Blogging</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Casey Kuhlman</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/governance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Spectrum of Public to Private Service Delivery</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-01-24-spectrum-service-delivery/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-01-24-spectrum-service-delivery/</guid><description>The people who most interested me were wary of centralized control, but they were not free market libertarians. They believed in the power of competition, but they also believed that some of society's most important achievements could not be incentivized with economic reward. They called themselves entrepreneurs but worked mostly in the public sector. They were equally suspicious of big government and big corporations. From a certain angle, they looked like a digital-age version of such nineteenth-century anarchists as Pierre-Joseph Proudhon or Mikhail Bakunin.</description></item><item><title>What Does Gerstle Mean Pro-People Development?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-05-27-gerstle-pro-people-development/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-05-27-gerstle-pro-people-development/</guid><description>David Gerstle, who writes for @change, among others is fastly becoming one of my favorite journalists commenting on Somalia.
I have my quibbles with some of the things he says, but mainly it is a difference of assumption rather than philosophy.
This week he wrote a post talking about the ineffectual nature of the stream of “governments” that have “ruled” Somalia since Siad Barre was thrown from power by a queer arrangement of circumstances and bad decisions.</description></item></channel></rss>