<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/</link><description>A Site About Resilience and Authoritarianism</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</managingEditor><webMaster>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</webMaster><copyright>All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/governance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Spectrum of Public to Private Service Delivery</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-01-24-spectrum-service-delivery/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-01-24-spectrum-service-delivery/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The people who most interested me were wary of centralized control, but they were not free market libertarians. They believed in the power of competition, but they also believed that some of society's most important achievements could not be incentivized with economic reward. They called themselves entrepreneurs but worked mostly in the public sector. They were equally suspicious of big government and big corporations. From a certain angle, they looked like a digital-age version of such nineteenth-century anarchists as Pierre-Joseph Proudhon or Mikhail Bakunin. Yet beneath that strange, hard-to-place eclecticism, a core philosophy seemed to unite all their efforts, even if it didn't fit comfortably into the existing categories of political belief.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>~ Future Perfect by Steven Johnson &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Future-Perfect-Case-Progress-Networked/dp/1594631840">Amazon&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Services are delivered by companies. But we need the government or else the greedy capitalists will take everything. But the government is inefficient and slow &amp;ndash; just look at the Post Office. But&amp;hellip; But&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The dirty little secret is that no one knows necessarily what the right answer to this question is because we are still learning the right solution for a particular and the right solution is constantly changing. Instead of thinking in binary terms maybe it would be more helpful to think in terms of a spectrum with fully public delivery on the one side (passing legislation would fit here &amp;ndash; we probably do not want the rule-making function of governance to be within the private sector and even more susceptible to private capture than it currently is) and fully private delivery on the other side (selling slurpees &amp;ndash; we probably do not want selling of fungible goods to be within the private sector which has little incentives to innovate). In between these extremes there is a very large space in which operators can work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the arrangements I work in routinely for Watershed's clients are Public-Private Partnerships or PPP's. You know these from such hits as the private vendors operating services within national parks, or stadium builds which are usually a mix of public and private financing. These partnerships allow for a wide variety of delivery possibilities that are not nearly as limiting as a simple binary question of public v. private. Instead of focusing on the binary nature of service delivery within our policy debates which characterizes the delivery of services as either &lt;em>purely private&lt;/em> or &lt;em>purely public&lt;/em> each with its advocate class and all unable to resolve their differences or get things done so that people can get to the task of l i v i n, perhaps we should think more in terms of a spectrum. Focus our thinking about service delivery on a spectrum rather than a binary on-off switch allows us to focus our debates on finding the right point along the spectrum to deliver the services which we are speaking to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To Europeans this debate that occupies our time, the government is great v. government sucks debate, is hilarious. I get asked about it a lot. It is intuitive to most Europeans that service delivery operates on a spectrum. Services in Europe are routinely modified within the spectrum and also change over time due to efficiencies, politics, or many other factors. Last year there was an outcry within the UK as the conservative government was trying to move the National Health Service along the spectrum towards the private side which raised many alarms for people. But that debate, and many others within the politics of service delivery in Europe happen without the sky is falling, scream at your TV, Nancy Grace style of debate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I like that part of Europe. A lot. Because generally when the population that doesn't know anything about the delivery of such services simply gets out of the way things happen in a pretty smooth way. Not all the time. But most of the time when people who don't know things about things let the people who do know things about things do their jobs things run pretty well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course there are differences between the two. Incentives for one are different. Private sector actors have incentives to optimize their profits. To think of short term gains over long term innovation. To reduce costs and simplify delivery mechanisms. These are all well and good, but there is a place for them. Public sector actors have a different set of incentives. To ensure the widest access to the services. To ensure the right costing is built into the system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The difference in these set of incentives (of which the above is meant to be illustrative) are important to understand. But our polity just needs to remember that there is space within these incentives for harmonization. Once we stop thinking in the simplistic terms of &amp;ldquo;Government good&amp;rdquo; | &amp;ldquo;Government bad&amp;rdquo; and start asking the question of how this service should be delivered based on what &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rdquo; are trying to accomplish. Then a whole world of policy solutions is opened to us.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Try it during the upcoming election season. Watch a debate and ask yourself if the debaters are being overly reductive in how they are approaching a service delivery question. Those that are not being overly reductive &amp;ndash; that are in the business of finding solutions which will actually move us along a path rather than simply spewing forth banal answers &amp;ndash; those are the ones that I will be voting for.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What Does Gerstle Mean Pro-People Development?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-05-27-gerstle-pro-people-development/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-05-27-gerstle-pro-people-development/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://humanrights.change.org/blog?author_id=351">&lt;img src="http://humanrights.change.org/blog?author_id=351" alt="Double rainbows from my roof">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://humanrights.change.org/blog?author_id=351">David Gerstle&lt;/a>, who writes for &lt;a href="http://change.org">@change&lt;/a>, among others is fastly becoming one of my favorite journalists commenting on Somalia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have my quibbles with some of the things he says, but mainly it is a difference of assumption rather than philosophy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This week he wrote a post talking about the ineffectual nature of the stream of “governments”  that have “ruled” Somalia since Siad Barre was thrown from power by a queer arrangement of circumstances and bad decisions.  (Yes, if we were discussing this over a beer I would have used finger quotes around those words.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gerstle’s argument is that Somalia has lacked a visionary unifier that was able to convince a wide-swath of the Somali community to band together.  This is true.  There has been no one.  Likely there will never be one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In history no one has been able to rule Somalis by consent.  Either it is by force or there is controlled anarchy.  And this controlled anarchy is likely to continue into the foreseeable future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here in Somaliland there was a group that was able to achieve some of what Gerstle is arguing for, but for a long calculus of reasons that I’m too bored with to go into here and now they were focussed on unifying the people and clans of Somaliland rather than the entirety of the Somali people.  Unfortunately for Somaliland and the rest this group of pragmatic visionaries is dead and no one has stepped up and been able to sell a vision to the Somalilanders of where Somaliland is going and why it should go in that direction.  But where is Somaliland now after the death of the original visionaries?  There is a crazy stew of controlled anarchy spiced up with a bit of controlling top-down authoritarianism just to make the stew interesting and unexpected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even though there is a lack of current visionaries, there is no lack of vision which is discussed and debated at nauseum while no one seems to take any steps in any direction – even those directions where everyone agrees.  Yet, despite these challenges, everywhere I look I see hope around me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A young generation is coming up with only knowledge of Somaliland.  They are educated and passionate about unification.  They have links with diaspora who are helping to curb the clanistic tendencies which the older generation feels deeper than the young.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Largely, Somalis and Americans have lots in common.  Especially when you are able to have a philosophical discussion about the role of government in people’s lives.  They are deeply distrustful of the government and very private sector focussed.  They are comedic, warm (after they know you), and pragmatic.  I see so much in common between the problems that Somaliland is facing and the problems that America is facing.  Every day I see the frustrations of people here and read about the frustrations of my friends and family back home.  Although the scale is different, the problems largely stem from the same source: a feeling of distrust in one’s government which should be there to help.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is a difficult proposition to project what will happen in Somalia or Somaliland.  The problem, as I see it, with the international approaches so far along with the local approaches, is that it is difficult to reconcile the philosophical desires of most Somalis with the history that they have faced in the modern era of authoritarian rule.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Simply put authoritarian rule will not work long term in Somalia.  Maybe it will work in more deferential cultures, but Somali culture is about as far from deferential as I’ve every experienced.  Someone, I do not doubt, will come along with a vision of how to reconcile these notions and will actually put into practice the tenants of the Somaliland Constitution which was built quite well as a decentralized structure with dissipated power very similar to the US governance model.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Such a visionary, powered by the continued education of most Somalilanders will be the double rainbow which will allow Somaliland to turn the corner.  It will not happen simply by a visionary telling the country what it has to do.  Somalis will rarely accept such orders.  But someone will come along – eventually, inshallah – that will be able to convince people of his or her vision of how to reconcile the dissonance between the historical predicates of Somalia and the cultural desires for decentralized power.  When this unselfish visionary comes along the world should ilaalayaa because these people that I have grown to love will be a powerful force.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>