<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>development 2.0 on underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/development-2.0/</link><description>Recent content in development 2.0 on underWater desert Blogging</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Casey Kuhlman</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/development-2.0/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why I Started Watershed Legal Services: My Journey from Expat Aid Worker to Expat Entrepreneur</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2011-04-23-why-i-started-watershed/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2011-04-23-why-i-started-watershed/</guid><description>a[![Ninja Law Firm via SolYoung @ flickr][2]][2] Ninja Law Firm via SolYoung @ flickr
I read an interesting article yesterday from a man who I referenced in my previous post as one of my favorite development bloggers: Owen Barder. Owen has joined a DC based development think-tank called Center for Global Development and in his [good-bye to Ethiopia post][2] he had an interesting thing to say about aid. He claims, and I heartily support, that development is much broader than simply aid, it is about trade policy, climate policy, monetary policy (which he didn’t actually mention), and numerous other policies which the developed world implements and in the globalized economy has massive effects in the developing world.</description></item><item><title>On NGO Marketing</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-10-25-ngo-marketing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-10-25-ngo-marketing/</guid><description>![Meeting via jcolman @ flickr]({{ site.url }}{{ site.root }}{{ site.images_dir }}/{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; }}/2325118043_ed2da74cc0.jpg)
Last week was the Hargeisa Trade Fair. Our business wanted a booth to network and develop further relationships with clients. You know, the type of thing that happens at conventions all around the world every day.
But the Hargeisa Trade Fair was a bit different. First off, they didn’t have that many booths. Granted we were a bit late to the game, but it was still fairly annoying that we were unable to secure a booth.</description></item><item><title>Bono Writes About Africa (My Eyes Begin to Roll)</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-04-18-bono-writes-africa-my-eyes-roll/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-04-18-bono-writes-africa-my-eyes-roll/</guid><description>I desperately wanted to hate this op-ed which the NYT published yesterday and Bono wrote, but at the end it was a rather good piece. There is this narrative which is beginning to form which is the first coherent, resonant, and positive narrative on Africa that I’ve heard.
Bono’s piece encapsulates the narrative quite well actually, but let me summarize. Africa is getting to get its act together. Although outliers like here where I live will remain, the rest of the continent (led by countries like Senegal, Ghana, Tanzania, and Botswana) are really moving forward.</description></item></channel></rss>