<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/</link><description>A Site About Resilience and Authoritarianism</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</managingEditor><webMaster>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</webMaster><copyright>All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/development-2.0/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why I Started Watershed Legal Services: My Journey from Expat Aid Worker to Expat Entrepreneur</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-04-23-why-i-started-watershed/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-04-23-why-i-started-watershed/</guid><description>&lt;p>a[![Ninja Law Firm via SolYoung @ flickr][2]][2]
Ninja Law Firm via SolYoung @ flickr&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I read an interesting article yesterday from a man who I referenced in my previous post as one of my favorite development bloggers: Owen Barder. Owen has joined a DC based development think-tank called Center for Global Development and in his [good-bye to Ethiopia post][2] he had an interesting thing to say about aid. He claims, and I heartily support, that development is much broader than simply aid, it is about trade policy, climate policy, monetary policy (which he didn’t actually mention), and numerous other policies which the developed world implements and in the globalized economy has massive effects in the developing world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/entry/why-i-started-watershed/4928948235_9882789b97">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/entry/why-i-started-watershed/4928948235_9882789b97&lt;/a>
[2]: &lt;a href="http://www.owen.org/blog/4540">http://www.owen.org/blog/4540&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The article returned my thoughts to something which I have pondered off and on for the eight months since we have opened the doors on &lt;a href="http://watershedlegal.com">Watershed Legal Services&lt;/a>, my small law firm in this corner of the Horn of Africa.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are an assortment of varied and divergently relevant reasons why I invested my time and money in this entity. It is a hodge-podge, a kaleidoscope which changes its predominant colors over time. For one, I wanted to get off the NGO train, to stop skimming the surface of places and to dig into a country. To plant roots. For another, my marriage wasn’t going to thrive in an environment where we were constantly moving as my wife is also a professional and the chances of two professionals finding professionally satisfying positions in a new country every two or three years was daunting at best. And I simply fell in love with Somalis and Somaliland – despite (or perhaps because of) its craziness, its madness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Those are mainly all personal reasons, but there were also some professional reasons which I have considered at length. Rightly or wrongly I was tired of a culture of giving. Now that is not to say that I have stopped giving, indeed I cannot count the number of pro bono hours that our small firm has performed in our short life. I am not tired of giving, I am tired of the expectation that I am here to give – full stop. I am tired of a culture where nothing will happen without a body with money external to the state saying yes we will  fund that. These are backwards to how I see the world. I have no problems with giving a man a fish. But when there are so many fish givers in a place that the giving of a fish becomes an expectation then I think we have reached a point where things should be reevaluated. It isn’t development, it isn’t sustainable, and something has to give. This is why I was excited to start a for-profit law firm, this is why we don’t chase projects in the same way that NGOs do, this is why we haven’t taken outside funding from foundations or other organizations who have shown willingness to assist organizations such as Watershed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Law is not something that can be given. It is, at its core, a conversation between power centers. This conversation ebbs and flows over time. It changes and must change in order to have life and to enable its success. While it is a conversation which can often be informed by actors abroad, if it is not a conversation within the society in which it is being imposed, it will never be successful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me put some meat on that paragraph. What I see from the other side of the table now that I have switched from a legal reform NGO to a practitioner within the country is a tangled mess of laws which will never be implemented here. I see laws built by consultants from other countries who have never bothered to learn the legal structures of this country and bring their own governance proclivities with them. The simple fact of a Kenyan consultant coming to Somaliland to write a law brings big troubles because until recently Kenya was a fundamentally British parliamentary system. Those types of governments operate in a fundamentally different way than governments on a different part of the spectrum. Somaliland, in contradistinction, is built upon an American model. You cannot simply take ideas of how the conversations between power centers works in one system and transplant them whole sale into a different system. Yes, there are often analogies, but not always. American notions of the separation of power and the reasons that America has been able to make an independent executive work requires a method of thought which differs in so many ways. It is like comparing how you talk to your close friends over a cup of coffee sitting on their couch to how you would talk to a new business associate. You talk fundamentally different because the social modes which develop around each of those situations is vastly different. The same is true about law.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So really it boils down to the fact that I wanted to help Somaliland develop its own way of conversing. I want to stop consultants coming from other countries dropping off finished laws and running away. I want to assist parliament and the government to learn how to converse with each other in a legal sense. I want to give young, sharp lawyers a chance to move beyond a simple contract for an NGO where they will never be pushed where they will stagnate and never have the chance to have the feeling of a bit of hard work pushed out the door and the ultimate relaxation and joy which follows.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That, my friends, is why I do what I do. That, my friends, is why I’m more professionally satisfied in these recent months than I’ve ever been in my life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On NGO Marketing</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-25-ngo-marketing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-25-ngo-marketing/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last week was the Hargeisa Trade Fair.  Our business wanted a booth to network and develop further relationships with clients.  You know, the type of thing that happens at conventions all around the world every day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But the Hargeisa Trade Fair was a bit different.  First off, they didn’t have that many booths.  Granted we were a bit late to the game, but it was still fairly annoying that we were unable to secure a booth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I chalked it up, before going, to a good development.  If the trade fair had sold out its booths as they were telling us then that must mean that there would be a lot of local business there, so no matter if we had a booth it would be beneficial to just go and network from the other side of the booth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So we went.  To the Hargeisa NGO Fair.  Save the Children had maybe a quarter of the booths.  Different UN agencies were there.  The Somaliland Ministry of Planning was there.  Tons of other NGOs had booths.  What was there, but only on the margins, were businesses.  This is how the game goes in a screwed up economy.  The businesses get pushed to the margins to make way for individuals empowered by my tax dollars.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t have any problems per se with STC buying a quarter of the booths at the trade fair to show off what they are doing.  My free market proclivities are, at times, binding.  That said, it is super annoying.  Mainly because it does not make much sense.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me begin here.  I have deep philosophical problems with the notion that development has turned into an industry, complete with &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/search?sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;q=mpaid">dedicated degrees&lt;/a>, [think tanks][3], and navel gazing [memes][4] about professionals v. amateurs.   While I can agree with the notion that professionalism and progress within the development sector is an overall benefit which helped lead us to [this point][5], the core of the development story is often lost.  This is an industry which is deeply entrenched on the Hill, with Number 10, and in Brussels.  But it is an industry which should, at least according to its own rhetoric, be working itself out of existence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[3]: &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/search?sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;q=mpaid#hl=en&amp;amp;expIds=17050,25657,25907,26486,26488,26492,26496,26504,26637,26992,27028,27182&amp;amp;sugexp=ldymls&amp;amp;xhr=t&amp;amp;q=development">http://www.google.com/search?sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;q=mpaid#hl=en&amp;amp;expIds=17050,25657,25907,26486,26488,26492,26496,26504,26637,26992,27028,27182&amp;amp;sugexp=ldymls&amp;amp;xhr=t&amp;amp;q=development&lt;/a> think tanks&amp;amp;cp=15&amp;amp;pf=p&amp;amp;sclient=psy&amp;amp;aq=f&amp;amp;aqi=g4g-o1&amp;amp;aql=&amp;amp;oq=development thi&amp;amp;gs_rfai=&amp;amp;pbx=1&amp;amp;fp=8cf21fc6377a49f1
[4]: &lt;a href="http://lindaraftree.wordpress.com/2010/06/26/amateurs-professionals-innovations-and-smart-aid/">http://lindaraftree.wordpress.com/2010/06/26/amateurs-professionals-innovations-and-smart-aid/&lt;/a>
[5]: &lt;a href="http://www.foreignpolicy.com/articles/2010/08/16/best_decade_ever?utm_source=hootsuite&amp;amp;utm_medium=twitter&amp;amp;utm_campaign=news">http://www.foreignpolicy.com/articles/2010/08/16/best_decade_ever?utm_source=hootsuite&amp;amp;utm_medium=twitter&amp;amp;utm_campaign=news&lt;/a> sharing&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instead, we have a very different current situation.  One of deepening entrenchment rather than working for your own demise.  Here in Hargeisa at least NGO’s are the craved jobs.  They suck up the brains of the country with their steady jobs, their culturally relevant salaries, and their extremely limited advancement opportunities.  And then the NGOs talk about brain drain.  How awful that smart people want to leave their country because they have reduced opportunities to pursue their dreams.  Isn’t a bit hypocritical to moan and complain about meta-brain-drain when micro-brain-drain is happening by the people doing the complaining?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then there are the brochures, the brilliant web sites, the signs on the land cruisers, etc.  I have nothing against charity:water producing a fantastic site.  I have nothing against glossy brochures showing pictures of people in trouble.  I have nothing against the UN putting “Donated by:” on every single vehicle they buy for governments.  What I have a problem with is why in the world this is happening at all in Hargeisa.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Marketing needs to have a purpose and an audience.  So what is the purpose and intended audience of the above cited things?  If the intended audience is donors who are the ones making the decisions whether to extend funding, start a new program with a given organization, restrict funding, etc. then I have no problem.  In that case you have a situation where marketing makes sense as the cost of doing business.  I may continue to have philosophical problems with the “industrialization” of the sector, but at least I can see a purpose to glossy brochures in fancy DC offices.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But here in Hargeisa?  I mean donors come here like twice a year.  What is the point the rest of the time?  Is this marketing aimed at the beneficiaries?  If so, then wouldn’t the money be more efficiently used to buying one more X (insert your pet project’s purpose here)?  This is the crux of what was annoying me last week about the NGO fun fair.  Why was the money being spent at all?  Fine if it was marketing on behalf of the beneficiaries of livelihood training projects that is one thing.  And I grant that *some *of the NGO fun fair booths &lt;em>were&lt;/em> doing that exact thing.  But the rest of it, I have no idea.  Do you?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some pictures we took from the fun fair are below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[flickr-gallery mode=&amp;quot;photoset&amp;rdquo; photoset=&amp;quot;72157625007133105&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bono Writes About Africa (My Eyes Begin to Roll)</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-04-18-bono-writes-africa-my-eyes-roll/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-04-18-bono-writes-africa-my-eyes-roll/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/04/18/opinion/18bono.html?pagewanted=1&amp;amp;hp">&lt;img src="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/04/18/opinion/18bono.html?pagewanted=1&amp;amp;hp" alt="photo from maaarine via flickr">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I desperately wanted to hate &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/04/18/opinion/18bono.html?pagewanted=1&amp;amp;hp">this&lt;/a> op-ed which the NYT published yesterday and Bono wrote, but at the end it was a rather good piece.  There is this narrative which is beginning to form which is the first coherent, resonant, and positive narrative on Africa that I’ve heard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bono’s piece encapsulates the narrative quite well actually, but let me summarize.  Africa is getting to get its act together.  Although outliers like here where I live will remain, the rest of the continent (led by countries like Senegal, Ghana, Tanzania, and Botswana) are really moving forward.  Last year was the first time since the 1960s where average per capita income for the entire continent rose.  Arts are flourishing, people are beginning to move up Maslow’s hierarchy which is developing a strong and engaged middle-class.  In summary, it is an exciting time in Africa for all the reasons it has always been exciting, but for new ones too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I did like some of the imagery in the piece.  Particularly how at Ghana University Mo Ibrahim was the rock star and Bono was the apprentice.  I like how Bono day dreams of owning NBC and NYT (but I wonder why NBC).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the end of the day, the taste that resides in my mouth is of optimism.  And that, in and of itself is a big step forward. Because the rest of this is going to take work, lots of work and hope will be the fuel of that engine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>