<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>politics on underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/politics/</link><description>Recent content in politics on underWater desert Blogging</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Casey Kuhlman</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Spectrum of Public to Private Service Delivery</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-01-24-spectrum-service-delivery/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-01-24-spectrum-service-delivery/</guid><description>The people who most interested me were wary of centralized control, but they were not free market libertarians. They believed in the power of competition, but they also believed that some of society's most important achievements could not be incentivized with economic reward. They called themselves entrepreneurs but worked mostly in the public sector. They were equally suspicious of big government and big corporations. From a certain angle, they looked like a digital-age version of such nineteenth-century anarchists as Pierre-Joseph Proudhon or Mikhail Bakunin.</description></item><item><title>My Unreasonable Optimism and Why John Dickerson&amp;#8217;s (@jdickerson) Series Should Matter</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2012-10-06-my-unreasonable-optimism-and-why-john-dickersons-jdickerson-series-should-matter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2012-10-06-my-unreasonable-optimism-and-why-john-dickersons-jdickerson-series-should-matter/</guid><description>My Dad and I have this ongoing debate about campaigns. It has been ongoing for four years that I can remember but perhaps longer. It revolves around the forthrightness of campaigns to speak to the electorate logically, with courage, and while keeping within the bounds of logic and reasonableness. Instead of what I desperately want campaigns to do they do the opposite, spiraling into ever more irrelevant crap. Gaffes and ah ha’s are fun and interesting political theater but that is all it is.</description></item><item><title>On Marines and Krulak&amp;#8217;s Three Blocks</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2012-09-18-on-marines-and-krulaks-three-blocks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2012-09-18-on-marines-and-krulaks-three-blocks/</guid><description>Someone emailed me tonight asking what I thought about the attack on the consulate in Benghazi. Being that I was a Marine officer once upon a moon, this person asked whether my blood was up about them passing away and what I thought about the President putting our people in danger like that. Their words. Yes, of course my blood was up. I felt deeply for their families and for the poor souls who had to notice their families and for the entire situation.</description></item><item><title>Compromise &amp;amp; Governing: On Reading @ryanlizza&amp;#8217;s The Obama Memos</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2012-01-27-compromise-and-governing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2012-01-27-compromise-and-governing/</guid><description>When I was in college my friend Dave and I would often fall asleep at some point during our millionth screening of Braveheart. We would often put the film on after the bars had closed and we had grabbed our drunken treat of the night and were not yet ready for bed. At the time we were training to be Marine officers and very interested in learning what it took to be a good leader.</description></item><item><title>The Preacher is Back. That&amp;#8217;s What I&amp;#8217;ve Been Waiting For.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2011-09-09-the-preacher-is-back-thats-what-ive-been-waiting-for/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2011-09-09-the-preacher-is-back-thats-what-ive-been-waiting-for/</guid><description>![obama postcard by Mr. Wright @ Flickr]({{ site.url }}{{ site.root }}{{ site.images_dir }}/{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; }}/2795798382_9996813e74.jpg)
I just finished watching the jobs speech and my first thought was “were have you been”? The historian-poet-preacher in him which I fell in love with in the Yes We Can and Race speeches (collectively rather than individually) had found his groove tonight.
Every artist struggles with finding their artistic voice, but for me, at this moment, this was balm to my soul.</description></item><item><title>OK, So He&amp;#8217;s Gone. What Now?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2011-05-02-ok-so-hes-gone-what-now/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2011-05-02-ok-so-hes-gone-what-now/</guid><description>![Bin Laden hates this car by afagen @ flickr]({{ site.url }}{{ site.root }}{{ site.images_dir }}/{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; }}/2506982921_9132061338.jpg)
So I woke up this morning to the news. Obama Killed Osama. In my groggy state, I couldn’t really piece together what was happening on my collated facebook and twitter streams until I saw something similar to the previous sentence. I think the first thing I cognized was a friend’s facebook post: “Osama, so 10 years ago.</description></item><item><title>Egypt is Burning: On Arab Protests</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2011-01-30-egypt-burning-arab-protests/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2011-01-30-egypt-burning-arab-protests/</guid><description>[![THIS COULD HAVE BEEN STRAIGHT OUT OF A MOVIE! #jan25 #egypt via Farrah3m @ Twitpic][2]][2] &amp;ldquo;THIS COULD HAVE BEEN STRAIGHT OUT OF A MOVIE! #jan25 #egypt&amp;rdquo; via Farrah3m @ Twitpic Two days ago, my father asked me for my thoughts on the protests throughout the Arab world. I wanted to compose my thoughts, to let the situation develop a bit further before I said anything. Now is the time to say something.</description></item><item><title>On Tea Partiers &amp;amp; Rule-Free Systems: Football, NASCAR &amp;amp; Regulatory Authority</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2011-01-26-tea-partiers-rule-free-systems-football-nascar-regulatory-authority/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2011-01-26-tea-partiers-rule-free-systems-football-nascar-regulatory-authority/</guid><description>“An association of men who will not quarrel with one another is a thing which has never yet existed, from the greatest confederacy of nations down to a town meeting or a vestry.” ~ Thomas Jefferson
![Tea partiers by jkarsh @ Flickr]({{ site.url }}{{ site.root }}{{ site.images_dir }}/{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; }}/4607302277_f9cc76dd12.jpg) Think these guys watch NASCAR? - Tea partiers by jkarsh @ Flickr
I know I am generalizing, but since many that I know and love subscribe to many of these philosophies maybe I do have a small bit of perspective here.</description></item><item><title>Leaked Wikis, #Cablegate, and Little Else</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-12-02-leaked-wikis-cablegate/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-12-02-leaked-wikis-cablegate/</guid><description>![does your roof leak? by nuanc @ flickr]({{ site.url }}{{ site.root }}{{ site.images_dir }}/{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; }}/90753362_9e747069b7.jpg) does your roof leak? by nuanc @ flickr
There has been tons of interesting commentary and analysis surrounding cablegate. I have been interested and have read quite a few of the original cables, especially the ones about Somalia as well as much of the journalistic coverage of the story and the analysis (punditry) side of the story.</description></item><item><title>Trail of the Octopus</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-02-16-trail-of-the-octopus/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-02-16-trail-of-the-octopus/</guid><description>Last night we were drinking some wine. I say this because my consumption of alcohol has decreased drastically over the past few years. Living in a dry country helps!
Our new roommate was telling us this story about Lockerbee. Steve, the new roommate, is a terribly interesting man to talk to. In fact, it would be daunting talking to him if he wasn't such a genuine and normal human. We see eye to eye on many of the problems around us and he is doing something quite remarkable.</description></item><item><title>Teddy Goes to Big Think</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-02-08-teddy-goes-to-big-think/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-02-08-teddy-goes-to-big-think/</guid><description>Am just now getting around to watching Big Think's Editorial Top Ten of the year as I wait until 3 this morning when the SuperBowl will begin. The premise of Big Think is amazing to me: grab a bunch of influential people, ask them a penetrating question and then let them speak for five minutes or more. It is interesting when you sit and listen to people without the flashing signals and bottom scroll bars and overly enthusiastic reporters that so often are too busy to understand what the hell they are talking about.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-11-05-23/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-11-05-23/</guid><description>Thank You America. From those of us who no longer live at home. Thank you for allowing us to proudly hold our heads high in foreign lands again. Thank you for reminding the entire world why they admire us. Thank you for making the world remember why we are the great shining beacon of hope in a foul, foul world. Thank you for the sheer emotion that has flowed freely from your voices, and your faces, and your hearts.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-11-05-24/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-11-05-24/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Things are moving so fast in race relations a Negro could be president
in 40 years. There's no question about it. In the next 40 years, a
Negro can achieve the same position that my brother has. . . . But we
have tried to make progress and we are making progress. . . . We are
not going to accept the status quo.&amp;rdquo;
~ Bobby Kennedy, Editorial in the Washington Post, May, 27, 1968</description></item><item><title>GOTV</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-11-04-gotv/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-11-04-gotv/</guid><description>When I was in elementary school both of my parents worked and my younger brother and I used to ride our bikes to school. It being Florida, I promise not to turn this into a in the snow, uphill both-ways story. I remember looking at the signs over the years as the cycle eventually became faster and shorter. Each November they would be there, demanding/requesting/mandating/asking for my vote for School Board or County Commissioner or Water Commissioner.</description></item><item><title>Cook for Me Donna!</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-10-08-cook-for-me-donna/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-10-08-cook-for-me-donna/</guid><description>I will bypass comment regarding last night’s debate. It is almost painful to watch the death of the Robertson/Nixon Conservative coalition happen before our eyes. If it hadn’t have turned so ugly at the end (like new deal liberalism died a violent death with LBJ), it would have been actually painful. Instead, I offer for your consumption a slightly different perspective.
[]1
~ # ~</description></item><item><title>Is This the Day the World Changes?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-09-30-is-this-the-day-the-world-changes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-09-30-is-this-the-day-the-world-changes/</guid><description>Maybe that is a bit provocative. Maybe it is ipso facto. I don't know. And we'll have to see.
I remember being maybe 5 or 6 and either watching this show, or at least the trailer for a show about life after the Soviets invaded America and took over. It was the type of propoganda that I have to suspect most of those who spent more time in the Cold War than I were constantly subjected to.</description></item><item><title>Debate Reaction</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-09-27-debate-reaction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-09-27-debate-reaction/</guid><description>Some initial thoughts. It is 6:30 in the morning here and I've now been up all night, so maybe this will not be as eloquent or complete as I'd like.
McCain did well on FP, as was to be expected. His best answer was on Georgia when he said that this was largely about energy and (didn't say but meant) that this is important to Putin in order to entrench himself.</description></item><item><title>Wow.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-09-25-wow/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-09-25-wow/</guid><description>There is simply no other word that I can conjure. I would like to remind everyone that McCain is 73 and has had two, three or four incidents with cancer. McCain has lived a tough life. The Presidency routinely causes men not with white hair to go white as an indication of the stresses that are placed on one's body. I know momma McCain is 92 or whatever, but she wasn't a Prisoner of War, didn't routinely have large amounts of G-force placed on her body over a significant portion of her adult life and didn't spend the rest of her adult life fighting, scrapping, and arguing with everyone and their brother on the hill.</description></item><item><title>Georgia v. Russia</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-08-18-georgia-v-russia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-08-18-georgia-v-russia/</guid><description>Because I am intellectually inferior and do not have so much time, I have few unique thoughts. There is some great analysis on the web about the short conflict. NYT has a great article on the tactics used by the Russians. I, for one, am not scared by the Russian's ability to employ combined arms in the same manner that we are. They simply do not have the culture that relies on decentralization necessary to affect true combine arms warfare in the way that we employ CA.</description></item><item><title>The Issue of Valor</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-08-16-the-issue-of-valor/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-08-16-the-issue-of-valor/</guid><description>[![R1874377885][2]][2] Photo courtesy of [here][2].
[]: http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e200e553e9de388833-pi [2]: http://patdollard.com/wp-content/uploads/r1874377885.jpg
Bing West, who my former co-author knows quite well, and I met once briefly in Iraq while he joined one of my patrols has an interesting interview in a blog I frequent: Small Wars Journal.
Part one is here. Part two is here.
I largely agree with his tactical analysis, especially the part where he exposes his institutional biases and lauds the Marines in Anbar.</description></item><item><title>Anti-Americanism</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-07-23-anti-americanism/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-07-23-anti-americanism/</guid><description>[![_40656678_flag_afp_203body][2]][2] To be honest, I’ve never fully understood the vehement Anti-Americanism that I have at times been the target of. I did understand it the few times I experienced it in Iraq. Mainly, it is the European anti-americanism that I do not fully understand. I usually dismiss it as some sort of a simple jealousy and unwillingness to part with the past and realize that the world has moved on. I know that that is a simplistic understanding of a complex issue.</description></item><item><title>HRC Showing Some Class, still a bit late</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-06-05-hrc-showing-some-class-still-a-bit-late/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-06-05-hrc-showing-some-class-still-a-bit-late/</guid><description>I have been question what her game is for weeks now. I have been questioning why the DNC elites don't shut her down. I have been questioning why there isn't droves and droves of supers to him after the election in a show of party unity. Some of this has begun. But why now? What has changed between yesterday and today that HRC only now is &amp;ldquo;suspending&amp;rdquo; her campaign. Further, suspending?</description></item><item><title>The Real Deal</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-06-04-the-real-deal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-06-04-the-real-deal/</guid><description>[![Bmchipsomodevillagetty][2]][2]
[][2] [(Photo: Chip Somodevilla/Getty.)][2] [Andrew Sullivan][3] has some phenomenal reactions about Barack’s seeming win up today. The first is a story that choked me up told by one of Andrew’s [readers][4]:  My grandfather, 86 years old and a veteran of WWII, just
gave me a call. He was calling all of his grandchildren to let them
know what an important night this was in the history of our country.</description></item><item><title>VeepStakes</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-05-29-veepstakes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-05-29-veepstakes/</guid><description>One of my favorite pundit-ers is Marc Ambinder who writes for the Atlantic.
He has a great article on how candidates go about selecting running mates. I'm not sure how it will play out for Obama, much less for McCain. I certainly hope that the robot-republican doesn't win. For Obama, I'm going to slow play my predictions, but I will say that I was a Richardson supporter before I was an Obama supporter.</description></item><item><title>McCain is All Class</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-04-23-mccain-is-all-class/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-04-23-mccain-is-all-class/</guid><description>Link: Jonathan Martin’s Blog – Politico.com.
I’m not a McCain supporter. However, I am very very pleased that he was able to secure the Republican nomination. The backstory is linked to above, but the letter below is prima facie evidence of McCain’s class as a human. It is shit like this that I highly respect. Very Well Done Mr. Senator.
Dear Chairman Daves,
From the beginning of this election, I have been committed to running a</description></item><item><title>My Boy and His Toy</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-04-23-my-boy-and-his-toy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-04-23-my-boy-and-his-toy/</guid><description>Link: John King of CNN Revels in His High-Tech Election Night Toy – New York Times.
NYT profiles the best political commentator on television. I once saw him point to this big map and circle a part of Florida and say something akin to: &amp;ldquo;This part of Florida right here, just south of Orlando is the home to the Non-Mexican, Non-Puerto Rican Latin population in Florida.&amp;rdquo; Who the hell knows that?</description></item><item><title>The Dumbest Debate in America</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-04-17-the-dumbest-debate-in-america/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-04-17-the-dumbest-debate-in-america/</guid><description>Link: The dumbest debate in America. The Guardian has a great op-ed which I think summarizes exactly how I felt about the debate last night. The crux of the matter boils down to this very well crafted sentence.
When a presidential debate in a nation roiled by two wars, an economic
crisis and a seven-year onslaught on civil liberties revolves around
questions about flag pins and casual friends, it would be easy to</description></item><item><title>Revisiting the Vietnam Syndrome</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-04-11-revisiting-the-vietnam-syndrome/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-04-11-revisiting-the-vietnam-syndrome/</guid><description>I grew up not when Vietnam was happening, but rather, I grew up in the dramatic artistic, historical and cultural shadow of the Vietnam era. That shadow colored much of what I did and what I valued, especially during the formative years of college where I was forming my world view and sharpening my military instincts. While in the Marines, Vietnam loomed as the most important historical, cultural, and tactical benchmark.</description></item><item><title>Obama&amp;#8217;s First Masterpiece?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-03-19-obamas-first-masterpiece/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-03-19-obamas-first-masterpiece/</guid><description>This speech is 40 minutes long and it will be the best thing that you do today. Do not let someone else help form your opinions on this speech. Form your own. The embed:
[]11111 Now, to my reactions. Everyone is right that it is brilliant and nuanced, honest and frank. Charles Murray, the conservative author who raised much controversy with the Bell Curve called the speech &amp;ldquo;brilliant.&amp;rdquo; Most politicos I’ve read have thought it was the most frank and honest speech on race during their lifetimes.</description></item><item><title>A Dubious Honor</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-02-28-a-dubious-honor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-02-28-a-dubious-honor/</guid><description>My old battalion has achieved a dubious honor. They are the first military unit to get deployed to Iraq for the Fifth time. Now that is a bit misleading because of the mobility of the military there are few individuals that have likely gone five times. But still…..
~ # ~</description></item><item><title>Courting my Boi</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-02-23-courting-my-boi/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-02-23-courting-my-boi/</guid><description>[![Billrichardson][2]][2]
[No Longer in Race, Richardson Is a Man Pursued][2]. It isn’t a secret that before he dropped out, I was hoping that Bill Richardson would make a good showing. Now that he is out of the race (no pun intended), I have been wondering whether he would be attractive to the candidates, and if he was in what regard. []: http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2008/02/23/billrichardson.jpg [2]: http://www.nytimes.com/2008/02/23/us/politics/23richardson.html?_r=1&amp;amp;hp&amp;amp;oref=slogin &amp;ldquo;No Longer in Race, Richardson Is a Man Pursued - New York Times&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Voting Machines</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-02-06-voting-machines/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-02-06-voting-machines/</guid><description>Can someone explain to me why we are even hearing about voting machines…? How flipping difficult can the code be? Why are these things untrustworthy? Other than the Chinese State (with its professionals) hacking into our systems, why are we unable to figure this out? There are a few candidates, you click one of them. A counter counts. Maybe I just don’t understand some nuances (which is troubling considering I’m going to do election policy and process reform), but it seems to me to be a non-issue.</description></item><item><title>Why Iraq Matters, but Doesn&amp;#8217;t Matter</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-02-06-why-iraq-matters-but-doesnt-matter/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-02-06-why-iraq-matters-but-doesnt-matter/</guid><description>During the last debate, I was talking with Super-Star about Iraq. The following is my analysis of the situation.
Iraq matters – a lot to voters. But Iraq shouldn’t matter. No matter what the candidates say to pander to their base each of them is going to do virtually identical things on Iraq. Iraq is complicated, but it isn’t that complicated. We know what we need to do now, that is clear.</description></item><item><title>Wonk Out</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-02-06-wonk-out/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-02-06-wonk-out/</guid><description>[![Benazirbhuttocfr][2]][2]
If you want to see one of the most nuanced foreign policy discussions among true professionals in the world, go to CFR.
[]: http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2008/02/05/benazirbhuttocfr.jpg
BTW, in case any are wondering, each of the major candidates is a member of CFR. ~ # ~</description></item><item><title>Another Reason</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-02-05-another-reason/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-02-05-another-reason/</guid><description>This is why I Support Barack. Not for the celebrities; Not because of his blatant appeals to people in my demographic; But Because of the Words. Listen to the Words, Big_Head once told me. I’m listening.
[]4444 This is what the creator said about this video. I’m not an artist, I do other things, but I agree with almost everything he says.
I was sitting in my recording studio watching the debates…</description></item><item><title>Debating &amp;amp; Afghanistan</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-02-02-debating-afghanistan/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-02-02-debating-afghanistan/</guid><description>Last night I nerded out, as I am wonk to do. Doug and I watched the entire debate in utter, wonk bliss. The shivs were there, but both candidates kept them under the table. Both candidates showed off the intricacies of their handle on the policy. Both candidates were eloquent, prepared and insightful. I won’t cry if Hillary wins. And, BTW, I won’t threaten to move to Canada if McCain wins as on my major issues of international reengagement and the environment they are all three virtually in alignment.</description></item><item><title>Jimmy Carter Speaks the Troof</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-01-15-jimmy-carter-speaks-the-troof/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-01-15-jimmy-carter-speaks-the-troof/</guid><description>[![Jimmycarter][2]][2]
[I Got What America Needs Right Here | The Onion][2] Jimmy Carter OpEd on the Onion. Don’t knock it, Jimmy knows his shit!
[]: http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2008/01/15/jimmycarter.jpg [2]: http://www.theonion.com/content/opinion/i_got_what_america_needs_right &amp;ldquo;I Got What America Needs Right Here | The Onion - America's Finest News Source&amp;rdquo;
~ # ~</description></item><item><title>Richardson is Out</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-01-12-richardson-is-out/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-01-12-richardson-is-out/</guid><description>I am sad to see Bill Richardson drop out of the Presidential Race. He has had my support for a long time because of his int’l credentials; his moderate but competent domestic policies; and most of all his realism. []3
Now I hope that he gets onto the backs of one of the two major campaigns, and by one I mean the right one for my target age bracket!
In other political news, NYT has a grand article about what Dean wants to attack McCain on.</description></item><item><title>Why the Democrats aren&amp;#8217;t ending the war. &amp;#8211; By Fred Kaplan &amp;#8211; Slate Magazine</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-12-21-why-the-democrats-arent-ending-the-war-by-fred-kaplan-slate-magazine/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-12-21-why-the-democrats-arent-ending-the-war-by-fred-kaplan-slate-magazine/</guid><description>This is one of the most informative and balanced pieces on Iraq I’ve read in AGES. Not sure of its accuracy, but it certainly isn’t too glowing about either party. I think this is the level of public debate that needs to really be entered into as I detest the black and white stay or leave debate which really gets no one anywhere. Some of the musings of politicos lately have been whether the American people are able to hear complexity out of their politicians.</description></item><item><title>Put this one in your toolkit</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-12-20-put-this-one-in-your-toolkit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-12-20-put-this-one-in-your-toolkit/</guid><description>[![Captainmorgan2][2]][2]
I remember one time when Evergreen and I were in the Marine Corps. He was so tired and it was so dark outside that he heated up a bag of peanut butter to put in his cheese ravioli bag of treats. It was so disgusting that he had to go hungry or eat it, considering the circumstances (we were on one meal a day for the exercise and all exhausted and constantly hungry) he ate it, but I will always remember the look on his face when he turned to me and said in his Texas draw, &amp;ldquo;Casey, put this one in your toolkit, always check if the bag is peanut butter or cheese cause if you get this one wrong it’ll costya.</description></item><item><title>Social Networking for Good</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-12-20-social-networking-for-good/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-12-20-social-networking-for-good/</guid><description>So, I’m not really sure what good can come about by &amp;ldquo;friending&amp;rdquo; on MySpace a bunch of organizations that do good work. I guess on one level it warms the heart of the friender, knowing that they are on the in with these organizations. I guess it can also bolster the &amp;ldquo;rolls&amp;rdquo; of the friendee, something that poli_sci has consistently told me is key to grassroots organizing as the bigger the rolls the more money they can potentially raise by leveraging that list to similar organizations that need to get a hold of similar people or from foundations who use the rolls as a proxy for the amount of good the organization will be able to accomplish (similar to a business plan for a small-business loan the grant writing proposal (apparently) can swing for or against often times based upon the size of the roll like the amount of the small-business owner’s money that is already invested in the business).</description></item><item><title>Cultural Questionings</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-12-19-cultural-questionings/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-12-19-cultural-questionings/</guid><description>[![Website_santa_hat5][2]][2]
I’m certainly no expert on Dutch culture or Dutch language, but can anyone tell me if there are even Dutch words for the following English equivalents: []: http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/12/19/website_santa_hat5.jpg
Pardon Me. Excuse Me. I’m Sorry. I Apologize. It Was My Fault. If there are, I certainly haven’t ever heard them. Back in the land I love, or the land that I love to make fun of for the holidays.</description></item><item><title>Hold on Saakashvili!</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-11-07-hold-on-saakashvili/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-11-07-hold-on-saakashvili/</guid><description>[![07georms2650][2]][2]
Georgia was [AMAZING][2]. Highlands and I went there this past summer and I really fell in love with the people, with the environment, with the food, with the wine, with most everything there. It is disappointing that there are many [allegations][3] of extensive human rights violations by the country and that there is the (real or not) perception of rampant corruption in the country. These allegations have led to [massive protests ][4]in beautiful old Tbilisi.</description></item><item><title>Nobel Racist</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-10-18-nobel-racist/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-10-18-nobel-racist/</guid><description>James Watson, pride of American science? A bloody racist is more like it. This angers me, it confirms, yet again, to the rest of the world what god damn idiots many Americans are. Controversial DNA Pioneer’s Talk Halted.
~ # ~</description></item><item><title>Georgia Politicians Get Jail Terms</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-08-28-georgia-politicians-get-jail-terms/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-08-28-georgia-politicians-get-jail-terms/</guid><description>This cannot be good for relations between Russia and Georgia. Highlands and I were just in Georgia a few weeks ago and it was a wonderful country with rugged mountains, wonderful people and a good government that is making many good steps (at least good as defined by Western governments, but this normative relativity varies in proportion to the square of your distance from Moscow). I fell in love with the country.</description></item><item><title>next issue</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-07-19-next-issue/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-07-19-next-issue/</guid><description>i like the SNL skit where they make fun of that sunday morning news show. and they use ‘next issue’ to punctuate debates. i’ll think of the name of it in a minute. i finish with the court tomorrow, although i’ll be in holland for another week and probably in and out of the office to tidy up a few things. the rest of the summer will be spent all over.</description></item><item><title>wow</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-07-17-wow-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-07-17-wow-2/</guid><description>i’m not naive enough to think that the causal links for this video can be traced all the way up the leadership chain to bush. whatever happened is probably too complex to comment upon. but what i can comment upon is that i hope to god this is some sick fucking joke, and if it is not then this simple-minded moron should be taken out of the gene pool. i know this much, none of my marines treated any iraqi’s like this and if i would have caught them they would have been taken out of the gene pool.</description></item><item><title>irrepressible.info</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-07-13-irrepressible-info/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-07-13-irrepressible-info/</guid><description>this is a fantastic idea which i actually wrote about in a paper. amnesty and an IT company have formed an ngo titled irrepressible.info which takes content that is banned categorically and decentralized it onto other people’s blogs. that way countries which have categorical firewalls which block user’s ability to visit certain pages (e.g. HRW, AI, etc.) are enabled to see the content. way to go technology. in other news i’m figuring out how to put code onto my blog…</description></item><item><title>stories from right here</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-07-03-stories-from-right-here/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-07-03-stories-from-right-here/</guid><description>I think that Nora Ephron thinks that she is hilarious. I think she is a bore. And a bitch, but that is a different story predicated on seeing her in Asssspen a few summers ago and being majorly turned off by her snooty attitude. Link.
There was another intersting article in the NYT’s which speaks about Buying into the Green Movement and links between hip stylings in the name of save the earth that really are consumerism light and still have drastic impact on the planet.</description></item><item><title>Beam It Down From the Web, Scotty</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-05-08-beam-it-down-from-the-web-scotty/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-05-08-beam-it-down-from-the-web-scotty/</guid><description>if you haven’t seen this article, you should. it is flippin’ crazy. i want to print out a nice tulia style burrito from amigos with chips, salsa and some water with that ICE….!!! wonder if this will enable humans to be even more lazy in their shopping and when they shop….could make xmas even an exciting time.
~ # ~</description></item><item><title>worrisome coding&amp;#8230;</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-03-08-worrisome-coding/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-03-08-worrisome-coding/</guid><description>i have become increasingly worried about the ubiquity of Times New Roman…as an ethos.
personally, i prefer Century New Schoolbook, but when i need a break, to relax, i choose garamond.
~ # ~</description></item><item><title>Be My Anti-Valentine</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-02-15-be-my-anti-valentine/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-02-15-be-my-anti-valentine/</guid><description>Check out this site. My office and I laughed for hours about some of the cards.
Link: meish.org :: Be My Anti-Valentine.
~ # ~</description></item><item><title>media created gaps in propaganda</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-02-07-media-created-gaps-in-propaganda/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-02-07-media-created-gaps-in-propaganda/</guid><description>THiS is a letter from the Prosecutor of the ICC. Yesterday I wrote about the gaps in the climate change debate. This document was written in February, 2006 and is the Prosecutor’s response to requests that he look into the Iraq situation. He lays out his legal authority and his decision space in a very nice, non-lawyer-friendly manner. And then he says, thank you but no. Now, there were no requests that he investigate US actors in Iraq, becuase the US and Iraq are not a state parties to the ICC.</description></item><item><title>The real deal?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-02-06-the-real-deal-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-02-06-the-real-deal-2/</guid><description>The real deal? is an article that addresses real or percieved gaps in the current debate on climate change. I agree heartily that there are gaps. i understand what this article is trying to argue, but i don’t agree. this article cites one israeli scientist that published one paper that may or may not have been peer reviewed and claims that there is a scientific debate. in fact what the IPCC found is that there is a greater than 90% chance that climate change is caused by human factors.</description></item><item><title>my chinese space</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-11-11-my-chinese-space/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-11-11-my-chinese-space/</guid><description>news corp generally, i think, sucks. however this is a good thing. the problem is that there are korean and japanese &amp;ldquo;versions&amp;rdquo; of social networking that blow my space’s flat categories and horrible layouts away. these asain sites are apparently [sic] with 3d anime that is user controlled where people build living spaces and avatars and interact in much more social ways. myspace is flat, not very interactive, and very western….</description></item><item><title>to plant a tree</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-11-08-to-plant-a-tree/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-11-08-to-plant-a-tree/</guid><description>the african environmental advocate who is the only african female nobel laureate is now starting a program to plant a billion trees world wide. advantages: soil stability, carbon sequestration, jobs, beauty.
disadvantages? can’t really think of anything, other than where is the $ going to come from. see, this is the type of solution that adam would advocate for. rather than spending gagillians of dollars on technological solutions that will only benefit a few smart, well-to-do people.</description></item><item><title>Chavez in Russia for arms deals</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-07-25-chavez-in-russia-for-arms-deals/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-07-25-chavez-in-russia-for-arms-deals/</guid><description>Chavez signs a deal with Russia. This is HUGE. I cannot believe that the US press is not picking up on this. Understandably there is a lot going on in the world and if you are passionately positioned on either side of the Israel-Arab tension then you would prefer to be hearing of other things and if you are positioned in the heat that is engulfing the entire west coast then you may also have other things on your mind.</description></item><item><title>Scientific Breakdown of Global Warming</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-07-25-scientific-breakdown-of-global-warming/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-07-25-scientific-breakdown-of-global-warming/</guid><description>YOU too should see an Inconvenient Truth. I saw it for the second time this past weekend when I was home in ORL. In case you don’t understand the science of it click here and become an informed voter.
Scientific American: If carbon dioxide makes up only a minute portion of the atmosphere, how can global warming be traced to it? And how can such a tiny amount of change produce such large effects?</description></item><item><title>there isn&amp;#8217;t much you can do, except realize&amp;#8230;</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-07-21-there-isnt-much-you-can-do-except-realize/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-07-21-there-isnt-much-you-can-do-except-realize/</guid><description>that africa is fucked.
~ # ~</description></item><item><title>this seems (mostly) right</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-07-21-this-seems-mostly-right/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-07-21-this-seems-mostly-right/</guid><description>most of you know where i want to go with my career. this has been cemented over the course of the summer and my participation in both meaningless and meaningful litigation and policy development here in the US. my platform: assisting developing countries in pulling themselves out of poverty without mortgaging their environments to do so.
the following excerpt is from a council on foreign relations publication on the nuclear deal the US cut with India to establish a commercial (thereby non-weapons grade or adaptable) nuclear deal where the US will help India establish a nuclear program.</description></item><item><title>self-marketing</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-02-11-self-marketing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-02-11-self-marketing/</guid><description>so there are these sites. some of you know of them. friendster. my space. facebook.com. they are all pretty much the same thing. they are sites that allow you to tell people about your self: fav movies, fav music, fav TV, quotes, &amp;ldquo;about me,&amp;rdquo; and other blase things. first you create yourself. just like any other document (real or fake, static or dynamic) you choose which aspects of yourself to accentuate and whatever.</description></item><item><title>its like an allergy</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-02-03-its-like-an-allergy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2006-02-03-its-like-an-allergy/</guid><description>so i think that i was born like 5 years too early. this is different than my usual time shifting desires where i think that i was born either fifty or twenty years too late. but any way back to my rant of the day. i think that i was born like 5 years too early. the main reason that leads me to say this is my utter inability to cross platform communicate.</description></item><item><title>t-shirt ideas</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-09-21-t-shirt-ideas/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-09-21-t-shirt-ideas/</guid><description>so i have the following t-shirt ideas that i thought would be funny.
[sic]
alPHA male (in white letters ona brilliant pink bkgnd)
if he was the last man alive (front)
would you eat Chit? (back)
and one other i cannot remember
~ # ~</description></item><item><title>take that pat benatar</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-09-19-take-that-pat-benatar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-09-19-take-that-pat-benatar/</guid><description>direct quote:
It was never suggested that we had in this country a surplus of brain toilers…
Supreme court decision, 1892. Still OH So true today.
~ # ~</description></item><item><title>Confluence of Space and Non-Space</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-08-12-confluence-of-space-and-non-space/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-08-12-confluence-of-space-and-non-space/</guid><description>the internet is a fabulous, and deadly, weapon for mass destruction of society. or maybe mass creation of different societies. i’m not certain.
what i can be certain of is that i spent a good amount of time on said contraption this evening. once i made the psychological and philosophical leap into the pool of law school, i made another leap. i’m gonna be a rock star. shit, i already have the hair for it, and fucking mick jagger and dylan cannot sing, so why should i be required to have that apptitude or ability?</description></item></channel></rss>