<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/</link><description>A Site About Resilience and Authoritarianism</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</managingEditor><webMaster>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</webMaster><copyright>All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Spectrum of Public to Private Service Delivery</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-01-24-spectrum-service-delivery/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-01-24-spectrum-service-delivery/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The people who most interested me were wary of centralized control, but they were not free market libertarians. They believed in the power of competition, but they also believed that some of society's most important achievements could not be incentivized with economic reward. They called themselves entrepreneurs but worked mostly in the public sector. They were equally suspicious of big government and big corporations. From a certain angle, they looked like a digital-age version of such nineteenth-century anarchists as Pierre-Joseph Proudhon or Mikhail Bakunin. Yet beneath that strange, hard-to-place eclecticism, a core philosophy seemed to unite all their efforts, even if it didn't fit comfortably into the existing categories of political belief.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>~ Future Perfect by Steven Johnson &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Future-Perfect-Case-Progress-Networked/dp/1594631840">Amazon&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Services are delivered by companies. But we need the government or else the greedy capitalists will take everything. But the government is inefficient and slow &amp;ndash; just look at the Post Office. But&amp;hellip; But&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The dirty little secret is that no one knows necessarily what the right answer to this question is because we are still learning the right solution for a particular and the right solution is constantly changing. Instead of thinking in binary terms maybe it would be more helpful to think in terms of a spectrum with fully public delivery on the one side (passing legislation would fit here &amp;ndash; we probably do not want the rule-making function of governance to be within the private sector and even more susceptible to private capture than it currently is) and fully private delivery on the other side (selling slurpees &amp;ndash; we probably do not want selling of fungible goods to be within the private sector which has little incentives to innovate). In between these extremes there is a very large space in which operators can work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the arrangements I work in routinely for Watershed's clients are Public-Private Partnerships or PPP's. You know these from such hits as the private vendors operating services within national parks, or stadium builds which are usually a mix of public and private financing. These partnerships allow for a wide variety of delivery possibilities that are not nearly as limiting as a simple binary question of public v. private. Instead of focusing on the binary nature of service delivery within our policy debates which characterizes the delivery of services as either &lt;em>purely private&lt;/em> or &lt;em>purely public&lt;/em> each with its advocate class and all unable to resolve their differences or get things done so that people can get to the task of l i v i n, perhaps we should think more in terms of a spectrum. Focus our thinking about service delivery on a spectrum rather than a binary on-off switch allows us to focus our debates on finding the right point along the spectrum to deliver the services which we are speaking to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To Europeans this debate that occupies our time, the government is great v. government sucks debate, is hilarious. I get asked about it a lot. It is intuitive to most Europeans that service delivery operates on a spectrum. Services in Europe are routinely modified within the spectrum and also change over time due to efficiencies, politics, or many other factors. Last year there was an outcry within the UK as the conservative government was trying to move the National Health Service along the spectrum towards the private side which raised many alarms for people. But that debate, and many others within the politics of service delivery in Europe happen without the sky is falling, scream at your TV, Nancy Grace style of debate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I like that part of Europe. A lot. Because generally when the population that doesn't know anything about the delivery of such services simply gets out of the way things happen in a pretty smooth way. Not all the time. But most of the time when people who don't know things about things let the people who do know things about things do their jobs things run pretty well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course there are differences between the two. Incentives for one are different. Private sector actors have incentives to optimize their profits. To think of short term gains over long term innovation. To reduce costs and simplify delivery mechanisms. These are all well and good, but there is a place for them. Public sector actors have a different set of incentives. To ensure the widest access to the services. To ensure the right costing is built into the system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The difference in these set of incentives (of which the above is meant to be illustrative) are important to understand. But our polity just needs to remember that there is space within these incentives for harmonization. Once we stop thinking in the simplistic terms of &amp;ldquo;Government good&amp;rdquo; | &amp;ldquo;Government bad&amp;rdquo; and start asking the question of how this service should be delivered based on what &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rdquo; are trying to accomplish. Then a whole world of policy solutions is opened to us.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Try it during the upcoming election season. Watch a debate and ask yourself if the debaters are being overly reductive in how they are approaching a service delivery question. Those that are not being overly reductive &amp;ndash; that are in the business of finding solutions which will actually move us along a path rather than simply spewing forth banal answers &amp;ndash; those are the ones that I will be voting for.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Unreasonable Optimism and Why John Dickerson&amp;#8217;s (@jdickerson) Series Should Matter</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-10-06-my-unreasonable-optimism-and-why-john-dickersons-jdickerson-series-should-matter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-10-06-my-unreasonable-optimism-and-why-john-dickersons-jdickerson-series-should-matter/</guid><description>&lt;p>My Dad and I have this ongoing debate about campaigns. It has been ongoing for four years that I can remember but perhaps longer. It revolves around the forthrightness of campaigns to speak to the electorate logically, with courage, and while keeping within the bounds of logic and reasonableness. Instead of what I desperately want campaigns to do they do the opposite, spiraling into ever more irrelevant crap. Gaffes and ah ha’s are fun and interesting political theater but that is all it is. Theater. Theater is a farce. And we must stop hiring representatives to govern us based on a farcical audition system. This I have felt deeply for a long time. It colors most of my political worldview, rightly or wrongly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>John Dickerson wrote a &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/WyS3iH" title="How To Measure for a President, by John Dickerson">series&lt;/a> of pieces this week that I hope with all the optimism my increasing cynicism can muster that someday it will be viewed as a transformative work. In his work he pleads with the electorate in a way I know he believes. I’ve spent an hour a week more or less for the past seven years and I believe that he believes every word he wrote. His authenticity is easy to trust and recognize with that much exposure. His argument is basically that we need to rethink about how we treat Presidential campaigns. We are covering the wrong things he says to the media elite. You are emphasizing the wrong things he says to the campaigns. We are rewarding the wrong behavior he tells the electorate. And all of them/us need to hear it because all have a roll in fixing it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So what can we the electorate do? In my opinion it is our duty to educate ourselves about the issues, about what the President can actually control, and to take a decision based upon those items rather than the metrics of how many gaffes some poor guy or girl exposed to immense pressure takes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An informed and reasonable electorate is the only way we can pull ourselves out of this death spiral of hyper partisanship, reactionary media coverage, and off the charts dissatisfaction. We the electorate have as much to do with this, perhaps more, than the candidates do. Political leaders aren’t really leaders at all. At least in a democracy they are supposed to represent their constituents’ interests. Vying too far outside of these, and the politician loses their representative title. We call those people here in Africa: Dictators. The simple fact is that a politician is constrained by public opinion. So an ill-informed electorate, purposefully or otherwise, will logically reward the loudest rather than the smartest. Here’s the rub. We get the country we demand folks. When we refuse to educate ourselves on what the President does when we don’t demand intellectual and reasoned debate rather than stupid gaffery we end up with….Fox News and MSNBC yelling past each other.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are in a difficult situation. Right now. In the short term, I’m pessimistic, but in the long term I’m optimistic. I remain hopeful for two primary reasons.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, the grip of push consumption models of information continues to wane and simultaneously individual trust is replacing brand trust within the media. The former matters because when one unplugs from cable and consumes media and information on a purely pull model one’s ability to consume and process that information substantially increases. When you are in the mood for bubble gum you aren’t receptive to political messaging. Subliminal and uninformed voters barely process TV adds anymore. We are numb to them. But when you are in the mood for political messaging, you are in much better frame of mind to process that information. This is augmented by – the latter – individual trust located within both of one’s social graphs and interest graphs. Both of these significantly increase the ease which one can enter into the information funnel at headlines and steadily work downward through the increasing complexity to extreme wonkland if interested merely by reading, thinking, and clicking. Twitter leads to articles lead to counter arguments lead to source data. While this information funnel needs some work, people like Ethan Zuckerman at the Berkman Center and other terribly smart guys are thinking deeply about how this can operate. It will get better. And we will get better at using it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The second reason I resist encroaching cynicism is the rise of the Maker class. Art from Andy Warhol to the Breakfast Club to Rage Against the Machine has been warning us against getting too big and too homogeneous  It won’t work the artists warned. And they led the world. Long before there was a consultant class there were independent artists. But now DIY is everywhere and not only because Home Depot wants to sell you some lumber. Big is out and small is in. And I for one am incredibly satisfied. Music, for me, has never been more diverse and more wonderful. Despite the RIAA apocolypsing, music is the best I have ever experienced. And I’ve been following music for a decent little while now. Food is similarly wonderful. Farm to table restaurants and good wines make the old suburban standbys just places you go by default when you’re not in the know or when you are resigned to mediocrity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Small is in. Small is great. But small is messy. It refuses to be categorized as easily. It celebrates the individual, with its flaws and eccentricities, not in tension with the community (as the rhetoric from the right so often tries to frame it) but as part of it. Integral to the flow of the community. But this becomes problematic politically. Or so some argue. If  we decentralize and fracture the currently coalitions underpinning the current form of the Republican and Democratic parties so wonder what will happen thereafter. Some wonder if we had more than two viable national parties whether people would be able to parse the differences. I have no idea whether that is true, but I know that music, which is much farther ahead of politics in this area, is better than it is ever been. This is why I remain (perhaps unreasonably) optimistic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On Marines and Krulak&amp;#8217;s Three Blocks</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-09-18-on-marines-and-krulaks-three-blocks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-09-18-on-marines-and-krulaks-three-blocks/</guid><description>&lt;p>Someone emailed me tonight asking what I thought about the attack on the consulate in Benghazi. Being that I was a Marine officer once upon a moon, this person asked whether my blood was up about them passing away and what I thought about the President putting our people in danger like that. Their words. Yes, of course my blood was up. I felt deeply for their families and for the poor souls who had to notice their families and for the entire situation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But there is a bigger picture here that I want to point out. These guys faced an impossible task. Utterly impossible. There was no right answer for them and all these people screaming about why aren’t our embassies safer and posting about the poor Marines do a disservice to their service. As Marines we are not in the business of allowing ourselves to be victimized. That, in my opinion,  is a bigger disservice to those Marines than a simple and honest answer: this is the fog of Krulak’s three block war. Before I explain Krulak’s theory, let us first try to picture the decisions these Marines had to take.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was not there that night in Benghazi and I make no claims on knowledge of the attack other than what I’ve seen on the news. The below should be taken for no more than it is meant to be: a thought experiment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You are in a safehouse and it is 9/11. You are in a predominately Muslim country and as opposed to all the other Muslim countries you’ve likely been in recently, in this one they don’t hate you. In fact you are accompanying the Ambassador to the heartland, the ground zero, of the movement your country helped to achieve power.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There have been riots but you likely pay those no mind. Not because you are negligent, but precisely because you are not scared of them. Even if you have been told of possible security concerns, you probably still pay them no mind. You understand the waxes and wanes of the moods of crowds. Sure you stay vigilant. Your helmet stays on and your weapon is there, but it is just people annoyed. They aren’t attacking you. And chances are damn good that you know what it feels like when a crowd turns on you, when the focus of collective disdain is you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Or perhaps you do feel it. Perhaps the security briefings and 9/11 and the feel of the crowd tingle your spidey senses. What are you going to do about it? Absolutely nothing. You just stay there, vigilant. Your helmet stays on and your weapon is there. And you watch. And wait. And listen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you hear the woosh of an RPG you barely have any time to react before the bang of the detonation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now what? Do you fire back? Who exactly are you going to fire at? You have very likely been taught that aimlessly shooting into crowds is an atrocious idea. Anyway, it is night and this is guard duty. You know you don’t have the full range of combined arms at your disposal you may have had in Afghanistan or Iraq. You know that you have only a few guys with small arms. And you have no idea who is shooting at you or how many they are. You are smart enough to know that now is not the time for asking the why. You are also smart enough to remember that this city is highly militarized and while they generally like you now, you understand damn well how fleeting that public opinion is. And shooting randomly into the crowd isn’t going to help.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even if you had the luck to see the shooters location and had tracked his movements through the crowds on grainy NVGs because you are a superhuman. And even if that guy was stupid enough to give you a clear shot. (It must be said that the chances for that happening are basically nil) How sure are you that you can make that shot in the midst of a heaving crowd at night from distance?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So do you go after him? If you pursue, you leave the place you are supposed to be guarding, and worse you leave the *person *you are supposed to be guarding. The Ambassador. In the olden days people were hung for decisions like those.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The ambassador. That jogs your mind. How is he?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The above sequence of thoughts took me twenty times longer to type then for you to process. Perhaps a hundred.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You inquire about the ambassador and are told that he is injured. There are people everywhere. People are shouting. It is dark. You have no idea who is who. Still the consulate is being fired on. Even if you were superhuman enough to track the shooter they have melted back into the crowd while you were checking on the ambassador.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This my friends is chaos. Utter and complete chaos. Not complexity. F-ing chaos. You can call it the shit, the fog of war, or any of the other catchy terms people give to it. But that’s it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I will say this. I am not sad that it was Marines that passed away that night. If it had to have been anyone I would gladly take Marines over private contractors, over anyone else. I want Marines on those walls because I know that they know how to make the best possible decision given the constraints in which they are forced to operate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We Marines have had a chip on our shoulder from basically the time of our birth. We have never really fit into the overall structure of the armed forces. We are neither the round peg nor the square hole. We are both. And we are neither. Our neither-ness makes us the first to have our money taken during defense drawdowns, but our both-ness makes us the first to be called on in a crisis. We pride ourselves on our ability to do more with less. To go anywhere and do anything that is asked of us. It is this adaptability, this chameleon like ability to properly react to chaos, that is the reason we guard (ceremonially these days) the White House and (not so ceremonially) embassies all around the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Training for these scenarios used to be standard faire. I have no idea whether it is anymore as I’ve been out of the game for a long time. We train for basically everything. From humanitarian intervention, to quasi conflict (like that night in Benghazi) in crowded spaces full of noncombatants, to full scale kill the enemy conflict. And last week Marines were doing all three of these. In numerous locations around the world. With grace and with honor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is this spectrum from completely mundane and non-violent (but foreign) to fully violent that General Krulak was talking about in 1999 when he wrote his seminal piece called the Strategic Corporal: Leadership in the Three Block War. I had graduated OCS but was not yet a Marine officer when he published that piece. And that piece of work is truly a seminal piece as it influenced greatly an entire generation of Marines. In it Krulak argued that the Marines needed to build a force capable of ratcheting up and down the violence as appropriate for the situation. This is incredibly dangerous stuff. It is much safer to retreat to bases and hide behind technological solutions than it is to get out of the bubble and walk the streets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But under Krulak’s tutelage the Marines adapted. And the fires of a zillion firefights and uneventful patrols have proved old Chuck was right. That young people can be trained to react appropriately and honorably under the craziest, most screwed, utterly chaotic of situations. Because, that’s what Marines, especially Marines who understand the challenges and risks inherent in the three block war, that’s what they do.  &lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to feel emotional about something that is fine. But don’t denigrate the honor of the Marines who died that evening in Benghazi by loftily screaming for more security, higher walls, more razor wire; by pretending that these Marines were some lambs to the slaughter. They may or may not have fought that night, but I have full faith and allegiance to the same that they most certainly had a good reason for whatever they did.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And I know even more than that they most certainly were not victims to be held up as a symbol in order to win votes. It was Remember the Maine that was the slogan, not Remember the Marines on the Maine.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Compromise &amp;amp; Governing: On Reading @ryanlizza&amp;#8217;s The Obama Memos</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-01-27-compromise-and-governing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-01-27-compromise-and-governing/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="hhttp://www.flickr.com/photos/barackobamadotcom/2913035652">&lt;img src="http://blog.caseykuhlman.com/assets/images/2012/2913035652_27460596bd.jpg" alt="Obama Barn by Barack Obama @ flickr" tit="Obama Barn by Barack Obama @ flickr" />&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I was in college my friend Dave and I would often fall asleep at some point during our millionth screening of Braveheart. We would often put the film on after the bars had closed and we had grabbed our drunken treat of the night and were not yet ready for bed. At the time we were training to be Marine officers and very interested in learning what it took to be a good leader. Near the beginning of the film there was a quote which I often thought about (at still think about):&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>You admire this man, this William Wallace. Uncompromising men are easy to admire. He has courage; so does a dog. But it is exactly the ability to &lt;em>compromise&lt;/em> that makes a man noble. And understand this: Edward Longshanks is the most ruthless king ever to sit on the throne of England. And none of us, and nothing of Scotland will remain, unless &lt;em>we&lt;/em> are as ruthless. Give ear to our nobles. Knowing their minds is the key to the throne.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>We would scoff at this quote. In our youth and lack of exposure to the world we felt that uncompromising was the way of the greatest leaders. That may still be true, but I have learned that it definitely is not true of the greatest rulers. Indeed, the greatest rulers are often those that are the greatest to compromise. Human nature being what it is, you will very rarely have complete agreement with a course of action. Multiply the amount of people a decision will affect and you necessarily multiply the different opinions (both rational and irrational) which will impact your decision before it is taken and laud or critique it after it is taken. This is a fundamental “problem” with ruling in a democracy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ryan Lizza has written a fantastically interesting piece for The New Yorker. He dives deeply into a trove of memos which circulated the Obama White House during the first term of that administration. He assembles a very interesting piece which does a great job of detailing the tensions that any President may face. I encourage everyone to read it, &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/zTXpzr" title="The Obama Memos">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is interesting for me, given my current diaspora state (relatively torn between Europe, America, and Africa), to compare the political processes which take place in a very new, somewhat inchoate democracy – Somaliland – to a very old, overly complex democracy – the US – while comparing both, which I view as an insider, to the relatively “clean” democratic processes that the Europeans embody. One of the difficult things in an independent executive system, where the governing functions of creating laws and putting those laws into action are separated between two branches of government, is that we tend to blame the “big man” for all of the problems. This happens in Somaliland just as often as it happens in the US. The realities of Presidential campaigns often do a disservice by blurring the lines. Much of the debate during a Presidential campaign revolves around big or small policy ideas that the President will have very little to no control over. As I was telling someone the other day, a President has an ability to stop a legislative action it doesn’t want to allow but it has little ability to make a legislative body do something that that body does not want to do. Yet these big policy ideas are a function of modern politics. Firstly they are easier to discuss than the minutae of what a President really does. Secondly, it is a method of acting somewhat uniformly in our very much decentralized system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Personally, reading the piece shows me what I was hoping to see. A President who has learned how to do what is possibly the most difficult and complex job on the planet. A President who remains willing to make compromises, but also has learned how to work the system. A President who still has standards and struggles to balance a bowing to the political winds with a deep devotion to his ideals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While Obama cannot get a large piece of greenhouse gas passed through (right now) domestically, he has floated a ton of money for research, innovation, and implementation of greenhouse reduction initiatives in other countries. While Obama faces complete stonewalling from his own legislators on jobs (right now), he has figured out how to incentivize job growth and business creation in other countries with entrepreneurial grants and collaborative agreements dominating much of the AID/DOS grants I’ve seen lately. While Obama cannot push forward comprehensive immigration reform (right now), he has put in place policies which make it much easier to get US visas (while remaining within the legislative caps mandated by various amendments to the Immigration and Nationalization Act) and illegal immigration flows are down – particularly from Mexico. These are largely international examples for a couple of reasons. First it is my area of interest so I follow it closer. Second the President has fundamentally more power over foreign policy than domestic policy. Third, Hillary – despite how divisive she may or may not be – is a brilliant bureaucrat and many of these initiatives are coming from her shop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No government is perfect, but where the President and his team have a reasonable amount of power I am genuinely pleased with what I see. There’s much to disagree with, but there is much more that I agree with. As we turn towards a full scale assault on us all with respect to choosing our next President one thing I would encourage everyone to do is to not get tricked by the red herrings of advertisements and debates and to focus on what the President can and does actually do on a daily / weekly / monthly / yearly basis. Choose wisely.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Preacher is Back. That&amp;#8217;s What I&amp;#8217;ve Been Waiting For.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-09-09-the-preacher-is-back-thats-what-ive-been-waiting-for/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-09-09-the-preacher-is-back-thats-what-ive-been-waiting-for/</guid><description>&lt;p>I just finished watching the jobs speech and my first thought was “were have you been”? The historian-poet-preacher in him which I fell in love with in the Yes We Can and Race speeches (collectively rather than individually) had found his groove tonight.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every artist struggles with finding their artistic voice, but for me, at this moment, this was balm to my soul. Someone, somewhere, does actually get it. But before I get to what I liked about the speech let me take a small detour and talk about how I think about my relationship between me and my government.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m currently staying at my brother’s, &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/kuhlman">@kuhlman&lt;/a>, house and he has a great dane. Due to our pomo lives we missed each other. He is off on a construction job overnight and I just returned from an overnight job myself. We missed each other and were not able to pass a key back and forth. When we were texting each other as to our current statuses and how we could coordinate this changeover, I asked him whether the house was locked. He responded, “Maggie’s the lock.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now Maggie is a wonderful bitch (which I mean literally). This bitch has a bark that will tear your hair off when she gets scared. I have no idea whether she has the bite to match it, and I like that I don’t know that, because her bark is scary enough. She is the perfect lock. See locks are on-off switches. But living, breathing beings are able to differentiate between when on is OK and off is OK. Sometimes the best lock is the one that can differentiate between when to bark and when to be happy because your friend is here to let you out to go take a piss.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And this is how I want my government to be. I don’t want to rely on my government unnecessarily. I understand that my successes and my failures are my own. But sometimes you want to know that if you are forced, due to the situations of living your life, to deviate from your normal patterns, that there will be a being there to have your back. You don’t want something that is impersonal and cannot differentiate between friend and foe. You want a bitch there that is both happy to see you and happy to go have a poo in the yard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That story said, there were many things that I loved about the Obama speech.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, he chastised both sides. He told some hard truths. These words were his preacher robes which I have not seen him don for a long, long time. Too long. And it was needed. Both sides of the political aisle have been being babies for a while now and the only people suffering are the middle class of America. This &lt;em>must&lt;/em> change. The only way to get shit done is to sometimes put aside the differences and realize that the betterment of the country is at stake. Since I’ve spent so much time in African countries where politics is so personality based I am especially receptive to the in-out-group mechanisms which operate in such an environment. And if you want to actually help, if you want to get something done in this world you’re going to have to figure out a compromise. Because, as the President of the United States, said “No single individual built America on their own. We built it together. .” What a great line. Sometimes we have to act as a community. Individualism is great, but no one at no time has EVER acted completely in isolation as an individual. We call those beings the last creature of their species. What is required, from time to time, is looking out for those that may not be as smart, or have the opportunities, or whatever as we fancy of ourselves. And in that vein, next week I hope to go pound some nails to help members of my family’s community who were affected by the tornadoes earlier this year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Second, it was perhaps the most patriotic speech which has been given during my lifetime. It was a call to action. It was competitive (which we Americans love). It told us that there was going to be some hard days ahead. This was the poet that I’ve been longing for. This was the inspiration that I’ve been hoping for. This was the America that I have studied and that I love. Just turn off your brain (I’ll get to the wonky stuff in a moment) and listen to the words of his speech and tell me that you are not inspired by &lt;em>something&lt;/em>, or even &lt;em>anything&lt;/em> in this speech. No matter your political affiliation this man gets that he was “hired” to execute the laws in the best interest of us all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Third, it cut through all the bullshit, stupid rhetoric which neither matters nor helps. He has learned from his own failures to properly leverage both the power of his position and the wave of people power which put him in that chair. This was a pragmatic speech to its core. What he said is exactly, *exactly, *what economists have proven matter for the economic development of your country. There are many opinions as to the best, but almost every economist will agree that what is necessary for economic development (this comes from my international development perspective) is: infrastructure, education, jobs for low-skilled individuals, and healthcare. We’ll leave aside for now the reasons why each of these exist. Similarly I’m going to take a mulligan on healthcare because I don’t have the energy to enter that debate as to why people that don’t have millions in the bank don’t *deserve *to not feel awful all the time, but if you care about that watch Sicko and shutup. But see here’s the thing. Our schools are falling apart. While we prosecute irrational wars overseas (which I’ve participated in and have some modicum of epistemic authority here), we’re not able to give the support that our teachers require to educate our children. Our infrastructure is subpar. Visit Europe and try to convince me that we are still number one. Drill, Baby, Drill.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So this is a short review, but my early take (before reading any punditry) is that it was brilliant and one of Obama’s best performances. On a personal level I’m happy for three reasons: (1) the poet I wanted is finding his voice, (2) the pragmatist we all need is finally leveraging his platform, and (3) the wonk in me is reassured that someone up there will bark when necessary and greet when necessary.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There were many great moments of this speech for me. But the one that stands out. The one that I will think of tomorrow. Is this.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>No single individual built America on their own. We built it together. We have been, and always will be, one nation, under God, indivisible, with liberty and justice for all; a nation with responsibilities to ourselves and with responsibilities to one another. Members of Congress, it is time for us to meet our responsibilities.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>What did you think of the speech?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OK, So He&amp;#8217;s Gone. What Now?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-05-02-ok-so-hes-gone-what-now/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-05-02-ok-so-hes-gone-what-now/</guid><description>&lt;p>So I woke up this morning to the news. Obama Killed Osama. In my groggy state, I couldn’t really piece together what was happening on my collated facebook and twitter streams until I saw something similar to the previous sentence. I think the first thing I cognized was a friend’s facebook post: “Osama, so 10 years ago.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I went to NYTimes.com and saw the huge headline and the gigantic picture of the President staring at me, resolute &amp;amp; determined. After reading the article, and then watching my Twitter feeds more closely than usual today (which has been a busy one and not really allowed me to dig as deep into the commentary as I would like), I think my overall thought is, “Osama, so 10 years ago.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is actually quite amazing to consider that it was almost 10 years ago that I was sitting with my Marine infantry officer friends in our boxers and t-shirts watching GWB announce to the world that our nation’s military was on its highest alert and looking around the room thinking, “Huh?” as a typhoon raged outside and we couldn’t even leave the building. That was 9-11-01. This is 02-05-11 (date formats have been shifted in accordance with my mindset).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The news, while large, seems quaint. Many nations with majority muslim populations have bigger problems today, and they now have viable outlets for those problems. Moderate muslims the world over have increasingly spoken out against extremism (exhibit A is the commercial I watch on Qatar based MBC movie channel which shows a young teenager watching extremist videos and ends with his mom watching him on one crying and then flashes something in Arabic which I assume says, “don’t be an idiot and blow yourself up”). Al Qaeda has fractured, has become cellular and largely unable to organize anything beyond a small isolated bombing for a long time now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My main question as to what now has much less to do with the muslim majority areas and much more to do with America. Our shorthand for “the enemy” is gone. So what will we do now? It is very difficult to motivate people, populations, and most importantly fighters to fight a war where they cannot “see” the reason that they are fighting. Our reason in Iraq left, but there was still a face there that was lingering, hovering over the consciousness. That face is now at the bottom of the ocean. I think we can smile that an evil human has gone, but the real point, the real concern I have, or better put, the hope that I hold to is that we Americans can now get back to showing the world that we know more than how to fight. That we know how to compete, how to build, how to innovate, how to drive progress, how to balance divergent political interests, how to develop systems which bring jobs and health and education. Let those be our exports. Instead of our current portfolio: facebook, google, and guided missiles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Concisely put by my friend: “Osama. So 10 Years Ago.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Egypt is Burning: On Arab Protests</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-01-30-egypt-burning-arab-protests/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-01-30-egypt-burning-arab-protests/</guid><description>&lt;p>[![THIS COULD HAVE BEEN STRAIGHT OUT OF A MOVIE! #jan25 #egypt via Farrah3m @ Twitpic][2]][2]
&amp;ldquo;THIS COULD HAVE BEEN STRAIGHT OUT OF A MOVIE! #jan25 #egypt&amp;rdquo; via Farrah3m @ Twitpic
Two days ago, my father asked me for my thoughts on the protests throughout the Arab world. I wanted to compose my thoughts, to let the situation develop a bit further before I said anything.  Now is the time to say something.
This is utterly fascinating to watch.  Al Jazeera is very much killing it with fantastic shots – news hasn’t captivated me in this same way since watching CNN from the Palestine Hotel in Baghdad in 1991.  On Friday I was sitting with my friends and we watched the following sequence unfold in real time: reports of police sending reinforcements into streets, video of police apcs flooding streets, video of protesters stopping one vehicle, video of  police scrambling and fighting their way out of back of vehicle protesters beating the driver, video of protesters trying and failing to tip apc over and “throw” into nile, reprieve, reports of army being called onto streets, video of apc being lit on fire, and for the next three hours they would every once in a while cut back to the same burning apc.  It was magical, riveting, unbelievable tv.
I was watching very closely when earlier (before the above sequence) a lone army apc came into the screen (was easy to tell as was painted different color, a fairly standard practice worldwide).  The people went utterly nuts.  And the army seemed to be cheering the protesters back.  It was pretty far away from the cameraman so it was difficult to see exactly, but it was super interesting.  That was before Mubarak called the army onto the streets.  The stoppage for the prayers was the other thing that fascinated me, but back to the army.  The Egyptian army is a conscript army, and it closer to the middle/lower classes than the police are, given that the police are not conscripts and are often hand chosen by the regime.
The story aside, what is my chat on this topic?  Three things strike me: (1) the interconnectedness of the pan-Arab movement may be among the causes of the downfall of the creators; (2) [Gladwell][2], you’re wrong; (3) the results of the variety of protests is going to differ, likely in proportion to GDP.
[2]: &lt;a href="http://www.newyorker.com/reporting/2010/10/04/101004fa_fact_gladwell">http://www.newyorker.com/reporting/2010/10/04/101004fa_fact_gladwell&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="pan-arab-movement">Pan-Arab Movement&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Yes, all of these are connected.  The Tunis protests, and their subsequent victories, beget the Egyptian protests, and as they say: as Egypt goes, so goes the Arab world.  But look at what I pulled just a few minutes off of Twitter:
[![][4]][4]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/entry/egypt-burning-arab-protests/scr">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/entry/egypt-burning-arab-protests/scr&lt;/a>
The protests just continue to spread: Sudan, Yemen, Syria, Algeria, Bahrain, Libya. The linkages that have been built, especially in the post-colonial world between the Arab nations, which was originally established as a bulwark against the West (among other reasons) is now making the spread of protest-ism violently, breathtakingly fast.
And yes, technology is helping to facilitate the spread.  I have seen[ twitpics of letters][4] from Tunisian protesters to Egyptian protesters with tips on how to fight the man.  Encouragement and organizing are all happening online.  Why else would Egypt completely pull the plug?
[4]: &lt;a href="http://globalguerrillas.typepad.com/globalguerrillas/2011/01/journal-example-of-open-source-tactical-innovation.html">http://globalguerrillas.typepad.com/globalguerrillas/2011/01/journal-example-of-open-source-tactical-innovation.html&lt;/a>
Third, and this is what is going to take longer to figure out.  But the end result of this wave, I suspect is going to distill rough correlative to GDP of the nations.  Tunisia and Egypt will likely see some fundamental changes.  Syria and Bahrain will likely see some changes, but not fundamental ones.  Libya, Sudan, and Yemen will likely have to wait a bit longer for fundamental changes within their countries.  I’m a Collier-ist and I am interested to see if this is going to validate his [theories ][5]that at about $3000 per capita GDP is some sort of a tipping point for democracy.  Thailand reached that and it beget massive protests, the countries listed above are there, China is approaching this threshold.  Yet, we will see.  Only after the fact will we see.
[5]: &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Wars-Guns-Votes-Democracy-Dangerous/dp/0061479640/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1296375235&amp;amp;sr=1-1-catcorr">http://www.amazon.com/Wars-Guns-Votes-Democracy-Dangerous/dp/0061479640/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1296375235&amp;amp;sr=1-1-catcorr&lt;/a>
The last thing I’ll note is that a power vacuum in Egypt is in precisely no one’s interest.
~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On Tea Partiers &amp;amp; Rule-Free Systems: Football, NASCAR &amp;amp; Regulatory Authority</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-01-26-tea-partiers-rule-free-systems-football-nascar-regulatory-authority/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-01-26-tea-partiers-rule-free-systems-football-nascar-regulatory-authority/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“An association of men who will not quarrel with one another is a thing which has never yet existed, from the greatest confederacy of nations down to a town meeting or a vestry.” ~ Thomas Jefferson&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I know I am generalizing, but since many that I know and love subscribe to many of these philosophies maybe I do have a small bit of perspective here.  Let me take a look at the Free Market system and rules.  Many have argued that rules are inherrently anti-market.  That the opposite of capitalism is rule-making by regulators.  Maybe that is right in some areas, but I would argue that it depends on the specific area in mind.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“The big-government crowd is drawn to the compulsory nature of centralized authority. They can’t imagine an undirected social order. Someone needs to be in charge—someone who knows better. Big government is audacious and conceited. By definition, government is the means by which citizens are forced to do that which they would not do voluntarily. Like pay high taxes. Or redistribute tax dollars to bail out the broken, bloated pension systems of state government employees. Or purchase, by federal mandate, a government-defined health-insurance plan that is unaffordable, unnecessary or unwanted. For the left, and for today’s Democratic Party, every solution to every perceived problem involves more government—top-down dictates from bureaucrats presumed to know better what you need. Tea partiers reject this nanny state philosophy of redistribution and control because it is bankrupting our country.” ~Dick Armey &amp;amp; Matt Kibbe @ &lt;a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748704407804575425061553154540.html">WSJ&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Reject Cap &amp;amp; Trade - Stop costly new regulations that would increase unemployment, raise consumer prices, and weaken the nation’s global competitiveness with virtually no impact on global temperatures.” ~ Tea Party Manifesto as defined by the Tea Party Patriots available &lt;a href="http://www.contractfromamerica.com/Idea.aspx">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Despite universal acknowledgement that Americans enjoy a free, open, and vibrant Internet, the FCC is relentlessly pursuing a massive regulatory regime that would stifle broadband expansion, create congestion, slow Internet speeds, jeopardize job retention and growth, and lead to higher prices for consumers.” ~ Virginia Tea Party Patriot Federation letter to the FCC re: Net Neutrality, excerpted &lt;a href="http://www.crunchgear.com/2010/08/13/the-tea-party-hates-net-neutrality-because-its-an-affront-to-free-speech-umm/">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Tea party members believe in this invisible hand spoken of by Adam Smith. Society is better off because of the free market. A person invents something so that they can make money, but in that self interest benefits society as a whole. Did the government invent the car, the computer, or airplane? Nope, self interested individuals invented these things. Did these inventions enrich society as a whole? Yes. Think about the amount of jobs created by the computer industry alone, everything these days (seemingly) has computer technology in it. Think about the amount of jobs created by the auto industry. When government steps into the free market it creates advantages for those it supports and disadvantages for those who is doesn’t support. The law of supply and demand has been tampered with, and the market is artificially manipulated. Sometimes these manipulations have a positive impact, only to come crashing back down. Most of the time they have a negative impact on the market.” ~ Available &lt;a href="http://hubpages.com/hub/what-the-tea-party-stands-for-free-markets">here&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Every generation needs a new revolution.” Thomas Jefferson&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I actually really like what the Tea Partiers have been able to accomplish, although I am about as far away from them policy-wise as possible, I like the fact that they are shaking things up for the entrenched political interests on both sides of the aisle.  That said, I think they are dead wrong when it comes to their hatred and shunning of rules, so I’d like to take a little moment here and explain things from my side.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Think about sports.  Particularly, think about football.  A lot of rules were made in football between the mid-80′s to mid-90′s which had to do with protecting the quarterback.  Why is this person special?  Likely it was less because of his primacy on the playing field, and more likely because of his primacy in the board room.  Fine, but when those rules were adopted I don’t remember (although maybe it happened) any pundits arguing for the demise of football as we know it.  They were saying, no we need some fair competition, and if I spend Y of my cap money on a quarterback, I should have the opportunity to let that investment play out.  There was still plenty of competition, not the least of which was during the off season for prime players.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then let’s look at the salary cap &amp;amp; profit sharing mechanism that the owners have set up.  If this was tried in Washington it would have about a 0% chance of surviving a first draft and whoever the unlucky sap was that had the job of writing a first draft would be instantly shunned as a communist.  But when it comes to our beloved sport we say how great it is that small market teams like Pittsburgh still have the same chance of surviving as big market teams like New York.  Indeed big markets haven’t dominated football in ages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Compare this to baseball.  That is the sport, for those of you who may remember, with the sticks and the balls and the clay in a diamond with a bunch of people basically standing around all the time.  There were two major turnoffs for many I know from my generation about baseball (besides it’s boring which I would argue against).  (1) “In baseball you can just go out and buy your team.  There is no thrill in just zero to winning.” It wasn’t satisfying when the Marlins bought a team and won the World Series in the late nineties.  Not at all satisfying.  (2) “They absolutely turned a blind eye to the steroid situation.”  Well, there you have it folks, rules (football) v. non-rules (baseball).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let us talk NASCAR.  I grew up watching Dale Earnhartt, Bill Elliot, and those guys.  I was a number 3 guy.  I went to the Dayton 500 and remember the after effects of a fantastic Ricky Rudd accident that is still likely shown on best 100 crashes of all time on late night Spike TV.  What do people like about NASCAR?  What I liked about it is that the competition is based on pure skill.  It is pure skill in driving, and it is pure skill in engineering.  But engineering in the fine-tune sense.  The driver with the fastest car (interpret: has built the most efficient system) who is the best driver on that day (interpret: has great adaptability) most of the time wins.  It is fast and loud and visciously entertaining to go to the races.  But really races boil down to (besides keeping your hipster appeal by “making fun of the white trash people.”) a human struggle to best their machine and their elements.  But if you want to talk about systems with rules, the NASCAR rule book is lots of pages long.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So rules, in and of themselves do not serve to stifle competition.  They often serve, instead, to shift power away from entrenched interests (NY Yankees) towards more of a meritocratic environment.   I’m all for rules if they allow two things: (1) lower barriers to entry (and no, it doesn’t matter to me if that comes at the cost of entrenched interests or people/entities with bigger bankrolls than I) and (2) promotes a meritocratic environment.  Those are the essential parts of the American dream which I hold onto.  I do not begrudge anyone their own perspectives and values that they hold on to, but those are the ones I hold as truisms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is also why I &lt;a href="http://watershedlegal.com/about">work with small businesses here in Somaliland&lt;/a>.  If you want to know the effects of zero rule making look here.  When people want to see how a society (which isn’t much different than an American one – a coming post) operates under anarchical situations pick up a book and see what is happening (beyond the terrorism) in the three different major areas of Somalia – each with a progressively more mature rule-making capability.  And then compare those with a more advanced rule making capability of neighboring Ethiopia.  You can draw a distinct and direct correlation between stability, progress, and rule-making authority.  The most anarchical is the least developed.  The least anarchical is the most developed.  And in those sentences I’m conflating anarchy as an antonym of exercised rule-making authority of a government.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Leaked Wikis, #Cablegate, and Little Else</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-12-02-leaked-wikis-cablegate/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-12-02-leaked-wikis-cablegate/</guid><description>&lt;p>There has been tons of interesting commentary and analysis surrounding cablegate.  I have been interested and have read quite a few of the original cables, especially the ones about Somalia as well as much of the journalistic coverage of the story and the analysis (punditry) side of the story.  I do not think I can add much to the really interesting and relevant commentary, from the punditry side, found in the below articles so I’ll just link to them. (list in semi-chronological order)&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Drezner: &lt;a href="http://drezner.foreignpolicy.com/posts/2010/11/29/the_utopianism_of_julian_assange">There are no Big Lies in the latest Wikileaks data dump&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rothkopf: &lt;a href="http://rothkopf.foreignpolicy.com/posts/2010/11/29/wikileaks_how_the_world_is_really_run">WikiLeaks: How the world is really run&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Spiro: &lt;a href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/opiniojurisfeed/~3/HXdMhbrik4k/">Wikileaks: It’s Tough Being a State (Some Are Taking Pity)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Walt: &lt;a href="http://walt.foreignpolicy.com/posts/2010/11/30/no_secrets">What if Wikileaks Became the Norm?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Thorpe: &lt;a href="http://kmonadollaraday.wordpress.com/2010/11/30/working-and-living-out-loud/">Working and living out loud&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drezner: &lt;a href="http://drezner.foreignpolicy.com/posts/2010/12/01/robert_gates_gets_the_last_word_on_wikileaks">Robert Gates gets the last word on WikiLeaks&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rothlopf: &lt;a href="http://rothkopf.foreignpolicy.com/posts/2010/12/01/wikileaks_winners_and_losers_early_edition">WikiLeaks winners and losers: Early edition&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>And to top it off, some legal analysis: &lt;a href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/opiniojurisfeed/~3/GGwM2RM8dN8/">Steve Vladeck on WikiLeaks&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>As to the more journalistic, rather than pundit coverage of the story, the first article I read in that sector is still my favorite.  I was struck by this quote in the second paragraph of &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/11/29/world/29cables.html?_r=2?_r=1&amp;amp;pagewanted=all">this NYT article&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The material was originally obtained by &lt;a href="http://topics.nytimes.com/top/reference/timestopics/organizations/w/wikileaks/index.html?inline=nyt-org" title="More articles about WikiLeaks.">WikiLeaks&lt;/a>, an organization devoted to revealing secret documents. WikiLeaks posted 220 cables, some redacted to protect diplomatic sources, in the first installment of the archive on its Web site on Sunday.”  It seems quite arrogant to me that WikiLeaks would redact the documents (if, indeed, they were the ones redacting), surely this must be an all-or-nothing organization.  It is not capable nor positioned to make the determination about sourcing which redacting would require.  I hope that the redactions were done within the cables themselves rather than by WikiLeaks.  The redactions were done by the NYTimes, which seems to me to be quite responsible journalism.  ”The Times, after consultations with the State Department, has withheld from articles and removed from documents it is posting online the names of some people who spoke privately to diplomats and might be at risk if they were publicly identified. The Times is also withholding some passages or entire cables whose disclosure could compromise American intelligence efforts.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The main thing I was struck upon reading the entirety of this article is that this entire deal is quite anticlimatic.  Most everything I’ve seen so far in the entirety of the coverage we knew more or less was happening.  Sure it lends some authority that official diplomatic cables contained the information and the clarity and precision of some of the information is quite striking, but all in all it seems quite benign for the most part.  Which leads me to question the utility of the leak.  I completely understand the vehemence of the Obama administration’s response, but I don’t really understand what all the hullabaloo is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The most interesting thing about all this is that everyone from the USG to the lowest individual here with me in Somaliland, we are learning together how to communicate in a web dominated world.  The technology keeps moving the ball before the norms and legalities of a situation have caught up with it and then technology moves the ball again, and again, and again.  Most people still fail to understand that their companies are likely archiving the emails from their work computers, and sometimes even their personal email when it is accessed from a work computer because the company is forced to under watch for due diligence reasons.  Much less to many people understand the privacy implications of their Facebook account.  I don’t even need to bring up the rest of the methods and tools for modern communication.  While the private / public barriers are still relatively strong, the grey area is widening and classifying itself.  In other words much of where we currently are is in a grey area but where exactly we are in that middle part of the spectrum and what the rules and norms are within that are difficult to decipher.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I shared a few days ago the following comment on Buzz, and my brother, &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/kuhlman">@kuhlman&lt;/a>, had a nice response to which I cannot add much.  I don’t agree entirely with his comment, but I’d like to give him the last word.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>While I appreciate the suggestion that “compartmentalization will be back in vogue real soon”, this and Robert Gate’s comments (also excerpted by Drezner in a later post) which suggest the inevitable indispensability of America bespeak a posture of American arrogance. Drezner asks rhetorically if he’s missing something, but doesn’t really believe that there is anything more (the so-called Big Lie). Why is it that shallowness must be the accompaniment to transparency? I agree that there is a great difference between the things we say in public and the things we say in private, but if we are to substantively engage our fellow global cohabitants in a meaningful discourse we must accept a conversation which allows for both deep, nuanced exchanges and the possibility that America is not indispensable.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Trail of the Octopus</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-16-trail-of-the-octopus/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-16-trail-of-the-octopus/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last night we were drinking some wine.  I say this because my consumption of alcohol has decreased drastically over the past few years.  Living in a dry country helps!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our new roommate was telling us this story about Lockerbee.  Steve, the new roommate, is a terribly interesting man to talk to.  In fact, it would be daunting talking to him if he wasn't such a genuine and normal human.  We see eye to eye on many of the problems around us and he is doing something quite remarkable.  He came here to S'land a few years ago and is now starting a dive business!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The synopsis of the story is that the US DIA and DEA were involved in this smuggling chain of drugs from Afghanistan through Iran and Syria and eventually to Europe.  Most of the drugs at that time were routed through Cyprus.  According to the story, the US wasn't actually smuggling things, but in return for CIA hostages in Lebanon being looked after by the criminal syndicates the syndicates were allowed to bring a certain amount of drugs into Europe.  The rest were confiscated by the DEA and the smugglers were paid for the drugs taken by the DEA.  Good usage of your tax dollars? &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyway after the Vicente shot down the Iranian airliner the Iranians got noticeably and reasonably upset and told Syria who told Hezbollah to smuggle a bomb onto the Pan-Am flight in retaliation.  The CIA somehow knew about this, as all their people who were leaving Frankfurt to come home for Christmas that year had previously been booked on the flight but then changed the day before to a TWA flight.  After the plane came down the Scottish policemen who were on scene were told to leave and go beyond some line while MI6 and the CIA took all the documents and papers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At this point in the story it sounded just like a good spy novel, but then the guy who was DIA in Cypress and knew about the deal blew the whistle and was charged with treason.  Subsequently he fled to Sweden and got asylum.  The book he wrote was banned in the UK and the US.  No matter whether it is true, false or some combination, I'm going to read it.  Thanks to the internet, it can be found &lt;a href="http://www.american-buddha.com/trail.ch.1.htm">here&lt;/a> if you are interested.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Teddy Goes to Big Think</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-08-teddy-goes-to-big-think/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-08-teddy-goes-to-big-think/</guid><description>&lt;p>Am just now getting around to watching Big Think's Editorial Top Ten of the year as I wait until 3 this morning when the SuperBowl will begin.  The premise of &lt;a href="http://http://bigthink.com/">Big Think &lt;/a>is amazing to me: grab a bunch of influential people, ask them a penetrating question and then let them speak for five minutes or more.  It is interesting when you sit and listen to people without the flashing signals and bottom scroll bars and overly enthusiastic reporters that so often are too busy to understand what the hell they are talking about.  The people I respec tthe most, are those that can take a step back from what is happening and try to see the bigger picture.  This site is trying to achieve something akin to that.   &lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is how  BT introduces the video:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Ted Kennedy was a model American politician: he rose from a famous&lt;br>
family, had significant personal wealth and connections, endured&lt;br>
scandals, and was a shrewd political operator. But what set Kennedy&lt;br>
apart from his peers was the authentic and uncompromising moral drive&lt;br>
that he brought to the Senate. He understood and used his advantages to&lt;br>
successfully push America in a better direction. In one of his last&lt;br>
interviews, Kennedy reflected with Big Think on his career, his family,&lt;br>
and his faith.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I must admit that I do not have terribly strong opinions either way on Teddy.  I heartily endorse, in principle, those values and goals which he fought for over all of the years.  However his personal scandals preclude me from full-scale fandom.  Yet, I really appreciate what he says in this video about citizen participation.  It is the key to forward progress.  And even though I think that the Tea Partiers are quite off key policy wise, I do endorse their collective action and their ability to leverage that to achieve their goals.  I also appreciate what BT says in their introduction, that Teddy used whatever influence and advantages that he was given and that he produced to try his best to work for those around them.  And he did keep doing that until the end of his life.  And so, I big you a late adieu lion of the senate.  May you rest in peace.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-11-05-23/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-11-05-23/</guid><description>&lt;p>Thank You America.
From those of us who no longer live at home.  Thank you for allowing us to proudly hold our heads high in foreign lands again.  Thank you for reminding the entire world why they admire us.  Thank you for making the world remember why we are the great shining beacon of hope in a foul, foul world.  Thank you for the sheer emotion that has flowed freely from your voices, and your faces, and your hearts.  We have felt it from here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From those of us that believe strongly in the power of collective voices exercised through the democratic process.  Thank you for reminding yourselves of the power of people.  Thank you for being patient.  Thank you for being respectful, at least at the end.  Thank you for being gracious both in success and in defeat.  Thank you for uniting in a way that Oprah and Jessie Jackson were&lt;br>
simple spectators to history just like Jonathon Lewis and Ahmed&lt;br>
Ismail.  Thank you for reminding everyone who has fought for their right to vote of the value of that fight.  We are stronger for the process, not necessarily for the winner.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And from me personally.  Thank you for engaging.  Thank you for debating, sometimes&lt;br>
collaboratively and sometimes combatitively.  Thank you for hoping.  Thank you for fearing.  Thank you for dreaming.  Thank you for dreading.  Thank you for talking. &lt;br>
Thank you for sharing.  Thank you for txting, and emailing, and facebooking, and&lt;br>
IMing, and calling, and mySpacing, and walking, and knocking.  Thank you&lt;br>
for engaging.  Thank you for not being complacent this time. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Take this moment America. 
Revel in the historionics; revel in the hysterionics; revel in your personal victory; revel in your personal defeat.  Because tomorrow we get to work.  All of us must get to work. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Progress only occurs collectively.  For those supporting the majority,&lt;br>
you must ensure accountability for the policies or modes of interaction&lt;br>
you value.  For those supporting the opposition, you must ensure&lt;br>
accountability for the policies or modes of interaction you value. &lt;br>
Conversations cannot become one sided any more.  No party or creed or ideology&lt;br>
maintains a monopoly on the path to our more perfect union.  Collectively, all voices,&lt;br>
are what can continue to perfect our union.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What you have believed, what you have discussed, what you have debated, do not lose these things.  Your voice works every day of every year.  Not only on a November Tuesday every other year.  Continue to fight, continue to work, continue to engage, continue to think.  Democracies are driven by the breadth &amp;amp; depth of the voices contained within.  Do not lose yours.  It has inherent value.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>![][1][![Photo Damon WinterThe New York Times][3]][3]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![Photo Damon WinterThe New York Times (2)][4]][4]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![Photo Doug Mills The New York Times][5]][5]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![Photo Spencer Platt Getty Images][6]][6]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Photos courtesy of [here][6].
~ # ~&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[1]: /Users/Casey/Desktop/Photo Damon WinterThe New York Times.JPG
[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e2010535d44eb5970b-pi">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e2010535d44eb5970b-pi&lt;/a>
[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e2010535da70ed970c-pi">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e2010535da70ed970c-pi&lt;/a>
[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e2010535da713a970c-pi">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e2010535da713a970c-pi&lt;/a>
[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e2010535d44f83970b-pi">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e2010535d44f83970b-pi&lt;/a>
[6]: &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/slideshow/2008/11/05/us/politics/11052008_Accept_13.html">http://www.nytimes.com/slideshow/2008/11/05/us/politics/11052008_Accept_13.html&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-11-05-24/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-11-05-24/</guid><description>&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Things are moving so fast in race relations a Negro could be president&lt;br>
in 40 years. There's no question about it. In the next 40 years, a&lt;br>
Negro can achieve the same position that my brother has. . . . But we&lt;br>
have tried to make progress and we are making progress. . . . We are&lt;br>
not going to accept the status quo.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ Bobby Kennedy, Editorial in the Washington Post, May, 27, 1968&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GOTV</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-11-04-gotv/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-11-04-gotv/</guid><description>&lt;p>When I was in elementary school both of my parents worked and my younger brother and I used to ride our bikes to school.  It being Florida, I promise not to turn this into a in the snow, uphill both-ways story.  I remember looking at the signs over the years as the cycle eventually became faster and shorter.  Each November they would be there, demanding/requesting/mandating/asking for my vote for School Board or County Commissioner or Water Commissioner.  Other than being annoyed that they would often clip my legs, I wasn't bothered that they were there.  I liked that fact that adults would be milling about the school because it usually meant that we had longer recesses. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>And that was really similar to how I felt about politics for a long time.  For much of the time where I would have a say in who became Water Commissioner I spent more time thinking than acting.  I found it to be extraordinarily difficult and an extremely long journey to finally settle on what I felt my political philosophy truly was.  Humans being social creatures, cultural conditioning is a difficult thing to avoid and determining what I truly felt in a vacuum was difficult. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>This was the first election that I entered where I felt a strong notion of myself.  Views on foreign policy, economic policy, constitutionalism, and the role of government now could really be discussed.  I felt empowered that I had finally be able to solidify some modicum of a baseline worldview, while being open for that to change and flex over time and experience.  I had finally reached a point in my development where I was able to understand possible, probably and unlikely consequences of specific policy choices, and where I was able to foresee balances and tensions in ideas and what that would mean to different demographics and spectra of societies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I did not vote in the primary.  Still voting in Florida, and being a registered Democrat, it mattered not what I did and so I did not waste my time.  But I had decided, were my voice asked for, who I would have voted for.  I made this decision based upon pure policy alignment.  I was not interested in delivery, or persona, or groundgame.  I was interested in reading.  I screamed at my television more times than my roommate could probably stand for candidates to wonk out, more, more, more.  Like a kid with a new toy, I wanted to hear more of their thinking so that I could dive deeper into the rabbit hole. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>My turn came in the general election.  And it was not easy.  I had prearranged for my absentee ballot to be sent to my father's house.  Surprisingly, I made a last minute trip to Europe in order to get a visa so that I can marry in the UK next year.  After coordinating plane flights, I asked that my ballot be sent to my girlfriend's place in Holland. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was away from the house when the first delivery attempt was made.  On the package slip it said that there was some money due and that the package was 8 kg.  It seemed odd at first, until I thought that my parents had likely stuck in my Xmas presents. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was also away from the house when the second delivery attempt was made.  I was up in Amsterdam getting said visa.  By now I had developed bronchitis and a sinus infection.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was at home when the third delivery attempt was made.  This was the day before I was to leave to return to H-town.  But I never heard the door bell.  Finally I went downstairs and saw the damn delivery slip.  After some investigation I realized that the door bell in our house didn't work.  Which is why my girlfriend a couple of days earlier when I was in bed had to rise me on the phone. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I called the number I was stunned.  I had to go across the country.  Literally to get the damn package.  So they said it would be ready for me to pick up at a given time.  So I hopped on for a 45 minute train ride (across the country in Holland is that far), followed by a 20 minute metro ride, a 10 minute tram ride, and a 2 mile walk in the now dark, freezing, coughing, sinuses clogged, abandoned, have-to-piss Rotterdam dockyard.  Finally I was about to give up.  And instead I found a bush.  After being able to think again I walked a little further and saw the stupid brown sign.  After another 45 minutes of hassling with Dutch people, and 50 euros, I had my package so I began the reverse trudge of 2 miles, followed by a 10 minute wait at a tram station which wasn't running because of an accident, followed by another 2 mile walk, followed by a 20 minute metro ride, and a 45 minute train ride back home.  The next morning before I left I filled out the ballot and dropped it off at the American Embassy on my way to Amsterdam.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was a challenge to vote.  But it wasn't nearly the challenges that others in history have had.  I have fought for, literally, the right to vote.  This was small potatoes.  And here's the kicker.  I would have done it had he been a muslim.  I would have done it had he been William Ayers best friend.  I would have done it had his emblem been a red background with yellow stars.  I would have done it because I believe that he is a transformative figure in two particular related areas.  His ability to discuss complexities and his ability to create an environment of rationed discussion are what I admire most about him.  Sure there is a policy alignment.  Sure there is the style, and look, the voice, the rhetoric.  Sure there is the belief, the hope, the liberal utopian twinge in my heart.  But none of those made my cough my way to the docks.  It was the fact that I value an actual discussion about what matters rather than some idiotic discussion of a washed up terorrist that no one in my generation remembers or cares about.  It was the fact that I value someone who is willing to lay out the tensions and why a specific avenue was chosen rather than some idiotic notion of dissent = unpatriotic.  This is what pushed me over.  This is what I've valued.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is why I voted for Barack Obama.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cook for Me Donna!</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-10-08-cook-for-me-donna/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-10-08-cook-for-me-donna/</guid><description>&lt;p>I will bypass comment regarding last night’s debate.  It is almost painful to watch the death of the Robertson/Nixon Conservative coalition happen before our eyes.  If it hadn’t have turned so ugly at the end (like new deal liberalism died a violent death with LBJ), it would have been actually painful. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instead, I offer for your consumption a slightly different perspective.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/D-__IdzH1b8&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">1&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Is This the Day the World Changes?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-09-30-is-this-the-day-the-world-changes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-09-30-is-this-the-day-the-world-changes/</guid><description>&lt;p>Maybe that is a bit provocative.  Maybe it is ipso facto.  I don't know.  And we'll have to see.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I remember being maybe 5 or 6 and either watching this show, or at least the trailer for a show about life after the Soviets invaded America and took over.  It was the type of propoganda that I have to suspect most of those who spent more time in the Cold War than I were constantly subjected to.  Over the years I have read or heard various references either to this show specifically or to the genre generally.  Mostly these have been referenced by pop culture historians and the like.  It all seemed a bit far-fetched to me.  I remember thinking at the time of seeing the show or trailer, how could such a thing actually happen.  The mechanisms for how it happened just did not compute.  After the thought, though, I constructed for days a novel in my head about a young boy who frustrates the Soveit's attempts to actually get a foothold in Orlando.  Essentially I was the young Che in my mind.  I largely constructed this dream world while in a tree behind my Aunt's house who I went to every afternoon following school.  It may seem odd that the failure of the bailout to pass brings up such a memory for me, but trust me it's not as random as it seems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It has been argued to me that there is enough liquid capital in the US economy to absorb the losses from the failed banks that the bailout was designed to absorb.  Although I have no hard evidence to backup my thinking, I have not been so sure.  It seems to me that the only viable financial institutions will be hoarding cash like a suburban mother buying cans for her bomb shelter during the Cuban Missile Crisis.  OK, I accept that Citi today finalized the deal for Wachovia, but perhaps they needed Wachovia's deposits to bolster their cash and were willing to absorb the liabilities on Wachovia's accounts, which when compared to Citi's must be miniscule.  So it seems to me that it was a short term tactic design to enhance their available cash.  Many of the bundled mortgages and other default credit swap items do not come ready packaged with a large amount of cash, however.  So I am not so sure that there will be an entity within the US economy capable of purchasing those at anything approaching market value. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>In many cases the financial industry would likely reach across the Atlantic.  But no one in Europe is willing to help.  First, they've all been burned by this nearly as bad as we have.  Secondly, they've got their own massive problems now with the Brit's having to broker numerous deals to bolster their banks (for the why, see 1).  Could we eat our pride and reach across the Pacific?  Maybe, Japan has already bought one of the failing banks (or a major piece I cannot remember and am too lazy to find a link). &lt;/p>
&lt;p>We will have to see what happens.  In my mind China's central bankers will wake up tomorrow and it will be Chinese Christmas for them.  They are likely the only ones that have enough liquid capital to do anything about this.  I have a distinct feeling that American's who didn't want the American government to own their homes may have a distinctly different feeling when they wake up and realize that the only people able to buy our mortgages are the Chinese sovereign wealth fund or one of the few tightly controlled Chinese banks. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>The real game changer, and why I am wondering whether in fifty years historians will pinpoint this day, is that this demonstrates once and for all the end of the dreams, hopes, fears of any continuation of American hegemony within the international community.  Military prowess?  Lost about the summer of 2005.  Moral authority?  Lost about the same time.  Ability to communicate?  Lost about January 2001.  Economic superiority?  Will it be lost?  I don't know.  But suspect that yes, yes it will.  American greed has driven the world's economy since about the mid-90s.  But what happens when American greed turns into American begging?  Don't know.  I will admit that this reads a bit doomsdayish, but I am not thinking that it will play any other way.  They will all blame us for their inevitable economic slow downs, but they will laugh at ours as it will likely be worse than theirs.  After those corrections the only ones left standing will likely be the Asians who had enough foresight and financial education to save relentlessly and not overextend their lines of credit and are now laughing at the stupid Americans that bought their goods (we and) they couldn't afford for so long.  But now they can afford their own goods.  And soon, we will not be able to.  So that is one observation. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another is reading the Roll Call analysis from the House vote is pretty amazing.  Sure Pelosi gave her speech.  Whatever.  Sure D 60-40 Y; R 33-67 Y.  That isn't what I think is interesting.  The statistic that is more interesting is this one (when combined with the last).  Of those House seats where the incumbent is in a tight race, only 21% voted Y.  Now combine that with the first and you have an imperfect estimate that more Republicans are in tight races than Democrats.  In other words the GOP is in more of a precarious position than I actually thought. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is some fundamental disconnect here that I admittedly do not understand.  As of earlier today the polls showed that only 11% of the public wanted the government to do nothing.  These ultimate free marketeers would reflect my general perception of how much of a percentage those types of people likely occupy in the American polity.  So that number made sense to me.  But what doesn't make sense is how that 11% was able to get what it wanted.  That is not to say the Bill is dead, but it is certainly in a coma on life support as it wasn't a narrow no.  It was a bipartisan, resounding No.  OK, fine.  But if this whole thing was negotiated by the leadership of both parties, what were the whips doing all weekend?  And I have no idea what the way forward is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I skimmed about half of the Bill during my lunch break today.  It seemed, well, not great, but not awful.  Obviously, the most vital part of the Bill is the power for Treasury to pay the principle and interest on the bank's Treasury deposits, which allows the banks to right off those bills for the time being and use their cash on hand for operating expenses.  This is a backhanded way for the Treasury to sink a ton of cash into the system without incurring inflationary pressures that seignurage normally requires.  That was the core of the Bill as far as getting the Banks to resume lending to one another, which is what is needed as far as corporations are concerned.  The other core of the Bill was the purchasing of the assets of institutions nearing failure or already failed.  This is where the government would own your home.  In my mind there were seemingly gigantic problems with that section.  Especially with the valuation as the Treasury was requried to purchase assets, but the valuation of the assets was not established by any sort of mechanism other than what the Treasury was thinking they were worth.  I thought how in hell does Treasury know what they are worth, especially the bundled assets.  The answer is that they do not and really have little ability to find out other than what the seller is asking.  This creates a seller's market.  Perhaps that was the intention.  Give the financial institutions a bit of a windfall, which creates incentives for iBankers not to take themselves and everything they own out of the system and move to their land in Montana to open up a free-range cattle ranch.  Perhaps it was not the intention and one of the re&lt;br>
asons the bill failed.  However, I see no other way to valuate the assets and am not sure what Congress and Paulson could have done. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>My main nervousness with the Bill was that it gave Treasury an insane amount of discretionary space.  Again, I see no other options so Congress was likely caught in a Catch-22 on that one.  The executive already has a massive amount of discretionary authority when it comes to economic policy in this country.  The Bill as drafted would have given the executive even more.  Although this is nice for Bushites who love the unitary executive theory, those of us who have a different philosophical conception of separation of powers may be concerned.  Certainly I was.  And still am.  As I think more and more about it, largely that concern is academic.  One major windfall for me is that the dollar's value is screaming through the roof as everyone clammers for cash-based assets.  This means the place Highlands and I want to buy in Edinburgh is getting cheaper by the Bush screwup.  Thanks buddy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One last thought and then am off to bed.  How will this play on Thursday night?  Am interested to see.  Likely Palin will play the &amp;ldquo;it's people like you in Washington that don't care about the American public&amp;rdquo; card.  He won't, but I wish Biden would play the &amp;ldquo;it's people like the idiots from your small town you love so much that got us into this mess by, like you, not understand a single damn thing about economics or finances&amp;rdquo; card. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Still hoping for if anything is passed we get some nice earmarks for mandatory financial literacy at the high school level…..&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Update: McCain's campaign just called to inform me that earmarks are the anti-Christ and I should not reference them anywhere.  How did they know that I typed that as I haven't posted this yet? &lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Debate Reaction</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-09-27-debate-reaction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-09-27-debate-reaction/</guid><description>&lt;p>Some initial thoughts.  It is 6:30 in the morning here and I've now been up all night, so maybe this will not be as eloquent or complete as I'd like.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>McCain did well on FP, as was to be expected.  His best answer was on Georgia when he said that this was largely about energy and (didn't say but meant) that this is important to Putin in order to entrench himself.  He shine when talking about Ukraine and the need to stabilize it while hoping to keep it as an ally to counterbalance growing Russian strength.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Obama did well on FP, probably better than expectations.  His best answer was on Iran when he spoke about how the invasion of Iraq took away the regional counterbalance and thus strengthened their position in the short term and medium term vis a vis the region. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>On Iran, they are both going the same way, just from different angles.  They want and need a regional counterbalance to Iranian influence.  Obama says we never should have gone into Iraq, McCain says we needed the surge.  They are both right about one and about the other, but their arguments miss each other because they are taking into account different temporal timeframes which require different consideration.  Obviously both know that, but these are their stump positions. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>The economy half was pure stump for both.  No surprises big surprises there.  Except McCain considering a suspension of spending, which if you noticed the second time he hedged from defense, VA and entitlements to defense, VA and critical (or vital, not sure) areas.  I'm not sure how he would classify vital areas any more than how Obama plans to quantify combat troops in his 16 month pledge.  But am not bothered, it is political and not substantive.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Random other observations.  I have CNN here and they had the red blue green real time reaction.  I never saw green reaction for McCain go about the second line.  And I rarely saw the red go above that line.  A couple of times when he tugged at heart-strings it got close to being above for the red.  The green and the blue were largely tracking each other through most of the debate.  There were divergences when Obama would attack Bush.  But for the most part they were flowing together.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think that Republicans will identify the number of times Obama pointed to areas of agreeance as a weakness or naivete area of Obama.  I enjoyed them.  Perhaps it is a difference of style.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I thought that McCain's patronizing of Obama was a bit overboard.  Fine one or two times say you don't get it, but nearly every answer that he gave was that way.  Not sure how it will play with voters, but the green line in the hall seemed to be turned off almost every time he said it. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was also struck by the shear about of mischaracterizations that McCain made of Obama's record.  I did not hear or do not remember but once or twice McCain have to parse Obama's words to clarify the record and recover from an attack.  I remember many many more times where that was the case. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was struck by McCain's answer on 9/11.  It was an open-ended question.  I heard him in the summer of 2006 give an excellent answer to a similar question where he talked about the root causes of terrorism and how those need to be addressed.  He spoke of poverty in Ramallah as well as how the Saudi system of government needs to be addressed with strength by the President, etc.  Views that are espoused by most main stream foreign policy realists.  Tonight's answer, and what I've heard him say on the trail is very different.  Much more neo-con.  I am not sure if he has gotten handled, there is some political coalition building going on or whether now that he is running for President he can assert some latent self that he could not as a Senator.  Whatever the case, he has seemingly drastically changed from what I perceived to be standard realist notions about the world to quite aggressive neo-con notions.  To include the League of Democracies.  It is absolutely idiotic, and every european I've talked to agrees.  So not sure who is going to join his League.  We already have enough international institutions.  We need to be clarifying and streamlining what they do rather that building more.  Here is a question.  How much of McCain's spending cuts will he need in order to facilitate the budget of the League of Democracies which will sit along side the G-8 and SC that currently fill the role he is looking to replace?  Will he keep funding the budgets of the secretariats of those two IOs and add a third?  It is cognitive dissonance to me.  But I have happily drunk the kool-aid so maybe I'm not the most objective observer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Obama's answers seemed to show him as what everyone perceives him to be an internationalist realist.  He did, and has all along, stressed non-proliferation.  And he is right that it is a major threat.  He did well not to back down on missile defense, but I wished he would have tied it in a bit better to his answer on the Russia question rather than on the 9/11 question.  I agree with him about small-scale WMDs being the major threat to homeland security.  I think that he was distancing himself from WMDs as a word and focusing on nuclear weapons as a political maneuver. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most rich moment of the debate was when McCain tried to tie Obama to Bush.  How much of a hot potato has he become?  Obama tried throughout to tie McCain to Bush.  McCain tried throughout to distance himself from Bush.  It was hilarious. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>I saw Biden give Obama campaign spin after the debate.  He did his thing.  Preceding him was a senior staffer from the McCain camp.  McCain: unleash the pit bull.  I want to see what she's got.  Looking forward to next Thursday.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So we'll have to see how it plays politically.  Neither hit it out of the park.  Neither made any big gaffes.  Largely I was bored as much of it was stump and only towards about Russia did they actually get off the stump and talk any substance. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now to my bed.&lt;br>
~ # ~&lt;/p>
&lt;p>UPDATE: They are both wrong.  The surge would technically be classified as neither a strategy nor a tactic.  It was an operational response designed to achieve a strategic objective.  So it was an operation. &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wow.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-09-25-wow/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-09-25-wow/</guid><description>&lt;p>There is simply no other word that I can conjure. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>I would like to remind everyone that McCain is 73 and has had two, three or four incidents with cancer.  McCain has lived a tough life.  The Presidency routinely causes men not with white hair to go white as an indication of the stresses that are placed on one's body.  I know momma McCain is 92 or whatever, but she wasn't a Prisoner of War, didn't routinely have large amounts of G-force placed on her body over a significant portion of her adult life and didn't spend the rest of her adult life fighting, scrapping, and arguing with everyone and their brother on the hill. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>After knowing that.  Please watch this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/nokTjEdaUGg&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">1&lt;/a>
~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Georgia v. Russia</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-08-18-georgia-v-russia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-08-18-georgia-v-russia/</guid><description>&lt;p>Because I am intellectually inferior and do not have so much time, I have few unique thoughts. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is some great analysis on the web about the short conflict. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2008/08/17/world/europe/17military.html?ex=1376712000&amp;amp;en=c604c9bdaa4063fd&amp;amp;ei=5124&amp;amp;partner=permalink&amp;amp;exprod=permalink">NYT &lt;/a>has a great article on the tactics used by the Russians.  I, for one, am not scared by the Russian's ability to employ combined arms in the same manner that we are.  They simply do not have the culture that relies on decentralization necessary to affect true combine arms warfare in the way that we employ CA. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://blog.foreignpolicy.com/node/9554">FP Passport&lt;/a> has an interesting article about the incitement of the conflict.  I think that it is fairly evenhanded account and I largely agree with the analysis, from what I know of things…which is limited!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The most militarily and culturally interesting point about the conflict is the &lt;a href="http://www.ethanzuckerman.com/blog/2008/08/16/misunderstanding-cyberwar/">absence &lt;/a>or &lt;a href="http://www.typepad.com/t/trackback/13425/32396074">presence &lt;/a>of cyberwar.  The big takeaway is that the Pentagon should not wash its hands of the R&amp;amp;D and of the C3 and of the practitioners responsible for employing and defending against these attacks.  Its rhetoric aside, I would not be surprised if they had, nor if they hadn't.  No matter what has been done, moving forward this is an area prime for research and defining where the battle-space will be and many other questions. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Issue of Valor</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-08-16-the-issue-of-valor/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-08-16-the-issue-of-valor/</guid><description>&lt;p>[![R1874377885][2]][2]  &lt;br>
Photo courtesy of [here][2].&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e200e553e9de388833-pi">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e200e553e9de388833-pi&lt;/a>
[2]: &lt;a href="http://patdollard.com/wp-content/uploads/r1874377885.jpg">http://patdollard.com/wp-content/uploads/r1874377885.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bing_West">Bing West&lt;/a>, who my former co-author knows quite well, and I met once briefly in Iraq while he joined one of my patrols has an interesting interview in a blog I frequent: &lt;a href="http://smallwarsjournal.com/">Small Wars Journal&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://smallwarsjournal.com/blog/2008/08/swj-interview-with-bing-west-p/">Part one is here&lt;/a>. &lt;a href="http://smallwarsjournal.com/blog/2008/08/part-2-swj-interview-with-bing/">Part two is here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I largely agree with his tactical analysis, especially the part where he exposes his institutional biases and lauds the Marines in Anbar. He also lauds Petraeus ordering people into the neighborhoods, which we were doing after entering Baghdad but ended when we were replaced by the First Cav Division. That is the right tactic now and it was the right tactic then.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I want to comment on something that West says in part two. The money quote is here:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The martial values of our society have deteriorated. During World War II, the&lt;br>
press scarcely mentioned and never photographed the dozens (over 140 in all) of&lt;br>
public hangings of American soldiers, and never mentioned the shootings of&lt;br>
German civilians or captured prisoners. The press considered such stories to be&lt;br>
out of bounds. In Iraq, the killings of civilians in Haditha, trumpeted as a&lt;br>
massacre, received vastly more press attention than any valorous action in the&lt;br>
war. The hue and cry was not motivated by a thirst for justice; when&lt;br>
investigations exonerated most of the Marines involved at Haditha, the press&lt;br>
wrote little and said less. In World War II, our nation highlighted courage and&lt;br>
quietly accepted mistakes. Today, we highlight mistakes and quietly accept&lt;br>
valor. On Iwo Jima in 1945, almost six thousand Americans died, many more than&lt;br>
in five years in Iraq. Iwo Jima was a strategic blunder. Today, the press and&lt;br>
Congress would be apoplectic about such a blunder. Courage, Aristotle said, is&lt;br>
the virtue that makes all other virtues possible. Geopolitical wisdom is&lt;br>
admirable, but martial valor is essential to sustain a democracy. American&lt;br>
society takes courage for granted, and the press ignores it. When we fight the&lt;br>
next war, this attitude will poorly serve the nation. Will soldiers risk their&lt;br>
lives, if society ignores courage?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are couple of levels to this comment.  The first is that this statement is ostensibly a tired critique of the &amp;ldquo;liberal media.&amp;rdquo;  The second, more interesting level, is that this is a lament by an old man that our society has gone &amp;ldquo;soft.&amp;rdquo;  Yet, these issues are not so easy to isolate because there is reverse causality, each one informing the other.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To be honest, I am tired of the liberal media critique for a number of reasons.  Media is selling a product, deal with it.  The editorial biases that major media outlets have is a reflection of their specific branding which is a reflection of their customer base and the advertising they need to sell in order to maintain a profit or at least operating costs.  Yes, this has always been the case but technology, specifically cable TV and the internet, have taken away the geographical limitations that newspapers and radio had during WWII.  In that era, I think that there was a professional ethos of objectivity because there was a realization that each media outlet had a virtual monopoly.  The social contract was objective reporting in return for the virtual monopoly on information maintained by the few radio outlets and one or two newspapers that society had access to.  Technology has changed that and there is no virtual monopoly at this time.  Media has adapted like any business would: &lt;a href="http://marcambinder.theatlantic.com/archives/2008/08/the_ideologies_of_audiences_fo.php">branding&lt;/a>.  This doesn't bother me because increased access in and of itself is a public good.  What does bother me is that society has not adapted by valuing critical thinking.  Something I've commented on before.  Yes, I would agree that many of the major media outlets do have a slightly left of center editorial bias.  This is generally reflective, I would posit, of those who continue to &amp;ldquo;buy&amp;rdquo; their product.  But it is also reflective of the fact that those who run major media outlets are fairly elitist and people in that demographic tend to be left of center on the American political spectrum.  Yet this is abrogated by the fact of access.  Those right of center, my father for instance, have plenty of sources that they can go to to feed their fire.  In no way is there a dearth of information.  The problem is laziness in finding that information and a lack of critical thinking about the information, where it comes from, who is writing it, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The deeper issue remains, however.  This is an area which is ripe for sociological research and I would be very interested to read such research as I have thought about this issue of whether current American society values valor on many occasions. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>The other night I was having a debate with my Swedish Dove roommate about NATO in Afghanistan mediated by an American-sympathizing Dane.  He said something that informs much of this debate: &amp;ldquo;How can you join a cause you do not believe in?&amp;rdquo;  I had a retort for that comment in the context of the Afghanistan debate but am not sure that I do in the context of the valor issue.  I think that that has a lot to do with it.  I think that American society learned much from the Vietnam experience.  Most people that I know who didn't agree with the war didn't call me a baby-killer for participating in it.  They had learned from the Vietnam war to separate those fighting from those ordering them to fight.  West's argument about how WWII was so valorous and how generally turned a blind eye to atrocities committed by Americans and held tightly to Iwo Jima flag raising moments is likely true.  Yet American society was not without its critics at the time.  The Nuremberg prosecutors and judges returning were pariahs for abrogating many of the protections that people felt vital in the case of war crimes tribunals.  The scourge of internment camps took years to overcome. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are many other items that one can point to that will show that American culture did not possess any self-critique of the methods used to fight WWII.  There is a certain lack of history there where the conversations of the citizenry are not as easy to catalog as today where many conversations are memorialized in blogs, podcasts and other Web 2.0 types of outlets. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, that is largely beside the point.  My feeling is that American's do value valor society-wide but it is hard for them to hold up valor when they do not believe unitarily in the cause as they did in WWII.  Every conflict that the US has participated in since WWII has reflected a more fractured society.  This is to be lauded rather than lamented.  It reflects that our democracy is maturing.  It reflects an ability of historians and media to report on and take action based upon the prevailing notions of the polity. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the beginning of Iraq, when there was a simpler view of that conflict, items that tended towards valor were reported.  Think about that woman who was a &amp;ldquo;prisoner of war.&amp;rdquo;  Think about the outcries of joy the day we pulled down the statute.  There are other examples.  Eventually as public opinion swung against the war and a more critical view of the mission itself the media changed what it was reporting on (the modification of its product both drove and was in response to changes in customer preferences). &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now all that aside, to the deeper issue.  My view is that American culture does value valor.  Our popular culture since at least the 1920s is essentially hero worship.  Our movies since the beginning have been homages to romantic heroes.  Our literature has similar tendencies when viewed on the macro-level.  Our music is a bit more fractured but largely is based upon romanticism and hero worship.  Now the form and persona of the hero definitely is a moving target, but there is always a level of courage required to overcome the problem.  When one compares American movies, literature and music to European movies, literature and music there is a tangible difference a major one is the romanticism that American pop culture seethes.  Another is the love of the hero.  These tangible differences, when combined with what I felt from others when I returned from Iraq (and not only in my red state, but also in the navy blue enclaves that I migrated to after getting out of the USMC), inform my thought that America is not about to lose its ability to mobilize valorous people. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>What politicians just need to realize is that it will never be easy to mobilize, yet I think that if we were to find ourselves truly and undoubtedly under attack the ability to mobilize heroic persons on the battlefield will not be difficult.  Yet, what politicians must also realize is that the self-critical nature of the maturing American democracy is going to debate any conflict that we will find ourselves in.  It always has and it always will.  This is a good thing.  Any burying in the sand by military hawks is unfortunate.  One way that as a society we have walked this line is by dislocating the military from modern culture.  This is unfortunate, but a complex topic I will leave for another day.  For now suffice it to say that personally I take West's comments with a grain of salt and do not agree with his dystopic view of America's ability to fight the conflicts that will keep our people safe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Anti-Americanism</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-07-23-anti-americanism/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-07-23-anti-americanism/</guid><description>&lt;p>[![_40656678_flag_afp_203body][2]][2] &lt;br>
To be honest, I’ve never fully understood the vehement Anti-Americanism that I have at times been the target of.  I did understand it the few times I experienced it in Iraq.  Mainly, it is the European anti-americanism that I do not fully understand.  I usually dismiss it as some sort of a simple jealousy and unwillingness to part with the past and realize that the world has moved on.  I know that that is a simplistic understanding of a complex issue.  That is why I enjoy reading well-phrased articles by European thinkers on the subject.  The UK Times ran [this][2] piece today, which I found quite thoughtful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e200e553ceba9c8834-pi">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e200e553ceba9c8834-pi&lt;/a>
[2]: &lt;a href="http://www.timesonline.co.uk/tol/comment/columnists/david_aaronovitch/article4374704.ece">http://www.timesonline.co.uk/tol/comment/columnists/david_aaronovitch/article4374704.ece&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Europeans that I’ve met during the election campaign, like their idealistically blinded progressive counterparts in the U.S. seem to think that Obama is going to cure everything that ills the nation.  As I said in my analysis of his foreign policy, that isn’t going to happen.  The inertia of what has already taken place over decades will constrain him; the centrifugal pull of bureaucratic organizational design will constrain him; and the fact that he isn’t a dictator and is still beholden to the other two branches of government will constrain him.  Obama will (hopefully) give a style, a flavor, and a presence to the US presidency that has been lacking since Reagan (or JFK, depending on which side of the aisle you sit).  That is what I am excited for.  However he will end up getting mocked and ridiculed by the Euro’s eventually.  He will get called a hawk and a war-monger.  He will likely be called many of the same things that GWB has been called.  My hope is that those calling names will be fewer, have less basis for their arguments and generally be classified as radical rather than mainstream. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>This last part sort of goes to the heart of the matter.  In many ways Europe needs us to be the war-mongering bad cop to their peacenik good cop.  It provides the security assurances as well as progress that have regulated most of the world (albeit badly in a very many instances) since the end of the Cold War.  And yet, no one on this side of the Atlantic is ever willing to admit that!  We grumble and saber rattle at the Iranians while they negotiate with the Iranians.  We scare people into their arms.  All the while, information is being passed back and forth under the table as there is no way you’ll be able to convince me that the intelligence services are not talking to each other on each of these issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>HRC Showing Some Class, still a bit late</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-05-hrc-showing-some-class-still-a-bit-late/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-05-hrc-showing-some-class-still-a-bit-late/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have been question what her game is for weeks now.  I have been questioning why the DNC elites don't shut her down.  I have been questioning why there isn't droves and droves of supers to him after the election in a show of party unity.  Some of this has begun.  But why now?  What has changed between yesterday and today that HRC only &lt;em>now&lt;/em> is &amp;ldquo;suspending&amp;rdquo; her campaign.  Further, suspending?  Come on.  Drop out, if something catastrophic were to happen (knocking furiously on wood) then she could still be elected at the convention. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Have seen a million reasons why the Clinton/Obama ticket will not happen.  Not the least of which is that Bill likely doesn't want the RNC looking too deeply into his sketchy financial dealings over the past few years.  Another theory is that if she really believes that he can't win better for her not to be running mate so as to position for 2012 and &amp;ldquo;I told you so.&amp;rdquo;  Were he to win, then she would be in the same position whether Veep, Cabinet or Senator.  Jimmy Carter has talked about getting all of the downsides of each rather than all of the upsides of each.  Despite the dystopian overtones, I understand his argument.  I think she gets into a revamped Cabinet.  Along with Edwards, Gore (I hope), and Biden – each in their functional areas of expertise.  That would be a liberal's wet dream cabinet.  Who does that leave?  MY BOY, RICHARDSON, Sebillius, Webb and a few others. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is &lt;a href="http://talkingpointsmemo.com/archives/198827.php">the email&lt;/a> that HRC sent to supporters:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Dear XXX,&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I wanted you to be one of the first to know: on Saturday, I will&lt;br>
hold an event in Washington D.C. to thank everyone who has supported my&lt;br>
campaign. Over the course of the last 16 months, I have been privileged&lt;br>
and touched to witness the incredible dedication and sacrifice of so&lt;br>
many people working for our campaign. Every minute you put into helping&lt;br>
us win, every dollar you gave to keep up the fight meant more to me&lt;br>
than I can ever possibly tell you.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>On Saturday, I will extend my congratulations to Senator Obama and&lt;br>
my support for his candidacy. This has been a long and hard-fought&lt;br>
campaign, but as I have always said, my differences with Senator Obama&lt;br>
are small compared to the differences we have with Senator McCain and&lt;br>
the Republicans.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I have said throughout the campaign that I would strongly support&lt;br>
Senator Obama if he were the Democratic Party's nominee, and I intend&lt;br>
to deliver on that promise.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When I decided to run for president, I knew exactly why I was&lt;br>
getting into this race: to work hard every day for the millions of&lt;br>
Americans who need a voice in the White House.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I made you — and everyone who supported me — a promise: to stand&lt;br>
up for our shared values and to never back down. I'm going to keep that&lt;br>
promise today, tomorrow, and for the rest of my life.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I will be speaking on Saturday about how together we can rally the&lt;br>
party behind Senator Obama. The stakes are too high and the task before&lt;br>
us too important to do otherwise.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I know as I continue my lifelong work for a stronger America and a&lt;br>
better world, I will turn to you for the support, the strength, and the&lt;br>
commitment that you have shown me in the past 16 months. And I will&lt;br>
always keep faith with the issues and causes that are important to you.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In the past few days, you have shown that support once again with&lt;br>
hundreds of thousands of messages to the campaign, and again, I am&lt;br>
touched by your thoughtfulness and kindness.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I can never possibly express my gratitude, so let me say simply, thank you.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Sincerely,&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Hillary Rodham Clinton&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Real Deal</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-04-the-real-deal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-04-the-real-deal/</guid><description>&lt;p>[![Bmchipsomodevillagetty][2]][2]&lt;br>
[][2]
[(Photo: Chip Somodevilla/Getty.)][2] &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[Andrew Sullivan][3] has some phenomenal reactions about Barack’s seeming win up today.  The first is a story that choked me up told by one of Andrew’s [readers][4]: &lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>My grandfather, 86 years old and a veteran of WWII, just&lt;br>
gave me a call. He was calling all of his grandchildren to let them&lt;br>
know what an important night this was in the history of our country.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Grandpa drove a truck for over 50 years, and he told the story of&lt;br>
how he drove with a team of drivers, 2 white (including him), and 4&lt;br>
black. When they stopped at the truck stops, the black drivers had to&lt;br>
use seperate restrooms and showers, and had to eat in a small room in&lt;br>
the back of the kitchen. Grandpa and his co-driver would eat in the&lt;br>
back with the rest of the team, and while they didn’t speak of it at&lt;br>
the time, they knew it was wrong yet felt powerless to change it, and&lt;br>
believed that it would never change.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Tonight, he told me, we have come full-circle. Many people,&lt;br>
especially the younger generation who supported Obama, will never fully&lt;br>
realize the historical import of what happened tonight. But he wanted&lt;br>
his grandchildren to know this story that he had never told us, and it&lt;br>
was the second time in my 33 years that I have heard my grandpa cry.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The other is Andrew’s [reaction ][2]to Barack’s speech he gave last night (you), this morning (me): &lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If I needed reassurance that this man is the most formidable force&lt;br>
in American politics today, his speech tonight confirmed it. It was&lt;br>
shrewd – with an artful positioning on Iraq. It was graceful – with&lt;br>
respect for McCain’s service and Clinton’s tenacity. It was brutal – in&lt;br>
turning around McCain’s Iraq visit meme to domestic economic woes. It&lt;br>
was patriotic – in its evocation of Gettysburg and the Second World&lt;br>
War. It was outer-directed: not for Obama the recourse to&lt;br>
self-satisfied identity politics of the kind used by the Clintons&lt;br>
because they often have nothing else. It was moving. I thought I even&lt;br>
saw some suggestions of tears as he remembered his grandmother. It was&lt;br>
also rhetorically more powerful than McCain – not by a small amount but&lt;br>
by a mile. Put McCain’s speech against Obama’s – and this was a&lt;br>
wipe-out. Not a victory. A wipe-out. Rhetorically, they are simply not&lt;br>
in the same league. And if the contrast tonight between McCain and&lt;br>
Obama holds for the rest of the campaign, McCain is facing a defeat of&lt;br>
historic proportions.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>One more thing: with McCain’s and Clinton’s speeches, you could not&lt;br>
forget the politics of it. With Obama, you forgot about that at times.&lt;br>
You actually lifted your eyes a little and believed a little and hoped&lt;br>
a little.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Yes, he can. And anyone who under-estimates that will regret it.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I awoke at five this morning and timed it perfectly as he was about to take the stage when I got the TV sorted.  CNN had audio but no visual as the signal was scrambled.  Luckily for me BBC carried the entire thing, except for a vital moment during his wind up at the end where the signal died and I cursed to all hell the Somali desert winds that were impeding my political joy. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>On a related note, the NY Times had this grand photo of the Obamas watching Hillary’s speech.  I think the frustration on Michelle’s face and the stoicism on Barack’s face are more telling than any words I can write.  As I thought more about it I became more and more irate at HRC’s intransigence and utter lack of class.  This night was all about her for her, and a third about her for Obama.  It is over.  She needs to face it and the DNC elites need to ensure that she faces it.  I am frustrated at the apparent spinelessness of the party supremos.  Why are they so scared of Bill’s wrath? &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although I couldn’t see her comment, I heard Donna Brazille (a superdelegate and CNN commentator) say something akin to, “well, I didn’t support him because he didn’t need me to put him over the top.”  That is utter crap.  You are a middle aged black woman.  Don’t tell me he doesn’t need your support!  The DNC could learn a lot from the discipline of the RNC.  I told Big_Head today when I called because of happiness that the DNC can be maddening with its uber-hippy notions of flaunting of discipline.  Sometimes that is fantastic, but this isn’t one of them.  And, by the way, if I hear one more time that HRC is doing this for her supporters I’m going to stab 48 pencils into the eye of the first person I see.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In any event, the man I came late to support is now the first candidate of color from a major American party.  Hooray!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, the [photo][5]: &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://andrewsullivan.theatlantic.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2008/06/03/bmchipsomodevillagetty.jpg">http://andrewsullivan.theatlantic.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2008/06/03/bmchipsomodevillagetty.jpg&lt;/a>
[2]: &lt;a href="http://andrewsullivan.theatlantic.com/the_daily_dish/2008/06/this-moment-1.html">http://andrewsullivan.theatlantic.com/the_daily_dish/2008/06/this-moment-1.html&lt;/a>
[3]: &lt;a href="http://andrewsullivan.theatlantic.com/the_daily_dish/">http://andrewsullivan.theatlantic.com/the_daily_dish/&lt;/a>
[4]: &lt;a href="http://www.typepad.com/t/trackback/2224950/29750642">http://www.typepad.com/t/trackback/2224950/29750642&lt;/a>
[5]: &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2008/06/04/us/politics/04assess.html?hp">http://www.nytimes.com/2008/06/04/us/politics/04assess.html?hp&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://graphics8.nytimes.com/images/2008/06/04/us/04assess.600.jpg" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now back to my real life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>VeepStakes</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-05-29-veepstakes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-05-29-veepstakes/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of my favorite pundit-ers is &lt;a href="http://marcambinder.theatlantic.com/">Marc Ambinder&lt;/a> who writes for the Atlantic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He has a great &lt;a href="http://marcambinder.theatlantic.com/cgi-bin/mt/mt-tb.cgi/21712">article&lt;/a> on how candidates go about selecting running mates. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>I'm not sure how it will play out for Obama, much less for McCain.  I certainly hope that the robot-republican doesn't win.  For Obama, I'm going to slow play my predictions, but I will say that I was a Richardson supporter before I was an Obama supporter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>McCain is All Class</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-04-23-mccain-is-all-class/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-04-23-mccain-is-all-class/</guid><description>&lt;p>Link: &lt;a href="http://www.politico.com/blogs/jonathanmartin/0408/McCain_implores_NC_GOP_to_not_air_ad.html" title="Jonathan Martin's Blog - Politico.com">Jonathan Martin’s Blog – Politico.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m not a McCain supporter.  However, I am very very pleased that he was able to secure the Republican nomination.  The backstory is linked to above, but the letter below is prima facie evidence of McCain’s class as a human.  It is shit like this that I highly respect.  Very Well Done Mr. Senator.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Dear Chairman Daves,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the beginning of this election, I have been committed to running a&lt;br>
respectful campaign based upon an honest debate about the great issues&lt;br>
confronting America today. I expect all state parties to do so as well.&lt;br>
The television advertisement you are planning to air degrades our&lt;br>
civics and distracts us from the very real differences we have with the&lt;br>
Democrats. In the strongest terms, I implore you to not run this&lt;br>
advertisement.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This ad does not live up to the very high standards we should hold&lt;br>
ourselves to in this campaign. We need to run a campaign that is worthy&lt;br>
of the people we seek to serve. There is no doubt that we will draw&lt;br>
sharp contrasts with the Democrats on fundamental issues critical to&lt;br>
the future course of our country. But we need not engage in political&lt;br>
tactics that only seek to divide the American people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once again, it is imperative that you withdraw this offensive advertisement.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>John McCain&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Boy and His Toy</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-04-23-my-boy-and-his-toy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-04-23-my-boy-and-his-toy/</guid><description>&lt;p>Link: &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2008/04/22/arts/television/22king.html?ref=todayspaper" title="John King of CNN Revels in His High-Tech Election Night Toy - New York Times">John King of CNN Revels in His High-Tech Election Night Toy – New York Times&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>NYT profiles the best political commentator on television.  I once saw him point to this big map and circle a part of Florida and say something akin to: &amp;ldquo;This part of Florida right here, just south of Orlando is the home to the Non-Mexican, Non-Puerto Rican Latin population in Florida.&amp;rdquo;  Who the hell knows that?  I rifled quickly through my mental database and could find no evidence, even after growing up in Orlando, to contradict that. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>And he does that with every state that he commentates on. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good win for HRC tonight.  Congrats.  One of the CNN guys said it best, &amp;ldquo;this is the best number to keep this campaign going.  Any more and she would have blown him out and the supers would mass migrate to her.  Any less and she would have been forced out. &amp;quot; &lt;br>
Now Obama gives his speech.  On and on the train moves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Dumbest Debate in America</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-04-17-the-dumbest-debate-in-america/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-04-17-the-dumbest-debate-in-america/</guid><description>&lt;p>Link: &lt;a href="http://commentisfree.guardian.co.uk/niall_stanage/2008/04/the_dumbest_debate_in_america.html" title="The dumbest debate in America? | Comment is free">The dumbest debate in America&lt;/a>.  The Guardian has a great op-ed which I think summarizes exactly how I felt about the debate last night.  The crux of the matter boils down to this very well crafted sentence.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When a presidential debate in a nation roiled by two wars, an economic&lt;br>
crisis and a seven-year onslaught on civil liberties revolves around&lt;br>
questions about flag pins and casual friends, it would be easy to&lt;br>
despair.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That is all for now.&lt;br>
~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Revisiting the Vietnam Syndrome</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-04-11-revisiting-the-vietnam-syndrome/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-04-11-revisiting-the-vietnam-syndrome/</guid><description>&lt;p>I grew up not when Vietnam was happening, but rather, I grew up in the dramatic artistic, historical and cultural shadow of the Vietnam era.  That shadow colored much of what I did and what I valued, especially during the formative years of college where I was forming my world view and sharpening my military instincts. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>While in the Marines, Vietnam loomed as the most important historical, cultural, and tactical benchmark.  We all felt that it was the closest &amp;ldquo;real war,&amp;rdquo; and although we valued those who had shot or been shot at at various time since such as GWI, Somalia, Liberia, etc. we kept real heroic thoughts for those who fought in Vietnam and (of course) in Korea and WWII. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>After I saw the tiny bit of combat that I did see &amp;ldquo;liberals&amp;rdquo; (as I used to call what now I call &amp;ldquo;us&amp;rdquo;) were adamant that Iraq was going to become the Vietnam of our generation.  I discounted that notion then.  But have been revisiting it mentally lately.  I will have to write in more detail about this at some other point, but it seems to me that the shadow of Vietnam has created another Vietnam.  In other words it is the fear of being judged as harshly as history judges Vietnam  which created the policy conditions that set us on the path we currently find ourselves. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>One small snippet (there are others) which I use only to illustrate my line of thinking:  much of the historical rhetoric on Vietnam has held that the civilians in DC kept too tight a leash on Westmoreland and as they constantly ratchetted up and down the military strategy the folks on the ground (both Vietnamese and US) were not able to adapt quickly enough and the changes in military strategy were never allowed to develop before they were changed again.  The lesson which I was taught more times than I can count is that if &lt;em>only the politicians had listened to the generals&lt;/em> then things wouldn’t have been messed up long term.  That lesson is good, but when taken to an extreme, maybe not.  Now we have conditions established that essentially mandate that when a general speaks no one should even question him.  Generals are inspired, intelligent, sophisticated technocrats.  They are not generalists.  Their focus is not wide-spectrum policies.  Even if they have interests in that realm, it isn’t usually their job (random king-like post-WWII occurrences aside).  They are &amp;amp; should be focussed on winning the battle on the ground.  The completely myopic focus from day negative one until today on &amp;ldquo;winning&amp;rdquo; in Iraq and how that can be done militarily has created a policy environment where state institution building has taken a second- third- or fourth-seat at conference tables which synchronize US policy.   &lt;a href="http://www.foreignaffairs.org/20080501faessay87305/steven-simon/the-price-of-the-surge.html">Many&lt;/a> are only NOW beginning to argue  (although I remember thinking unsophisticated versions of this thought when I was in Baghdad afterglowing from pulling down the statute) that it is precisely this lack of focus on domestic political and bureaucratic institutions that is widely responsible for the ongoing violence in Iraq. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is more here, but between trying to move, trying to move to Somalia, applying for the bar, finishing up my spring semester, and trying to look good for my lady I do not have time to fully explore this, but if I expanded it into a book I would title it: *Misguided by History: The Lessons NeoCons Learned Wrongly from Vietnam.  *&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before leaving, I need to point out that I am heartily uncomfortable with the Sunni Awakening as a policy measure.  When Big-Perm first told me that about it and how it had been the focus of his civil affairs work in the second half of 2007 in Anbar I was concerned.  The more I read about it, the more my concern grows.  My concerns essentially hinge on the US arming and empowering those who have very little stake in keeping a cohesive state.  For instance, from the article above:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The Sunni sheiks, meanwhile, are getting rich from the surge. The United States has budgeted $150 million to pay Sunni tribal groups this year, and the sheiks take as much as 20 percent of every payment to a former insurgent — which means that commanding 200 fighters can be worth well over a hundred thousand dollars a year for a tribal chief.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Whenever we do decide to leave, if those incentives still exist then chaos at a maximum and violence at a minimum will be a direct result of our short-sided efforts to reduce US casaulties.  What needs to happen is that we need to take away the incentives to breed chaos and violence.  I’m not sure how that happens, but that is a question for Ambassador Cocker, not for the widely regarded General Petraeus.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Obama&amp;#8217;s First Masterpiece?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-03-19-obamas-first-masterpiece/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-03-19-obamas-first-masterpiece/</guid><description>&lt;p>This speech is 40 minutes long and it will be the best thing that you do today.  Do not let someone else help form your opinions on this speech.  Form your own.  The embed:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/pWe7wTVbLUU&amp;amp;hl=en" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">1&lt;/a>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/pWe7wTVbLUU&amp;amp;hl=en" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">1&lt;/a>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/pWe7wTVbLUU&amp;amp;hl=en" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">1&lt;/a>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/pWe7wTVbLUU&amp;amp;hl=en" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">1&lt;/a>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/pWe7wTVbLUU&amp;amp;hl=en" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">1&lt;/a>
Now, to my reactions.  Everyone is right that it is brilliant and nuanced, honest and frank.  Charles Murray, the conservative author who raised much controversy with the &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Bell-Curve-Intelligence-Structure-Paperbacks/dp/0684824299/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1205868373&amp;amp;sr=8-1">Bell Curve&lt;/a> called the speech &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://corner.nationalreview.com/post/?q=MjI3MWMyOGFkNmQ2MGFjNzRhYzYwMGVhZWJhMjcyOGM=">brilliant&lt;/a>.&amp;rdquo;  &lt;a href="http://time-blog.com/real_clear_politics/2008/03/speech_reax.html">Most politicos&lt;/a> I’ve read have thought it was the most frank and honest speech on race during their lifetimes.  That is likely true.  I don’t cover politics, but I do play someone who does on television, and I can certainly say that it qualified in that regard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apparently, this is meant to be the week of &lt;a href="http://www.politico.com/blogs/bensmith/0308/Moving_on_from_race.html">speeches&lt;/a>&lt;br>
for Barack.  I truly hope that his speech tomorrow on Iraq and his&lt;br>
speech the next day on the economy (with its linkages to Iraq) will be&lt;br>
as complex as this one.  This speech, I admit, was not full of&lt;br>
solutions.  It was a world-view dissertation.  For a long time I have&lt;br>
argued that the &amp;ldquo;Barack is vacuous&amp;rdquo;  line is complete intellectual&lt;br>
dishonesty.  I am excited for him to shine. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>But I have two reactions that (hopefully) are not completely informed by the massive amounts of punditry that I’ve read since watching the speech.  People will likely dissect the speech in every shape and form.  I actually have little to say that will likely be unique about the content of his speech and prefer to analyze it at a pomo remove. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Point 1:  I am struck that &lt;a href="http://marcambinder.theatlantic.com/cgi-bin/mt/mt-tb.cgi/20061">Barack wrote this alone&lt;/a> and it was not a collaborative effort.  On the one hand I am hesitant to endorse someone who keeps his own company, especially someone who is managing one of the most complex organizations in the world and will never have a complete handle on the issues and the facts and will be reliant on others to distill what is important because there simply is not enough seconds in the day to be able to grab everything.  Too closehold of a management style is disadvantageous in the political spectrum.  Yet on the other hand, the President (though the &amp;ldquo;face&amp;rdquo;) needs to be able to have solidly held beliefs that are formed by a distinctive world view.  Too little of an idea about what one’s views are can be detrimental.  Clinton was magical at being a complete vacuum of world view and basing many decisions upon short-term political gains.  The gist of the Republican argument since the Clinton administration is that they hold to their beliefs and do not shift with the winds of the moment.  Barack seems willing to say anything you can do, I can do….better (he would argue).  Although there is a fine line here, I would prefer to have a President that does not change with the winds of the moment and is willing to keep his own company as long as he is open to dissent and flexible enough to know when to change.  It is like the old christian poem which ends with the &amp;ldquo;wisdom to know the difference.&amp;rdquo; This is where the trust of politics comes into play (trust, I would argue is one of the major normative bases for identity politics which is as unavoidable in modern America as it was in the recent &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2007/12/23/magazine/23kenya-t.html?ex=1356066000&amp;amp;en=c558476ab344449e&amp;amp;ei=5124&amp;amp;partner=permalink&amp;amp;exprod=permalink">Kenyan elections&lt;/a>).   &lt;/p>
&lt;p>More important, intellectually, than the trust factor (to me), is that Obama is willing to buck the political trend when he feels strongly about an issue.  There was no polling to help refine his views on this issue.  He did not need that.  He has experienced things acutely in his short life that resonate with both of my major iterations.  His expose about white frustration at affirmative action and urban crime were very much how I’ve thought at times in my life.  His discussion of black anger because of a history which has seemed to pit the world against the black community is very much in line with my current views after talking to those who have studied education much more in depth than I have.  Both of these resonated with me in a very real and powerful way.  But yet, he did not need to have some whites and blacks on a committee to tell him their stories.  His story is incredibly unique in that he intimately understands both of these major sides to the coin without having to rely on someone to tell him &amp;ldquo;what the American people think.&amp;rdquo;  Yes, obviously there is a danger here because a politician should &lt;em>never&lt;/em> close off inputs, dissent and alternate world views.  No one that I’ve heard has made that claim against Barack so I am comfortable that an Obama administration would not be closed off.  Yet it seems to be principled in a way that other campaigns likely will not be, precisely because he is able to relate in a way that most intellectuals and elites cannot. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was sitting at my computer watching this on YouTube, I closed my eyes and just listened to the speech and thought, &amp;ldquo;Damn, if we can elect this man I can be publicly proud to be an American again….No matter if I’m in Somalia or Sierra Leone or Holland or Scotland or Chattanooga.&amp;rdquo;  In my opinion, THAT is why we elect a President.  Sure there are policy stances and we want the government to be receptive to our concerns.  Those are supremely important, but for me, that is what I base my legislative voting decisions upon.  Presidential decisions present me with an entirely different calculus because the President has a fundamentally different job.  I’m sure that any of the three candidates will do things that I agree and disagree with, but which one of them will make me proudly tell people I’m American and not make me want to tell people I’m Canadian when I travel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Point 2:  I think that there will likely be continued rumblings about the complexity of the speech and people will likely argue that it is only going to be accessible to elites and that mainstream America will not be affected by this speech.  That is true if mainstream America does not watch and listen to the speech and actually reflect on the truthiness of what Barack is saying.  But there is nothing that stood out to me as particularly complex or inaccessible about what he was saying.  I have been continually annoyed over the years at the lack of complexity in political discourse.  Many have written books on the dumbing of America.  Go to Amazon and I’m sure that you will find hundreds.  I like Obama not so much because I agree with his message (although that obviously helps) but more because I respect his willingness to engage in complex dialogue with his supporters and detractors alike. Culturally I agree with those who decry the lack of complex political debate and I become concerned as to how long our &amp;ldquo;greatness&amp;rdquo; (whatever that is) will be sustainable if we continue to patronize people rather than force them to think critically about issues and form their own opinions.I think that changes in media dissemination (mainly meaning the internet, etc.) both help and hurt. Although there is increased access to something like a major policy speech by a candidate, there is also increased shrillness both for and against it and thinly veiled for and against coverage. The point is not that technology has helped or hurt our culture, it is that if there is a continued cultural reliance upon other’s analysis rather than source-level inquiries and critical thinking then I question where we shall end up. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>To bring the argument back around on itself (hopefully without being circular), this is precisely what Obama does in this speech.  He has formed his own opinions based upon his experiences and his understanding of the facts that do not come across as colored and polished in the same way that most others (black or white) would come across giving a similar speech.  He talked for 40 minutes straight and rarely looked at any notes, yet was eloquent in a way that made me believe that he truly understood what he was saying.  I feel (no matter whether it is true or not) that he had formed those opinions himself based on his thought and not Mark Penn telling him what the American people want to hear. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Intellect should not be a dirty word and critical thought is not&lt;br>
something that people in small liberal arts colleges engage in over&lt;br>
hipster beers or free-trade coffee.  Critical thought simply means&lt;br>
forming your own opinions on matters based upon a reading of the facts&lt;br>
as you think they exist.  Yet, these seem to be dirty words.  Not sure,&lt;br>
but, like I always say, I’m all about Dirty Deeds, Done Dirt Cheap. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Dubious Honor</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-28-a-dubious-honor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-28-a-dubious-honor/</guid><description>&lt;p>My old battalion has achieved &lt;a href="http://blog.foreignpolicy.com/node/8277">a dubious honor&lt;/a>.  They are the first military unit to get deployed to Iraq for the Fifth time.  Now that is a bit misleading because of the mobility of the military there are few individuals that have likely gone five times.  But still…..&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Courting my Boi</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-23-courting-my-boi/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-23-courting-my-boi/</guid><description>&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![Billrichardson][2]][2]&lt;br>
[No Longer in Race, Richardson Is a Man Pursued][2].  It isn’t a secret that before he dropped out, I was hoping that Bill Richardson would make a good showing.  Now that he is out of the race (no pun intended), I have been wondering whether he would be attractive to the candidates, and if he was in what regard. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2008/02/23/billrichardson.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2008/02/23/billrichardson.jpg&lt;/a>
[2]: &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2008/02/23/us/politics/23richardson.html?_r=1&amp;amp;hp&amp;amp;oref=slogin">http://www.nytimes.com/2008/02/23/us/politics/23richardson.html?_r=1&amp;amp;hp&amp;amp;oref=slogin&lt;/a> &amp;ldquo;No Longer in Race, Richardson Is a Man Pursued - New York Times&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Seems that both candidates are courting him.  Not sure to what extent they are lobbying for his endorsement, for his superdelegate vote, or for him to be a running mate or cabinet level position (Sec State most likely). &lt;/p>
&lt;p>I, and to a certain extent, Big_Head have been lusting after an Obama – Richardson Ticket for about a year now (or, alternatively a Richardson – Obama ticket).  This would make much sense for Obama.  In my mind it would make more sense than the Obama – Clinton &amp;ldquo;dream ticket&amp;rdquo; that many pundits speak of.  In the Obama – Clinton situation, you get all of the policies that are essentially the same.  You get experiences that are not that different.  And, most importantly, you get no additional bonuses (Clinton supporters are HIGHLY unlikely to not support Barack) with a bunch of turnoffs (all the moderates who have been known for a time to be anti-Hillary. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>An Obama – Richardson ticket would seem to me to present the opposite.  No one seems to be anti-Bill in the way that many moderates and conservatives.  There seems to be a contingent of conservatives that are likely to migrate to Barack if they are suitably anti-McCain…which, BTW, I don’t really understand but have heard many tell me personally that they would migrate Barack’s way now that John is the Republican nominee.  Further, Richardson can ADD to Obama’s base if he was on the ticket in the way that Clinton would not really be able to add. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clinton holds a very partisan Democratic base who I do not see migrating away if Barack is the candidate.  Clinton’s base has never been noted to be moderates.  Barack has been winning those since Iowa, and has continued to.  Richardson brings experiences that will bolster the ticket (especially in the foreign policy realm where I would admit Barack appears to me to be a bit weaker than McCain).  Richardson also will be able to identify with Hispanic moderates and help Barack win that HUGE vote in the general.  Hillary has done OK with the Latin vote to date, but I do not see it being the same without the identity politics that would come into play if Richardson was the running mate. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, we’ll have to see how it plays out.  All of this is (obviously) predicated on Barack pulling it out March 4 and afterwards.  I think that is increasingly going to be realized.  But, again, we never know!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Voting Machines</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-06-voting-machines/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-06-voting-machines/</guid><description>&lt;p>Can someone explain to me why we are even hearing about voting machines…?  How flipping difficult can the code be?  Why are these things untrustworthy?  Other than the Chinese State (with its professionals) hacking into our systems, why are we unable to figure this out?  There are a few candidates, you click one of them.  A counter counts.  Maybe I just don’t understand some nuances (which is troubling considering I’m going to do election policy and process reform), but it seems to me to be a non-issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why Iraq Matters, but Doesn&amp;#8217;t Matter</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-06-why-iraq-matters-but-doesnt-matter/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-06-why-iraq-matters-but-doesnt-matter/</guid><description>&lt;p>During the last debate, I was talking with Super-Star about Iraq.  The following is my analysis of the situation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Iraq matters – a lot to voters.  But Iraq shouldn’t matter.  No matter what the candidates say to pander to their base each of them is going to do virtually identical things on Iraq.  Iraq is complicated, but it isn’t that complicated.  We know what we need to do now, that is clear.  Despite pleas to &amp;ldquo;End the War&amp;rdquo; that is essentially an ephemeral campaign promise. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sweet.  We’re going to the Situation Room.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![Iraqmap_2][2]][2]&lt;br>
Anyway.  The reason that they will all do the same thing but be able to say completely different things is because of the nuances.  They are simply talking the nuances, but this is how it will most likely play out. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://www.theglobaleducationproject.org/mideast/info/maps/iraq-map.gif">http://www.theglobaleducationproject.org/mideast/info/maps/iraq-map.gif&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is a terrorist threat in Iraq.  We knew that the time that they would be coming for us.  To me, at the time when we were invading this was the most convincing argument.  I’ve said before, I’ll say again that although it doesn’t really justify the war in my mind, at least I was happy to go there to provide the fly trap. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, I have problems with that, because whereever there is fighting there is collateral damage and now Sunnis in Western Iraq are paying the price for the neocon idea of better over there than here. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now that there is a terrorist threat, we need to keep fighting them there.  Al Qaeda is sending its best fighters into the loosely populated areas of Western Iraq.  Those missions that the young Marines are carrying out in the western deserts are vital to our national security, because those fighters do have backing that enables a long enough reach to threaten vital interests.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the point that Republicans play up and Democrats gloss over.  Neither Obama nor Hillary nor McCain nor anyone (except maybe Ron Paul) is going to stop the terrorist hunting missions in the West. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Baghdad.  Located in the virtual geographic center of the country Baghdad is a conundrum.  It is as close as a melting pot as Iraq has, and certainly one of the more cosmopolitan centers east of Jordan.  What happens there is connected to what is happening in the West, but only loosely.  They inform one another, but there is little tight causal connection.  What is happening in Baghdad is tribal tensions that have built up over millennium colliding with the realities of politics colliding with patronage networks that require bolstering or maintenance.  The issues there are raw political ones that happen in any post-conflict scenario. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some of the bombings are to get power in the parliament; some of the bombings are organized crime who is fighting other organized crime for territory; some of the bombings are terrorist and ideological based; and I’m sure that other bombings are the same.  So not all the bombs that get reported are the same.  Yes, the bombings have reduced.  That is because the surge is working.  At least it is working in Baghdad, where it needed to work because that is the center of gravity for Iraq and it must retain some modicum of stability if Iraq is going to be able to figure out how to solve its other problems.  Rumsfeld was just as wrong as he was right.  A small elite force could topple Saddam’s regime.  We did it beautifully.  But without any planning, without enough troops, without sufficient oversight of general’s things soon spiraled out of control.  The only way to regain momentum and control in Baghdad was to flood the streets with soldiers.  That reduces the capability of insurgents and organized crime and backhanded, violent political operative’s ability to operate.  This is what is causing the reduction in violence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The solution here must be resolved by the Iraqis.  They need to be forced into political reconciliation.  They need to be forced into policing organized crime.  They need to take the lead on rooting out the insurgents that escape our corridor around the Western Desert area.  We need to help them in all this, but this has to Iraqi driven, the US can only do so much.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the aspect of Iraq that the Democrats play up and the Republicans glaze over.  Both parties are going to keep significant numbers of troops in Baghdad for a set period of time and then force the Iraqis into figuring it out.  At the end of this set period we are going to begin to draw down our troop structure.  When Iraqis begin taking over Baghdad we will see significant reductions in troop strengths.  But no one is going to pull the Marines out of western Iraq.  Not for a while yet. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>The rest of Iraq.  The rest of Iraq is just as nuanced.  Drugs, Crime, Terrorists, all of these will seep across the borders, making it easier for them to come to Europe.  The Europeans don’t want that.  We don’t want that.  The provincial solution is to help the Iraqi’s secure their borders.  We are doing this to a certain extent and for the most part will continue to do this.  I see little change here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So at the end of the day Cut And Run = 100 Years in Iraq = Retreat in Defeat.  At the end of the day they are all realists and are all going to do the same thing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wonk Out</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-06-wonk-out/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-06-wonk-out/</guid><description>&lt;p>[![Benazirbhuttocfr][2]][2]&lt;br>
If you want to see one of the most nuanced foreign policy discussions among true professionals in the world, go to CFR.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2008/02/05/benazirbhuttocfr.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2008/02/05/benazirbhuttocfr.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BTW, in case any are wondering, each of the major candidates is a member of CFR. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Another Reason</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-05-another-reason/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-05-another-reason/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is why &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/underwater/2008/02/debating-afghan.html">I Support&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://www.barackobama.com/index.php">Barack.&lt;/a>  Not for the celebrities; Not because of his blatant appeals to people in my demographic; But Because of the Words.  Listen to the Words, Big_Head once told me.  &lt;a href="http://www.indiefeedpp.libsyn.com/index.php?post_id=302667">I’m listening&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/2fZHou18Cdk&amp;amp;rel=1&amp;amp;border=1" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">4&lt;/a>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/2fZHou18Cdk&amp;amp;rel=1&amp;amp;border=1" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">4&lt;/a>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/2fZHou18Cdk&amp;amp;rel=1&amp;amp;border=1" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">4&lt;/a>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/2fZHou18Cdk&amp;amp;rel=1&amp;amp;border=1" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">4&lt;/a>
This is what the creator said about this video.  I’m not an artist, I do other things, but I agree with almost everything he says.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I was sitting in my recording studio watching the debates…&lt;br>
Torn between the candidates&lt;br>
I was never really big on politics…&lt;br>
and actually I’m still not big on politics…&lt;br>
but 4 years ago, me and the black eyed peas supported Kerry…&lt;br>
And we supported Kerry with all our might…&lt;br>
We performed and performed and performed for the DNC…&lt;br>
doing all we could do to get the youth involved…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The outcome of the last 2 elections has saddened me…&lt;br>
on how unfair, backwards, upside down, unbalanced, untruthful,&lt;br>
corrupt, and just simply, how wrong the world and &amp;ldquo;politics&amp;rdquo; are…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So this year i wanted to get involved and do all i could early…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And i found myself torn…&lt;br>
because this time it’s not that simple…&lt;br>
our choices aren’t as clear as the last elections …&lt;br>
last time it was so obvious…&lt;br>
Bush and war vs. no bush and no war…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But this time it’s not that simple…&lt;br>
and there are a lot of people that are torn just like i am…&lt;br>
So for awhile I put it off and i was going to wait until it was decided for me…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then came New Hampshire…&lt;br>
And i was captivated…&lt;br>
Inspired…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I reflected on my life…&lt;br>
and the blessings I have…&lt;br>
and the people who fought for me to have these rights and blessings…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>and I’m not talking about a &amp;ldquo;black thing&amp;rdquo;&lt;br>
I’m talking about a &amp;ldquo;human thing&amp;rdquo; me as a &amp;ldquo;person&amp;rdquo;&lt;br>
an American…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That speech made me think of Martin Luther King…&lt;br>
Kennedy…&lt;br>
and Lincoln…&lt;br>
and all the others that have fought for what we have today…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>what America is &amp;ldquo;supposed&amp;rdquo; to be…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>freedom…&lt;br>
equality…&lt;br>
and truth…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>and thats not what we have today…&lt;br>
we think we are free…&lt;br>
but in reality terror and fear controls our decisions…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>this is not the America that our pioneers and leaders fought and&lt;br>
died for…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>and then there was New Hampshire&lt;/p>
&lt;p>it was that speech…&lt;br>
like many great speeches…&lt;br>
that one moved me…&lt;br>
because words and ideas are powerful…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It made me think…&lt;br>
and realize that today we have &amp;ldquo;very few&amp;rdquo; leaders…&lt;br>
maybe none…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>but that speech…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>it inspired me…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>it inspired me to look inside myself and outwards towards the world…&lt;br>
it inspired me to want to change myself to better the world…&lt;br>
and take a &amp;ldquo;leap&amp;rdquo; towards change…&lt;br>
and hope that others become inspired to do the same…&lt;br>
change themselves..&lt;br>
change their greed…&lt;br>
change their fears…&lt;br>
and if we &amp;ldquo;change that&amp;rdquo;&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;then hey&amp;rdquo;..&lt;br>
we got something right…???…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 week later after the speech settled in me…&lt;br>
I began making this song…&lt;br>
I came up with the idea to turn his speech into a song…&lt;br>
because that speech effected and touched my inner core like nothing in a very long time…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>it spoke to me…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>because words and ideas are powerful…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I just wanted to add a melody to those words…&lt;br>
I wanted the inspiration that was bubbling inside me to take over…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>so i let it..&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wasn’t afraid to stand for something…&lt;br>
to stand for &amp;ldquo;change&amp;rdquo;…&lt;br>
I wasn’t afraid of &amp;ldquo;fear&amp;rdquo;…&lt;br>
it was pure inspiration…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>so I called my friends…&lt;br>
and they called their friends…&lt;br>
in a matter of 2 days…&lt;br>
We made the song and video…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Usually this process would take months…&lt;br>
a bunch of record company people figuring out strategies and release dates…&lt;br>
interviews…&lt;br>
all that stuff…&lt;br>
but this time i took it in my own hands…&lt;br>
so i called my friends sarah pantera, mike jurkovac, fred goldring, and jesse dylan to help make it happen…&lt;br>
and they called their friends..&lt;br>
and we did it together in 48 hours…&lt;br>
and instead of putting it in the hands of profit we put it in the hands of inspiration…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>then we put it on the net for the world to feel…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you are truly inspired..&lt;br>
magic happens…&lt;br>
incredible things happen…&lt;br>
love happens..&lt;br>
(and with that combination)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;love, and inspiration&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>change happens…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;change for the better&amp;rdquo;&lt;br>
Inspiration breeds change…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Positive change&amp;rdquo;…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>no one on this planet is truly experienced to handle the obstacles we face today…&lt;br>
Terror, fear, lies, agendas, politics, money, all the above…&lt;br>
It’s all scary…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Martin Luther King didn’t have experience to lead…&lt;br>
Kennedy didn’t have experience to lead…&lt;br>
Susan B. Anthony…&lt;br>
Nelson Mandella…&lt;br>
Rosa Parks…&lt;br>
Gandhi…&lt;br>
Anne Frank…&lt;br>
and everyone else who has had a hand in molding the freedoms we have and take for granted today…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>no one truly has experience to deal with the world today…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>they just need &amp;ldquo;desire, strength, courage ability, and passion&amp;rdquo; to change…&lt;br>
and to stand for something even when people say it’s not possible…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>America would not be here &amp;ldquo;today&amp;rdquo; if we didn’t stand and fight for&lt;br>
change &amp;ldquo;yesterday&amp;rdquo;…&lt;br>
Everything we have as a &amp;ldquo;people&amp;rdquo; is because of the &amp;ldquo;people&amp;rdquo; who fought for&lt;br>
change…&lt;br>
and whoever is the President has to realize we have a lot of changing to do&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m not trying to convince people to see things how i do…&lt;br>
I produced this song to share my new found inspiration and how I’ve been moved…&lt;br>
I hope this song will make you feel…&lt;br>
love…&lt;br>
and think…&lt;br>
and be inspired just like the speech inspired me…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>that’s all…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let’s all come together like America is supposed to…&lt;br>
Like Japan did after Hiroshima…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>that was less than 65 years ago…&lt;br>
and look at Japan now…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>they did it together…&lt;br>
they did it…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;We can’t?…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Are you serious..?..&lt;/p>
&lt;p>WE CAN!!!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes we can…&lt;br>
A United &amp;ldquo;America&amp;rdquo;&lt;br>
Democrats, Republicans and Independents together…&lt;br>
Building a new America&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We can do it…&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;TOGETHER&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This is the original speech which inspired the song, it is art in its own right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/Fe751kMBwms&amp;amp;rel=1" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">5&lt;/a>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/Fe751kMBwms&amp;amp;rel=1" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">5&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Debating &amp;amp; Afghanistan</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-02-debating-afghanistan/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-02-debating-afghanistan/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last night I nerded out, as I am wonk to do.  Doug and I watched the entire debate in utter, wonk bliss.  The shivs were there, but both candidates kept them under the table. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Both candidates showed off the intricacies of their handle on the policy.  Both candidates were eloquent, prepared and insightful. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>I won’t cry if Hillary wins.  And, BTW, I won’t threaten to move to Canada if McCain wins as on my major issues of international reengagement and the environment they are all three virtually in alignment.  Although I worry about what McCain will do to the Supreme Court when Stevens or RBG croaks and that that will have long term deleterious effects for our country.  Even if you are a conservative you must know that will not be good for the country. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yet, I was inspired by Barak; I was reassured that he can be wonkish plus still give me optimism.  For calling myself a progressive, I’ve come around slowly on Barak due to concerns about this issue, but also just because it is difficult to believe. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>For so much of my life politicians have been somethings that really haven’t impacted on my life, and if they have it has not be positive.  I feel disenfranchised from the entire process.  While Big_Head has been in love with political process for a while, I’ve come around slowly.  It has taken this election to engage me.  Now I pray at the alter of John King’s bibliographical mind and crazy hands on that freaking board on CNN that I love. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>But more than that I’ve come around to believe.  To really want someone to win, not just shrug my shoulders, and certainly not shake my head. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think that when people get passionate about politics, especially left-wingers, they fail to understand how things really work in Washington.  I think for the most part Barak and Hillary will be able to accomplish very similar things in Washington.  Both will take aggressive stances on progressive issues, and with a Democratic congress will push through some things and will see some other things fail.  Both will do approximately the same thing that McCain will do on Iraq and will likely take very similar foreign policy stances – in reality (no matter what any one says on the trail to pander to their bases).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So on the one hand the problems and solutions are so complex that there is a limiting  mechanism that kicks in after inauguration.  I am interested when people really debate what a President’s position is on many of these issues, as if the Executive didn’t have to go to Congress.  Most of what is being talked about in the debates, no matter who wins, is going to have to get pushed through Congress.  It is not like if Hillary wins we get universal healthcare the next day.  The President can only do so much on domestic issues.  That aside.  At the end of the day, for me, their relative collapse on the issues cuts towards Obama. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sure there is the thing about Hillary and the war, and maybe that will resonate with some people, especially core partisans.  She is getting demolished by the press for the answer she gave about Iraq.  But those people are playing partisan politics via the media.  I thought her answer was straight-forward and honest, it was eloquent, pragmatic and reasoned and I whole heartedly disagree with those people that have been turned off by that answer.  I thought what she said was on point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But, that isn’t what I care about.  I care about hope.  And I feel that I’ve found it in Obama.  I’m engaged, and, for once, I’m optimistic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is much more analysis in my head but this should suffice for now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After the dem’s debate finished, I kept flipping through my Gazillion channels to find more punditry as John King was cut off too quickly for my likes.  Flipped through CSPAN, and there was a Senate Foreign Relations Hearing about what the HELL are we going to do in Afghanistan.  It was UTTERLY fascinating!!!!  Afghanistan is so messed up right now.  If you want to know about it, read the Foreignpolicy.com article below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://blog.foreignpolicy.com/node/8014" title="It seems Europe is determined to lose in Afghanistan | FP Passport">It seems Europe is determined to lose in Afghanistan&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the major problems that I see occurring time and again is the lack of judicial sector reform.  I think that post-conflict transitions are going to soon be in a place where my aggresive ROL reforms that I’ve been formulating in my head will become international best practices.  We need to train police and judges and prosecutors and defense attorneys better after a country &amp;ldquo;cleans up&amp;rdquo; (whatever that means).  For now that is all I’ll say as I’m still formulating most of the theorem. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Jimmy Carter Speaks the Troof</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-01-15-jimmy-carter-speaks-the-troof/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-01-15-jimmy-carter-speaks-the-troof/</guid><description>&lt;p>[![Jimmycarter][2]][2]&lt;br>
[I Got What America Needs Right Here | The Onion][2]  Jimmy Carter OpEd on the Onion.  Don’t knock it, Jimmy knows his shit!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2008/01/15/jimmycarter.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2008/01/15/jimmycarter.jpg&lt;/a>
[2]: &lt;a href="http://www.theonion.com/content/opinion/i_got_what_america_needs_right">http://www.theonion.com/content/opinion/i_got_what_america_needs_right&lt;/a> &amp;ldquo;I Got What America Needs Right Here | The Onion - America's Finest News Source&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Richardson is Out</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-01-12-richardson-is-out/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-01-12-richardson-is-out/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am sad to &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2008/01/10/us/politics/10richardson.html?ref=politics">see Bill Richardson drop out &lt;/a>of &lt;a href="http://thecaucus.blogs.nytimes.com/2008/01/10/richardson-drops-out/">the Presidential Race&lt;/a>.  He has had my support for a long time because of his int’l credentials; his moderate but competent domestic policies; and most of all his realism. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/tjOuL5qwNIc&amp;amp;rel=1&amp;amp;border=1" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">3&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now I hope that he gets onto the backs of one of the two major campaigns, and by one I mean the right one for my target age bracket!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In other political news, NYT has a grand article about what &lt;a href="http://thecaucus.blogs.nytimes.com/2008/01/11/democrats-mccain-and-the-iraq-war/">Dean wants to attack McCain on&lt;/a>.  Very good journalism I say.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why the Democrats aren&amp;#8217;t ending the war. &amp;#8211; By Fred Kaplan &amp;#8211; Slate Magazine</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-12-21-why-the-democrats-arent-ending-the-war-by-fred-kaplan-slate-magazine/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-12-21-why-the-democrats-arent-ending-the-war-by-fred-kaplan-slate-magazine/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.slate.com/id/2180470/fr/rss/" title="Why the Democrats aren't ending the war. - By Fred Kaplan - Slate Magazine">This&lt;/a> is one of the most informative and balanced pieces on Iraq I’ve read in AGES.  Not sure of its accuracy, but it certainly isn’t too glowing about either party.  I think this is the level of public debate that needs to really be entered into as I detest the black and white stay or leave debate which really gets no one anywhere.  Some of the musings of politicos lately have been whether the American people are able to hear complexity out of their politicians.  Most times I scream yes, but after a trip to Waffle House I think maybe not. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Put this one in your toolkit</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-12-20-put-this-one-in-your-toolkit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-12-20-put-this-one-in-your-toolkit/</guid><description>&lt;p>[![Captainmorgan2][2]][2]&lt;br>
I remember one time when Evergreen and I were in the Marine Corps.  He was so tired and it was so dark outside that he heated up a bag of peanut butter to put in his cheese ravioli bag of treats.  It was so disgusting that he had to go hungry or eat it, considering the circumstances (we were on one meal a day for the exercise and all exhausted and constantly hungry) he ate it, but I will always remember the look on his face when he turned to me and said in his Texas draw, &amp;ldquo;Casey, put this one in your toolkit, always check if the bag is peanut butter or cheese cause if you get this one wrong it’ll costya.&amp;rdquo;  The story is mainly funny to me because of the look of utter destituteness that was on Evergreen’s face when he took that first bite and embarked on the slow realization of what had happened to him, and the realization was slow because of how absolutely exhausted and hungry we all were after a long night of patrolling or whatever we had been doing all we wanted to do was sit down and have a bit of a meal before we started the next day (all this happened just before dawn) of the same grueling stuff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/12/20/captainmorgan2.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/12/20/captainmorgan2.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So now, I give you all one.  Never freeze the European Captain, because unlike American Captain, it freezes.  Not really sure why, but it does.  I am neither hungry, nor thirsty, nor exhausted, nor destitute like Evergreen was in that story, so maybe this isn’t terrible funny, but it IS informative and gives me an excuse to pose a picture of the good Captain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Social Networking for Good</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-12-20-social-networking-for-good/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-12-20-social-networking-for-good/</guid><description>&lt;p>So, I’m not really sure what good can come about by &amp;ldquo;friending&amp;rdquo; on MySpace a bunch of organizations that do good work.  I guess on one level it warms the heart of the friender, knowing that they are on the in with these organizations.  I guess it can also bolster the &amp;ldquo;rolls&amp;rdquo; of the friendee, something that poli_sci has consistently told me is key to grassroots organizing as the bigger the rolls the more money they can potentially raise by leveraging that list to similar organizations that need to get a hold of similar people or from foundations who use the rolls as a proxy for the amount of good the organization will be able to accomplish (similar to a business plan for a small-business loan the grant writing proposal (apparently) can swing for or against often times based upon the size of the roll like the amount of the small-business owner’s money that is already invested in the business). 
It seems, to me, that the other thing that is happening is that it keeps my bookmarks clean.  Anally retentive people’s ears perk up at this.  I can just go to mySpace and find out about organizations rather than having to open each in a separate tab in my firefox browser (i find it amusing that the firefox browser tags itself as a misspelled word). 
Have just seen the MySpace Impact Awards.  Apparently MySpace gives these away every quarter, or month or something.  It is a $10k grant, but more importantly (for most organizations) is the free advertising that MySpace will deliver to its 40Zillion users.  The criteria for winning are supposedly:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The Committee will select three (3) finalists from all entries eligible&lt;br>
for the Grand Prize that are received during the Contest Submission&lt;br>
Period based on the discretion of each of the judges, based on the&lt;br>
following judging criteria (the “Judging Criteria”):  25% relevance to&lt;br>
the month’s category, 25% use of MySpace toolset to promote the cause&lt;br>
(i.e. good profile design, incorporating multi-media, active engagement&lt;br>
with the MySpace community, etc.), 25% breadth of reach and appeal, and&lt;br>
25% fit with the culture of MySpace.
I included the criteria because it is interesting how subjective it all is.  Hipsters judging hipsters.  Nevertheless.  They have six main categories, they seem to rotate every month or quarter whenever the award is given:
[![][2]][2]
[![][3]][3]
[![][4]][4]
[![][5]][5]
[![][6]][6]
[![][7]][7]
Find something you care about, get involved.  Do some good. 
~ # ~
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.myspace.com/impactawards">http://www.myspace.com/impactawards&lt;/a>
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.myspace.com/impactawards">http://www.myspace.com/impactawards&lt;/a>
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.myspace.com/impactawards">http://www.myspace.com/impactawards&lt;/a>
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.myspace.com/impactawards">http://www.myspace.com/impactawards&lt;/a>
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.myspace.com/impactawards">http://www.myspace.com/impactawards&lt;/a>
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.myspace.com/impactawards">http://www.myspace.com/impactawards&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Cultural Questionings</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-12-19-cultural-questionings/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-12-19-cultural-questionings/</guid><description>&lt;p>[![Website_santa_hat5][2]][2]&lt;br>
I’m certainly no expert on Dutch culture or Dutch language, but can anyone tell me if there are even Dutch words for the following English equivalents: &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/12/19/website_santa_hat5.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/12/19/website_santa_hat5.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Pardon Me.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Excuse Me.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I’m Sorry.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I Apologize.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It Was My Fault.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>If there are, I certainly haven’t ever heard them.  Back in the land I love, or the land that I love to make fun of for the holidays.  Well, I’ll be in Scotland for the holidays proper but here in Hague before/afta. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nothing special to report, so Happy Holidays to all!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hold on Saakashvili!</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-11-07-hold-on-saakashvili/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-11-07-hold-on-saakashvili/</guid><description>&lt;p>[![07georms2650][2]][2]&lt;br>
Georgia was [AMAZING][2].  Highlands and I went there this past summer and I really fell in love with the people, with the environment, with the food, with the wine, with most everything there.  It is disappointing that there are many [allegations][3] of extensive human rights violations by the country and that there is the (real or not) perception of rampant corruption in the country.  These allegations have led to [massive protests ][4]in beautiful old Tbilisi.  There are huge possibilities for good in this country and I hope that the President, Saakashvili is smart enough to be able to quell this thing without having to resort to Soviet era tactics of repression.  I will be an unequivocal supporter of him if he can figure out a way to address the core of what the protestors are saying (his administration is a bastion of cronyism and the opposition’s voice is being suppressed using state resources). &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/11/07/07georms2650.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/11/07/07georms2650.jpg&lt;/a>
[2]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/photos/im_so_caucasian/index.html">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/photos/im_so_caucasian/index.html&lt;/a>
[3]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/underwater/2007/08/georgia-politic.html">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/underwater/2007/08/georgia-politic.html&lt;/a>
[4]: &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2007/11/08/world/europe/08georgia.html?hp">http://www.nytimes.com/2007/11/08/world/europe/08georgia.html?hp&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Photo by: Shakh Aivazov/The Associated Press&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nobel Racist</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-18-nobel-racist/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-18-nobel-racist/</guid><description>&lt;p>James Watson, pride of American science?  A bloody racist is more like it.  This angers me, it confirms, yet again, to the rest of the world what god damn idiots many Americans are. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/aponline/world/AP-Britain-Controversial-Scientist.html" title="Controversial DNA Pioneer's Talk Halted - New York Times">Controversial DNA Pioneer’s Talk Halted&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Georgia Politicians Get Jail Terms</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-08-28-georgia-politicians-get-jail-terms/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-08-28-georgia-politicians-get-jail-terms/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://english.aljazeera.net/NR/exeres/38CFA15A-E13A-4C57-98A1-930E500439DD.htm" title="Al Jazeera English - News - Georgia Politicians Get Jail Terms">This&lt;/a> cannot be good for relations between Russia and Georgia.  Highlands and I were just in Georgia a few weeks ago and it was a wonderful country with rugged mountains, wonderful people and a good government that is making many good steps (at least good as defined by Western governments, but this normative relativity varies in proportion to the square of your distance from Moscow).  I fell in love with the country. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>When we left the country to go to Azerbaijan (Which is another story entirely, that autocratic, authoritarian, repressive state took our Lonely Planet guidebook and in general I have very little good to say about Az, except that many of the non-government people we met were quite nice.) Russia &amp;ldquo;bombed&amp;rdquo; Georgia.  The bomb was a dud that landed in some farmer’s backyard about half-way between Tbilisi (the capital) and the border with Russia.  There were a lot of odd things about that that I thought at the time but cannot currently remember.  Nonetheless it was sketchy at best. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Saakashvili, Georgia’s president, was supposed to meet with Putin in order to quell some of the tensions, (at least ostensibly) but I am not sure whether that happened or not.  Whether it did or not seems immaterial to this inflaming further tensions between the two.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>next issue</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-19-next-issue/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-19-next-issue/</guid><description>&lt;p>i like the SNL skit where they make fun of that sunday morning news show.  and they use ‘next issue’ to punctuate debates.  i’ll think of the name of it in a minute. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>i finish with the court tomorrow, although i’ll be in holland for another week and probably in and out of the office to tidy up a few things.  the rest of the summer will be spent all over.  a map is embedded for you to follow along.  the highlights.  fly to Tbilisi, Georgia, then go to the Georgian Mountains to dodge sketchy Chechnyan Separatists and their land mines.  Then down to the Georgian Wine Country to get drunk.  Then to Azerbaijan mainly because I like its name.  Then back to Schipel to drop Highlands off and pick up my dad.  Then to Prague, Berlin, Cologne and then back to Amsterdam.  Then I have two nights and a day with Highlands and then I fly from AMS to Miami via London.  So it will be crazy.  Pictures and Updated Where is Casey as we go along.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> 
MapKit.display();&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>wow</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-17-wow-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-17-wow-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>i’m not naive enough to think that the causal links for this video can be traced all the way up the leadership chain to bush.  whatever happened is probably too complex to comment upon.  but what i can comment upon is that i hope to god this is some sick fucking joke, and if it is not  then this simple-minded moron should be taken out of the gene pool.  i know this much, none of my marines treated any iraqi’s like this and if i would have caught them they would have been taken out of the gene pool. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>the worst thing, I think is how proud this son of a bitch thinks that he is about what he did.  hopefully it is a joke.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>irrepressible.info</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-13-irrepressible-info/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-13-irrepressible-info/</guid><description>&lt;p>this is a fantastic idea which i actually wrote about in a paper.  amnesty and an IT company have formed an ngo titled &lt;a href="http://irrepressible.info/">irrepressible.info&lt;/a> which takes content that is banned categorically and decentralized it onto other people’s blogs.  that way countries which have categorical firewalls which block user’s ability to visit certain pages (e.g. HRW, AI, etc.) are enabled to see the content.  way to go technology.  in other news i’m figuring out how to put code onto my blog…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>var irr_lang = ‘en’;&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br>
~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>stories from right here</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-03-stories-from-right-here/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-03-stories-from-right-here/</guid><description>&lt;p>I think that Nora Ephron thinks that she is hilarious.  I think she is a bore.  And a bitch, but that is a different story predicated on seeing her in Asssspen a few summers ago and being majorly turned off by her snooty attitude.  &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2007/07/01/opinion/01ephron.html?em&amp;amp;ex=1183608000&amp;amp;en=d78d8e63a86f389d&amp;amp;ei=5087" title="The Six Stages of E-Mail - New York Times">Link&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There was another intersting article in the NYT’s which speaks about Buying into the Green Movement and links between hip stylings in the name of save the earth that really are consumerism light and still have drastic impact on the planet.  lexus hybid SUV?  still requires massive amounts of corrosives and other chemicals to build, still gets 22 MPG (my car with regular gas engine averages 30 MPG).  &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2007/07/01/fashion/01green.html?em&amp;amp;ex=1183608000&amp;amp;en=7374899c96860ba1&amp;amp;ei=5087">Link.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>highlands is visiting the highlands.  we spoke last night and she told me funny stories from the local papers about the scottish baggage handler who helped the police apprehend the terrorists at the glasgow airport by punching him….what a concept…too bad those at virginia tech didn’t have a little more scot blood in them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>as for the weekend, i did nothing and it was fantabulous.  i did meet with one of my mentors which was great.  we are hopefully going to be working on some good projects this fall, the nice thing for me is that they may link to what i’m doing now.  it will be quite nice to not be starting from step one, as per the norm in law school.  it will be nice to be able to dive deeply having much of the introduction stuff out of the way.  but for now i’m working on my paper from SL titled:  Sleepy Justice: Sierra Leone’s Lack of Self-Help in Judicial Sector Reform…or something similar.  I’ll post it when it is presentable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Beam It Down From the Web, Scotty</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-05-08-beam-it-down-from-the-web-scotty/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-05-08-beam-it-down-from-the-web-scotty/</guid><description>&lt;p>if you haven’t seen &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2007/05/07/technology/07copy.html?em&amp;amp;ex=1178769600&amp;amp;en=5712293e5df2be10&amp;amp;ei=5087" title="Beam It Down From the Web, Scotty - New York Times">this&lt;/a> article, you should.  it is flippin’ crazy. i want to print out a nice tulia style burrito from amigos with chips, salsa and some water with that ICE….!!! wonder if this will enable humans to be even more lazy in their shopping and when they shop….could make xmas even an exciting time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>worrisome coding&amp;#8230;</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-03-08-worrisome-coding/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-03-08-worrisome-coding/</guid><description>&lt;p>i have become increasingly worried about the ubiquity of Times New Roman…as an ethos.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>personally, i prefer Century New Schoolbook, but when i need a break, to relax, i choose garamond.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Be My Anti-Valentine</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-15-be-my-anti-valentine/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-15-be-my-anti-valentine/</guid><description>&lt;p>Check out this site.  My office and I laughed for hours about some of the cards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Link: &lt;a href="http://www.meish.org/vd/" title="meish.org :: Be My Anti-Valentine">meish.org :: Be My Anti-Valentine&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>media created gaps in propaganda</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-07-media-created-gaps-in-propaganda/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-07-media-created-gaps-in-propaganda/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.icc-cpi.int/library/organs/otp/OTP_letter_to_senders_re_Iraq_9_February_2006.pdf">THiS is&lt;/a> a letter from the Prosecutor of the ICC. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yesterday I wrote about the gaps in the climate change debate.  This document was written in February, 2006 and is the Prosecutor’s response to requests that he look into the Iraq situation.  He lays out his legal authority and his decision space in a very nice, non-lawyer-friendly manner.  And then he says, thank you but no. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, there were no requests that he investigate US actors in Iraq, becuase the US and Iraq are not a state parties to the ICC.  In order for the ICC to prosecute something one of three things has to happen.  (1) The action was perpetrated by a national of one of the state parties. (2) The action was perpetrated on the territory of one of the state parties. (3) Either the territory where the action took place or the nationality of the actor must concede jurisdiction on a case by case basis.  None of those things happened with regards to the US actors in Iraq.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, with regards to the Brits and Aussies who are, actually, world citizens and a part of the ICC, their nationals were subject to the jurisdiction of the ICC.  That means that the prosecutor had the power to investigate their soldiers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now all this is a prelude to my point.  I am intrigued by what he says.  He says that there was a basis for a reasonable belief that crimes were commited, but that the gravity of the crimes was low enough that he was not going to pursue an investigation.  Everyone gets so wrapped around the axel on Iraq, and rightly so, it is a quagmire.  However, it is telling when he says that the number of victims of crimes in Iraq totals in the dozens (less than forty total).  In the three cases where he has actually pursued full investigations (two of which led to indictments and one has a case starting soon) the number of victims totals in the thousands or millions.  This disparity is so huge and is completely missed by the media.  We spend so much of our media attention on Iraq and other things (NaSA love triangles I hear is currently popular for infotainment) and so very little on the real humanity of the situation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is about all I have to say about that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The real deal?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-06-the-real-deal-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-06-the-real-deal-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.canada.com/nationalpost/story.html?id=156df7e6-d490-41c9-8b1f-106fef8763c6&amp;amp;k=44510" title="The real deal?">The real deal?&lt;/a> is an article that addresses real or percieved gaps in the current debate on climate change.  I agree heartily that there are gaps. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>i understand what this article is trying to argue, but i don’t agree. this article cites one israeli scientist that published one paper that may or may not have been peer reviewed and claims that there is a scientific debate. in fact what the IPCC found is that there is a greater than 90% chance that climate change is caused by human factors. the FDA uses a figure something on the order of 20 – 30 % chance that there is a link between a drug and side effect or between a food and harmful effect in order to make policy decisions about whether to approve a drug, take it off the shelves or whatnot. the EPA uses an even lower figure as to the chance of a causal actually exists and whether or not to make policy decisions based upon it. in each of these policy realms where science is invoked it will never be precise. there will always be critics. however what policy makers must do is to set limits and do an economic analysis of the cost and benefits in real monetary terms and in (i would argue) human terms. now if the EPA and FDA make decisions in the presence of a 30% (maximum) probability that there is a causal link that will impact, what are we doing absolutely nothing when there is now a high degree of consensus that the probability of the human-climate change link is three times that high. i understand the argument that if some regulation/legislation were passed then it will have more drastic overall economic consequences to the entire economy rather than the relatively isolated sectoral effects that would be felt when the other, but similar, governmental bodies pass science-based policy measures. however when the probability of the causal link is this high, it seems that we have reached the point that something needs to be done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>there are various ways that, on its face, this one scientists’ arguments implode on themselves. i will put those aside b/c they are too easy to address.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i agree that there is a gap in the media’s propoganda machine. but gaps are inevitable. they will exist no matter the issue. the only way to fix that from a policy perspective is transparency (something that cam and I are basing much of our ethos on). there has been, to date, a lack of transparency in the government as to why nothing has been done. because of this lack of governmental/political debate we are left to propoganda from whatever side one must swing on. if inaction is the proper action (which i categorically deny that it is correct here, but in other situations inaction may be more efficient/equitable), then the populace needs to be convinced by the government that failed to act as to why they chose inaction. this is the feedback loop that i think only partially exists.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>my chinese space</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-11-11-my-chinese-space/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-11-11-my-chinese-space/</guid><description>&lt;p>news corp generally, i think, sucks.  however this is a good thing.  the problem is that there are korean and japanese &amp;ldquo;versions&amp;rdquo; of social networking that blow my space’s flat categories and horrible layouts away.  these asain sites are apparently [sic] with 3d anime that is user controlled where people build living spaces and avatars and interact in much more social ways.  myspace is flat, not very interactive, and very western….identifying yourself by your likes in certain predefined categories and then being able to &amp;ldquo;hook up&amp;rdquo; with those of the same preferences.  despite john cusak’s rant in high fidelity, it is a fairly arbitrary way to build and maintain relationships.  that aside it is a good thing if myspace can creap into the chinese market for many reasons.  any additional means of communication that chinese web users have is another way for the rest of the world to get access to the real attrocities that are going on there, if there are any.  and i’m sure there are.  i’m writing an entire paper that is, essentially, railing on the traditional way that law regulates things, how that is not exactly analogizeable to the internet, and how a different approach would work much better for the us companies, for human rights advocates, and for web users in internet suppressing countries.  congress has been extremely myopic in its one publicly contemplated response to the collusion with china by google, yahoo and microsoft.  i intend to show how a different approach, less rooted in traditional legality, would have much better results legally as well as policy-ly.  it will be out after christmas.  now back to writing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Link: &lt;a href="http://www.danwei.org/media_business/rupert_murdoch_and_wendy_in_to.php" title="Rupert Murdoch and Wendy in town for a shmooze">Rupert Murdoch and Wendy in town for a shmooze&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>to plant a tree</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-11-08-to-plant-a-tree/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-11-08-to-plant-a-tree/</guid><description>&lt;p>the african environmental advocate who is the only african female nobel laureate is now starting a program to plant a billion trees world wide.  advantages: soil stability, carbon sequestration, jobs, beauty.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>disadvantages?  can’t really think of anything, other than where is the $ going to come from. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>see, this is the type of solution that &lt;a href="http://www.grist.org/news/maindish/2005/01/13/werbach-reprint/">adam&lt;/a> would advocate for.  rather than spending gagillians of dollars on technological solutions that will only benefit a few smart, well-to-do people.  the distribution of the benefits of this solution are correct: it benefits financially those that need it, it benefits environmentally on a regional (soil stability) and global level (carbon sequestration).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Link: &lt;a href="http://today.reuters.co.uk/news/articlenews.aspx?type=scienceNews&amp;amp;storyID=2006-11-08T131740Z_01_WAL844945_RTRIDST_0_SCIENCE-ENVIRONMENT-TREES-DC.XML&amp;amp;pageNumber=0&amp;amp;imageid=&amp;amp;cap=&amp;amp;sz=13&amp;amp;WTModLoc=NewsArt-C1-ArticlePage2" title="Africa's Nobel laureate says plant a billion trees | Science&amp;amp;Health | Science | Reuters.co.uk">Africa’s Nobel laureate says plant a billion trees | Science&amp;amp;Health | Science | Reuters.co.uk&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>my uncle planted trees for a while.  he seems to look on that time in his life fondly.  hard work, but out in nature.  maybe if i don’t get a lawyer job i can just do this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chavez in Russia for arms deals</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-07-25-chavez-in-russia-for-arms-deals/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-07-25-chavez-in-russia-for-arms-deals/</guid><description>&lt;p>Chavez signs a deal with Russia.  This is HUGE.  I cannot believe that the US press is not picking up on this.  Understandably there is a lot going on in the world and if you are passionately positioned on either side of the Israel-Arab tension then you would prefer to be hearing of other things and if you are positioned in the heat that is engulfing the entire west coast then you may also have other things on your mind. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, this has massive, long term implications for US Policy in our hemisphere.  In my mind it is more impactful than the Cuban missile crisis for this reason:  Cuba was an isolate proxy with limited economic power.  Venezuela has a relatively stable government, Chavez is fairly entrenched for the foreseeable future, their oil reserves enable the country to pursue a long-term, viable economy.  Cuba had none of these, they relied completely on the Soviets for whatever materiel and training support needed.  Ven on the other hand will not have to rely on anyone for the materiel support or the economic support.  They will have to get the education and training in order to really utilize any advanced weapon systems, but for state actors that is easy enough to achieve.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The real problem is that to date the US has successfully kept any of the countries in our hemisphere from becoming a real military powerhouse unless their governments are imperialistic proxies and beholden to us.  Ven is a wildcard and Chavez’s recent efforts to expand his power and influence in the region will only be amplified if he can get his hands on some symbols of nationalistic power and entrance into a more elite group. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is too much here and I wish that I would be seeing more on it, this has large not in my backyard implications as well as (and I may be being a bit fatalistic) it may signal the beginning of the end of the monroe doctrine (which would crumble not from external pressure from the rest of the world, but from internal pressure from the &amp;ldquo;protectorate&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Source: &lt;a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/world/europe/5213334.stm" title="BBC NEWS | World | Europe | Chavez in Russia for arms deals">BBC NEWS. Chavez in Russia for arms deals&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Scientific Breakdown of Global Warming</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-07-25-scientific-breakdown-of-global-warming/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-07-25-scientific-breakdown-of-global-warming/</guid><description>&lt;p>YOU too should see an Inconvenient Truth.  I saw it for the second time this past weekend when I was home in ORL.  In case you don’t understand the science of it click here and become an informed voter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.sciam.com/print_version.cfm?articleID=000F22D3-EBEF-14C0-AB7083414B7F4945" title="Scientific American: If carbon dioxide makes up only a minute portion of the atmosphere, how can global warming be traced to it? And how can such a tiny amount of change produce such large effects?">Scientific American: If carbon dioxide makes up only a minute portion of the atmosphere, how can global warming be traced to it? And how can such a tiny amount of change produce such large effects?&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>there isn&amp;#8217;t much you can do, except realize&amp;#8230;</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-07-21-there-isnt-much-you-can-do-except-realize/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-07-21-there-isnt-much-you-can-do-except-realize/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://hrw.org/campaigns/drc/2006/katanga/slideshow.htm">that africa is fucked.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>this seems (mostly) right</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-07-21-this-seems-mostly-right/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-07-21-this-seems-mostly-right/</guid><description>&lt;p>most of you know where i want to go with my career.  this has been cemented over the course of the summer and my participation in both meaningless and meaningful litigation and policy development here in the US.  my platform: assisting developing countries in pulling themselves out of poverty without mortgaging their environments to do so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>the following excerpt is from a &lt;a href="http://www.cfr.org/publication/11123/india_nuclear_deal.html">council on foreign relations publication&lt;/a> on the nuclear deal the US cut with India to establish a commercial (thereby non-weapons grade or adaptable) nuclear deal where the US will help India establish a nuclear program.  i think that these types of programs are positives in stable governments, but we shouldn’t be rushing to make them.  in a stable government transparency breeds accountability.  but in an unstable government such a program would merely injest an unnecessary skill set into a population group that may use it for non-commercial practices.  i think that if we use this as a carrot/stick approach in our outlook to developing followup programs with other developing countries we will be OK.  what i don’t really think is right, and i think what this guy is arguing, is that this sort of deal should be a paradigm for our future energy dealings with other nations.  i hesitate to christen any sort of &amp;ldquo;deal&amp;rdquo; as a paradigm when it is between countries.  treaties and intergovernmental contracts are not bridges that flow from a single paradigm and are modified to fit the specifics of the dirt structure and width that must be spanned.  these these are too societally dependent and when we try to establish paradigms or iconic deals we only set ourselves up for failures b/c we will inevitably discount the next deal and not thoroughly think through all the parameters that must be analyzed in the negotiation phase.  in short we will just base it on the last deal, b/c that one worked.  this laziness seems to happen a lot in politics and foreign relations and what i am wholeheartedly opposed to.  so here is the quote:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;h5 id="beyond-india-engaging-developing-countries">Beyond India: Engaging Developing Countries&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>Until now, developing countries have adamantly refused to limit their&lt;br>
emissions of greenhouse gases. These countries are wary that the possible high&lt;br>
costs of climate change mitigation will jeopardize their development goals. The&lt;br>
result of that opposition is the CDM—a system that compensates developing&lt;br>
countries for the full extra cost of any policies to control emissions. The CDM&lt;br>
was a good idea in principle, but in practice it is not working well. The scheme&lt;br>
has become mired in red tape as countries and investors try to establish their&lt;br>
baseline levels of emissions and the reduction in emissions from each project.&lt;br>
(The difference between the baseline and the reduced level is the key to the CDM&lt;br>
concept—that difference becomes a credit that can be used to offset emission&lt;br>
obligations elsewhere in the world, such as in Europe’s emission trading&lt;br>
system). The problems have encouraged gaming and they have caused CDM investors&lt;br>
to focus on activities that are easy to quantify and which are marginal in&lt;br>
nature. Indeed, energy projects account for just 17% of the CDM pipeline. Almost&lt;br>
none of the energy projects are of the type that will lead to fundamental&lt;br>
changes in countries’ energy systems.&lt;a href="#_ftn5">[5]&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If the India nuclear deal is successful, it will frame a new approach to&lt;br>
engaging developing countries in a climate strategy. This approach would focus&lt;br>
on finding game-changing policies that align with reluctant countries’&lt;br>
interests.&lt;a href="#_ftn6">[6]&lt;/a> Rather than involving hundreds of&lt;br>
small and marginal projects, this style of engagement would focus on just a&lt;br>
handful of large pivotal actions involving just a few critical countries. This&lt;br>
concept is incidentally at the core of the Asia-Pacific Partnership on Clean&lt;br>
Development and Climate, whose six members, including India and the U.S.,&lt;br>
account for half the world’s greenhouse gas emissions. That Partnership has&lt;br>
promise, but it remains young. Success with this nuclear deal could offer a&lt;br>
credible example of practical actions that the Partnership could encourage.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I admit to not having researched the &amp;ldquo;Partnership&amp;rdquo; that he cites at the end of the passage.  I know this much, if we keep basing our energy requirements upon coal we are not really going to get anywhere.  keeping coal production stationary without anything more is only going to hurt, even if we keep up with rising energy demands by substituting that additional delta with nuclear (therefore non-carbon emitting) energy.  this is for two reasons, one: the coal is going to likely get dirtier.  this has been happening over the past three decades as coal producers have seen a decrease in the BTU’s per ton of coal b/c it is not as &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; of coal.  most of the established mines are beginning to get the dregs and new exploration and development costs capital.  if i was in the energy industry (which is oxymoronic) i would sink all my capital investment money that i could spare into something else since the political and regulatory regime is inevitably going to get rockier in the next five to ten years.  there is too much risk there.  this flows into the second reason why we need to reduce and not to contain the amount of coal we use in energy production.  people (and the more likely players in my model, at least in america: the insurance companies, once the legal system actually holds them accountable for paying for the hurricanes and stops them from evading those payouts) are going to get sick of it.  they are going to eventually hold some political system accountable when the links are clearly established and the green left finally puts it all together into a cohesive package (rove style).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ok that is all for now.  this is deeply integrated in my mind: enviroments, trade, geopolitics, policies, economics, societies and cultural sytems.  i hope to keep blogging more on these themes and less on other banalities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>self-marketing</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-02-11-self-marketing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-02-11-self-marketing/</guid><description>&lt;p>so there are these sites.  some of you know of them.  friendster. my space. facebook.com.  they are all pretty much the same thing.  they are sites that allow you to tell people about your self:  fav movies, fav music, fav TV, quotes, &amp;ldquo;about me,&amp;rdquo; and other blase things. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>first you create yourself.  just like any other document (real or fake, static or dynamic) you choose which aspects of yourself to accentuate and whatever. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>after you have created yourself then you find friends.  many times one of your friends will have beaten you to the site and will already have created themself on the site.  sometimes you will be the first of your close friends.  whatever.  so then you ask them to be your little online friend.  and then they accept.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>once you have friends then you start to leave little funny messages on each other’s &amp;ldquo;walls&amp;rdquo; (bulletin boards, etc.).  mostly they are responsive so if someone is looking at your page they will only get half the story and thus be confused.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>you can then really mess the process up.  you can start to blog on these sites.  you can add pictures to the sites.  you can tag said pictures with your friends names so the pictures show up on their sites.  you can tell your entire community of friends about parties or plans.  you can take it to the next level by getting third-party add on templates which will fuck with the page’s CSS code to make it highly annoying to people like me.  you can add songs. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>it is fucking crazy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BUT, the craziness of it is not what i want to talk about on this not sunny, not cloudy, not cold, not warm, not spring, not summer saturday afternoon.  what i really want to talk about is how people choose to portray themselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>first you can read an article from a blogger who i’ve been reading for a few years.  she put it better than i can.  but i would like to update and respond to some of what she has said.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i have noticed some trends.  people tend to choose one way to portray themselves:  ironic, straightup, post-ironic, fun, withheld, intellectual, whatever the case may be.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i guess that is it.  and i cannot find the article.  so this sux.  sorry for wasting your time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>its like an allergy</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-02-03-its-like-an-allergy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-02-03-its-like-an-allergy/</guid><description>&lt;p>so i think that i was born like 5 years too early.  this is different than my usual time shifting desires where i think that i was born either fifty or twenty years too late.  but any way back to my rant of the day.  i think that i was born like 5 years too early. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>the main reason that leads me to say this is my utter inability to cross platform communicate.  i have reached this level that many my age haven’t.  i mean, hell, i do blog.  that comes from always being a tech-head, an occupational hazard from being born to a dude who was poking around with magnetic screwdrivers inside of IBM PC’s, XT’s and the sleek yet subdued AT’s at that strip mall computer joint circa 84 when the auto parts store fired him, or he left.  not sure i was small.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>yeah, so cross platform communication.  i have think i am an utter master at the independent forms of communication.  i can text while holding an apple in my mouth, changing my ipod music and driving with my knee over snowy vail pass.  i can blog.  i can talk on my cell phone.  i can talk to people.  i can email.  i can post messages on the wall’s of my friend’s facebook.com pages. i can see who was looking at my pages on friendster or my space.  i can virtual stalk my friends and laugh at their IM away messages and can even induce a few chuckles myself.  i can IM harrassing messages to my &amp;ldquo;colleagues&amp;rdquo; when they are called on in class and for some reason the IT people haven’t blocked the internet that particular class (of course this only happens when i remember to bring my wireless PCMCIA card, b/c i’m not advanced tech-boy and do not have this snazzy internal wireless thing….no wires….fucking genius.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>what i cannot really well is to transfer across these platforms.  for some reason i feel like communications which happened in one forum should stay in that forum only.  i have always known this, but it was driven home to me today when someone came up to me and said, &amp;ldquo;i just added you as a friend on facebook.&amp;rdquo; &lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;i know.&amp;rdquo;  i said with my crunched eyebrows face.  i’m not sure if i was confused as to whether he genuinely thought he was informing me.  was i confused b/c i’m not really his friend and we never talk and suddenly his clicking on my profile and the &amp;ldquo;add friend&amp;rdquo; button is the lubrication to get the ole’ engine of friendship and get to know ya started up again.  was i confused b/c i just don’t like to communicate out of context.  i’m not sure why i gave him that look, but i certainly did.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>oh well, it started a nice little chat with my new friend.  i know he is my friend to because i have a fucking web page with my name in bold and big font and he is listed under my friends.  maybe it is all growing on me.  maybe i just like to know who my friends are.  where do i title my BFF?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>t-shirt ideas</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-09-21-t-shirt-ideas/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-09-21-t-shirt-ideas/</guid><description>&lt;p>so i have the following t-shirt ideas that i thought would be funny.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[sic]&lt;br>
alPHA male (in white letters ona brilliant pink bkgnd)&lt;br>
if he was the last man alive (front)&lt;br>
    would you eat Chit?  (back)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>and one other i cannot remember&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>take that pat benatar</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-09-19-take-that-pat-benatar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-09-19-take-that-pat-benatar/</guid><description>&lt;p>direct quote:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It was never suggested that we had in this country a surplus of brain toilers…&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Supreme court decision, 1892.  Still OH So true today.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Confluence of Space and Non-Space</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-08-12-confluence-of-space-and-non-space/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-08-12-confluence-of-space-and-non-space/</guid><description>&lt;p>the internet is a fabulous, and deadly, weapon for mass destruction of society.  or maybe mass creation of different societies.  i’m not certain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>what i can be certain of is that i spent a good amount of time on said contraption this evening.  once i made the psychological and philosophical leap into the pool of law school, i made another leap.  i’m gonna be a rock star.  shit, i already have the hair for it, and fucking mick jagger and dylan cannot sing, so why should i be required to have that apptitude or ability?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>in that vein i decided that it was time to begin establishing my base of groupies.  well, how do you do that when registration/orientation is six days away?  you get on the secured forums and whore yourself out.  then you find out that all the kids are about aim, not any of the other messenger services, so you pick up that ole’ axe, dust it off, plug it into the foot pedal and then into the amp and you strum a couple of notes.  gingerly, tentatively, just testing out the ole’ axe to see what sound she may be capable of.  then you get a little more confident and so you play a little tune, and before you know it you are completely rocking out until your mom knocks on the door, but since you’re rocking out so hard you don’t hear her and then she opens the door to ask if you wanna wanna fanta fanta and she is on one of those fucking jet ski’s jetting through a faux-water-like surface with a fake wake and you don’t know how to reply so you just stare at her and let your axe hang around your neck, but the ole’ axe didn’t have a shoulder strap when you picked up that ole’ thing so when you let it hang, it doesn’t hang as much as fall to the ground and makes a huge, horrible cord-esque/reverb-esque sound that is lovely to you, but horrible to mom and when it dies down you look at her and say, &amp;ldquo;see what you did?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>yeah nothing like that happened to me, nothing even remotely close to that happened to me, nothing even in the spirit of that metaphor happened to me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i did however &amp;ldquo;meet&amp;rdquo; some people.  virtually, that means over the internet for the older listeners among you, &amp;ldquo;meet&amp;rdquo;-ed some people.  threw out a few funny emails, a bit of IM-ing banter, some networking (apparently friendster is D_E_A_D dead, in case you cared, the new friendster is facebook) sites where you put up your shit and they can all track you down….or something.  so my shite is out there and we’ll see how much of a rock star i can become.  needless to say, i’m getting it on virtual style. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>whatever happened to anticipation?  to getting to know people after you meet them on the big &amp;ldquo;first day of school&amp;rdquo; and then wondering which group you have the chance to fit in?  and if it is a conglomeration then maybe you should start your own group?  very uncomfortable….very exciting.  i guess i’ll only taste that.  but for now i’m happy being an internet rock star&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>