<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/</link><description>A Site About Resilience and Authoritarianism</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</managingEditor><webMaster>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</webMaster><copyright>All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Spectrum of Public to Private Service Delivery</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-01-24-spectrum-service-delivery/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-01-24-spectrum-service-delivery/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The people who most interested me were wary of centralized control, but they were not free market libertarians. They believed in the power of competition, but they also believed that some of society's most important achievements could not be incentivized with economic reward. They called themselves entrepreneurs but worked mostly in the public sector. They were equally suspicious of big government and big corporations. From a certain angle, they looked like a digital-age version of such nineteenth-century anarchists as Pierre-Joseph Proudhon or Mikhail Bakunin. Yet beneath that strange, hard-to-place eclecticism, a core philosophy seemed to unite all their efforts, even if it didn't fit comfortably into the existing categories of political belief.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>~ Future Perfect by Steven Johnson &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Future-Perfect-Case-Progress-Networked/dp/1594631840">Amazon&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Services are delivered by companies. But we need the government or else the greedy capitalists will take everything. But the government is inefficient and slow &amp;ndash; just look at the Post Office. But&amp;hellip; But&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The dirty little secret is that no one knows necessarily what the right answer to this question is because we are still learning the right solution for a particular and the right solution is constantly changing. Instead of thinking in binary terms maybe it would be more helpful to think in terms of a spectrum with fully public delivery on the one side (passing legislation would fit here &amp;ndash; we probably do not want the rule-making function of governance to be within the private sector and even more susceptible to private capture than it currently is) and fully private delivery on the other side (selling slurpees &amp;ndash; we probably do not want selling of fungible goods to be within the private sector which has little incentives to innovate). In between these extremes there is a very large space in which operators can work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the arrangements I work in routinely for Watershed's clients are Public-Private Partnerships or PPP's. You know these from such hits as the private vendors operating services within national parks, or stadium builds which are usually a mix of public and private financing. These partnerships allow for a wide variety of delivery possibilities that are not nearly as limiting as a simple binary question of public v. private. Instead of focusing on the binary nature of service delivery within our policy debates which characterizes the delivery of services as either &lt;em>purely private&lt;/em> or &lt;em>purely public&lt;/em> each with its advocate class and all unable to resolve their differences or get things done so that people can get to the task of l i v i n, perhaps we should think more in terms of a spectrum. Focus our thinking about service delivery on a spectrum rather than a binary on-off switch allows us to focus our debates on finding the right point along the spectrum to deliver the services which we are speaking to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To Europeans this debate that occupies our time, the government is great v. government sucks debate, is hilarious. I get asked about it a lot. It is intuitive to most Europeans that service delivery operates on a spectrum. Services in Europe are routinely modified within the spectrum and also change over time due to efficiencies, politics, or many other factors. Last year there was an outcry within the UK as the conservative government was trying to move the National Health Service along the spectrum towards the private side which raised many alarms for people. But that debate, and many others within the politics of service delivery in Europe happen without the sky is falling, scream at your TV, Nancy Grace style of debate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I like that part of Europe. A lot. Because generally when the population that doesn't know anything about the delivery of such services simply gets out of the way things happen in a pretty smooth way. Not all the time. But most of the time when people who don't know things about things let the people who do know things about things do their jobs things run pretty well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course there are differences between the two. Incentives for one are different. Private sector actors have incentives to optimize their profits. To think of short term gains over long term innovation. To reduce costs and simplify delivery mechanisms. These are all well and good, but there is a place for them. Public sector actors have a different set of incentives. To ensure the widest access to the services. To ensure the right costing is built into the system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The difference in these set of incentives (of which the above is meant to be illustrative) are important to understand. But our polity just needs to remember that there is space within these incentives for harmonization. Once we stop thinking in the simplistic terms of &amp;ldquo;Government good&amp;rdquo; | &amp;ldquo;Government bad&amp;rdquo; and start asking the question of how this service should be delivered based on what &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rdquo; are trying to accomplish. Then a whole world of policy solutions is opened to us.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Try it during the upcoming election season. Watch a debate and ask yourself if the debaters are being overly reductive in how they are approaching a service delivery question. Those that are not being overly reductive &amp;ndash; that are in the business of finding solutions which will actually move us along a path rather than simply spewing forth banal answers &amp;ndash; those are the ones that I will be voting for.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Unreasonable Optimism and Why John Dickerson&amp;#8217;s (@jdickerson) Series Should Matter</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-10-06-my-unreasonable-optimism-and-why-john-dickersons-jdickerson-series-should-matter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-10-06-my-unreasonable-optimism-and-why-john-dickersons-jdickerson-series-should-matter/</guid><description>&lt;p>My Dad and I have this ongoing debate about campaigns. It has been ongoing for four years that I can remember but perhaps longer. It revolves around the forthrightness of campaigns to speak to the electorate logically, with courage, and while keeping within the bounds of logic and reasonableness. Instead of what I desperately want campaigns to do they do the opposite, spiraling into ever more irrelevant crap. Gaffes and ah ha’s are fun and interesting political theater but that is all it is. Theater. Theater is a farce. And we must stop hiring representatives to govern us based on a farcical audition system. This I have felt deeply for a long time. It colors most of my political worldview, rightly or wrongly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>John Dickerson wrote a &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/WyS3iH" title="How To Measure for a President, by John Dickerson">series&lt;/a> of pieces this week that I hope with all the optimism my increasing cynicism can muster that someday it will be viewed as a transformative work. In his work he pleads with the electorate in a way I know he believes. I’ve spent an hour a week more or less for the past seven years and I believe that he believes every word he wrote. His authenticity is easy to trust and recognize with that much exposure. His argument is basically that we need to rethink about how we treat Presidential campaigns. We are covering the wrong things he says to the media elite. You are emphasizing the wrong things he says to the campaigns. We are rewarding the wrong behavior he tells the electorate. And all of them/us need to hear it because all have a roll in fixing it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So what can we the electorate do? In my opinion it is our duty to educate ourselves about the issues, about what the President can actually control, and to take a decision based upon those items rather than the metrics of how many gaffes some poor guy or girl exposed to immense pressure takes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An informed and reasonable electorate is the only way we can pull ourselves out of this death spiral of hyper partisanship, reactionary media coverage, and off the charts dissatisfaction. We the electorate have as much to do with this, perhaps more, than the candidates do. Political leaders aren’t really leaders at all. At least in a democracy they are supposed to represent their constituents’ interests. Vying too far outside of these, and the politician loses their representative title. We call those people here in Africa: Dictators. The simple fact is that a politician is constrained by public opinion. So an ill-informed electorate, purposefully or otherwise, will logically reward the loudest rather than the smartest. Here’s the rub. We get the country we demand folks. When we refuse to educate ourselves on what the President does when we don’t demand intellectual and reasoned debate rather than stupid gaffery we end up with….Fox News and MSNBC yelling past each other.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are in a difficult situation. Right now. In the short term, I’m pessimistic, but in the long term I’m optimistic. I remain hopeful for two primary reasons.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, the grip of push consumption models of information continues to wane and simultaneously individual trust is replacing brand trust within the media. The former matters because when one unplugs from cable and consumes media and information on a purely pull model one’s ability to consume and process that information substantially increases. When you are in the mood for bubble gum you aren’t receptive to political messaging. Subliminal and uninformed voters barely process TV adds anymore. We are numb to them. But when you are in the mood for political messaging, you are in much better frame of mind to process that information. This is augmented by – the latter – individual trust located within both of one’s social graphs and interest graphs. Both of these significantly increase the ease which one can enter into the information funnel at headlines and steadily work downward through the increasing complexity to extreme wonkland if interested merely by reading, thinking, and clicking. Twitter leads to articles lead to counter arguments lead to source data. While this information funnel needs some work, people like Ethan Zuckerman at the Berkman Center and other terribly smart guys are thinking deeply about how this can operate. It will get better. And we will get better at using it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The second reason I resist encroaching cynicism is the rise of the Maker class. Art from Andy Warhol to the Breakfast Club to Rage Against the Machine has been warning us against getting too big and too homogeneous  It won’t work the artists warned. And they led the world. Long before there was a consultant class there were independent artists. But now DIY is everywhere and not only because Home Depot wants to sell you some lumber. Big is out and small is in. And I for one am incredibly satisfied. Music, for me, has never been more diverse and more wonderful. Despite the RIAA apocolypsing, music is the best I have ever experienced. And I’ve been following music for a decent little while now. Food is similarly wonderful. Farm to table restaurants and good wines make the old suburban standbys just places you go by default when you’re not in the know or when you are resigned to mediocrity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Small is in. Small is great. But small is messy. It refuses to be categorized as easily. It celebrates the individual, with its flaws and eccentricities, not in tension with the community (as the rhetoric from the right so often tries to frame it) but as part of it. Integral to the flow of the community. But this becomes problematic politically. Or so some argue. If  we decentralize and fracture the currently coalitions underpinning the current form of the Republican and Democratic parties so wonder what will happen thereafter. Some wonder if we had more than two viable national parties whether people would be able to parse the differences. I have no idea whether that is true, but I know that music, which is much farther ahead of politics in this area, is better than it is ever been. This is why I remain (perhaps unreasonably) optimistic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On Marines and Krulak&amp;#8217;s Three Blocks</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-09-18-on-marines-and-krulaks-three-blocks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-09-18-on-marines-and-krulaks-three-blocks/</guid><description>&lt;p>Someone emailed me tonight asking what I thought about the attack on the consulate in Benghazi. Being that I was a Marine officer once upon a moon, this person asked whether my blood was up about them passing away and what I thought about the President putting our people in danger like that. Their words. Yes, of course my blood was up. I felt deeply for their families and for the poor souls who had to notice their families and for the entire situation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But there is a bigger picture here that I want to point out. These guys faced an impossible task. Utterly impossible. There was no right answer for them and all these people screaming about why aren’t our embassies safer and posting about the poor Marines do a disservice to their service. As Marines we are not in the business of allowing ourselves to be victimized. That, in my opinion,  is a bigger disservice to those Marines than a simple and honest answer: this is the fog of Krulak’s three block war. Before I explain Krulak’s theory, let us first try to picture the decisions these Marines had to take.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was not there that night in Benghazi and I make no claims on knowledge of the attack other than what I’ve seen on the news. The below should be taken for no more than it is meant to be: a thought experiment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You are in a safehouse and it is 9/11. You are in a predominately Muslim country and as opposed to all the other Muslim countries you’ve likely been in recently, in this one they don’t hate you. In fact you are accompanying the Ambassador to the heartland, the ground zero, of the movement your country helped to achieve power.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There have been riots but you likely pay those no mind. Not because you are negligent, but precisely because you are not scared of them. Even if you have been told of possible security concerns, you probably still pay them no mind. You understand the waxes and wanes of the moods of crowds. Sure you stay vigilant. Your helmet stays on and your weapon is there, but it is just people annoyed. They aren’t attacking you. And chances are damn good that you know what it feels like when a crowd turns on you, when the focus of collective disdain is you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Or perhaps you do feel it. Perhaps the security briefings and 9/11 and the feel of the crowd tingle your spidey senses. What are you going to do about it? Absolutely nothing. You just stay there, vigilant. Your helmet stays on and your weapon is there. And you watch. And wait. And listen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you hear the woosh of an RPG you barely have any time to react before the bang of the detonation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now what? Do you fire back? Who exactly are you going to fire at? You have very likely been taught that aimlessly shooting into crowds is an atrocious idea. Anyway, it is night and this is guard duty. You know you don’t have the full range of combined arms at your disposal you may have had in Afghanistan or Iraq. You know that you have only a few guys with small arms. And you have no idea who is shooting at you or how many they are. You are smart enough to know that now is not the time for asking the why. You are also smart enough to remember that this city is highly militarized and while they generally like you now, you understand damn well how fleeting that public opinion is. And shooting randomly into the crowd isn’t going to help.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even if you had the luck to see the shooters location and had tracked his movements through the crowds on grainy NVGs because you are a superhuman. And even if that guy was stupid enough to give you a clear shot. (It must be said that the chances for that happening are basically nil) How sure are you that you can make that shot in the midst of a heaving crowd at night from distance?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So do you go after him? If you pursue, you leave the place you are supposed to be guarding, and worse you leave the *person *you are supposed to be guarding. The Ambassador. In the olden days people were hung for decisions like those.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The ambassador. That jogs your mind. How is he?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The above sequence of thoughts took me twenty times longer to type then for you to process. Perhaps a hundred.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You inquire about the ambassador and are told that he is injured. There are people everywhere. People are shouting. It is dark. You have no idea who is who. Still the consulate is being fired on. Even if you were superhuman enough to track the shooter they have melted back into the crowd while you were checking on the ambassador.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This my friends is chaos. Utter and complete chaos. Not complexity. F-ing chaos. You can call it the shit, the fog of war, or any of the other catchy terms people give to it. But that’s it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I will say this. I am not sad that it was Marines that passed away that night. If it had to have been anyone I would gladly take Marines over private contractors, over anyone else. I want Marines on those walls because I know that they know how to make the best possible decision given the constraints in which they are forced to operate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We Marines have had a chip on our shoulder from basically the time of our birth. We have never really fit into the overall structure of the armed forces. We are neither the round peg nor the square hole. We are both. And we are neither. Our neither-ness makes us the first to have our money taken during defense drawdowns, but our both-ness makes us the first to be called on in a crisis. We pride ourselves on our ability to do more with less. To go anywhere and do anything that is asked of us. It is this adaptability, this chameleon like ability to properly react to chaos, that is the reason we guard (ceremonially these days) the White House and (not so ceremonially) embassies all around the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Training for these scenarios used to be standard faire. I have no idea whether it is anymore as I’ve been out of the game for a long time. We train for basically everything. From humanitarian intervention, to quasi conflict (like that night in Benghazi) in crowded spaces full of noncombatants, to full scale kill the enemy conflict. And last week Marines were doing all three of these. In numerous locations around the world. With grace and with honor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is this spectrum from completely mundane and non-violent (but foreign) to fully violent that General Krulak was talking about in 1999 when he wrote his seminal piece called the Strategic Corporal: Leadership in the Three Block War. I had graduated OCS but was not yet a Marine officer when he published that piece. And that piece of work is truly a seminal piece as it influenced greatly an entire generation of Marines. In it Krulak argued that the Marines needed to build a force capable of ratcheting up and down the violence as appropriate for the situation. This is incredibly dangerous stuff. It is much safer to retreat to bases and hide behind technological solutions than it is to get out of the bubble and walk the streets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But under Krulak’s tutelage the Marines adapted. And the fires of a zillion firefights and uneventful patrols have proved old Chuck was right. That young people can be trained to react appropriately and honorably under the craziest, most screwed, utterly chaotic of situations. Because, that’s what Marines, especially Marines who understand the challenges and risks inherent in the three block war, that’s what they do.  &lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to feel emotional about something that is fine. But don’t denigrate the honor of the Marines who died that evening in Benghazi by loftily screaming for more security, higher walls, more razor wire; by pretending that these Marines were some lambs to the slaughter. They may or may not have fought that night, but I have full faith and allegiance to the same that they most certainly had a good reason for whatever they did.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And I know even more than that they most certainly were not victims to be held up as a symbol in order to win votes. It was Remember the Maine that was the slogan, not Remember the Marines on the Maine.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Compromise &amp;amp; Governing: On Reading @ryanlizza&amp;#8217;s The Obama Memos</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-01-27-compromise-and-governing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-01-27-compromise-and-governing/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="hhttp://www.flickr.com/photos/barackobamadotcom/2913035652">&lt;img src="http://blog.caseykuhlman.com/assets/images/2012/2913035652_27460596bd.jpg" alt="Obama Barn by Barack Obama @ flickr" tit="Obama Barn by Barack Obama @ flickr" />&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I was in college my friend Dave and I would often fall asleep at some point during our millionth screening of Braveheart. We would often put the film on after the bars had closed and we had grabbed our drunken treat of the night and were not yet ready for bed. At the time we were training to be Marine officers and very interested in learning what it took to be a good leader. Near the beginning of the film there was a quote which I often thought about (at still think about):&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>You admire this man, this William Wallace. Uncompromising men are easy to admire. He has courage; so does a dog. But it is exactly the ability to &lt;em>compromise&lt;/em> that makes a man noble. And understand this: Edward Longshanks is the most ruthless king ever to sit on the throne of England. And none of us, and nothing of Scotland will remain, unless &lt;em>we&lt;/em> are as ruthless. Give ear to our nobles. Knowing their minds is the key to the throne.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>We would scoff at this quote. In our youth and lack of exposure to the world we felt that uncompromising was the way of the greatest leaders. That may still be true, but I have learned that it definitely is not true of the greatest rulers. Indeed, the greatest rulers are often those that are the greatest to compromise. Human nature being what it is, you will very rarely have complete agreement with a course of action. Multiply the amount of people a decision will affect and you necessarily multiply the different opinions (both rational and irrational) which will impact your decision before it is taken and laud or critique it after it is taken. This is a fundamental “problem” with ruling in a democracy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ryan Lizza has written a fantastically interesting piece for The New Yorker. He dives deeply into a trove of memos which circulated the Obama White House during the first term of that administration. He assembles a very interesting piece which does a great job of detailing the tensions that any President may face. I encourage everyone to read it, &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/zTXpzr" title="The Obama Memos">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is interesting for me, given my current diaspora state (relatively torn between Europe, America, and Africa), to compare the political processes which take place in a very new, somewhat inchoate democracy – Somaliland – to a very old, overly complex democracy – the US – while comparing both, which I view as an insider, to the relatively “clean” democratic processes that the Europeans embody. One of the difficult things in an independent executive system, where the governing functions of creating laws and putting those laws into action are separated between two branches of government, is that we tend to blame the “big man” for all of the problems. This happens in Somaliland just as often as it happens in the US. The realities of Presidential campaigns often do a disservice by blurring the lines. Much of the debate during a Presidential campaign revolves around big or small policy ideas that the President will have very little to no control over. As I was telling someone the other day, a President has an ability to stop a legislative action it doesn’t want to allow but it has little ability to make a legislative body do something that that body does not want to do. Yet these big policy ideas are a function of modern politics. Firstly they are easier to discuss than the minutae of what a President really does. Secondly, it is a method of acting somewhat uniformly in our very much decentralized system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Personally, reading the piece shows me what I was hoping to see. A President who has learned how to do what is possibly the most difficult and complex job on the planet. A President who remains willing to make compromises, but also has learned how to work the system. A President who still has standards and struggles to balance a bowing to the political winds with a deep devotion to his ideals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While Obama cannot get a large piece of greenhouse gas passed through (right now) domestically, he has floated a ton of money for research, innovation, and implementation of greenhouse reduction initiatives in other countries. While Obama faces complete stonewalling from his own legislators on jobs (right now), he has figured out how to incentivize job growth and business creation in other countries with entrepreneurial grants and collaborative agreements dominating much of the AID/DOS grants I’ve seen lately. While Obama cannot push forward comprehensive immigration reform (right now), he has put in place policies which make it much easier to get US visas (while remaining within the legislative caps mandated by various amendments to the Immigration and Nationalization Act) and illegal immigration flows are down – particularly from Mexico. These are largely international examples for a couple of reasons. First it is my area of interest so I follow it closer. Second the President has fundamentally more power over foreign policy than domestic policy. Third, Hillary – despite how divisive she may or may not be – is a brilliant bureaucrat and many of these initiatives are coming from her shop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No government is perfect, but where the President and his team have a reasonable amount of power I am genuinely pleased with what I see. There’s much to disagree with, but there is much more that I agree with. As we turn towards a full scale assault on us all with respect to choosing our next President one thing I would encourage everyone to do is to not get tricked by the red herrings of advertisements and debates and to focus on what the President can and does actually do on a daily / weekly / monthly / yearly basis. Choose wisely.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Preacher is Back. That&amp;#8217;s What I&amp;#8217;ve Been Waiting For.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-09-09-the-preacher-is-back-thats-what-ive-been-waiting-for/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-09-09-the-preacher-is-back-thats-what-ive-been-waiting-for/</guid><description>&lt;p>I just finished watching the jobs speech and my first thought was “were have you been”? The historian-poet-preacher in him which I fell in love with in the Yes We Can and Race speeches (collectively rather than individually) had found his groove tonight.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every artist struggles with finding their artistic voice, but for me, at this moment, this was balm to my soul. Someone, somewhere, does actually get it. But before I get to what I liked about the speech let me take a small detour and talk about how I think about my relationship between me and my government.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m currently staying at my brother’s, &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/kuhlman">@kuhlman&lt;/a>, house and he has a great dane. Due to our pomo lives we missed each other. He is off on a construction job overnight and I just returned from an overnight job myself. We missed each other and were not able to pass a key back and forth. When we were texting each other as to our current statuses and how we could coordinate this changeover, I asked him whether the house was locked. He responded, “Maggie’s the lock.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now Maggie is a wonderful bitch (which I mean literally). This bitch has a bark that will tear your hair off when she gets scared. I have no idea whether she has the bite to match it, and I like that I don’t know that, because her bark is scary enough. She is the perfect lock. See locks are on-off switches. But living, breathing beings are able to differentiate between when on is OK and off is OK. Sometimes the best lock is the one that can differentiate between when to bark and when to be happy because your friend is here to let you out to go take a piss.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And this is how I want my government to be. I don’t want to rely on my government unnecessarily. I understand that my successes and my failures are my own. But sometimes you want to know that if you are forced, due to the situations of living your life, to deviate from your normal patterns, that there will be a being there to have your back. You don’t want something that is impersonal and cannot differentiate between friend and foe. You want a bitch there that is both happy to see you and happy to go have a poo in the yard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That story said, there were many things that I loved about the Obama speech.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, he chastised both sides. He told some hard truths. These words were his preacher robes which I have not seen him don for a long, long time. Too long. And it was needed. Both sides of the political aisle have been being babies for a while now and the only people suffering are the middle class of America. This &lt;em>must&lt;/em> change. The only way to get shit done is to sometimes put aside the differences and realize that the betterment of the country is at stake. Since I’ve spent so much time in African countries where politics is so personality based I am especially receptive to the in-out-group mechanisms which operate in such an environment. And if you want to actually help, if you want to get something done in this world you’re going to have to figure out a compromise. Because, as the President of the United States, said “No single individual built America on their own. We built it together. .” What a great line. Sometimes we have to act as a community. Individualism is great, but no one at no time has EVER acted completely in isolation as an individual. We call those beings the last creature of their species. What is required, from time to time, is looking out for those that may not be as smart, or have the opportunities, or whatever as we fancy of ourselves. And in that vein, next week I hope to go pound some nails to help members of my family’s community who were affected by the tornadoes earlier this year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Second, it was perhaps the most patriotic speech which has been given during my lifetime. It was a call to action. It was competitive (which we Americans love). It told us that there was going to be some hard days ahead. This was the poet that I’ve been longing for. This was the inspiration that I’ve been hoping for. This was the America that I have studied and that I love. Just turn off your brain (I’ll get to the wonky stuff in a moment) and listen to the words of his speech and tell me that you are not inspired by &lt;em>something&lt;/em>, or even &lt;em>anything&lt;/em> in this speech. No matter your political affiliation this man gets that he was “hired” to execute the laws in the best interest of us all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Third, it cut through all the bullshit, stupid rhetoric which neither matters nor helps. He has learned from his own failures to properly leverage both the power of his position and the wave of people power which put him in that chair. This was a pragmatic speech to its core. What he said is exactly, *exactly, *what economists have proven matter for the economic development of your country. There are many opinions as to the best, but almost every economist will agree that what is necessary for economic development (this comes from my international development perspective) is: infrastructure, education, jobs for low-skilled individuals, and healthcare. We’ll leave aside for now the reasons why each of these exist. Similarly I’m going to take a mulligan on healthcare because I don’t have the energy to enter that debate as to why people that don’t have millions in the bank don’t *deserve *to not feel awful all the time, but if you care about that watch Sicko and shutup. But see here’s the thing. Our schools are falling apart. While we prosecute irrational wars overseas (which I’ve participated in and have some modicum of epistemic authority here), we’re not able to give the support that our teachers require to educate our children. Our infrastructure is subpar. Visit Europe and try to convince me that we are still number one. Drill, Baby, Drill.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So this is a short review, but my early take (before reading any punditry) is that it was brilliant and one of Obama’s best performances. On a personal level I’m happy for three reasons: (1) the poet I wanted is finding his voice, (2) the pragmatist we all need is finally leveraging his platform, and (3) the wonk in me is reassured that someone up there will bark when necessary and greet when necessary.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There were many great moments of this speech for me. But the one that stands out. The one that I will think of tomorrow. Is this.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>No single individual built America on their own. We built it together. We have been, and always will be, one nation, under God, indivisible, with liberty and justice for all; a nation with responsibilities to ourselves and with responsibilities to one another. Members of Congress, it is time for us to meet our responsibilities.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>What did you think of the speech?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OK, So He&amp;#8217;s Gone. What Now?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-05-02-ok-so-hes-gone-what-now/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-05-02-ok-so-hes-gone-what-now/</guid><description>&lt;p>So I woke up this morning to the news. Obama Killed Osama. In my groggy state, I couldn’t really piece together what was happening on my collated facebook and twitter streams until I saw something similar to the previous sentence. I think the first thing I cognized was a friend’s facebook post: “Osama, so 10 years ago.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I went to NYTimes.com and saw the huge headline and the gigantic picture of the President staring at me, resolute &amp;amp; determined. After reading the article, and then watching my Twitter feeds more closely than usual today (which has been a busy one and not really allowed me to dig as deep into the commentary as I would like), I think my overall thought is, “Osama, so 10 years ago.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is actually quite amazing to consider that it was almost 10 years ago that I was sitting with my Marine infantry officer friends in our boxers and t-shirts watching GWB announce to the world that our nation’s military was on its highest alert and looking around the room thinking, “Huh?” as a typhoon raged outside and we couldn’t even leave the building. That was 9-11-01. This is 02-05-11 (date formats have been shifted in accordance with my mindset).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The news, while large, seems quaint. Many nations with majority muslim populations have bigger problems today, and they now have viable outlets for those problems. Moderate muslims the world over have increasingly spoken out against extremism (exhibit A is the commercial I watch on Qatar based MBC movie channel which shows a young teenager watching extremist videos and ends with his mom watching him on one crying and then flashes something in Arabic which I assume says, “don’t be an idiot and blow yourself up”). Al Qaeda has fractured, has become cellular and largely unable to organize anything beyond a small isolated bombing for a long time now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My main question as to what now has much less to do with the muslim majority areas and much more to do with America. Our shorthand for “the enemy” is gone. So what will we do now? It is very difficult to motivate people, populations, and most importantly fighters to fight a war where they cannot “see” the reason that they are fighting. Our reason in Iraq left, but there was still a face there that was lingering, hovering over the consciousness. That face is now at the bottom of the ocean. I think we can smile that an evil human has gone, but the real point, the real concern I have, or better put, the hope that I hold to is that we Americans can now get back to showing the world that we know more than how to fight. That we know how to compete, how to build, how to innovate, how to drive progress, how to balance divergent political interests, how to develop systems which bring jobs and health and education. Let those be our exports. Instead of our current portfolio: facebook, google, and guided missiles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Concisely put by my friend: “Osama. So 10 Years Ago.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Egypt is Burning: On Arab Protests</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-01-30-egypt-burning-arab-protests/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-01-30-egypt-burning-arab-protests/</guid><description>&lt;p>[![THIS COULD HAVE BEEN STRAIGHT OUT OF A MOVIE! #jan25 #egypt via Farrah3m @ Twitpic][2]][2]
&amp;ldquo;THIS COULD HAVE BEEN STRAIGHT OUT OF A MOVIE! #jan25 #egypt&amp;rdquo; via Farrah3m @ Twitpic
Two days ago, my father asked me for my thoughts on the protests throughout the Arab world. I wanted to compose my thoughts, to let the situation develop a bit further before I said anything.  Now is the time to say something.
This is utterly fascinating to watch.  Al Jazeera is very much killing it with fantastic shots – news hasn’t captivated me in this same way since watching CNN from the Palestine Hotel in Baghdad in 1991.  On Friday I was sitting with my friends and we watched the following sequence unfold in real time: reports of police sending reinforcements into streets, video of police apcs flooding streets, video of protesters stopping one vehicle, video of  police scrambling and fighting their way out of back of vehicle protesters beating the driver, video of protesters trying and failing to tip apc over and “throw” into nile, reprieve, reports of army being called onto streets, video of apc being lit on fire, and for the next three hours they would every once in a while cut back to the same burning apc.  It was magical, riveting, unbelievable tv.
I was watching very closely when earlier (before the above sequence) a lone army apc came into the screen (was easy to tell as was painted different color, a fairly standard practice worldwide).  The people went utterly nuts.  And the army seemed to be cheering the protesters back.  It was pretty far away from the cameraman so it was difficult to see exactly, but it was super interesting.  That was before Mubarak called the army onto the streets.  The stoppage for the prayers was the other thing that fascinated me, but back to the army.  The Egyptian army is a conscript army, and it closer to the middle/lower classes than the police are, given that the police are not conscripts and are often hand chosen by the regime.
The story aside, what is my chat on this topic?  Three things strike me: (1) the interconnectedness of the pan-Arab movement may be among the causes of the downfall of the creators; (2) [Gladwell][2], you’re wrong; (3) the results of the variety of protests is going to differ, likely in proportion to GDP.
[2]: &lt;a href="http://www.newyorker.com/reporting/2010/10/04/101004fa_fact_gladwell">http://www.newyorker.com/reporting/2010/10/04/101004fa_fact_gladwell&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="pan-arab-movement">Pan-Arab Movement&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Yes, all of these are connected.  The Tunis protests, and their subsequent victories, beget the Egyptian protests, and as they say: as Egypt goes, so goes the Arab world.  But look at what I pulled just a few minutes off of Twitter:
[![][4]][4]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/entry/egypt-burning-arab-protests/scr">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/entry/egypt-burning-arab-protests/scr&lt;/a>
The protests just continue to spread: Sudan, Yemen, Syria, Algeria, Bahrain, Libya. The linkages that have been built, especially in the post-colonial world between the Arab nations, which was originally established as a bulwark against the West (among other reasons) is now making the spread of protest-ism violently, breathtakingly fast.
And yes, technology is helping to facilitate the spread.  I have seen[ twitpics of letters][4] from Tunisian protesters to Egyptian protesters with tips on how to fight the man.  Encouragement and organizing are all happening online.  Why else would Egypt completely pull the plug?
[4]: &lt;a href="http://globalguerrillas.typepad.com/globalguerrillas/2011/01/journal-example-of-open-source-tactical-innovation.html">http://globalguerrillas.typepad.com/globalguerrillas/2011/01/journal-example-of-open-source-tactical-innovation.html&lt;/a>
Third, and this is what is going to take longer to figure out.  But the end result of this wave, I suspect is going to distill rough correlative to GDP of the nations.  Tunisia and Egypt will likely see some fundamental changes.  Syria and Bahrain will likely see some changes, but not fundamental ones.  Libya, Sudan, and Yemen will likely have to wait a bit longer for fundamental changes within their countries.  I’m a Collier-ist and I am interested to see if this is going to validate his [theories ][5]that at about $3000 per capita GDP is some sort of a tipping point for democracy.  Thailand reached that and it beget massive protests, the countries listed above are there, China is approaching this threshold.  Yet, we will see.  Only after the fact will we see.
[5]: &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Wars-Guns-Votes-Democracy-Dangerous/dp/0061479640/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1296375235&amp;amp;sr=1-1-catcorr">http://www.amazon.com/Wars-Guns-Votes-Democracy-Dangerous/dp/0061479640/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1296375235&amp;amp;sr=1-1-catcorr&lt;/a>
The last thing I’ll note is that a power vacuum in Egypt is in precisely no one’s interest.
~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On Tea Partiers &amp;amp; Rule-Free Systems: Football, NASCAR &amp;amp; Regulatory Authority</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-01-26-tea-partiers-rule-free-systems-football-nascar-regulatory-authority/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-01-26-tea-partiers-rule-free-systems-football-nascar-regulatory-authority/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“An association of men who will not quarrel with one another is a thing which has never yet existed, from the greatest confederacy of nations down to a town meeting or a vestry.” ~ Thomas Jefferson&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I know I am generalizing, but since many that I know and love subscribe to many of these philosophies maybe I do have a small bit of perspective here.  Let me take a look at the Free Market system and rules.  Many have argued that rules are inherrently anti-market.  That the opposite of capitalism is rule-making by regulators.  Maybe that is right in some areas, but I would argue that it depends on the specific area in mind.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“The big-government crowd is drawn to the compulsory nature of centralized authority. They can’t imagine an undirected social order. Someone needs to be in charge—someone who knows better. Big government is audacious and conceited. By definition, government is the means by which citizens are forced to do that which they would not do voluntarily. Like pay high taxes. Or redistribute tax dollars to bail out the broken, bloated pension systems of state government employees. Or purchase, by federal mandate, a government-defined health-insurance plan that is unaffordable, unnecessary or unwanted. For the left, and for today’s Democratic Party, every solution to every perceived problem involves more government—top-down dictates from bureaucrats presumed to know better what you need. Tea partiers reject this nanny state philosophy of redistribution and control because it is bankrupting our country.” ~Dick Armey &amp;amp; Matt Kibbe @ &lt;a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748704407804575425061553154540.html">WSJ&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Reject Cap &amp;amp; Trade - Stop costly new regulations that would increase unemployment, raise consumer prices, and weaken the nation’s global competitiveness with virtually no impact on global temperatures.” ~ Tea Party Manifesto as defined by the Tea Party Patriots available &lt;a href="http://www.contractfromamerica.com/Idea.aspx">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Despite universal acknowledgement that Americans enjoy a free, open, and vibrant Internet, the FCC is relentlessly pursuing a massive regulatory regime that would stifle broadband expansion, create congestion, slow Internet speeds, jeopardize job retention and growth, and lead to higher prices for consumers.” ~ Virginia Tea Party Patriot Federation letter to the FCC re: Net Neutrality, excerpted &lt;a href="http://www.crunchgear.com/2010/08/13/the-tea-party-hates-net-neutrality-because-its-an-affront-to-free-speech-umm/">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Tea party members believe in this invisible hand spoken of by Adam Smith. Society is better off because of the free market. A person invents something so that they can make money, but in that self interest benefits society as a whole. Did the government invent the car, the computer, or airplane? Nope, self interested individuals invented these things. Did these inventions enrich society as a whole? Yes. Think about the amount of jobs created by the computer industry alone, everything these days (seemingly) has computer technology in it. Think about the amount of jobs created by the auto industry. When government steps into the free market it creates advantages for those it supports and disadvantages for those who is doesn’t support. The law of supply and demand has been tampered with, and the market is artificially manipulated. Sometimes these manipulations have a positive impact, only to come crashing back down. Most of the time they have a negative impact on the market.” ~ Available &lt;a href="http://hubpages.com/hub/what-the-tea-party-stands-for-free-markets">here&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Every generation needs a new revolution.” Thomas Jefferson&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I actually really like what the Tea Partiers have been able to accomplish, although I am about as far away from them policy-wise as possible, I like the fact that they are shaking things up for the entrenched political interests on both sides of the aisle.  That said, I think they are dead wrong when it comes to their hatred and shunning of rules, so I’d like to take a little moment here and explain things from my side.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Think about sports.  Particularly, think about football.  A lot of rules were made in football between the mid-80′s to mid-90′s which had to do with protecting the quarterback.  Why is this person special?  Likely it was less because of his primacy on the playing field, and more likely because of his primacy in the board room.  Fine, but when those rules were adopted I don’t remember (although maybe it happened) any pundits arguing for the demise of football as we know it.  They were saying, no we need some fair competition, and if I spend Y of my cap money on a quarterback, I should have the opportunity to let that investment play out.  There was still plenty of competition, not the least of which was during the off season for prime players.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then let’s look at the salary cap &amp;amp; profit sharing mechanism that the owners have set up.  If this was tried in Washington it would have about a 0% chance of surviving a first draft and whoever the unlucky sap was that had the job of writing a first draft would be instantly shunned as a communist.  But when it comes to our beloved sport we say how great it is that small market teams like Pittsburgh still have the same chance of surviving as big market teams like New York.  Indeed big markets haven’t dominated football in ages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Compare this to baseball.  That is the sport, for those of you who may remember, with the sticks and the balls and the clay in a diamond with a bunch of people basically standing around all the time.  There were two major turnoffs for many I know from my generation about baseball (besides it’s boring which I would argue against).  (1) “In baseball you can just go out and buy your team.  There is no thrill in just zero to winning.” It wasn’t satisfying when the Marlins bought a team and won the World Series in the late nineties.  Not at all satisfying.  (2) “They absolutely turned a blind eye to the steroid situation.”  Well, there you have it folks, rules (football) v. non-rules (baseball).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let us talk NASCAR.  I grew up watching Dale Earnhartt, Bill Elliot, and those guys.  I was a number 3 guy.  I went to the Dayton 500 and remember the after effects of a fantastic Ricky Rudd accident that is still likely shown on best 100 crashes of all time on late night Spike TV.  What do people like about NASCAR?  What I liked about it is that the competition is based on pure skill.  It is pure skill in driving, and it is pure skill in engineering.  But engineering in the fine-tune sense.  The driver with the fastest car (interpret: has built the most efficient system) who is the best driver on that day (interpret: has great adaptability) most of the time wins.  It is fast and loud and visciously entertaining to go to the races.  But really races boil down to (besides keeping your hipster appeal by “making fun of the white trash people.”) a human struggle to best their machine and their elements.  But if you want to talk about systems with rules, the NASCAR rule book is lots of pages long.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So rules, in and of themselves do not serve to stifle competition.  They often serve, instead, to shift power away from entrenched interests (NY Yankees) towards more of a meritocratic environment.   I’m all for rules if they allow two things: (1) lower barriers to entry (and no, it doesn’t matter to me if that comes at the cost of entrenched interests or people/entities with bigger bankrolls than I) and (2) promotes a meritocratic environment.  Those are the essential parts of the American dream which I hold onto.  I do not begrudge anyone their own perspectives and values that they hold on to, but those are the ones I hold as truisms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is also why I &lt;a href="http://watershedlegal.com/about">work with small businesses here in Somaliland&lt;/a>.  If you want to know the effects of zero rule making look here.  When people want to see how a society (which isn’t much different than an American one – a coming post) operates under anarchical situations pick up a book and see what is happening (beyond the terrorism) in the three different major areas of Somalia – each with a progressively more mature rule-making capability.  And then compare those with a more advanced rule making capability of neighboring Ethiopia.  You can draw a distinct and direct correlation between stability, progress, and rule-making authority.  The most anarchical is the least developed.  The least anarchical is the most developed.  And in those sentences I’m conflating anarchy as an antonym of exercised rule-making authority of a government.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Leaked Wikis, #Cablegate, and Little Else</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-12-02-leaked-wikis-cablegate/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-12-02-leaked-wikis-cablegate/</guid><description>&lt;p>There has been tons of interesting commentary and analysis surrounding cablegate.  I have been interested and have read quite a few of the original cables, especially the ones about Somalia as well as much of the journalistic coverage of the story and the analysis (punditry) side of the story.  I do not think I can add much to the really interesting and relevant commentary, from the punditry side, found in the below articles so I’ll just link to them. (list in semi-chronological order)&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Drezner: &lt;a href="http://drezner.foreignpolicy.com/posts/2010/11/29/the_utopianism_of_julian_assange">There are no Big Lies in the latest Wikileaks data dump&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rothkopf: &lt;a href="http://rothkopf.foreignpolicy.com/posts/2010/11/29/wikileaks_how_the_world_is_really_run">WikiLeaks: How the world is really run&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Spiro: &lt;a href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/opiniojurisfeed/~3/HXdMhbrik4k/">Wikileaks: It’s Tough Being a State (Some Are Taking Pity)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Walt: &lt;a href="http://walt.foreignpolicy.com/posts/2010/11/30/no_secrets">What if Wikileaks Became the Norm?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Thorpe: &lt;a href="http://kmonadollaraday.wordpress.com/2010/11/30/working-and-living-out-loud/">Working and living out loud&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drezner: &lt;a href="http://drezner.foreignpolicy.com/posts/2010/12/01/robert_gates_gets_the_last_word_on_wikileaks">Robert Gates gets the last word on WikiLeaks&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rothlopf: &lt;a href="http://rothkopf.foreignpolicy.com/posts/2010/12/01/wikileaks_winners_and_losers_early_edition">WikiLeaks winners and losers: Early edition&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>And to top it off, some legal analysis: &lt;a href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/opiniojurisfeed/~3/GGwM2RM8dN8/">Steve Vladeck on WikiLeaks&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>As to the more journalistic, rather than pundit coverage of the story, the first article I read in that sector is still my favorite.  I was struck by this quote in the second paragraph of &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/11/29/world/29cables.html?_r=2?_r=1&amp;amp;pagewanted=all">this NYT article&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The material was originally obtained by &lt;a href="http://topics.nytimes.com/top/reference/timestopics/organizations/w/wikileaks/index.html?inline=nyt-org" title="More articles about WikiLeaks.">WikiLeaks&lt;/a>, an organization devoted to revealing secret documents. WikiLeaks posted 220 cables, some redacted to protect diplomatic sources, in the first installment of the archive on its Web site on Sunday.”  It seems quite arrogant to me that WikiLeaks would redact the documents (if, indeed, they were the ones redacting), surely this must be an all-or-nothing organization.  It is not capable nor positioned to make the determination about sourcing which redacting would require.  I hope that the redactions were done within the cables themselves rather than by WikiLeaks.  The redactions were done by the NYTimes, which seems to me to be quite responsible journalism.  ”The Times, after consultations with the State Department, has withheld from articles and removed from documents it is posting online the names of some people who spoke privately to diplomats and might be at risk if they were publicly identified. The Times is also withholding some passages or entire cables whose disclosure could compromise American intelligence efforts.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The main thing I was struck upon reading the entirety of this article is that this entire deal is quite anticlimatic.  Most everything I’ve seen so far in the entirety of the coverage we knew more or less was happening.  Sure it lends some authority that official diplomatic cables contained the information and the clarity and precision of some of the information is quite striking, but all in all it seems quite benign for the most part.  Which leads me to question the utility of the leak.  I completely understand the vehemence of the Obama administration’s response, but I don’t really understand what all the hullabaloo is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The most interesting thing about all this is that everyone from the USG to the lowest individual here with me in Somaliland, we are learning together how to communicate in a web dominated world.  The technology keeps moving the ball before the norms and legalities of a situation have caught up with it and then technology moves the ball again, and again, and again.  Most people still fail to understand that their companies are likely archiving the emails from their work computers, and sometimes even their personal email when it is accessed from a work computer because the company is forced to under watch for due diligence reasons.  Much less to many people understand the privacy implications of their Facebook account.  I don’t even need to bring up the rest of the methods and tools for modern communication.  While the private / public barriers are still relatively strong, the grey area is widening and classifying itself.  In other words much of where we currently are is in a grey area but where exactly we are in that middle part of the spectrum and what the rules and norms are within that are difficult to decipher.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I shared a few days ago the following comment on Buzz, and my brother, &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/kuhlman">@kuhlman&lt;/a>, had a nice response to which I cannot add much.  I don’t agree entirely with his comment, but I’d like to give him the last word.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>While I appreciate the suggestion that “compartmentalization will be back in vogue real soon”, this and Robert Gate’s comments (also excerpted by Drezner in a later post) which suggest the inevitable indispensability of America bespeak a posture of American arrogance. Drezner asks rhetorically if he’s missing something, but doesn’t really believe that there is anything more (the so-called Big Lie). Why is it that shallowness must be the accompaniment to transparency? I agree that there is a great difference between the things we say in public and the things we say in private, but if we are to substantively engage our fellow global cohabitants in a meaningful discourse we must accept a conversation which allows for both deep, nuanced exchanges and the possibility that America is not indispensable.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Trail of the Octopus</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-16-trail-of-the-octopus/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-16-trail-of-the-octopus/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last night we were drinking some wine.  I say this because my consumption of alcohol has decreased drastically over the past few years.  Living in a dry country helps!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our new roommate was telling us this story about Lockerbee.  Steve, the new roommate, is a terribly interesting man to talk to.  In fact, it would be daunting talking to him if he wasn't such a genuine and normal human.  We see eye to eye on many of the problems around us and he is doing something quite remarkable.  He came here to S'land a few years ago and is now starting a dive business!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The synopsis of the story is that the US DIA and DEA were involved in this smuggling chain of drugs from Afghanistan through Iran and Syria and eventually to Europe.  Most of the drugs at that time were routed through Cyprus.  According to the story, the US wasn't actually smuggling things, but in return for CIA hostages in Lebanon being looked after by the criminal syndicates the syndicates were allowed to bring a certain amount of drugs into Europe.  The rest were confiscated by the DEA and the smugglers were paid for the drugs taken by the DEA.  Good usage of your tax dollars? &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyway after the Vicente shot down the Iranian airliner the Iranians got noticeably and reasonably upset and told Syria who told Hezbollah to smuggle a bomb onto the Pan-Am flight in retaliation.  The CIA somehow knew about this, as all their people who were leaving Frankfurt to come home for Christmas that year had previously been booked on the flight but then changed the day before to a TWA flight.  After the plane came down the Scottish policemen who were on scene were told to leave and go beyond some line while MI6 and the CIA took all the documents and papers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At this point in the story it sounded just like a good spy novel, but then the guy who was DIA in Cypress and knew about the deal blew the whistle and was charged with treason.  Subsequently he fled to Sweden and got asylum.  The book he wrote was banned in the UK and the US.  No matter whether it is true, false or some combination, I'm going to read it.  Thanks to the internet, it can be found &lt;a href="http://www.american-buddha.com/trail.ch.1.htm">here&lt;/a> if you are interested.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Teddy Goes to Big Think</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-08-teddy-goes-to-big-think/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-08-teddy-goes-to-big-think/</guid><description>&lt;p>Am just now getting around to watching Big Think's Editorial Top Ten of the year as I wait until 3 this morning when the SuperBowl will begin.  The premise of &lt;a href="http://http://bigthink.com/">Big Think &lt;/a>is amazing to me: grab a bunch of influential people, ask them a penetrating question and then let them speak for five minutes or more.  It is interesting when you sit and listen to people without the flashing signals and bottom scroll bars and overly enthusiastic reporters that so often are too busy to understand what the hell they are talking about.  The people I respec tthe most, are those that can take a step back from what is happening and try to see the bigger picture.  This site is trying to achieve something akin to that.   &lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is how  BT introduces the video:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Ted Kennedy was a model American politician: he rose from a famous&lt;br>
family, had significant personal wealth and connections, endured&lt;br>
scandals, and was a shrewd political operator. But what set Kennedy&lt;br>
apart from his peers was the authentic and uncompromising moral drive&lt;br>
that he brought to the Senate. He understood and used his advantages to&lt;br>
successfully push America in a better direction. In one of his last&lt;br>
interviews, Kennedy reflected with Big Think on his career, his family,&lt;br>
and his faith.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I must admit that I do not have terribly strong opinions either way on Teddy.  I heartily endorse, in principle, those values and goals which he fought for over all of the years.  However his personal scandals preclude me from full-scale fandom.  Yet, I really appreciate what he says in this video about citizen participation.  It is the key to forward progress.  And even though I think that the Tea Partiers are quite off key policy wise, I do endorse their collective action and their ability to leverage that to achieve their goals.  I also appreciate what BT says in their introduction, that Teddy used whatever influence and advantages that he was given and that he produced to try his best to work for those around them.  And he did keep doing that until the end of his life.  And so, I big you a late adieu lion of the senate.  May you rest in peace.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>