<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>politics on underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/politics/</link><description>Recent content in politics on underWater desert Blogging</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Spectrum of Public to Private Service Delivery</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-01-24-spectrum-service-delivery/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-01-24-spectrum-service-delivery/</guid><description>Let's stop thinking in binary terms about the delivery of services. There is a spectrum from purely public (government driven) to purely private (corporate driven) delivery of services. When we think about this as a spectrum rather than a binary situation, my opinion is that political debates about the delivery of services gets a lot easier and we focus on providing solutions rather than zero sum arguments which no one can ever win.</description></item><item><title>My Unreasonable Optimism and Why John Dickerson&amp;#8217;s (@jdickerson) Series Should Matter</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-10-06-my-unreasonable-optimism-and-why-john-dickersons-jdickerson-series-should-matter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-10-06-my-unreasonable-optimism-and-why-john-dickersons-jdickerson-series-should-matter/</guid><description>My Dad and I have this ongoing debate about campaigns. It has been ongoing for four years that I can remember but perhaps longer. It revolves around the forthrightness of campaigns to speak to the electorate logically, with courage, and while keeping within the bounds of logic and reasonableness. Instead of what I desperately want campaigns to do they do the opposite, spiraling into ever more irrelevant crap. Gaffes and ah ha’s are fun and interesting political theater but that is all it is. Theater. Theater is a farce. And we must stop hiring representatives to govern us based on a farcical audition system. This I have felt deeply for a long time. It colors most of my political worldview, rightly or wrongly.</description></item><item><title>Micro-States; Pirates; Terrorists; The London Conference: What a Fascinating Time for Watchers of Somalis</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-01-30-micro-states-pirates-terrorists-the-london-conference-what-a-fascinating-time-for-watchers-of-somalis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-01-30-micro-states-pirates-terrorists-the-london-conference-what-a-fascinating-time-for-watchers-of-somalis/</guid><description>For almost four years now I’ve been a careful observer of Somali politicians. For three of those years I was paid to try to be their lawyer. To provide them expert international legal assistance tied to a deep network full of some of the finest international practitioners and thinkers in the world. But they rarely, if ever, wanted that help. So largely I invented work, I went into meetings and had a product to sell. &lt;em>I can’t buy you new computers, but I how about I help you write that legal framework that Parliament has required you to do&lt;/em>?</description></item><item><title>Compromise &amp;amp; Governing: On Reading @ryanlizza&amp;#8217;s The Obama Memos</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-01-27-compromise-and-governing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-01-27-compromise-and-governing/</guid><description>Ryan Lizza has again written a marvelous piece on Obama and his team. Just as he did with his watershed piece on the Obama campaign, he has written a long and worthwhile piece on Obama's first term to date. If you want to understand the fundamental contradictions that come with governing, and if you want to learn what you elect a President to truly do, read it - after you read my thoughts.</description></item><item><title>The Preacher is Back. That&amp;#8217;s What I&amp;#8217;ve Been Waiting For.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-09-09-the-preacher-is-back-thats-what-ive-been-waiting-for/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-09-09-the-preacher-is-back-thats-what-ive-been-waiting-for/</guid><description>I just finished watching Obama's job speech, I haven't read or listened to any of the punditry and here's what I think. I'm happy because FINALLY the human I hoped I was voting for is emerging.</description></item><item><title>On The Somali Famine: A Thought Collage</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-07-30-somali-famine-collage/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-07-30-somali-famine-collage/</guid><description>This post is a compilation of sources, commentary and thought. It is a collage on the famine in the South of Somalia, the media storm which is surrounding it, and possible things to do.</description></item><item><title>OK, So He&amp;#8217;s Gone. What Now?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-05-02-ok-so-hes-gone-what-now/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-05-02-ok-so-hes-gone-what-now/</guid><description>So I woke up this morning to the news. Obama Killed Osama. In my groggy state, I couldn't really piece together what was happening on my collated facebook and twitter streams until I saw something similar to the previous sentence. I think the first thing I cognized was a friend's facebook post: &amp;lsquo;Osama, so 10 years ago.&amp;rsquo;</description></item><item><title>On Tea Partiers &amp;amp; Rule-Free Systems: Football, NASCAR &amp;amp; Regulatory Authority</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-01-26-tea-partiers-rule-free-systems-football-nascar-regulatory-authority/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-01-26-tea-partiers-rule-free-systems-football-nascar-regulatory-authority/</guid><description>I know I am generalizing, but since many that I know and love subscribe to many of these philosophies maybe I do have a small bit of perspective here. Let me take a look at the Free Market system and rules. Many have argued that rules are inherrently anti-market. That the opposite of capitalism is rule-making by regulators. Maybe that is right in some areas, but I would argue that it depends on the specific area in mind.</description></item></channel></rss>