<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>politics on underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/politics/</link><description>Recent content in politics on underWater desert Blogging</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Casey Kuhlman</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Spectrum of Public to Private Service Delivery</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-01-24-spectrum-service-delivery/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-01-24-spectrum-service-delivery/</guid><description>The people who most interested me were wary of centralized control, but they were not free market libertarians. They believed in the power of competition, but they also believed that some of society's most important achievements could not be incentivized with economic reward. They called themselves entrepreneurs but worked mostly in the public sector. They were equally suspicious of big government and big corporations. From a certain angle, they looked like a digital-age version of such nineteenth-century anarchists as Pierre-Joseph Proudhon or Mikhail Bakunin.</description></item><item><title>My Unreasonable Optimism and Why John Dickerson&amp;#8217;s (@jdickerson) Series Should Matter</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2012-10-06-my-unreasonable-optimism-and-why-john-dickersons-jdickerson-series-should-matter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2012-10-06-my-unreasonable-optimism-and-why-john-dickersons-jdickerson-series-should-matter/</guid><description>My Dad and I have this ongoing debate about campaigns. It has been ongoing for four years that I can remember but perhaps longer. It revolves around the forthrightness of campaigns to speak to the electorate logically, with courage, and while keeping within the bounds of logic and reasonableness. Instead of what I desperately want campaigns to do they do the opposite, spiraling into ever more irrelevant crap. Gaffes and ah ha’s are fun and interesting political theater but that is all it is.</description></item><item><title>Micro-States; Pirates; Terrorists; The London Conference: What a Fascinating Time for Watchers of Somalis</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2012-01-30-micro-states-pirates-terrorists-the-london-conference-what-a-fascinating-time-for-watchers-of-somalis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2012-01-30-micro-states-pirates-terrorists-the-london-conference-what-a-fascinating-time-for-watchers-of-somalis/</guid><description>For almost four years now I’ve been a careful observer of Somali politicians. For three of those years I was paid to try to be their lawyer. To provide them expert international legal assistance tied to a deep network full of some of the finest international practitioners and thinkers in the world. But they rarely, if ever, wanted that help. So largely I invented work, I went into meetings and had a product to sell.</description></item><item><title>Compromise &amp;amp; Governing: On Reading @ryanlizza&amp;#8217;s The Obama Memos</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2012-01-27-compromise-and-governing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2012-01-27-compromise-and-governing/</guid><description>When I was in college my friend Dave and I would often fall asleep at some point during our millionth screening of Braveheart. We would often put the film on after the bars had closed and we had grabbed our drunken treat of the night and were not yet ready for bed. At the time we were training to be Marine officers and very interested in learning what it took to be a good leader.</description></item><item><title>The Preacher is Back. That&amp;#8217;s What I&amp;#8217;ve Been Waiting For.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2011-09-09-the-preacher-is-back-thats-what-ive-been-waiting-for/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2011-09-09-the-preacher-is-back-thats-what-ive-been-waiting-for/</guid><description>![obama postcard by Mr. Wright @ Flickr]({{ site.url }}{{ site.root }}{{ site.images_dir }}/{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; }}/2795798382_9996813e74.jpg)
I just finished watching the jobs speech and my first thought was “were have you been”? The historian-poet-preacher in him which I fell in love with in the Yes We Can and Race speeches (collectively rather than individually) had found his groove tonight.
Every artist struggles with finding their artistic voice, but for me, at this moment, this was balm to my soul.</description></item><item><title>On The Somali Famine: A Thought Collage</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2011-07-30-somali-famine-collage/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2011-07-30-somali-famine-collage/</guid><description>The original photo is here, my alteration is here. If I had to title the alteration, I would call it An Homage to Motherhood.
This post is a bit random in nature, but it is a compilation of some sources and commentary and thought. So think of it as more of a collage than a strict narrative. Much of this was originally posted on Google .
Thought 1: Early Warning Systems Worked We’ve known this was coming for well over six months.</description></item><item><title>OK, So He&amp;#8217;s Gone. What Now?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2011-05-02-ok-so-hes-gone-what-now/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2011-05-02-ok-so-hes-gone-what-now/</guid><description>![Bin Laden hates this car by afagen @ flickr]({{ site.url }}{{ site.root }}{{ site.images_dir }}/{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; }}/2506982921_9132061338.jpg)
So I woke up this morning to the news. Obama Killed Osama. In my groggy state, I couldn’t really piece together what was happening on my collated facebook and twitter streams until I saw something similar to the previous sentence. I think the first thing I cognized was a friend’s facebook post: “Osama, so 10 years ago.</description></item><item><title>On Tea Partiers &amp;amp; Rule-Free Systems: Football, NASCAR &amp;amp; Regulatory Authority</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2011-01-26-tea-partiers-rule-free-systems-football-nascar-regulatory-authority/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2011-01-26-tea-partiers-rule-free-systems-football-nascar-regulatory-authority/</guid><description>“An association of men who will not quarrel with one another is a thing which has never yet existed, from the greatest confederacy of nations down to a town meeting or a vestry.” ~ Thomas Jefferson
![Tea partiers by jkarsh @ Flickr]({{ site.url }}{{ site.root }}{{ site.images_dir }}/{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; }}/4607302277_f9cc76dd12.jpg) Think these guys watch NASCAR? - Tea partiers by jkarsh @ Flickr
I know I am generalizing, but since many that I know and love subscribe to many of these philosophies maybe I do have a small bit of perspective here.</description></item></channel></rss>