<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/</link><description>A Site About Resilience and Authoritarianism</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</managingEditor><webMaster>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</webMaster><copyright>All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Spectrum of Public to Private Service Delivery</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-01-24-spectrum-service-delivery/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-01-24-spectrum-service-delivery/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The people who most interested me were wary of centralized control, but they were not free market libertarians. They believed in the power of competition, but they also believed that some of society's most important achievements could not be incentivized with economic reward. They called themselves entrepreneurs but worked mostly in the public sector. They were equally suspicious of big government and big corporations. From a certain angle, they looked like a digital-age version of such nineteenth-century anarchists as Pierre-Joseph Proudhon or Mikhail Bakunin. Yet beneath that strange, hard-to-place eclecticism, a core philosophy seemed to unite all their efforts, even if it didn't fit comfortably into the existing categories of political belief.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>~ Future Perfect by Steven Johnson &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Future-Perfect-Case-Progress-Networked/dp/1594631840">Amazon&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Services are delivered by companies. But we need the government or else the greedy capitalists will take everything. But the government is inefficient and slow &amp;ndash; just look at the Post Office. But&amp;hellip; But&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The dirty little secret is that no one knows necessarily what the right answer to this question is because we are still learning the right solution for a particular and the right solution is constantly changing. Instead of thinking in binary terms maybe it would be more helpful to think in terms of a spectrum with fully public delivery on the one side (passing legislation would fit here &amp;ndash; we probably do not want the rule-making function of governance to be within the private sector and even more susceptible to private capture than it currently is) and fully private delivery on the other side (selling slurpees &amp;ndash; we probably do not want selling of fungible goods to be within the private sector which has little incentives to innovate). In between these extremes there is a very large space in which operators can work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the arrangements I work in routinely for Watershed's clients are Public-Private Partnerships or PPP's. You know these from such hits as the private vendors operating services within national parks, or stadium builds which are usually a mix of public and private financing. These partnerships allow for a wide variety of delivery possibilities that are not nearly as limiting as a simple binary question of public v. private. Instead of focusing on the binary nature of service delivery within our policy debates which characterizes the delivery of services as either &lt;em>purely private&lt;/em> or &lt;em>purely public&lt;/em> each with its advocate class and all unable to resolve their differences or get things done so that people can get to the task of l i v i n, perhaps we should think more in terms of a spectrum. Focus our thinking about service delivery on a spectrum rather than a binary on-off switch allows us to focus our debates on finding the right point along the spectrum to deliver the services which we are speaking to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To Europeans this debate that occupies our time, the government is great v. government sucks debate, is hilarious. I get asked about it a lot. It is intuitive to most Europeans that service delivery operates on a spectrum. Services in Europe are routinely modified within the spectrum and also change over time due to efficiencies, politics, or many other factors. Last year there was an outcry within the UK as the conservative government was trying to move the National Health Service along the spectrum towards the private side which raised many alarms for people. But that debate, and many others within the politics of service delivery in Europe happen without the sky is falling, scream at your TV, Nancy Grace style of debate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I like that part of Europe. A lot. Because generally when the population that doesn't know anything about the delivery of such services simply gets out of the way things happen in a pretty smooth way. Not all the time. But most of the time when people who don't know things about things let the people who do know things about things do their jobs things run pretty well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course there are differences between the two. Incentives for one are different. Private sector actors have incentives to optimize their profits. To think of short term gains over long term innovation. To reduce costs and simplify delivery mechanisms. These are all well and good, but there is a place for them. Public sector actors have a different set of incentives. To ensure the widest access to the services. To ensure the right costing is built into the system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The difference in these set of incentives (of which the above is meant to be illustrative) are important to understand. But our polity just needs to remember that there is space within these incentives for harmonization. Once we stop thinking in the simplistic terms of &amp;ldquo;Government good&amp;rdquo; | &amp;ldquo;Government bad&amp;rdquo; and start asking the question of how this service should be delivered based on what &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rdquo; are trying to accomplish. Then a whole world of policy solutions is opened to us.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Try it during the upcoming election season. Watch a debate and ask yourself if the debaters are being overly reductive in how they are approaching a service delivery question. Those that are not being overly reductive &amp;ndash; that are in the business of finding solutions which will actually move us along a path rather than simply spewing forth banal answers &amp;ndash; those are the ones that I will be voting for.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Unreasonable Optimism and Why John Dickerson&amp;#8217;s (@jdickerson) Series Should Matter</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-10-06-my-unreasonable-optimism-and-why-john-dickersons-jdickerson-series-should-matter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-10-06-my-unreasonable-optimism-and-why-john-dickersons-jdickerson-series-should-matter/</guid><description>&lt;p>My Dad and I have this ongoing debate about campaigns. It has been ongoing for four years that I can remember but perhaps longer. It revolves around the forthrightness of campaigns to speak to the electorate logically, with courage, and while keeping within the bounds of logic and reasonableness. Instead of what I desperately want campaigns to do they do the opposite, spiraling into ever more irrelevant crap. Gaffes and ah ha’s are fun and interesting political theater but that is all it is. Theater. Theater is a farce. And we must stop hiring representatives to govern us based on a farcical audition system. This I have felt deeply for a long time. It colors most of my political worldview, rightly or wrongly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>John Dickerson wrote a &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/WyS3iH" title="How To Measure for a President, by John Dickerson">series&lt;/a> of pieces this week that I hope with all the optimism my increasing cynicism can muster that someday it will be viewed as a transformative work. In his work he pleads with the electorate in a way I know he believes. I’ve spent an hour a week more or less for the past seven years and I believe that he believes every word he wrote. His authenticity is easy to trust and recognize with that much exposure. His argument is basically that we need to rethink about how we treat Presidential campaigns. We are covering the wrong things he says to the media elite. You are emphasizing the wrong things he says to the campaigns. We are rewarding the wrong behavior he tells the electorate. And all of them/us need to hear it because all have a roll in fixing it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So what can we the electorate do? In my opinion it is our duty to educate ourselves about the issues, about what the President can actually control, and to take a decision based upon those items rather than the metrics of how many gaffes some poor guy or girl exposed to immense pressure takes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An informed and reasonable electorate is the only way we can pull ourselves out of this death spiral of hyper partisanship, reactionary media coverage, and off the charts dissatisfaction. We the electorate have as much to do with this, perhaps more, than the candidates do. Political leaders aren’t really leaders at all. At least in a democracy they are supposed to represent their constituents’ interests. Vying too far outside of these, and the politician loses their representative title. We call those people here in Africa: Dictators. The simple fact is that a politician is constrained by public opinion. So an ill-informed electorate, purposefully or otherwise, will logically reward the loudest rather than the smartest. Here’s the rub. We get the country we demand folks. When we refuse to educate ourselves on what the President does when we don’t demand intellectual and reasoned debate rather than stupid gaffery we end up with….Fox News and MSNBC yelling past each other.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are in a difficult situation. Right now. In the short term, I’m pessimistic, but in the long term I’m optimistic. I remain hopeful for two primary reasons.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, the grip of push consumption models of information continues to wane and simultaneously individual trust is replacing brand trust within the media. The former matters because when one unplugs from cable and consumes media and information on a purely pull model one’s ability to consume and process that information substantially increases. When you are in the mood for bubble gum you aren’t receptive to political messaging. Subliminal and uninformed voters barely process TV adds anymore. We are numb to them. But when you are in the mood for political messaging, you are in much better frame of mind to process that information. This is augmented by – the latter – individual trust located within both of one’s social graphs and interest graphs. Both of these significantly increase the ease which one can enter into the information funnel at headlines and steadily work downward through the increasing complexity to extreme wonkland if interested merely by reading, thinking, and clicking. Twitter leads to articles lead to counter arguments lead to source data. While this information funnel needs some work, people like Ethan Zuckerman at the Berkman Center and other terribly smart guys are thinking deeply about how this can operate. It will get better. And we will get better at using it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The second reason I resist encroaching cynicism is the rise of the Maker class. Art from Andy Warhol to the Breakfast Club to Rage Against the Machine has been warning us against getting too big and too homogeneous  It won’t work the artists warned. And they led the world. Long before there was a consultant class there were independent artists. But now DIY is everywhere and not only because Home Depot wants to sell you some lumber. Big is out and small is in. And I for one am incredibly satisfied. Music, for me, has never been more diverse and more wonderful. Despite the RIAA apocolypsing, music is the best I have ever experienced. And I’ve been following music for a decent little while now. Food is similarly wonderful. Farm to table restaurants and good wines make the old suburban standbys just places you go by default when you’re not in the know or when you are resigned to mediocrity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Small is in. Small is great. But small is messy. It refuses to be categorized as easily. It celebrates the individual, with its flaws and eccentricities, not in tension with the community (as the rhetoric from the right so often tries to frame it) but as part of it. Integral to the flow of the community. But this becomes problematic politically. Or so some argue. If  we decentralize and fracture the currently coalitions underpinning the current form of the Republican and Democratic parties so wonder what will happen thereafter. Some wonder if we had more than two viable national parties whether people would be able to parse the differences. I have no idea whether that is true, but I know that music, which is much farther ahead of politics in this area, is better than it is ever been. This is why I remain (perhaps unreasonably) optimistic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Micro-States; Pirates; Terrorists; The London Conference: What a Fascinating Time for Watchers of Somalis</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-01-30-micro-states-pirates-terrorists-the-london-conference-what-a-fascinating-time-for-watchers-of-somalis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-01-30-micro-states-pirates-terrorists-the-london-conference-what-a-fascinating-time-for-watchers-of-somalis/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/burningmax/2987516225/">&lt;img src="http://blog.caseykuhlman.com/assets/images/2012/2987516225_11e2cef572.jpg" alt="somali-days by burningmax @ flickr" tit="somali-days by burningmax @ flickr" />&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For almost four years now I’ve been a careful observer of Somali politicians. For three of those years I was paid to try to be their lawyer. To provide them expert international legal assistance tied to a deep network full of some of the finest international practitioners and thinkers in the world. But they rarely, if ever, wanted that help. So largely I invented work, I went into meetings and had a product to sell. &lt;em>I can’t buy you new computers, but I how about I help you write that legal framework that Parliament has required you to do&lt;/em>?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve spent a lot of time with Somali politicians, and I also spend a lot of time with other people who spend a lot of their time with Somali politicians. This is an expat’s life when you live in a pretty small town. I reference Hargeisa, a town of, oh, 500,00 to 1M people depending on who’s estimating as a small town.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And that it truly is. This is one of the most amazing things when you really get to know an African town. To learn how inter-connected things are is fascinating. This is what makes me do something foolish like invest everything I have into starting a law firm in a country which has very little (if any) law. Judges routinely dismiss cases with little to no justification. Parliamentarians make no estimates, and rarely even discuss, what the effects of this law will be in the next month, much less the next year – so legislation (a lot of it quite decent) is routinely ignored.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yet things work. I don’t believe in libertarianism – much to my father’s chagrin – it is incredibly unjust and inefficient. But I can say the Somalis are teaching me how to respect it, and how to work within its boundaries. I know a little but more importantly I truly care deeply about this place. I have spent more time in this place than I had in any one place since I was in college. I have joined, in many ways, the ranks of the diaspora (only the opposite way that that term is used).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a long time, when I first arrived, it seemed like no one really got what the hell was happening down here. See Nairobi is a long way away. And after the 2008 Hargeisa bombings, when pretty much all of the expats left the connections between Hargeisa and Nairobi were even more tenuous. So a disconnect really felt like it developed. Luckily, over the course of the previous year it has &lt;em>felt&lt;/em> like “Nairobi” is starting to get it. I don’t agree with everything I’m hearing coming out of the high level cluster meetings and typical other rumor mill stuff, but I must say that I agree with a lot of it (see, e.g., &lt;a href="http://blogs.fco.gov.uk/mattbaugh/2012/01/1a7/london-conference-on-somalia-building-momentum/" title="London Conference, Building Momentum">this initiative&lt;/a> by the UK’s government).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I did not think that a harder military strategy off the coast would reduce piracy. I really felt that a tribunal in Somaliland along with a huge police building effort in Puntland was the best possible shot at fixing things (basically pirate DDR is what needs to happen); I still feel this needs to happen, but the military situation seems to be putting a recent damper on the number of attacks. So they may be right, they may be wrong, but at least they aren’t &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/zA7LWR" title="Somali Pirates Seize 80% Fewer Ships as Early Strikes Work‎">dead wrong&lt;/a>. Not the way they were dead wrong in the early nighties when everyone that knew anything about Somalia would tell you how clearly wrong some of the actions were.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nairobi (by which I mean the big money and big – even if distant – powers), seems to be starting to understand two things: there has to be some element of external assistance to stabilize the situation, BUT the Somalis want to have assurances that this isn’t an invasion or their territorial fires start overheating. To do that largely means staying the hell out of the politics BUT also helping to create the conditions of stability long enough for the Somalis to figure out how they will be represented and what the terms are – which can often take months or years – even where you have a majority clan conferences these things take lots of time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most Somali analysts are quick to point out that the reason the South cannot seem to fix itself is that the Italians castrated the clan leader system. The problem has been for a long time that no one had the moral authority – among the Southern clans – to stand up to the gangsters that kept hijacking clan resources, state resources, international resources. They just continued to gobble them up like locusts and when they reached an end to their resources they just started gobbling each other. From the early warlord phase into the ICU takeover this is what continued happening.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But a couple of other things were happening also beneath the surface of that. For twenty years there seems to have been an identity crisis within much of the Somali community. This identity, just like lots of things in our lives, runs to the safest place it can find when it is threatened. For most Somalis that is somewhere around one or two or three or four or five clans below the major clan level. It varies by the individual and their experience where this safe place is. One thing I can say for sure, that for most people I’ve met in four years Northerners, Southerners, Easterners and Westerners, for the vast vast percentage of these people that place is no where even close to the pan-Somali level. This is and will for a long time remain the invalidity in the argument that the pan-Somali movement was a viable option without a dictator.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even after twenty years Somaliland politicians bicker nearly continuously; lack of trust within Somaliland is rife. The same can be said, only the distrust rises as you go clockwise around the circle.This deep distrust is deep seated in Somali lore going back to way before the mad mullah. By the time you get to Isaaq’s grandsons, they were already fighting with each other. I don’t like all my cousins, but I certainly know I’m not ready to fight with them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Luckily the Somalilanders – at the end and often despite this distrust – they make it work. Things haven’t fallen apart here and actually are going pretty well. It has taken a long time to solidify the post-conflict gains and to begin the development phase of their state building, but it is going. And, perhaps more importantly, it is going at a Somali pace. Somaliland really did have to retract after it separated from the South into basically a federated microstate solution. Sure there was a central government created at the Burco conference. But the amount of power and influence of that government was marginal. One cannot compare the power that Silanyo has with the power that Tuur had. The central government was present, but it has taken almost two decades of steady work before anyone gives it any mind about being anything other than a minor inconvenience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is another incredibly fascinating thing about being here now, this is the point where the Somaliland Government is really figuring itself and really trying to exert some will.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This gets us to the microstate solution. In my view, it should be endorsed as it is probably the best viable option currently. Some of the donors seem to be realizing that – as reflected in much of the language coming from the UK as well as the US’s two-track policy shift. In my opinion, the donors need to throttle back the incentives for state capture. When the mandate for the TFG ends UNDP needs to have the political courage to stop paying Parliamentarian salaries, and other than emergency aid the rest of the money flowing into the South needs to end. Then the donors need to let the Somalis work from their grassroots (microstate) levels up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Equal with this the Somalis have to take ownership. They really have to stop blaming &lt;em>all&lt;/em> of their problems on the international community and take ownership for their own mistakes. I can fully accept many Somalis gripes about the prior actions of external actors. And I fully understand their paranoia about external interventions in their problems. But equally they have to trust a bit more. And they have to take a lot more ownership. This is, at its most elemental, a Somali problem, and they have to be the ones to figure the solutions out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am cautiously optimistic about London Conference. A lot of the right things appear to being said. We will see what will happen but if the donors really wanted to get to the roots of the problems, they need to just shut up and they need to hold their next conference in a place which is neutral &lt;em>enough&lt;/em> to get all of the important-to-Somalis people under a great big, giant ass tree and then they need to not show up and to not pay. And then let them stay there until they figure it out. It will take a hell of a long time, but it will get done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It has taken the fine work of a lot of Somalis and Westerners for the awareness to be sufficiently raised as to why we’re here and what the hell can we do about it. I must say for the first time in a while I’m cautiously optimistic about all of the Somali region.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more perspective on the London Conference here are a few articles I thought highly incisive, particularly from the Somaliland view point: &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/zh7Zcm" title="Somaliland and the London Conference on Somalia">Article 1&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/z1OXHx" title="Six Elements for Success of Somali Conference in UK">Article 2&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Compromise &amp;amp; Governing: On Reading @ryanlizza&amp;#8217;s The Obama Memos</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-01-27-compromise-and-governing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-01-27-compromise-and-governing/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="hhttp://www.flickr.com/photos/barackobamadotcom/2913035652">&lt;img src="http://blog.caseykuhlman.com/assets/images/2012/2913035652_27460596bd.jpg" alt="Obama Barn by Barack Obama @ flickr" tit="Obama Barn by Barack Obama @ flickr" />&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I was in college my friend Dave and I would often fall asleep at some point during our millionth screening of Braveheart. We would often put the film on after the bars had closed and we had grabbed our drunken treat of the night and were not yet ready for bed. At the time we were training to be Marine officers and very interested in learning what it took to be a good leader. Near the beginning of the film there was a quote which I often thought about (at still think about):&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>You admire this man, this William Wallace. Uncompromising men are easy to admire. He has courage; so does a dog. But it is exactly the ability to &lt;em>compromise&lt;/em> that makes a man noble. And understand this: Edward Longshanks is the most ruthless king ever to sit on the throne of England. And none of us, and nothing of Scotland will remain, unless &lt;em>we&lt;/em> are as ruthless. Give ear to our nobles. Knowing their minds is the key to the throne.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>We would scoff at this quote. In our youth and lack of exposure to the world we felt that uncompromising was the way of the greatest leaders. That may still be true, but I have learned that it definitely is not true of the greatest rulers. Indeed, the greatest rulers are often those that are the greatest to compromise. Human nature being what it is, you will very rarely have complete agreement with a course of action. Multiply the amount of people a decision will affect and you necessarily multiply the different opinions (both rational and irrational) which will impact your decision before it is taken and laud or critique it after it is taken. This is a fundamental “problem” with ruling in a democracy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ryan Lizza has written a fantastically interesting piece for The New Yorker. He dives deeply into a trove of memos which circulated the Obama White House during the first term of that administration. He assembles a very interesting piece which does a great job of detailing the tensions that any President may face. I encourage everyone to read it, &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/zTXpzr" title="The Obama Memos">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is interesting for me, given my current diaspora state (relatively torn between Europe, America, and Africa), to compare the political processes which take place in a very new, somewhat inchoate democracy – Somaliland – to a very old, overly complex democracy – the US – while comparing both, which I view as an insider, to the relatively “clean” democratic processes that the Europeans embody. One of the difficult things in an independent executive system, where the governing functions of creating laws and putting those laws into action are separated between two branches of government, is that we tend to blame the “big man” for all of the problems. This happens in Somaliland just as often as it happens in the US. The realities of Presidential campaigns often do a disservice by blurring the lines. Much of the debate during a Presidential campaign revolves around big or small policy ideas that the President will have very little to no control over. As I was telling someone the other day, a President has an ability to stop a legislative action it doesn’t want to allow but it has little ability to make a legislative body do something that that body does not want to do. Yet these big policy ideas are a function of modern politics. Firstly they are easier to discuss than the minutae of what a President really does. Secondly, it is a method of acting somewhat uniformly in our very much decentralized system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Personally, reading the piece shows me what I was hoping to see. A President who has learned how to do what is possibly the most difficult and complex job on the planet. A President who remains willing to make compromises, but also has learned how to work the system. A President who still has standards and struggles to balance a bowing to the political winds with a deep devotion to his ideals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While Obama cannot get a large piece of greenhouse gas passed through (right now) domestically, he has floated a ton of money for research, innovation, and implementation of greenhouse reduction initiatives in other countries. While Obama faces complete stonewalling from his own legislators on jobs (right now), he has figured out how to incentivize job growth and business creation in other countries with entrepreneurial grants and collaborative agreements dominating much of the AID/DOS grants I’ve seen lately. While Obama cannot push forward comprehensive immigration reform (right now), he has put in place policies which make it much easier to get US visas (while remaining within the legislative caps mandated by various amendments to the Immigration and Nationalization Act) and illegal immigration flows are down – particularly from Mexico. These are largely international examples for a couple of reasons. First it is my area of interest so I follow it closer. Second the President has fundamentally more power over foreign policy than domestic policy. Third, Hillary – despite how divisive she may or may not be – is a brilliant bureaucrat and many of these initiatives are coming from her shop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No government is perfect, but where the President and his team have a reasonable amount of power I am genuinely pleased with what I see. There’s much to disagree with, but there is much more that I agree with. As we turn towards a full scale assault on us all with respect to choosing our next President one thing I would encourage everyone to do is to not get tricked by the red herrings of advertisements and debates and to focus on what the President can and does actually do on a daily / weekly / monthly / yearly basis. Choose wisely.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Preacher is Back. That&amp;#8217;s What I&amp;#8217;ve Been Waiting For.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-09-09-the-preacher-is-back-thats-what-ive-been-waiting-for/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-09-09-the-preacher-is-back-thats-what-ive-been-waiting-for/</guid><description>&lt;p>I just finished watching the jobs speech and my first thought was “were have you been”? The historian-poet-preacher in him which I fell in love with in the Yes We Can and Race speeches (collectively rather than individually) had found his groove tonight.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every artist struggles with finding their artistic voice, but for me, at this moment, this was balm to my soul. Someone, somewhere, does actually get it. But before I get to what I liked about the speech let me take a small detour and talk about how I think about my relationship between me and my government.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m currently staying at my brother’s, &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/kuhlman">@kuhlman&lt;/a>, house and he has a great dane. Due to our pomo lives we missed each other. He is off on a construction job overnight and I just returned from an overnight job myself. We missed each other and were not able to pass a key back and forth. When we were texting each other as to our current statuses and how we could coordinate this changeover, I asked him whether the house was locked. He responded, “Maggie’s the lock.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now Maggie is a wonderful bitch (which I mean literally). This bitch has a bark that will tear your hair off when she gets scared. I have no idea whether she has the bite to match it, and I like that I don’t know that, because her bark is scary enough. She is the perfect lock. See locks are on-off switches. But living, breathing beings are able to differentiate between when on is OK and off is OK. Sometimes the best lock is the one that can differentiate between when to bark and when to be happy because your friend is here to let you out to go take a piss.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And this is how I want my government to be. I don’t want to rely on my government unnecessarily. I understand that my successes and my failures are my own. But sometimes you want to know that if you are forced, due to the situations of living your life, to deviate from your normal patterns, that there will be a being there to have your back. You don’t want something that is impersonal and cannot differentiate between friend and foe. You want a bitch there that is both happy to see you and happy to go have a poo in the yard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That story said, there were many things that I loved about the Obama speech.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, he chastised both sides. He told some hard truths. These words were his preacher robes which I have not seen him don for a long, long time. Too long. And it was needed. Both sides of the political aisle have been being babies for a while now and the only people suffering are the middle class of America. This &lt;em>must&lt;/em> change. The only way to get shit done is to sometimes put aside the differences and realize that the betterment of the country is at stake. Since I’ve spent so much time in African countries where politics is so personality based I am especially receptive to the in-out-group mechanisms which operate in such an environment. And if you want to actually help, if you want to get something done in this world you’re going to have to figure out a compromise. Because, as the President of the United States, said “No single individual built America on their own. We built it together. .” What a great line. Sometimes we have to act as a community. Individualism is great, but no one at no time has EVER acted completely in isolation as an individual. We call those beings the last creature of their species. What is required, from time to time, is looking out for those that may not be as smart, or have the opportunities, or whatever as we fancy of ourselves. And in that vein, next week I hope to go pound some nails to help members of my family’s community who were affected by the tornadoes earlier this year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Second, it was perhaps the most patriotic speech which has been given during my lifetime. It was a call to action. It was competitive (which we Americans love). It told us that there was going to be some hard days ahead. This was the poet that I’ve been longing for. This was the inspiration that I’ve been hoping for. This was the America that I have studied and that I love. Just turn off your brain (I’ll get to the wonky stuff in a moment) and listen to the words of his speech and tell me that you are not inspired by &lt;em>something&lt;/em>, or even &lt;em>anything&lt;/em> in this speech. No matter your political affiliation this man gets that he was “hired” to execute the laws in the best interest of us all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Third, it cut through all the bullshit, stupid rhetoric which neither matters nor helps. He has learned from his own failures to properly leverage both the power of his position and the wave of people power which put him in that chair. This was a pragmatic speech to its core. What he said is exactly, *exactly, *what economists have proven matter for the economic development of your country. There are many opinions as to the best, but almost every economist will agree that what is necessary for economic development (this comes from my international development perspective) is: infrastructure, education, jobs for low-skilled individuals, and healthcare. We’ll leave aside for now the reasons why each of these exist. Similarly I’m going to take a mulligan on healthcare because I don’t have the energy to enter that debate as to why people that don’t have millions in the bank don’t *deserve *to not feel awful all the time, but if you care about that watch Sicko and shutup. But see here’s the thing. Our schools are falling apart. While we prosecute irrational wars overseas (which I’ve participated in and have some modicum of epistemic authority here), we’re not able to give the support that our teachers require to educate our children. Our infrastructure is subpar. Visit Europe and try to convince me that we are still number one. Drill, Baby, Drill.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So this is a short review, but my early take (before reading any punditry) is that it was brilliant and one of Obama’s best performances. On a personal level I’m happy for three reasons: (1) the poet I wanted is finding his voice, (2) the pragmatist we all need is finally leveraging his platform, and (3) the wonk in me is reassured that someone up there will bark when necessary and greet when necessary.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There were many great moments of this speech for me. But the one that stands out. The one that I will think of tomorrow. Is this.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>No single individual built America on their own. We built it together. We have been, and always will be, one nation, under God, indivisible, with liberty and justice for all; a nation with responsibilities to ourselves and with responsibilities to one another. Members of Congress, it is time for us to meet our responsibilities.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>What did you think of the speech?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On The Somali Famine: A Thought Collage</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-07-30-somali-famine-collage/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-07-30-somali-famine-collage/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/oxfameastafrica/5974209957/in/photostream/" title="Original via Oxffam East Africa @ Flickr">&lt;img src="http://www.flickr.com/photos/oxfameastafrica/5974209957/in/photostream/" alt="New arrivals wait to get processed original via Oxfam East Africa @ Flickr" title="Original via Oxffam East Africa @ Flickr">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>The original photo is &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/oxfameastafrica/5974209957/in/photostream/" title="Original via Oxffam East Africa @ Flickr">here&lt;/a>, my alteration is &lt;a href="http://blog.caseykuhlman.com/wp-content/blogs.dir/4/files/2011/07/5974209957_75f686bf8b_o-e1312029321201.jpg" title="My alteration">here&lt;/a>. If I had to title the alteration, I would call it An Homage to Motherhood&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This post is a bit random in nature, but it is a compilation of some sources and commentary and thought. So think of it as more of a collage than a strict narrative. Much of this was originally posted on &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/nunfsy" title="Original Post">Google &lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="thought-1-early-warning-systems-worked">Thought 1: Early Warning Systems Worked&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We’ve known this was coming for well over six months. According to &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/r1eFZk">here&lt;/a>, it has been well known since November 2010 which seems about right to me. Those that are paid to do handle these things were trying their best (more on that in a minute) to address the situation but were unable to deliver the food aid at that time. There’s little to suggest that anything has changed in the interim and delivery of the aid will somehow be magically easier.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Up here in Somaliland we were taking bucket showers as early as March of this year. Although it does take a while to get to the point where there is a certified famine (due to a strict criteria to certify a disaster/drought as a famine), all of the early warning systems worked. The rains ended up coming for Somaliland, but they did not come (until a couple of weeks ago, and way too late for the livestock and vegetables) for the South. Yet in Somaliland the Government took a lot of steps to ease the suffering of the pastoralists and farmers in their territory.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Amaryta Sen is famous for saying that all famines are avoidable failures of governments. Somaliland’s government passed that test. Ministers were out escorting water tankers into the country-side, TV shows on water conservation were aired on national television (not that Somalis need these lessons, but anyway), and mostly it was a local re-distribution effort rather than an international aid effort.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is an impossible hypothetical what would have happened if the rains had not come to Somaliland. Yet, I suspect that the efforts would have been decently well-thought out and executed as a community. All of it would have been led by Somalis with the international community playing a supporting role, as it should be.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="thought-2-extent-of-suffering">Thought 2: Extent of Suffering&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The famine is confined to two regions of very Southern Somalia which are sparsely populated to begin with. Although millions are at risk, it isn’t millions that are actually suffering. This isn’t meant to minimize the suffering of those that are suffering, it is simply to bring some perspective. I’m not cynical, how can you be when you look at pictures like &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/qYLsnF" title="mourning at the grave of a 3 y/o">this&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Coincidentally, these are the same areas where al-Shabaab has a very strong control over the population. One picture that has certainly caught my eye is of a Shabaab soldier with rows and rows of squatting women behind him looking distraught. The photographer obviously focused on the warrior, but the women in the background are the stars of the shot for me. It is a soberingly iconic reminder of what is really going on. See the picture &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/q5CAfm" title="shabaab soldier and women">here&lt;/a>, and look close.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shabaab has been playing both sides of this issue. First they banned nearly every aid agency from working in their zones. This was a long time ago, and ironically enough when I’ve been in Nairobi talking to people who work in the South they were telling me that the (non-Somali) agencies which were allowed to continue working were faith-based organizations like &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/nhch7c">World Vision&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/r07JSt">ADRA&lt;/a>. Mostly these organizations were headed by one or at most two Kenyans and largely they were left alone to do their work, except for one young aid worker I heard about who was killed by Shabaab for proselytizing. We may feel bad for the man’s family, but it was a bit of &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/n2KAxP">Darwinism&lt;/a> at work if you ask me.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="thought-3-aid-agencydysfunctionalism--restrictions">Thought 3: Aid Agency Dysfunctionalism &amp;amp; Restrictions&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>WFP-Somalia is, for those of us that have been in/worked on Somalia for more than 30 seconds, about the &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/oomANF">most&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/n58Y82">dysfunctional&lt;/a>&lt;a href="http://wsl.so/oqX8Y5"> organization&lt;/a>. I have serious doubts that the increases in aid will end up as food in bellies – except for (maybe) those that are working in Daadab where it is a bit more straight-forward to deliver and where there is some semblance of oversight. Also there are fundamental structural problems with the way aid agencies (including NGOs and UN organs) are built and work. See &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/p7M6aZ">here&lt;/a> for a great discussion of this (but rather technical if you’re not into the biz of aid/development). The summary:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In summary, a major reason why aid agency presence has not translated into reduced vulnerability to, for example, famine, is due to aid agencies not being geared to do just that:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Aid agencies do not build their programs around context, but are influenced by donor interest, assumptions, internal capacity and their own models of approach.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Aid agencies don’t have resources that can be quickly tasked from one mode of operation (development) to another (emergency response).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Aid agencies’ internal measuring systems do not hold them accountable to how well they reduce the risk of a disaster happening, only on how well they acheive project deliverables.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>And aid agencies own internal systems and staffing do not allow a seamless transition from a long-term development presence to an emergency response.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Yes, the international community has made many mistakes. But I do not believe that it is the role of the international community to lead at times like this. I strongly believe that the role of the international community is to support local efforts with materiale, technical assistance, logistics expertise, and funding. I am disheartened by the increasing frequency of calls for an intervention on the level of the 92/93 intervention which burst the New World Order bubble and ushered in a decade of UN futility as the world’s largest NGO body of political discourse.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even though it is true that the international community, US, UK, Italy, etc. are definitely not without fault, I’m terribly tired of the narrative which places the entirety of the blame on these external parties. An example is here, where there is an entire, well written &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/quvuzF">post&lt;/a> by an educated Somali without the smallest hint of acceptance for any responsibility by the Somali community for what is happening (other than a few “criminals”). Here’s the crux of his argument.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If we had had foresight and acted upon it; if the Marines had disarmed the warlords; if the U.N. Security Council had issued arrest warrants for the warlords early on, stopping them from prolonging the failure of the state; if the Security Council had dealt with the warlords — who had denied starving millions access to food — speedily and decisively, in the same way it dealt with the genocidal regimes in Serbia, Rwanda, Sierra Leone and Sudan, then al-Qaeda would not have established a secure base from which to plan terrorist attacks. Our country would not have been hamstrung by the enormity of our problem, nor would it have become the world’s worst humanitarian disaster.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>A friend on G asked me a good question:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I would be interested if anybody knows some more details on the reason Al-Shabab has refused to let the aid organisations in. I mean, no matter what they publicly say, I am sure they feel the pressure of famine too. So why is it not possible to find some kind of middle ground? Are the NGOs reluctant to give up control over food deliveries? If yes, is that justified? &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/p3m5eU" title="Peter Dorrie on Google Plus">~Peter Dorrie&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>My answer was that that’s part of it. Another big part of it is donor restrictions on supporting terrorist organizations. It is difficult to say with any certainty what Shabaab’s position is as they are terribly decentralized and non-uniform. Their position isn’t terribly rational but it is basically isolationist (like N.Korea, Taliban, Myanmar, etc.). They came to power on an anti-invaders platform and largely have kept to that meme throughout. On top of their irrationalities on banning bras, samosas, music, and anything that is fun, the group is funadamentally more nationalistic than it is Islamist (which is why I have always questioned the depth of their linkages with an Arab-led organization like Al-Qaeda).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are other things in play. According to &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/rpMQUy">this&lt;/a> article which examines this in a bit more detail.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The first point I would make is that al Shabab is minimizing the crisis because, as many observers and experts are saying, the movement itself likely made the famine worse. Famines often (always?) result not only from failed rains or population growth, but also government policies, especially denial and inaction. . . . Every indication points to the conclusion that al Shabab not only fit into this regional trend [of refusing to recognize or limiting acknowledgement of the extent of a drought/famine because it highlights the ruling organization's shortcomings or racism], but was – because of its limited resources, its preoccupation with the civil war, and its ideology – a particularly bad offender.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My second thought is that when looking at al Shabab’s hostility to outsiders, it is worthwhile to try to understand the movement’s thinking from the inside. . . . The movement is made up mostly of young men (its name, after all, is Arabic for “the youth”), many of whom were children, or were not even born yet, when the Somali state collapsed in 1991. They have only known war and instability. They have seen weak would-be central governments come and go, they have seen clan rivalry tear at the social and political fabric of the country, and they have seen a parade of external actors, some of whom, like Ethiopia when it occupied Somalia from late 2006 to early 2009, carried out massive violence. Growing up in that environment would brutalize many people and make them deeply suspicious of outsiders.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But the famine strikes directly at the relationship between al Shabab and its constituents. The movement is taking a huge risk if it tries to solve this problem through violence and denial. Al Shabab controls territory, and so it must have some local support – support that is likely based in large part on al Shabab’s ability to offer some security and stability after years of fighting. Allowing the famine to go unchecked could destroy whatever local legitimacy al Shabab possesses, potentially resulting in infighting, fragmentation, rebellions, or desertions. From this perspective, it is not difficult to see why al Shabab originally decided to re-admit external aid agencies. And yet it now seems that paranoia and suspicion of outsiders are winning out in the leadership’s thinking.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>For an aid worker’s perception of this see &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/r9qxK6">this&lt;/a> great article by &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/pUP9XF">@morealtitude&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>An invitation from al Shabbab central command may sound like a good enough reason to think aid workers would be safe re-entering south-central, but in fact it isn’t. Like many insurgency groups, al Shabbab is as much a network of affiliated warlords as it is a hierarchical paramilitary organization. Fighters on the ground- the ones with guns, grenades and IEDs- will align themselves first with their local commander, and only after that with al Shabbab central. Then there’s the assumption that the message is even getting down to those field grunts and their captains. Or the notion that some 16-year-old with an AKM, who’s never been to school but has spent the last ten years being told that westerners are pillaging his country and deserve to die, will pay any attention to some recent order from someone he’s never heard, when he sees an NGO Land Cruiser drive past.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="thought-4-the-role-of-somalis">Thought 4: The Role of Somalis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Through all that I’ve read, I am most heartened by the diaspora involvement. Pull up &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/oIgTvU">#feedsomalia&lt;/a> and you’ll see lots of activity. New, caring diaspora members are increasing their networks and ability to influence. This is a long-term positive.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While the immediate causes of the crisis have been the drought and insecurity in the south, there is something more fundamental at play here. &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/rdLcUg">This&lt;/a> article digs a bit beyond the boilerplate rhetoric.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Drought is not a new environmental condition for much of Africa but a recurring one. The semi-arid Horn of Africa and the entire Sahelian region — running just south of the Sahara Desert across the continent — have long experienced erratic rainfall. While climate change may be exacerbating rainfall variability, traditional livelihoods in the region are adaptable to deal with situations when rainfall is not dependable. . . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Traditionally, herders ranged widely across the landscape in search of better pasture, focusing on areas as meteorological conditions dictated. The approach worked because, unlike fenced-in pastures in North America, it was incredibly flexible and adapted to variable rainfall. As farming has expanded, including in some instances to large-scale commercial farms, the routes of herders have become more concentrated and more vulnerable to drought. [Note, the conflict between the pastoralists and agriculturalists is one of the many, many causes of insecurity in the south.] . . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just as death from exposure is not an inherent result of a cold winter, famine is not a natural consequence of drought. Simply put, the structure of human society often determines who is affected and to what degree.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Fundamentally, the core of the problem is a breakdown of the social redistribution networks which are a basis of Somali culture (see Somaliland’s reaction described above). The diaspora &lt;em>should&lt;/em> be taking the lead, as they are much closer to the realities of the situation than the US Representative for Somalia (we don’t have an ambassador any longer) is to the situation. The more Somali community leaders take charge, accept the situation, and work towards a solution – the faster the entire situation (meaning more than the famine which is temporary) will stabilize and improve.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more on the diaspora’s efforts, see &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/n5pN4r">here&lt;/a> (among other &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/oIgTvU">places&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="thought-6-starvation-porn">Thought 6: Starvation Porn&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://wsl.so/prWxac">Poverty/Starvation Porn&lt;/a> is very real and am happy that it is being talked about outside of the echo chamber of the “aid bloggers/tweeters” (for lack of a better label). There have been some great &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/om4GAY">articles&lt;/a> which have challenged the ethics of this type of coverage, which have come out of the situation. Here’s his punch-line:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Because it’s a cycle. African governments know that drought is coming and they don’t prepare. Foreign charities working there talk about long-term plans to help people become self-sufficient but they’ve been failing to achieve them for 20 years. It’s as much about politics and war and poor economic policies as it is about no rain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m no expert but I know that much. I also know it’s wrong that every few years we’re faced with an “emergency” that could have been prevented, that aid groups must frantically try to raise money to respond to, that journalists need to find emaciated babies at death’s door and film and photograph and write about them before the world gives a damn.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>While there &lt;em>is some&lt;/em> value in showing the extent of suffering, it definitely skews the situation. While that is great marketing for aid organizations, as most of us who have worked in the developing world intuitively understand increases in aid flows do not necessarily end up as food in bellies or kids’ butts on school benches. As Haiti and Japan have shown there is an absorptive capacity formula to disaster relief whereby increases in aid can end up resulting in more rotten food or spoiled medicines rather than where it was intended. As &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/njzSQL">this&lt;/a> post from a former World Vision worker puts it, “Poverty is not an image, or a statistic; poverty has a face, a name and a story.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, most aid workers are quick to admit that there is a dualism to poverty porn as am sure they are quite happy with what they get in their bank account at the end of the month (and largely it is money that is well deserved as this is very hard work). But it is not easy to see what you’re working on cheapened by skewed coverage. Some of the ads for help, in particular the one on the Tumblr dashboard (can’t upload screenshot for some reason but at least the kids in the photo are smiling).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An aid worker / blogger who I have lots of respect for has put it this way in &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/p7M6aZ">this article&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Articles are starting to look like a fill-the-blanks template that the reporters are all sharing around: Quote some stats about the famine; talk about the complicating factor of al Shabbab making life difficult in Somalia; drop in some pithy quotes about the fact that short-term aid is repetitive and doesn’t solve the underlying problems (always with a nod to the fact that, well, of course it saves lives now); then end on the dark yet hopeful twist that while aid agencies clearly don’t have it right, clearly what’s needed is ‘long-term solutions’. Yeah, cool, thanks. . . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But what I’m really ratty about is not that what the media are saying is wrong &lt;em>per se&lt;/em>. My problem is, they’re making noise but missing the point. . . . [Point 1] By rabbiting on about long-term solutions (I’m sorry, what solutions did you suggest, exactly?), they make it sound like nobody’s ever come up with that idea before. . . . Point two is, these solutions aren’t simple in the real-world.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="thought-7-what-can-be-done--what-can-you-do">Thought 7: What Can Be Done / What Can You Do&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Military intervention is about the worst solution human minds could conjure. History should be a lesson here. Somalis are phenomenal at skewing international interventions intended to help as invasions of their sovereignty. And in general Somalis are pretty duplicitous as to outsiders.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Second worst idea to me is trying to deliver via trucks and ground workers within the Shabaab zones. I fundamentally disagree that the US Gov should “work with Shabaab” as &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/r1eFZk">this&lt;/a> article by Richard Dowden of the Royal African Society argues. This is a golden opportunity for the Somalis to see the results of their acquiescence to Shabaab’s presence. The easiest thing one can learn from Somali history is that when they’re sick of you they’ll find a way to overthrow you. When the communities within the Shabaab zones get sick of them they will kick them out of those communities and I know if I was living in these communities I would certainly be pretty circumspect about Shabaab. Of course no one wants to stay “starve them out” as that is cruel and inhumane treatment, but delivery within Shabaab’s areas I am 64.8% sure will end in a worse situation than never going in. As &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/pUP9XF">@morealtitude&lt;/a> put it &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/r9qxK6">here&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Letting aid workers in solves many problems for al Shabbab. It demonstrates to its own people that it’s taking steps to solve the problem. It helps slow the outflux of refugees. It brings in resources that bolster the population- which may be appropriated by fighters at times, or the effects may be indirect, such as more money in the economy that supports fighters’ families which in turn supports them. And, if aid agencies don’t do the right thing by al Shabbab, it gives them fresh ammunition in the polarizing of its people against the west.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Not increasing aid at all within Somalia is the best possible solution in my mind. The best option within Somalia is to stay out of the diaspora’s way with respect to their remittance flows into Somalia so people can purchase from local markets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was talking the other day with a few friends who work in this area. They told me that the real heart-break is that after people have trekked to the refugee camps in Kenya and Ethiopia they are finding that the food isn’t there. In these refugee camps there is a host government who is not impeding the delivery of aid and there is a relatively well-trekked cow-path for the logisticians to follow. Increasing the flows to these areas is a relatively straight-forward process and will ease one of the main problems while staying away from the quagmire.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next best options are to work through Somali NGOs and increase the flows that they are delivering, continue and maybe increase the &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/r7VE6P">air drops&lt;/a> (although these have to be terribly costly from a utilitarian point of view, and finally increase more traditional types of delivery within Mogadishu which the TFG / AMISOM troop relatively control.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to give here are some organizations (in the order I would give to them if I had disposable income and wasn’t already fully invested in Somalis):&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://wsl.so/qdaZLT">MSF&lt;/a> (Doctors without Borders who provide extensive medical care in the refugee camps)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://wsl.so/rgGS3S">Save the Children&lt;/a> (who have been working in the camps since the beginning)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://wsl.so/ojJQ0R">OXFAM-AUS&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/qCEFxc">OXFAM-UK&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/n7LClH">OXFAM-US&lt;/a> (Who also provides water and other services in the camps)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://wsl.so/pfIBe4">IRC&lt;/a> (Who provides a number of services within the refugee camps)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OK, So He&amp;#8217;s Gone. What Now?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-05-02-ok-so-hes-gone-what-now/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-05-02-ok-so-hes-gone-what-now/</guid><description>&lt;p>So I woke up this morning to the news. Obama Killed Osama. In my groggy state, I couldn’t really piece together what was happening on my collated facebook and twitter streams until I saw something similar to the previous sentence. I think the first thing I cognized was a friend’s facebook post: “Osama, so 10 years ago.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I went to NYTimes.com and saw the huge headline and the gigantic picture of the President staring at me, resolute &amp;amp; determined. After reading the article, and then watching my Twitter feeds more closely than usual today (which has been a busy one and not really allowed me to dig as deep into the commentary as I would like), I think my overall thought is, “Osama, so 10 years ago.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is actually quite amazing to consider that it was almost 10 years ago that I was sitting with my Marine infantry officer friends in our boxers and t-shirts watching GWB announce to the world that our nation’s military was on its highest alert and looking around the room thinking, “Huh?” as a typhoon raged outside and we couldn’t even leave the building. That was 9-11-01. This is 02-05-11 (date formats have been shifted in accordance with my mindset).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The news, while large, seems quaint. Many nations with majority muslim populations have bigger problems today, and they now have viable outlets for those problems. Moderate muslims the world over have increasingly spoken out against extremism (exhibit A is the commercial I watch on Qatar based MBC movie channel which shows a young teenager watching extremist videos and ends with his mom watching him on one crying and then flashes something in Arabic which I assume says, “don’t be an idiot and blow yourself up”). Al Qaeda has fractured, has become cellular and largely unable to organize anything beyond a small isolated bombing for a long time now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My main question as to what now has much less to do with the muslim majority areas and much more to do with America. Our shorthand for “the enemy” is gone. So what will we do now? It is very difficult to motivate people, populations, and most importantly fighters to fight a war where they cannot “see” the reason that they are fighting. Our reason in Iraq left, but there was still a face there that was lingering, hovering over the consciousness. That face is now at the bottom of the ocean. I think we can smile that an evil human has gone, but the real point, the real concern I have, or better put, the hope that I hold to is that we Americans can now get back to showing the world that we know more than how to fight. That we know how to compete, how to build, how to innovate, how to drive progress, how to balance divergent political interests, how to develop systems which bring jobs and health and education. Let those be our exports. Instead of our current portfolio: facebook, google, and guided missiles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Concisely put by my friend: “Osama. So 10 Years Ago.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On Tea Partiers &amp;amp; Rule-Free Systems: Football, NASCAR &amp;amp; Regulatory Authority</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-01-26-tea-partiers-rule-free-systems-football-nascar-regulatory-authority/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-01-26-tea-partiers-rule-free-systems-football-nascar-regulatory-authority/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“An association of men who will not quarrel with one another is a thing which has never yet existed, from the greatest confederacy of nations down to a town meeting or a vestry.” ~ Thomas Jefferson&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I know I am generalizing, but since many that I know and love subscribe to many of these philosophies maybe I do have a small bit of perspective here.  Let me take a look at the Free Market system and rules.  Many have argued that rules are inherrently anti-market.  That the opposite of capitalism is rule-making by regulators.  Maybe that is right in some areas, but I would argue that it depends on the specific area in mind.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“The big-government crowd is drawn to the compulsory nature of centralized authority. They can’t imagine an undirected social order. Someone needs to be in charge—someone who knows better. Big government is audacious and conceited. By definition, government is the means by which citizens are forced to do that which they would not do voluntarily. Like pay high taxes. Or redistribute tax dollars to bail out the broken, bloated pension systems of state government employees. Or purchase, by federal mandate, a government-defined health-insurance plan that is unaffordable, unnecessary or unwanted. For the left, and for today’s Democratic Party, every solution to every perceived problem involves more government—top-down dictates from bureaucrats presumed to know better what you need. Tea partiers reject this nanny state philosophy of redistribution and control because it is bankrupting our country.” ~Dick Armey &amp;amp; Matt Kibbe @ &lt;a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748704407804575425061553154540.html">WSJ&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Reject Cap &amp;amp; Trade - Stop costly new regulations that would increase unemployment, raise consumer prices, and weaken the nation’s global competitiveness with virtually no impact on global temperatures.” ~ Tea Party Manifesto as defined by the Tea Party Patriots available &lt;a href="http://www.contractfromamerica.com/Idea.aspx">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Despite universal acknowledgement that Americans enjoy a free, open, and vibrant Internet, the FCC is relentlessly pursuing a massive regulatory regime that would stifle broadband expansion, create congestion, slow Internet speeds, jeopardize job retention and growth, and lead to higher prices for consumers.” ~ Virginia Tea Party Patriot Federation letter to the FCC re: Net Neutrality, excerpted &lt;a href="http://www.crunchgear.com/2010/08/13/the-tea-party-hates-net-neutrality-because-its-an-affront-to-free-speech-umm/">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Tea party members believe in this invisible hand spoken of by Adam Smith. Society is better off because of the free market. A person invents something so that they can make money, but in that self interest benefits society as a whole. Did the government invent the car, the computer, or airplane? Nope, self interested individuals invented these things. Did these inventions enrich society as a whole? Yes. Think about the amount of jobs created by the computer industry alone, everything these days (seemingly) has computer technology in it. Think about the amount of jobs created by the auto industry. When government steps into the free market it creates advantages for those it supports and disadvantages for those who is doesn’t support. The law of supply and demand has been tampered with, and the market is artificially manipulated. Sometimes these manipulations have a positive impact, only to come crashing back down. Most of the time they have a negative impact on the market.” ~ Available &lt;a href="http://hubpages.com/hub/what-the-tea-party-stands-for-free-markets">here&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Every generation needs a new revolution.” Thomas Jefferson&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I actually really like what the Tea Partiers have been able to accomplish, although I am about as far away from them policy-wise as possible, I like the fact that they are shaking things up for the entrenched political interests on both sides of the aisle.  That said, I think they are dead wrong when it comes to their hatred and shunning of rules, so I’d like to take a little moment here and explain things from my side.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Think about sports.  Particularly, think about football.  A lot of rules were made in football between the mid-80′s to mid-90′s which had to do with protecting the quarterback.  Why is this person special?  Likely it was less because of his primacy on the playing field, and more likely because of his primacy in the board room.  Fine, but when those rules were adopted I don’t remember (although maybe it happened) any pundits arguing for the demise of football as we know it.  They were saying, no we need some fair competition, and if I spend Y of my cap money on a quarterback, I should have the opportunity to let that investment play out.  There was still plenty of competition, not the least of which was during the off season for prime players.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then let’s look at the salary cap &amp;amp; profit sharing mechanism that the owners have set up.  If this was tried in Washington it would have about a 0% chance of surviving a first draft and whoever the unlucky sap was that had the job of writing a first draft would be instantly shunned as a communist.  But when it comes to our beloved sport we say how great it is that small market teams like Pittsburgh still have the same chance of surviving as big market teams like New York.  Indeed big markets haven’t dominated football in ages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Compare this to baseball.  That is the sport, for those of you who may remember, with the sticks and the balls and the clay in a diamond with a bunch of people basically standing around all the time.  There were two major turnoffs for many I know from my generation about baseball (besides it’s boring which I would argue against).  (1) “In baseball you can just go out and buy your team.  There is no thrill in just zero to winning.” It wasn’t satisfying when the Marlins bought a team and won the World Series in the late nineties.  Not at all satisfying.  (2) “They absolutely turned a blind eye to the steroid situation.”  Well, there you have it folks, rules (football) v. non-rules (baseball).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let us talk NASCAR.  I grew up watching Dale Earnhartt, Bill Elliot, and those guys.  I was a number 3 guy.  I went to the Dayton 500 and remember the after effects of a fantastic Ricky Rudd accident that is still likely shown on best 100 crashes of all time on late night Spike TV.  What do people like about NASCAR?  What I liked about it is that the competition is based on pure skill.  It is pure skill in driving, and it is pure skill in engineering.  But engineering in the fine-tune sense.  The driver with the fastest car (interpret: has built the most efficient system) who is the best driver on that day (interpret: has great adaptability) most of the time wins.  It is fast and loud and visciously entertaining to go to the races.  But really races boil down to (besides keeping your hipster appeal by “making fun of the white trash people.”) a human struggle to best their machine and their elements.  But if you want to talk about systems with rules, the NASCAR rule book is lots of pages long.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So rules, in and of themselves do not serve to stifle competition.  They often serve, instead, to shift power away from entrenched interests (NY Yankees) towards more of a meritocratic environment.   I’m all for rules if they allow two things: (1) lower barriers to entry (and no, it doesn’t matter to me if that comes at the cost of entrenched interests or people/entities with bigger bankrolls than I) and (2) promotes a meritocratic environment.  Those are the essential parts of the American dream which I hold onto.  I do not begrudge anyone their own perspectives and values that they hold on to, but those are the ones I hold as truisms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is also why I &lt;a href="http://watershedlegal.com/about">work with small businesses here in Somaliland&lt;/a>.  If you want to know the effects of zero rule making look here.  When people want to see how a society (which isn’t much different than an American one – a coming post) operates under anarchical situations pick up a book and see what is happening (beyond the terrorism) in the three different major areas of Somalia – each with a progressively more mature rule-making capability.  And then compare those with a more advanced rule making capability of neighboring Ethiopia.  You can draw a distinct and direct correlation between stability, progress, and rule-making authority.  The most anarchical is the least developed.  The least anarchical is the most developed.  And in those sentences I’m conflating anarchy as an antonym of exercised rule-making authority of a government.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>