<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>somalia on underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/somalia/</link><description>Recent content in somalia on underWater desert Blogging</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Casey Kuhlman</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/somalia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What&amp;#8217;s this about attacking pirates on land?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2012-03-26-whats-this-about-attacking-pirates-on-land/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2012-03-26-whats-this-about-attacking-pirates-on-land/</guid><description>So there was some chatter Friday on my Twitter feed about how EU NAVFOR (the EU’s Naval Forces) would be authorized to attack on land. For example:
New EUNAVFOR guidelines allow attacking #pirate targets on late, while #NATO task force stays maritime. #somalia
— Jay Bahadur (@PuntlandPirates) March 23, 2012
My thoughts were quickly to escalation. Escalation is important not only for reasons that anyone who feels attacked or invaded would be willing to increase the violence to protect their stuff, but also because Somalis feel incredibly threatened right now.</description></item><item><title>Micro-States; Pirates; Terrorists; The London Conference: What a Fascinating Time for Watchers of Somalis</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2012-01-30-micro-states-pirates-terrorists-the-london-conference-what-a-fascinating-time-for-watchers-of-somalis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2012-01-30-micro-states-pirates-terrorists-the-london-conference-what-a-fascinating-time-for-watchers-of-somalis/</guid><description>For almost four years now I’ve been a careful observer of Somali politicians. For three of those years I was paid to try to be their lawyer. To provide them expert international legal assistance tied to a deep network full of some of the finest international practitioners and thinkers in the world. But they rarely, if ever, wanted that help. So largely I invented work, I went into meetings and had a product to sell.</description></item><item><title>On The Somali Famine: A Thought Collage</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2011-07-30-somali-famine-collage/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2011-07-30-somali-famine-collage/</guid><description>The original photo is here, my alteration is here. If I had to title the alteration, I would call it An Homage to Motherhood.
This post is a bit random in nature, but it is a compilation of some sources and commentary and thought. So think of it as more of a collage than a strict narrative. Much of this was originally posted on Google .
Thought 1: Early Warning Systems Worked We’ve known this was coming for well over six months.</description></item><item><title>On Going Local: Finding Your Happy Place</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-10-12-local-finding-happy-place/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-10-12-local-finding-happy-place/</guid><description>On Going Local is a new (short) series that I’ll be running which will attempt to look at my life from an objective perspective as I transition from and NGO worker into an entrepreneur here in the developing world.
![My Happy Place via Lady_k @ flickr]({{ site.url }}{{ site.root }}{{ site.images_dir }}/{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; }}/4431206216_8eacda9a75_z.jpg) Photo via Lady_k @ flickr
I’ve been here in Somaliland now for around two and a half years now.</description></item><item><title>Decoding the Somali Mind: A Guide for Expats (Anecdotal, Not Definitive Version): Wants v. Needs</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-06-28-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-v/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-06-28-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-v/</guid><description>This is a new series containing a few stories which have stood out in my time here in Somaliland and have helped me to understand a bit more a culture that in many ways is very different from my own, but in many ways is not. This series explores those differences.
[![want need syrup by thebrianmeyer @ flickr][2]][2]
Every development worker I’ve ever met, and I can say with confidence, without exception, hates the following phrase with a passion: “What we really need is….</description></item><item><title>Decoding the Somali Mind: A Guide for Expats (Anecdotal, Not Definitive Version): Introduction</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-06-21-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-06-21-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version/</guid><description>This is a new series containing a few stories which have stood out in my time here in Somaliland and have helped me to understand a bit more a culture that in many ways is very different from my own, but in many ways is now. This series explores those differences.
[![BraiNut 1.0 via sath.es @flickr][2]][2] via sath.es @flickr
I have lived &amp;amp; worked with Somalis here in Somaliland for over two years now.</description></item><item><title>Understanding War [in Mogadishu]</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-04-17-understanding-war-in-mogadishu/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-04-17-understanding-war-in-mogadishu/</guid><description>This week the World Food Program (WFP) shoved out a press release about how piracy was raising food prices in South-Central Somalia. At first glance, most people who would read such a report will likely think, oh the poor people in Mogadishu. Of course, I share their sentiments.
However, there is a deeper issue at work here. One that I’m not sure many people realize. The conclusion (because I’m a lawyer and we put these things up front) is that this rise in cost of business may have drastically good effects for the conflict in the South.</description></item></channel></rss>