<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/</link><description>A Site About Resilience and Authoritarianism</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</managingEditor><webMaster>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</webMaster><copyright>All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/somalia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What&amp;#8217;s this about attacking pirates on land?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-03-26-whats-this-about-attacking-pirates-on-land/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-03-26-whats-this-about-attacking-pirates-on-land/</guid><description>&lt;p>So there was some chatter Friday on my Twitter feed about how EU NAVFOR (the EU’s Naval Forces) would be authorized to attack on land. For example:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>New EUNAVFOR guidelines allow attacking &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/search/%23pirate">#pirate&lt;/a> targets on late, while &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/search/%23NATO">#NATO&lt;/a> task force stays maritime. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/search/%23somalia">#somalia&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>— Jay Bahadur (@PuntlandPirates) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PuntlandPirates/status/183275482962341888">March 23, 2012&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>My thoughts were quickly to escalation. Escalation is important not only for reasons that &lt;em>anyone&lt;/em> who feels attacked or invaded would be willing to increase the violence to protect their stuff, but also because Somalis feel incredibly threatened right now. With four other countries operating uninvited in their country along with a bunch of other global jihadists who have very little – but not non-negligible – constituencies within Somali areas. If ever there was a time to beat the hornet’s nest, when they already are upset is not the time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apparently this chatter was due to a press release by the EU which is available &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/GUnMps" title="EU Extends Counter Piracy Mission Off Coast of Somalia">here&lt;/a> (title: EU Extends Counter Piracy Mission Off Coast of Somalia). Their complete release (my emphasis):&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>On Friday 23 March 2012 the Council of the European Union confirmed its intention to extend the EU Naval Force (EU NAVFOR) counter-piracy mission, Operation ATLANATA off the Somali coast until December 2014.  At the same time the Council also extended the area of operations &lt;em>to include Somali coastal territory&lt;/em> and internal waters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today’s decision will enable Operation Atalanta Forces to work directly with the Transitional  Federal Government and other Somali entities to support their fight against piracy in the coastal areas.  In accordance with the relevant UN Security Council resolutions, the Somali government has notified the UN Secretary General of its acceptance of the EU’s offer for this new collaboration.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Speaking about the extension of the mandate and area of operations, Rear Admiral Duncan Potts, who is the Operational Commander of the EU Naval Force, said “The extension of the mandate until the end of 2014 confirms the EU’s commitment to fighting piracy off the Horn of Africa. Piracy has caused so much misery to the Somali people and to the crews of ships transiting the area and it is right that &lt;em>we continue to move forward in our efforts&lt;/em>”.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Those five words towards the end of the first paragraph and those eight words at the end of that small press release are important. ICTY was set up because of just about as many words.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The BBC ran an &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/GUpBCV" title="Somalia pirates: EU approves attacks on land bases">article&lt;/a> headlined “Somalia pirates: EU approves attacks on land bases.” Here’s the highlights from the article:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Spanish Foreign Minister Jose Manuel Garcia-Margallo told reporters: “The EU plan is to allow attacks on land installations when ships are assaulted at sea,” adding that “much care” would be taken to avoid civilian deaths….&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rear Admiral Duncan Potts, the operation commander for the EU Naval Force in Somalia, said … ”At sea we’ve had an effect on the pirates’ ability to operate but we haven’t changed the strategic conditions, which is why we want to target every stage of their operations.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The Minister seems to be implying that only self-defence combined with hot pursuit would be a trigger for attack of land targets; whereas the EU’s commander is seemingly signalling something entirely different that the EU is interested in attacking more strategically to disrupt the entire ecosystem’s operation. That disparity aside, what is difficult to contemplate is what will actually happen with this. We don’t have the actual directive at this point (if you have a copy I’d love to see it) so how can we tell legally what the heck is going on?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are also problems (in my mind at least) with the use of force at all, but at least on the high seas to stop an operation in progress we can skirt around many of the IHL issues that could be invoked. IHL is the acronym for International Humanitarian Law which is known by many laypersons as the Law of War. There are two sets of basic sets of rules that can be used to regulate the activities of the piracy enforcement regime. IHL is one. I do not think that it is involved. After living and lawyering in the Somali region for four years, I remain deeply skeptical as to the purported links between those accused of acts of piracy and those involved in the conflict not of an international character between the various factions on land within South-Central Somalia. From time to time there are reports that Shabaab is somehow involved, but I have yet to see those sufficiently substantiated (at least in my mind). This is important, because without these linkages then IHL will not be operative and another body of law will control the piracy enforcement regime: International Human Rights Law (IHRL).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is much more complex then this, but let me simplify for the purposes of this post: IHL is very lenient set of rules compared to IHRL in the area of the application of violence. The language used by the Rear Admiral above is very much in keeping with IHL norms that allow military commanders to target and attack based on the overall military advantage of such attacks. In other words, German industrial towns pose no direct threat to the allies during WWII, but the allies legally leveled these cities due to the overall military advantage of shutting down the industrial system that was supplying German troops with arms and ammunition. Human rights law has a very different take on the application of violence due to the paramount importance that it places on the right to life alongside fair trial rights. Human rights law does not allow the application of violence with such a sweeping scope as IHL. It requires a much more surgical approach along with some provocation. The standard under IHRL is that there must be an immediate threat to life in order for a law enforcement officer to kill a suspect, or else the suspect must be taken to court where fair trial rights can be invoked to decide of the suspect can be put to death.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://wsl.so/GUtQyd" title="Beth Van Schaack">Beth Van Schaack&lt;/a> wrote an Opinion Juris &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/GY8mgp" title="A Response to Douglas Guilfoyle by Beth Van Schaack">post&lt;/a> about this IHLIHRL issue about a while ago (November, 2010):&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>[Professor Guilfoyle] concludes that in the majority of circumstances, piracy is a law enforcement problem, not a law of war problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The seemingly facile conclusion of the article, however, dodges the more difficult question of the impact of a potential nexus between acts of piracy and the ongoing non-international armed conflict in Somalia between the beleaguered Transitional Federal Government and a loose coalition of fundamentalist militias. If such a link is eventually established or confirmed, IHL may apply to some acts of piracy committed in order to fund organized armed groups or regional warlords engaged in the protracted insurgency against the government of Somalia. The article would have made a more significant contribution had it focused more searchingly on this question of what type or degree of war nexus would be necessary to trigger the application of IHL.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One implication of such a nexus would be that attacks on commercial vessels such as we have seen in the Gulf of Aden may become prosecutable as war crimes (&lt;em>viz&lt;/em>, violence to life and person or the taking of hostages)….&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Regardless of the application of IHL, the international community should not lose sight of the fact that international human rights law remains applicable to the collective international response to acts of piracy. In a companion piece, Professor Guilfoyle focuses on the law governing the extraterritorial application of human rights law, the principle of non-refoulement, the prohibition of arbitrary detention, and due process protections (see Douglas Guilfoyle, Counter-Piracy Law Enforcement and Human Rights, 59 Int’l &amp;amp; Comp L Q 141 (2010)). In addition, the prohibitions of summary execution and other arbitrary deprivations of the right to life also establish limitations of necessity and proportionality on uses of force against individuals in the exercise of national and international police powers (see McCann v UK, 21 EHRR 97 (1996)).&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The distinction between the two sets of rules are important not only because they have very different rules in how they authorize law enforcement or military personnel to apply violence towards a given situation, but also they are important to our understanding of the cultural dynamics of a given situation. When we think something is regulated by IHL we mentally apply a militaristic point of view to a situation. This is the problem when we call it the War on Terrorism when in my opinion it should be more properly characterized as a law enforcement situation against acts of terrorism. In any event, the conflict between the US and Al Qaeda aside, when it comes to Somalis the law enforcement versus military lens is extraordinarily important because as I said earlier Somalis already feel they are under attack. Largely there is a perception that the pirates are basically Robin Hood.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sending military task forces to attack land targets in Eyl or any of the other pirate areas would be disastrous foreign policy as it would not only endanger all of us Westerners that operate in the Somali region but it would also have a counter effect to the desired end state. The Somali society has been turning against the pirate culture slowly by slowly, but attacks on land targets would allow them to leverage the nationalistic undercurrents within Somali culture to regain their cultural momentum.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I can basically think of no policy which would be worse than this policy and I truly hope that when the EUNAVFOR implements it, they take a close look at both the legal and cultural effects of what they are doing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Micro-States; Pirates; Terrorists; The London Conference: What a Fascinating Time for Watchers of Somalis</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-01-30-micro-states-pirates-terrorists-the-london-conference-what-a-fascinating-time-for-watchers-of-somalis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012/2012-01-30-micro-states-pirates-terrorists-the-london-conference-what-a-fascinating-time-for-watchers-of-somalis/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/burningmax/2987516225/">&lt;img src="http://blog.caseykuhlman.com/assets/images/2012/2987516225_11e2cef572.jpg" alt="somali-days by burningmax @ flickr" tit="somali-days by burningmax @ flickr" />&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For almost four years now I’ve been a careful observer of Somali politicians. For three of those years I was paid to try to be their lawyer. To provide them expert international legal assistance tied to a deep network full of some of the finest international practitioners and thinkers in the world. But they rarely, if ever, wanted that help. So largely I invented work, I went into meetings and had a product to sell. &lt;em>I can’t buy you new computers, but I how about I help you write that legal framework that Parliament has required you to do&lt;/em>?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve spent a lot of time with Somali politicians, and I also spend a lot of time with other people who spend a lot of their time with Somali politicians. This is an expat’s life when you live in a pretty small town. I reference Hargeisa, a town of, oh, 500,00 to 1M people depending on who’s estimating as a small town.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And that it truly is. This is one of the most amazing things when you really get to know an African town. To learn how inter-connected things are is fascinating. This is what makes me do something foolish like invest everything I have into starting a law firm in a country which has very little (if any) law. Judges routinely dismiss cases with little to no justification. Parliamentarians make no estimates, and rarely even discuss, what the effects of this law will be in the next month, much less the next year – so legislation (a lot of it quite decent) is routinely ignored.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yet things work. I don’t believe in libertarianism – much to my father’s chagrin – it is incredibly unjust and inefficient. But I can say the Somalis are teaching me how to respect it, and how to work within its boundaries. I know a little but more importantly I truly care deeply about this place. I have spent more time in this place than I had in any one place since I was in college. I have joined, in many ways, the ranks of the diaspora (only the opposite way that that term is used).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a long time, when I first arrived, it seemed like no one really got what the hell was happening down here. See Nairobi is a long way away. And after the 2008 Hargeisa bombings, when pretty much all of the expats left the connections between Hargeisa and Nairobi were even more tenuous. So a disconnect really felt like it developed. Luckily, over the course of the previous year it has &lt;em>felt&lt;/em> like “Nairobi” is starting to get it. I don’t agree with everything I’m hearing coming out of the high level cluster meetings and typical other rumor mill stuff, but I must say that I agree with a lot of it (see, e.g., &lt;a href="http://blogs.fco.gov.uk/mattbaugh/2012/01/1a7/london-conference-on-somalia-building-momentum/" title="London Conference, Building Momentum">this initiative&lt;/a> by the UK’s government).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I did not think that a harder military strategy off the coast would reduce piracy. I really felt that a tribunal in Somaliland along with a huge police building effort in Puntland was the best possible shot at fixing things (basically pirate DDR is what needs to happen); I still feel this needs to happen, but the military situation seems to be putting a recent damper on the number of attacks. So they may be right, they may be wrong, but at least they aren’t &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/zA7LWR" title="Somali Pirates Seize 80% Fewer Ships as Early Strikes Work‎">dead wrong&lt;/a>. Not the way they were dead wrong in the early nighties when everyone that knew anything about Somalia would tell you how clearly wrong some of the actions were.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nairobi (by which I mean the big money and big – even if distant – powers), seems to be starting to understand two things: there has to be some element of external assistance to stabilize the situation, BUT the Somalis want to have assurances that this isn’t an invasion or their territorial fires start overheating. To do that largely means staying the hell out of the politics BUT also helping to create the conditions of stability long enough for the Somalis to figure out how they will be represented and what the terms are – which can often take months or years – even where you have a majority clan conferences these things take lots of time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most Somali analysts are quick to point out that the reason the South cannot seem to fix itself is that the Italians castrated the clan leader system. The problem has been for a long time that no one had the moral authority – among the Southern clans – to stand up to the gangsters that kept hijacking clan resources, state resources, international resources. They just continued to gobble them up like locusts and when they reached an end to their resources they just started gobbling each other. From the early warlord phase into the ICU takeover this is what continued happening.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But a couple of other things were happening also beneath the surface of that. For twenty years there seems to have been an identity crisis within much of the Somali community. This identity, just like lots of things in our lives, runs to the safest place it can find when it is threatened. For most Somalis that is somewhere around one or two or three or four or five clans below the major clan level. It varies by the individual and their experience where this safe place is. One thing I can say for sure, that for most people I’ve met in four years Northerners, Southerners, Easterners and Westerners, for the vast vast percentage of these people that place is no where even close to the pan-Somali level. This is and will for a long time remain the invalidity in the argument that the pan-Somali movement was a viable option without a dictator.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even after twenty years Somaliland politicians bicker nearly continuously; lack of trust within Somaliland is rife. The same can be said, only the distrust rises as you go clockwise around the circle.This deep distrust is deep seated in Somali lore going back to way before the mad mullah. By the time you get to Isaaq’s grandsons, they were already fighting with each other. I don’t like all my cousins, but I certainly know I’m not ready to fight with them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Luckily the Somalilanders – at the end and often despite this distrust – they make it work. Things haven’t fallen apart here and actually are going pretty well. It has taken a long time to solidify the post-conflict gains and to begin the development phase of their state building, but it is going. And, perhaps more importantly, it is going at a Somali pace. Somaliland really did have to retract after it separated from the South into basically a federated microstate solution. Sure there was a central government created at the Burco conference. But the amount of power and influence of that government was marginal. One cannot compare the power that Silanyo has with the power that Tuur had. The central government was present, but it has taken almost two decades of steady work before anyone gives it any mind about being anything other than a minor inconvenience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is another incredibly fascinating thing about being here now, this is the point where the Somaliland Government is really figuring itself and really trying to exert some will.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This gets us to the microstate solution. In my view, it should be endorsed as it is probably the best viable option currently. Some of the donors seem to be realizing that – as reflected in much of the language coming from the UK as well as the US’s two-track policy shift. In my opinion, the donors need to throttle back the incentives for state capture. When the mandate for the TFG ends UNDP needs to have the political courage to stop paying Parliamentarian salaries, and other than emergency aid the rest of the money flowing into the South needs to end. Then the donors need to let the Somalis work from their grassroots (microstate) levels up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Equal with this the Somalis have to take ownership. They really have to stop blaming &lt;em>all&lt;/em> of their problems on the international community and take ownership for their own mistakes. I can fully accept many Somalis gripes about the prior actions of external actors. And I fully understand their paranoia about external interventions in their problems. But equally they have to trust a bit more. And they have to take a lot more ownership. This is, at its most elemental, a Somali problem, and they have to be the ones to figure the solutions out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am cautiously optimistic about London Conference. A lot of the right things appear to being said. We will see what will happen but if the donors really wanted to get to the roots of the problems, they need to just shut up and they need to hold their next conference in a place which is neutral &lt;em>enough&lt;/em> to get all of the important-to-Somalis people under a great big, giant ass tree and then they need to not show up and to not pay. And then let them stay there until they figure it out. It will take a hell of a long time, but it will get done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It has taken the fine work of a lot of Somalis and Westerners for the awareness to be sufficiently raised as to why we’re here and what the hell can we do about it. I must say for the first time in a while I’m cautiously optimistic about all of the Somali region.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more perspective on the London Conference here are a few articles I thought highly incisive, particularly from the Somaliland view point: &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/zh7Zcm" title="Somaliland and the London Conference on Somalia">Article 1&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/z1OXHx" title="Six Elements for Success of Somali Conference in UK">Article 2&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On The Somali Famine: A Thought Collage</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-07-30-somali-famine-collage/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-07-30-somali-famine-collage/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/oxfameastafrica/5974209957/in/photostream/" title="Original via Oxffam East Africa @ Flickr">&lt;img src="http://www.flickr.com/photos/oxfameastafrica/5974209957/in/photostream/" alt="New arrivals wait to get processed original via Oxfam East Africa @ Flickr" title="Original via Oxffam East Africa @ Flickr">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>The original photo is &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/oxfameastafrica/5974209957/in/photostream/" title="Original via Oxffam East Africa @ Flickr">here&lt;/a>, my alteration is &lt;a href="http://blog.caseykuhlman.com/wp-content/blogs.dir/4/files/2011/07/5974209957_75f686bf8b_o-e1312029321201.jpg" title="My alteration">here&lt;/a>. If I had to title the alteration, I would call it An Homage to Motherhood&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This post is a bit random in nature, but it is a compilation of some sources and commentary and thought. So think of it as more of a collage than a strict narrative. Much of this was originally posted on &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/nunfsy" title="Original Post">Google &lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="thought-1-early-warning-systems-worked">Thought 1: Early Warning Systems Worked&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We’ve known this was coming for well over six months. According to &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/r1eFZk">here&lt;/a>, it has been well known since November 2010 which seems about right to me. Those that are paid to do handle these things were trying their best (more on that in a minute) to address the situation but were unable to deliver the food aid at that time. There’s little to suggest that anything has changed in the interim and delivery of the aid will somehow be magically easier.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Up here in Somaliland we were taking bucket showers as early as March of this year. Although it does take a while to get to the point where there is a certified famine (due to a strict criteria to certify a disaster/drought as a famine), all of the early warning systems worked. The rains ended up coming for Somaliland, but they did not come (until a couple of weeks ago, and way too late for the livestock and vegetables) for the South. Yet in Somaliland the Government took a lot of steps to ease the suffering of the pastoralists and farmers in their territory.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Amaryta Sen is famous for saying that all famines are avoidable failures of governments. Somaliland’s government passed that test. Ministers were out escorting water tankers into the country-side, TV shows on water conservation were aired on national television (not that Somalis need these lessons, but anyway), and mostly it was a local re-distribution effort rather than an international aid effort.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is an impossible hypothetical what would have happened if the rains had not come to Somaliland. Yet, I suspect that the efforts would have been decently well-thought out and executed as a community. All of it would have been led by Somalis with the international community playing a supporting role, as it should be.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="thought-2-extent-of-suffering">Thought 2: Extent of Suffering&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The famine is confined to two regions of very Southern Somalia which are sparsely populated to begin with. Although millions are at risk, it isn’t millions that are actually suffering. This isn’t meant to minimize the suffering of those that are suffering, it is simply to bring some perspective. I’m not cynical, how can you be when you look at pictures like &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/qYLsnF" title="mourning at the grave of a 3 y/o">this&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Coincidentally, these are the same areas where al-Shabaab has a very strong control over the population. One picture that has certainly caught my eye is of a Shabaab soldier with rows and rows of squatting women behind him looking distraught. The photographer obviously focused on the warrior, but the women in the background are the stars of the shot for me. It is a soberingly iconic reminder of what is really going on. See the picture &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/q5CAfm" title="shabaab soldier and women">here&lt;/a>, and look close.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shabaab has been playing both sides of this issue. First they banned nearly every aid agency from working in their zones. This was a long time ago, and ironically enough when I’ve been in Nairobi talking to people who work in the South they were telling me that the (non-Somali) agencies which were allowed to continue working were faith-based organizations like &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/nhch7c">World Vision&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/r07JSt">ADRA&lt;/a>. Mostly these organizations were headed by one or at most two Kenyans and largely they were left alone to do their work, except for one young aid worker I heard about who was killed by Shabaab for proselytizing. We may feel bad for the man’s family, but it was a bit of &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/n2KAxP">Darwinism&lt;/a> at work if you ask me.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="thought-3-aid-agencydysfunctionalism--restrictions">Thought 3: Aid Agency Dysfunctionalism &amp;amp; Restrictions&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>WFP-Somalia is, for those of us that have been in/worked on Somalia for more than 30 seconds, about the &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/oomANF">most&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/n58Y82">dysfunctional&lt;/a>&lt;a href="http://wsl.so/oqX8Y5"> organization&lt;/a>. I have serious doubts that the increases in aid will end up as food in bellies – except for (maybe) those that are working in Daadab where it is a bit more straight-forward to deliver and where there is some semblance of oversight. Also there are fundamental structural problems with the way aid agencies (including NGOs and UN organs) are built and work. See &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/p7M6aZ">here&lt;/a> for a great discussion of this (but rather technical if you’re not into the biz of aid/development). The summary:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In summary, a major reason why aid agency presence has not translated into reduced vulnerability to, for example, famine, is due to aid agencies not being geared to do just that:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Aid agencies do not build their programs around context, but are influenced by donor interest, assumptions, internal capacity and their own models of approach.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Aid agencies don’t have resources that can be quickly tasked from one mode of operation (development) to another (emergency response).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Aid agencies’ internal measuring systems do not hold them accountable to how well they reduce the risk of a disaster happening, only on how well they acheive project deliverables.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>And aid agencies own internal systems and staffing do not allow a seamless transition from a long-term development presence to an emergency response.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Yes, the international community has made many mistakes. But I do not believe that it is the role of the international community to lead at times like this. I strongly believe that the role of the international community is to support local efforts with materiale, technical assistance, logistics expertise, and funding. I am disheartened by the increasing frequency of calls for an intervention on the level of the 92/93 intervention which burst the New World Order bubble and ushered in a decade of UN futility as the world’s largest NGO body of political discourse.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even though it is true that the international community, US, UK, Italy, etc. are definitely not without fault, I’m terribly tired of the narrative which places the entirety of the blame on these external parties. An example is here, where there is an entire, well written &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/quvuzF">post&lt;/a> by an educated Somali without the smallest hint of acceptance for any responsibility by the Somali community for what is happening (other than a few “criminals”). Here’s the crux of his argument.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If we had had foresight and acted upon it; if the Marines had disarmed the warlords; if the U.N. Security Council had issued arrest warrants for the warlords early on, stopping them from prolonging the failure of the state; if the Security Council had dealt with the warlords — who had denied starving millions access to food — speedily and decisively, in the same way it dealt with the genocidal regimes in Serbia, Rwanda, Sierra Leone and Sudan, then al-Qaeda would not have established a secure base from which to plan terrorist attacks. Our country would not have been hamstrung by the enormity of our problem, nor would it have become the world’s worst humanitarian disaster.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>A friend on G asked me a good question:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I would be interested if anybody knows some more details on the reason Al-Shabab has refused to let the aid organisations in. I mean, no matter what they publicly say, I am sure they feel the pressure of famine too. So why is it not possible to find some kind of middle ground? Are the NGOs reluctant to give up control over food deliveries? If yes, is that justified? &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/p3m5eU" title="Peter Dorrie on Google Plus">~Peter Dorrie&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>My answer was that that’s part of it. Another big part of it is donor restrictions on supporting terrorist organizations. It is difficult to say with any certainty what Shabaab’s position is as they are terribly decentralized and non-uniform. Their position isn’t terribly rational but it is basically isolationist (like N.Korea, Taliban, Myanmar, etc.). They came to power on an anti-invaders platform and largely have kept to that meme throughout. On top of their irrationalities on banning bras, samosas, music, and anything that is fun, the group is funadamentally more nationalistic than it is Islamist (which is why I have always questioned the depth of their linkages with an Arab-led organization like Al-Qaeda).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are other things in play. According to &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/rpMQUy">this&lt;/a> article which examines this in a bit more detail.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The first point I would make is that al Shabab is minimizing the crisis because, as many observers and experts are saying, the movement itself likely made the famine worse. Famines often (always?) result not only from failed rains or population growth, but also government policies, especially denial and inaction. . . . Every indication points to the conclusion that al Shabab not only fit into this regional trend [of refusing to recognize or limiting acknowledgement of the extent of a drought/famine because it highlights the ruling organization's shortcomings or racism], but was – because of its limited resources, its preoccupation with the civil war, and its ideology – a particularly bad offender.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My second thought is that when looking at al Shabab’s hostility to outsiders, it is worthwhile to try to understand the movement’s thinking from the inside. . . . The movement is made up mostly of young men (its name, after all, is Arabic for “the youth”), many of whom were children, or were not even born yet, when the Somali state collapsed in 1991. They have only known war and instability. They have seen weak would-be central governments come and go, they have seen clan rivalry tear at the social and political fabric of the country, and they have seen a parade of external actors, some of whom, like Ethiopia when it occupied Somalia from late 2006 to early 2009, carried out massive violence. Growing up in that environment would brutalize many people and make them deeply suspicious of outsiders.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But the famine strikes directly at the relationship between al Shabab and its constituents. The movement is taking a huge risk if it tries to solve this problem through violence and denial. Al Shabab controls territory, and so it must have some local support – support that is likely based in large part on al Shabab’s ability to offer some security and stability after years of fighting. Allowing the famine to go unchecked could destroy whatever local legitimacy al Shabab possesses, potentially resulting in infighting, fragmentation, rebellions, or desertions. From this perspective, it is not difficult to see why al Shabab originally decided to re-admit external aid agencies. And yet it now seems that paranoia and suspicion of outsiders are winning out in the leadership’s thinking.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>For an aid worker’s perception of this see &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/r9qxK6">this&lt;/a> great article by &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/pUP9XF">@morealtitude&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>An invitation from al Shabbab central command may sound like a good enough reason to think aid workers would be safe re-entering south-central, but in fact it isn’t. Like many insurgency groups, al Shabbab is as much a network of affiliated warlords as it is a hierarchical paramilitary organization. Fighters on the ground- the ones with guns, grenades and IEDs- will align themselves first with their local commander, and only after that with al Shabbab central. Then there’s the assumption that the message is even getting down to those field grunts and their captains. Or the notion that some 16-year-old with an AKM, who’s never been to school but has spent the last ten years being told that westerners are pillaging his country and deserve to die, will pay any attention to some recent order from someone he’s never heard, when he sees an NGO Land Cruiser drive past.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="thought-4-the-role-of-somalis">Thought 4: The Role of Somalis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Through all that I’ve read, I am most heartened by the diaspora involvement. Pull up &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/oIgTvU">#feedsomalia&lt;/a> and you’ll see lots of activity. New, caring diaspora members are increasing their networks and ability to influence. This is a long-term positive.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While the immediate causes of the crisis have been the drought and insecurity in the south, there is something more fundamental at play here. &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/rdLcUg">This&lt;/a> article digs a bit beyond the boilerplate rhetoric.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Drought is not a new environmental condition for much of Africa but a recurring one. The semi-arid Horn of Africa and the entire Sahelian region — running just south of the Sahara Desert across the continent — have long experienced erratic rainfall. While climate change may be exacerbating rainfall variability, traditional livelihoods in the region are adaptable to deal with situations when rainfall is not dependable. . . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Traditionally, herders ranged widely across the landscape in search of better pasture, focusing on areas as meteorological conditions dictated. The approach worked because, unlike fenced-in pastures in North America, it was incredibly flexible and adapted to variable rainfall. As farming has expanded, including in some instances to large-scale commercial farms, the routes of herders have become more concentrated and more vulnerable to drought. [Note, the conflict between the pastoralists and agriculturalists is one of the many, many causes of insecurity in the south.] . . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just as death from exposure is not an inherent result of a cold winter, famine is not a natural consequence of drought. Simply put, the structure of human society often determines who is affected and to what degree.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Fundamentally, the core of the problem is a breakdown of the social redistribution networks which are a basis of Somali culture (see Somaliland’s reaction described above). The diaspora &lt;em>should&lt;/em> be taking the lead, as they are much closer to the realities of the situation than the US Representative for Somalia (we don’t have an ambassador any longer) is to the situation. The more Somali community leaders take charge, accept the situation, and work towards a solution – the faster the entire situation (meaning more than the famine which is temporary) will stabilize and improve.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more on the diaspora’s efforts, see &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/n5pN4r">here&lt;/a> (among other &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/oIgTvU">places&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="thought-6-starvation-porn">Thought 6: Starvation Porn&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://wsl.so/prWxac">Poverty/Starvation Porn&lt;/a> is very real and am happy that it is being talked about outside of the echo chamber of the “aid bloggers/tweeters” (for lack of a better label). There have been some great &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/om4GAY">articles&lt;/a> which have challenged the ethics of this type of coverage, which have come out of the situation. Here’s his punch-line:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Because it’s a cycle. African governments know that drought is coming and they don’t prepare. Foreign charities working there talk about long-term plans to help people become self-sufficient but they’ve been failing to achieve them for 20 years. It’s as much about politics and war and poor economic policies as it is about no rain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m no expert but I know that much. I also know it’s wrong that every few years we’re faced with an “emergency” that could have been prevented, that aid groups must frantically try to raise money to respond to, that journalists need to find emaciated babies at death’s door and film and photograph and write about them before the world gives a damn.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>While there &lt;em>is some&lt;/em> value in showing the extent of suffering, it definitely skews the situation. While that is great marketing for aid organizations, as most of us who have worked in the developing world intuitively understand increases in aid flows do not necessarily end up as food in bellies or kids’ butts on school benches. As Haiti and Japan have shown there is an absorptive capacity formula to disaster relief whereby increases in aid can end up resulting in more rotten food or spoiled medicines rather than where it was intended. As &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/njzSQL">this&lt;/a> post from a former World Vision worker puts it, “Poverty is not an image, or a statistic; poverty has a face, a name and a story.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, most aid workers are quick to admit that there is a dualism to poverty porn as am sure they are quite happy with what they get in their bank account at the end of the month (and largely it is money that is well deserved as this is very hard work). But it is not easy to see what you’re working on cheapened by skewed coverage. Some of the ads for help, in particular the one on the Tumblr dashboard (can’t upload screenshot for some reason but at least the kids in the photo are smiling).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An aid worker / blogger who I have lots of respect for has put it this way in &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/p7M6aZ">this article&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Articles are starting to look like a fill-the-blanks template that the reporters are all sharing around: Quote some stats about the famine; talk about the complicating factor of al Shabbab making life difficult in Somalia; drop in some pithy quotes about the fact that short-term aid is repetitive and doesn’t solve the underlying problems (always with a nod to the fact that, well, of course it saves lives now); then end on the dark yet hopeful twist that while aid agencies clearly don’t have it right, clearly what’s needed is ‘long-term solutions’. Yeah, cool, thanks. . . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But what I’m really ratty about is not that what the media are saying is wrong &lt;em>per se&lt;/em>. My problem is, they’re making noise but missing the point. . . . [Point 1] By rabbiting on about long-term solutions (I’m sorry, what solutions did you suggest, exactly?), they make it sound like nobody’s ever come up with that idea before. . . . Point two is, these solutions aren’t simple in the real-world.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="thought-7-what-can-be-done--what-can-you-do">Thought 7: What Can Be Done / What Can You Do&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Military intervention is about the worst solution human minds could conjure. History should be a lesson here. Somalis are phenomenal at skewing international interventions intended to help as invasions of their sovereignty. And in general Somalis are pretty duplicitous as to outsiders.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Second worst idea to me is trying to deliver via trucks and ground workers within the Shabaab zones. I fundamentally disagree that the US Gov should “work with Shabaab” as &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/r1eFZk">this&lt;/a> article by Richard Dowden of the Royal African Society argues. This is a golden opportunity for the Somalis to see the results of their acquiescence to Shabaab’s presence. The easiest thing one can learn from Somali history is that when they’re sick of you they’ll find a way to overthrow you. When the communities within the Shabaab zones get sick of them they will kick them out of those communities and I know if I was living in these communities I would certainly be pretty circumspect about Shabaab. Of course no one wants to stay “starve them out” as that is cruel and inhumane treatment, but delivery within Shabaab’s areas I am 64.8% sure will end in a worse situation than never going in. As &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/pUP9XF">@morealtitude&lt;/a> put it &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/r9qxK6">here&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Letting aid workers in solves many problems for al Shabbab. It demonstrates to its own people that it’s taking steps to solve the problem. It helps slow the outflux of refugees. It brings in resources that bolster the population- which may be appropriated by fighters at times, or the effects may be indirect, such as more money in the economy that supports fighters’ families which in turn supports them. And, if aid agencies don’t do the right thing by al Shabbab, it gives them fresh ammunition in the polarizing of its people against the west.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Not increasing aid at all within Somalia is the best possible solution in my mind. The best option within Somalia is to stay out of the diaspora’s way with respect to their remittance flows into Somalia so people can purchase from local markets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was talking the other day with a few friends who work in this area. They told me that the real heart-break is that after people have trekked to the refugee camps in Kenya and Ethiopia they are finding that the food isn’t there. In these refugee camps there is a host government who is not impeding the delivery of aid and there is a relatively well-trekked cow-path for the logisticians to follow. Increasing the flows to these areas is a relatively straight-forward process and will ease one of the main problems while staying away from the quagmire.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next best options are to work through Somali NGOs and increase the flows that they are delivering, continue and maybe increase the &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/r7VE6P">air drops&lt;/a> (although these have to be terribly costly from a utilitarian point of view, and finally increase more traditional types of delivery within Mogadishu which the TFG / AMISOM troop relatively control.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to give here are some organizations (in the order I would give to them if I had disposable income and wasn’t already fully invested in Somalis):&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://wsl.so/qdaZLT">MSF&lt;/a> (Doctors without Borders who provide extensive medical care in the refugee camps)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://wsl.so/rgGS3S">Save the Children&lt;/a> (who have been working in the camps since the beginning)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://wsl.so/ojJQ0R">OXFAM-AUS&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/qCEFxc">OXFAM-UK&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="http://wsl.so/n7LClH">OXFAM-US&lt;/a> (Who also provides water and other services in the camps)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://wsl.so/pfIBe4">IRC&lt;/a> (Who provides a number of services within the refugee camps)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On Going Local: Finding Your Happy Place</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-12-local-finding-happy-place/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-12-local-finding-happy-place/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>On Going Local is a new (short) series that I’ll be running which will attempt to look at my life from an objective perspective as I transition from and NGO worker into an entrepreneur here in the developing world.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve been here in Somaliland now for around two and a half years now.  It has been a wonderful time, and I’ve enjoyed every minute of it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are many aspects of Somali / Somaliland society &amp;amp; culture that I have found it easy to adjust too.  But there are a few things which have been difficult.  Not the least of which is the six day work week.  Being an Islamic country, we take Friday off.  But that most people take off.  Going from a two day weekend to a one day weekend with shorter days throughout the six was a big adjustment and I’m not sure that I will ever fully adjust to it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, this is about space.  Physical space.  Like most development workers I lived for a long time in a &lt;a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/caseykuhlman/SomalilandCompound02" title="Gorgorka Luxury Estates">gigantic house&lt;/a> shared among an assortment of other expatriates, cleaners, cooks, guards, and staff.  It can be a fantastically good time having all the excitement of different activities, smells, and languages around you.  For a little while…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a time, though, it becomes stifling.  For one thing, you are never “off duty.”  At any time of the day or night someone may come and knock on your door.  Someone’s family member is sick and they need money; someone’s mobile phone was stolen and they need money; the guards caught two people making out in a dark corner behind the house; all sound tracked to random gunshots due to land disputes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most development or aid workers I know always like to say it’s not a job, it’s a lifestyle.  And that is all well and good, but it isn’t a lifestyle I was very interested in.  Sure you can try to set boundaries, but you don’t want to incentivize the people working with you to not tell you what is happening.   That can lead to all kinds of problems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This balance is incredibly difficult to achieve between having some personal space (when the standard living situation is tenement and shared, college-esque, except we’re not college age anymore) and being “open.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have recently moved out of that mansion into what would be normal to me.  Luckily enough it is also what would be normal to a middle-class Somali.  Instead of ten bedrooms (some of which were office space), I now have three.  Instead of having to walk 15 minutes to get to the kitchen, it now takes me 15 seconds.  I don’t have to worry about staff all of the time as I only have someone who comes to clean for me a few days a week &amp;amp; when I’m at the office.  It is safer this way, as you are a target when you live in a mansion.  You can do what you like without having to worry about being disturbed.  You can metaphorically unpack your bags.  You can find normality in an otherwise frantic existence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The place I’m living now actually feels like a home rather than a dorm.  And that is fantastic.  I love my old roommates dearly, but it is so nice to have something that is “yours.”  And when my wife comes down next year for a bit, my life will be complete!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Decoding the Somali Mind: A Guide for Expats (Anecdotal, Not Definitive Version): Wants v. Needs</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-28-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-v/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-28-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-v/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This is a new series containing a few stories which have stood out in my time here in Somaliland and have helped me to understand a bit more a culture that in many ways is very different from my own, but in many ways is not. This series explores those differences.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![want need syrup by thebrianmeyer @ flickr][2]][2]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every development worker I’ve ever met, and I can say with confidence, without exception, hates the following phrase with a passion: “What we &lt;em>really&lt;/em> need is….”  Hearing that phrase pretty much ruins your entire day.  Usually, but not always, it is accompanied by a veiled threat of what will happen if the particular worker does not comply.  Well, that happens when one is dealing with governmental clients.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a preliminary (and because despite my non-traditional path I am still a trained lawyer), let me define what I’m talking about when I say “wants” and “needs.”  I would define (for the purposes of this piece only, &lt;em>see supra&lt;/em>) “needs” as those things which are required to perform a given task, whereas I would define “wants” as those things which are not required but would be beneficial to accomplish a given task.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do I “need” internet to survive? No.   Do I “need” internet to do my job? Yes (reasons for this answer will be detailed in a forthcoming post).  I say this almost flippantly, but in any culture it is incredibly easy to conflate these concepts and trying to differentiate between the two will depend largely upon an individual’s perspective.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Especially when it comes to legislative action, determining whether a mechanism or a “thing” is needed or wanted is incredibly difficult to determine with accuracy.  One of the arts of political action is convincing others of one’s perspective as to whether something is a needed requirement or a wanted luxury.  This is one of  the many reasons why so many politicians are trained lawyers – as we get paid to use words to twist concepts to convince individuals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yet, when it comes to Somali society figuring out such a differential is complicated by the Somali language.  In Somali, to say “I want X” one would say “X waan doonayaa,” whereas to say “I need X” one would say “X waan doonayaa.”  The root of the verb (“doon”) means both of the concepts expressed in the English words “want” and “need.”  It isn’t a far leap to see that this makes it even more difficult to differentiate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first time I was running a workshop here in Hargeisa talking to legislators about the differences in these concepts my translator was struggling and I was having a hard time understanding why it was difficult to pose the question to the participants.  At the break I pulled my translator aside and tried to figure out why he was having such trouble getting across what I was trying to say.  He was also extremely frustrated but didn’t say much other than he would do his best.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Months later, when I was learning Somali, it became clear to me that the difficulty my translator had experienced much earlier was a function of the Somali language.  After I had learned a modicum of Somali than I changed some of the curriculum of the workshop from wants and needs to requirements and luxuries.  After that it was much easier for my translator to get the preliminary concepts across so that the participants could have a good discussion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of my favorite all time stories during my years here in Somaliland falls (loosely) under this concept of wants v. needs.  In October, 2008, there were three suicide bombs detonated in different places here in Hargeisa: the Ethiopian Embassy, the UNDP compound, and the Presidential mansion.  After these bombings there were probably four of us expatriates who stuck around while everyone else ran away to Nairobi.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My team and I worked day and night for the two weeks after the bombings preparing a series of documents to help the government and parliament understand the legal mechanisms for reacting to terrorism that have been emplaced under (1) international law; and (2) national laws within the region.  The government told me very early on that they were looking to emplace something like the Somaliland Patriot Act and so we had done tons of research on the topic for the government.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We broke up the delivery of the work product among the different affected clients: namely the Ministry of Interior, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, and the Ministry of Justice.  I was in with the Minister of Justice briefing him on the current problems that they would have if they wanted to prosecute suspected terrorists under their current penal code.  I had included in my briefing a bunch on due process as well as the international human rights mechanisms, which had been imputed into the Somaliland Constitution, that currently limited their ability to move forward with prosecutions prior to further legislative action.  About 2/3d’s of the way through my presentation the Vice Minister of Justice barged into the briefing and sat down.  He waited for about thirty seconds before he turned to me and said the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This is all well and good, but what Somaliland really *needs *is you to call up the CIA and brief them on what is happening here.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Seriously, Mr. Vice Minister, do you really think that I have the CIA’s number on my speed dial?  My sarcastic side said.  For once, I controlled that and tried my best to explain in a temperate tone that I had no contacts with the CIA and that even if I did they wouldn’t listen to me.  I caught the Minister’s eyes rolling slightly while the Vice Minister was on his tirade after my response so I knew I was on OK ground and I just moved along with my briefing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After we finished, and we were leaving the Vice Minister (who I had never spoken to once prior to this exchange) walked out to our vehicle with us.  He told me that he knew exactly who I was and that he was going to hold me personally liable for informing the CIA of what was happening here in Somaliland.  I assured him in the most even tones I could conjure at that moment that there was nothing I could do for him on this issue and that he should use the Minister of Foreign Affairs rather than some external NGO worker.  He was never convinced.  And I wasn’t convinced that he was mentally stable enough to be a Vice Minister.  I left completely flabbergasted.  To this day, there is no Somaliland Patriot Act.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Decoding the Somali Mind: A Guide for Expats (Anecdotal, Not Definitive Version): Introduction</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-21-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-21-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This is a new series containing a few stories which have stood out in my time here in Somaliland and have helped me to understand a bit more a culture that in many ways is very different from my own, but in many ways is now. This series explores those differences.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![BraiNut 1.0 via sath.es @flickr][2]][2]
via sath.es @flickr&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have lived &amp;amp; worked with Somalis here in Somaliland for over two years now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have, like many expats before me, sat in rooms on the floor with rugs underneath us cushions behind our backs, mauis’s (skirts) on sporting wife-beaters drinking the sweetest teas one has ever drank and (as my wife likes to say) sticking green leaves up our noses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Equally I have sat many nights, like many expats before me, on a veranda, a glass of wine in hand, cool breezes of Hargeisa swirling around, dressed in jeans and semi-glamorous (but always purposively casual) shirts, some ipod attached to portable speakers, listening to music that is on the verge of being hip back home and talking about the deep cultural differences between us and those that fill our daily lives (our clients, our friends, our colleagues, people we meet around).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have had a steady turnover in Hargeisa of expatriates lately.  And over that time there seems to be an increasing amount of tension between the expatriates and the Somalilanders.  I am not sure exactly why this seems to be happening (because this is Somaliland it is spoken of in metaphors and resides fully in the subtextual zone), but it has become increasingly tangible to me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the course of the past year there has been this tit-for-tat between the powerful voices for the expatriates and the powerful voices for the Somalilanders.  The problem is that those of us who aren’t given powerful voices become batted around as the game is played by others.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Something happened to me recently which I would like to use (again cloaked in metaphor and subtext, because this is how to communicate in Somaliland) as a tuusaale (example).  One of my best expat friends here in Hargeisa (who is a development worker) recently had some professional dealings with one of my best Somali friends (who is a mid-level government employee).  Due to forces above and beyond either’s control the dealings did not turn out well and both became frustrated by the situation (for very different reasons but that is beside the point).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a while I was caught in the middle of everything but the biggest problem was that I was getting completely different stories as to what happened from either “side” (so to say).  There was so little alignment between the stories that for a while I wondered if these were two completely different situations involving different people completely.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Later I started to piece it together, to connect the people that were being referenced by one story with how I organize those relationships when I’m talking to the other side, to connect the things that I knew were more important to one side with those that had little emphasis in the other’s side of the story.  I don’t know much about mediation, but I was trying to see these events through each side’s cultural lens and come to some sort of objective understanding of what likely transpired.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was only after spending literally hours trying to dig through and cross-check and re-examine and then start all over again that I was able to ferret out what may have actually happened.  And only after that did I realize that the actualities of the situation were out of the control of either party.  That happens in development work and it is one of the occupational hazards of this work.  However, the relational aspects of the situation were very much aggravated by the cultural differences between the parties.  It is this part – the cultural misunderstandings and their attendant relational aspects which causes (in my mind) undue hardships in development work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is why I wanted to write a few words over the course of the next little while trying to tell a few stories that have taught me a ton about humanity and culture (and which is which).  A few stories which I think of and use when I’m trying to analyze things through a foreign cultural lens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If I had to pick one of the most intellectually satisfying aspects of working here in Somaliland, it has been the opportunity to dig deep into a culture and a way of thinking and seeing the world that is very different than my own.  Each of the cultural differences, while stark at times, belies evidence of our common humanity.  Every time I become frustrated with the cultural differences then something will happen to me which will reinforce the common humanity which is always there.  The tenderness of a father’s reprimand, or a shared joke, or an extraordinarily kind act.  These things accompany each and every one of the cultural differences.  So I hope to share a few of these stories along the way as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Understanding War [in Mogadishu]</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-04-17-understanding-war-in-mogadishu/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-04-17-understanding-war-in-mogadishu/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.wfp.org/content/somalia-pirates-target-food-pushing-prices">&lt;img src="http://www.wfp.org/content/somalia-pirates-target-food-pushing-prices" alt="">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This week the World Food Program (WFP) shoved out a &lt;a href="http://www.wfp.org/content/somalia-pirates-target-food-pushing-prices">press release&lt;/a> about how piracy was raising food prices in South-Central Somalia.  At first glance, most people who would read such a report will likely think, oh the poor people in Mogadishu.  Of course, I share their sentiments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, there is a deeper issue at work here.  One that I’m not sure many people realize.  The conclusion (because I’m a lawyer and we put these things up front) is that this rise in cost of business may have drastically good effects for the conflict in the South.  Here’s how I get there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Those brains who study war break themselves into two-sides of the same coin (since they are academics largely they have to classify and camp-ify themselves in order to create non-existent academic conflict to drive conscriptions to their own camp to drive their own popularity to drive their tenure track – but that is a story for a different day).  I’m too lazy to look up what the classifications of the two sides are, but generally one camp focuses on the structural conditions for conflict to begin (guns, poverty, etc.) and another camp focuses on the social conditions for conflict to begin (ethnic diversity, natural resources, etc.).  Or something like that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These camps have outlined pretty logical paths for those who seek to mitigate, manage, or militate conflict to follow.  If conflict A is characterized as an X conflict than follow path Z to recovery.  Fair enough, and it has worked in several instances.  In Liberia (prototypical charasmatic leader led conflict), once Charles Taylor left then the conflict subsided almost instantaneously.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The difficulty for conflict academics and practitioners (and no I didn’t mistype that) when it comes to Somalia is that every category for conflict can be found.  Not only can every one be found, but the primacy of each driver of conflict into primary, secondary, tertiary, etc.  driver of the conflict will depend on the time and location in which one analyzes the conflict.  The drivers are like a kaleidoscope which is constantly fluctuating over time in each location.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is a post-modern hell for people who study these things – which answers my own question about the lack of detailed academic research on Somalia (that and the difficulty in getting correct information).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After living here for two years and studying and thinking through the conflict at length (because there is little else to do during a Somalia evening), and despite the kaleidoscopic nature of the conflict, a few themes can be extracted.  The first of which is that in the far south around the major rivers the conflict is really and truly about natural resources and land.  Which is why my organization has put in to do a project focused on conflict mitigation of natural resources driven low-level conflicts throughout Somalia – but particularly in that region.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The other major theme, and how this connects with the WFP report, is that the business community in Mogadishu is quite happy with the anarchical situation.  Let me explain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If Somalis were Americans a large percentage of them would be mid-nineties salesmen.  The ones that would drive the 2.0 Trans Am, sport their cell phones in belt holsters, and have lunch meetings at Hooters.  They are quite money focused (certainly more than many from West Africa), and this has some good consequences.  Here in the north the private sector is very vibrant and is driving much of the development; there remains a good environment for doing business – certainly better than the neighbors in the region.  However, the focus on money can make many a bit myopic as they are always chasing pennies and don’t see the dollars.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have met businessmen from the south who laugh at their colleagues here in the north who &lt;em>only&lt;/em> make 67% profit (I’m referencing the telecom sector here) as opposed to in the south where they make double that. There are tons of instances in the history of the southern conflict where it has been oscillating towards some resolution but the business community ensures that instability returns quickly.  They are convinced that the anarchy allows them to live like kings and do whatever they want – in their minds make more money.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yet from my point of view they are looking at the wrong metric.  I think they should be looking at the total amount of profit.  Sure they can make a higher percentage in Mogadishu than the guys can here in H-town, but the pot is bigger here so in the end they make more money.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is where the dissonance approaches resonance frequency for me.  The  rhetoric has failed to show these men that peace will inevitably make them richer.  Although their profit margins will fall, their total  revenue will rise at a faster rate and they will end up with more money in their pockets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Simple talking has failed to convince them of such a result, so here is where I’m optimistic about the WFP report.  If the pirates can (ironically) be the ones that raise the costs for the large importers then the effects of that rise in the cost of business will ripple throughout and maybe the arguments for resolution of the conflict will gain more weight.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Or maybe the businessmen will simply launch their own navies as they already have their own armies. I don’t know, but I remain optimistic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>