<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>campaigns on underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/campaigns/</link><description>Recent content in campaigns on underWater desert Blogging</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/campaigns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Unreasonable Optimism and Why John Dickerson&amp;#8217;s (@jdickerson) Series Should Matter</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012-10-06-my-unreasonable-optimism-and-why-john-dickersons-jdickerson-series-should-matter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012-10-06-my-unreasonable-optimism-and-why-john-dickersons-jdickerson-series-should-matter/</guid><description>My Dad and I have this ongoing debate about campaigns. It has been ongoing for four years that I can remember but perhaps longer. It revolves around the forthrightness of campaigns to speak to the electorate logically, with courage, and while keeping within the bounds of logic and reasonableness. Instead of what I desperately want campaigns to do they do the opposite, spiraling into ever more irrelevant crap. Gaffes and ah ha’s are fun and interesting political theater but that is all it is. Theater. Theater is a farce. And we must stop hiring representatives to govern us based on a farcical audition system. This I have felt deeply for a long time. It colors most of my political worldview, rightly or wrongly.</description></item><item><title>Compromise &amp;amp; Governing: On Reading @ryanlizza&amp;#8217;s The Obama Memos</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012-01-27-compromise-and-governing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012-01-27-compromise-and-governing/</guid><description>Ryan Lizza has again written a marvelous piece on Obama and his team. Just as he did with his watershed piece on the Obama campaign, he has written a long and worthwhile piece on Obama's first term to date. If you want to understand the fundamental contradictions that come with governing, and if you want to learn what you elect a President to truly do, read it - after you read my thoughts.</description></item></channel></rss>