<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>somaliland/somalia on underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/somaliland/somalia/</link><description>Recent content in somaliland/somalia on underWater desert Blogging</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/somaliland/somalia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What&amp;#8217;s this about attacking pirates on land?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012-03-26-whats-this-about-attacking-pirates-on-land/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012-03-26-whats-this-about-attacking-pirates-on-land/</guid><description>On Friday, I was hearing chatter about how the EU issued a new directive authorizing the EUNAVFOR to attack land targets. This is an awful idea that will have strategic and operational consequences - all of which that will be negative. In addition I have serious concerns as to the legality of the application of violence on land as a solution to the so called Piracy Problem.</description></item><item><title>Micro-States; Pirates; Terrorists; The London Conference: What a Fascinating Time for Watchers of Somalis</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012-01-30-micro-states-pirates-terrorists-the-london-conference-what-a-fascinating-time-for-watchers-of-somalis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2012-01-30-micro-states-pirates-terrorists-the-london-conference-what-a-fascinating-time-for-watchers-of-somalis/</guid><description>For almost four years now I’ve been a careful observer of Somali politicians. For three of those years I was paid to try to be their lawyer. To provide them expert international legal assistance tied to a deep network full of some of the finest international practitioners and thinkers in the world. But they rarely, if ever, wanted that help. So largely I invented work, I went into meetings and had a product to sell. &lt;em>I can’t buy you new computers, but I how about I help you write that legal framework that Parliament has required you to do&lt;/em>?</description></item><item><title>On The Somali Famine: A Thought Collage</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011-07-30-somali-famine-collage/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011-07-30-somali-famine-collage/</guid><description>This post is a compilation of sources, commentary and thought. It is a collage on the famine in the South of Somalia, the media storm which is surrounding it, and possible things to do.</description></item><item><title>On Colonies, the AU &amp;amp; Borders: Somaliland&amp;#8217;s Recognition Journey</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011-07-24-on-colonies-and-borders/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011-07-24-on-colonies-and-borders/</guid><description>One of the legal criteria for statehood is established borders. There is a serious and very well, although often, hidden question as to where Somaliland's borders are. In this post I try to parse this a bit mainly from the perspective of international law, but also from the political perspective as well.</description></item><item><title>What Does it Mean to be Independent: Somaliland&amp;#8217;s Recognition Journey</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011-07-20-somalilands-recognition-journey/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011-07-20-somalilands-recognition-journey/</guid><description>After having been in Somaliland, one of the world's most advanced unrecognized countries, for well over three years I have thought much about what it means to be a state, to have your independence, to maintain your sovereignty and many related issues. In this post, I try to parse the differences between Somaliland, South Sudan and the Libyan Rebels.</description></item><item><title>Understanding the Somaliland Elections (2 of 3): The Contenders</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010-06-26-understanding-somaliland-elections-2-3-contenders/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010-06-26-understanding-somaliland-elections-2-3-contenders/</guid><description>Today Somaliland is holding its Presidential elections. To understand the significance of this event, one must understand the road that it has taken the Somalilanders to get to this point. This election has been delayed for over two years. This entry contains a small background on the three men on the ballot.</description></item><item><title>Understanding the Somaliland Elections (3 of 3): The Arguments</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010-06-26-understanding-somaliland-elections-3-3-arguments/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010-06-26-understanding-somaliland-elections-3-3-arguments/</guid><description>Today Somaliland is holding its Presidential elections. To understand the significance of this event, one must understand the road that it has taken the Somalilanders to get to this point. This election has been delayed for over two years. This entry contains a small background on the arguments that have been given by three men on the ballot.</description></item><item><title>Understanding the Somaliland Elections (1 of 3): Background</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010-06-25-understanding-somaliland-elections-1-3-background/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010-06-25-understanding-somaliland-elections-1-3-background/</guid><description>Today Somaliland is holding its Presidential elections. To understand the significance of this event, one must understand the road that it has taken the Somalilanders to get to this point. This election has been delayed for over two years. This entry contains a small background on that time.</description></item><item><title>What Does Gerstle Mean Pro-People Development?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010-05-27-gerstle-pro-people-development/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010-05-27-gerstle-pro-people-development/</guid><description>It is a difficult proposition to project what will happen in Somalia or Somaliland. The problem, as I see it, with the international approaches so far along with the local approaches, is that it is difficult to reconcile the philosophical desires of most Somalis with the history that they have faced in the modern era of authoritarian rule. But someone will come along - eventually, inshallah - that will be able to convince people of his or her vision of how to reconcile the dissonance between the historical predicates of Somalia and the cultural desires for decentralized power. When this unselfish visionary comes along the world should ilaalayaa because these people that I have grown to love will be a powerful force.</description></item></channel></rss>