<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>virtual currency on underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/virtual-currency/</link><description>Recent content in virtual currency on underWater desert Blogging</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Casey Kuhlman</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/virtual-currency/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What the Esteemed (and Very Smart) Law Professors Missed at the HLS Ethereum Talk</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-04-16-etherum-visits-harvard/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-04-16-etherum-visits-harvard/</guid><description>![Ethereum Logo]({{ site.url }}{{ site.root }}{{ site.images_dir }}/{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; }}/ethereum.png)
Introduction Yesterday a very interesting event happened. And I had the pleasure to listen in. Primavera De Filippi talked Ethereum at a Berkman luncheon.
For those who do not know Berkman is a center at Harvard University. For those who do not know Harvard, welcome to earth. Berkman is officially the Berkman Center for Internet and Society. It is a joint research center housed in Harvard's Law School with the following mission:</description></item><item><title>Linking Virtual Automatic Contracts to IRL Events</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-03-04-irl-links-with-virtual-automatic-contracts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-03-04-irl-links-with-virtual-automatic-contracts/</guid><description>I have been droning on about virtual automatic contracts for a few posts now.
By the by, today is a bit of an exciting day because later this evening I will be going to the Ethereum meetup in Amsterdam. This will be an interesting opportunity for me to speak with others who are interested in exploring the possibilities of virtual automatic contracts generally and also to see specifically some more details as to how Ethereum smart contracts will work.</description></item></channel></rss>