<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/</link><description>A Site About Resilience and Authoritarianism</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</managingEditor><webMaster>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</webMaster><copyright>All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/relational-thinking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>On Aid Professionals &amp;#8211; Random Thoughts on the Meme</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-11-09-on-aid-professionals/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-11-09-on-aid-professionals/</guid><description>&lt;p>There has been an interesting debate lately in the development sphere about professionalism v. amateurism and the pros and cons of each.  For a breakdown see the always reliable &lt;a href="http://goodintents.org/staffing-or-employment/volunteers-vs-professionals-aid-debates">Good Intents&lt;/a>.  There has been some great writing and thinking on this topic.  I would encourage reading through Saundra’s list (above citation) as there are some very worthwhile entries.  I have two small things to say, but have little to no argument with the trend the meme is going (which has been summarized very well by Saundra – again – and I’ve cited below).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![Dangling Professional via kenyee @ flickr][3]][3]&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="relationalists-v-substantialists">Relationalists v. Substantialists&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As I’ve written before, I tend to think with a different lens than many of my peers from America who live here in Africa.  I’m a relationalist caught in a substantialist world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It seems indicative that those who are arguing that there is a space for both seem to be approaching their argument from a relationalist point of view.  My favorite post so far in this vein is [Penelope’s][3].  Another crew seem to be saying that there is little room for “amateurs” whatsoever, and they structure their argument from a substantialist point of view.  My favorite post so far in this vein is [J from Tales][4] (who wrote a series, but this post is my favorite).  A third crew is somehow in the middle and it essentially argues that it is all about the effects rather than the background.  My favorite post in the “can’t we all get along” vein is [Saundra’s][5].&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The skills on J’s list, for instance, are completely substantialist.  They don’t require much in the way of relational capacity.  That may be fine for humanitarian workers who come in an go out rather frequently.  The success of their work, I would argue, depends less on their ability to have successful trust-based relationships than it does on their analytical and problem-solving skills.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Humanitarian work – by which I’m defining as those lifesaving response mechanisms which are attempting to provide a baseline to human existence – can and should be the type of work that is dominated by scientific, analytical people.  I’m not saying that WFP P-4 disaster response team leaders (I have no idea what they are called, but I bet it isn’t too far from this) can’t, shouldn’t, or won’t get to know people where they are going next, but I would argue that their job description likely doesn’t absolutely require it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thad Allen gave a [nice talk][6] to HBR recently which I heard on their Ideacast podcast.  He spoke about leadership through a major disaster and the measures that he took.  I was struck that there was little to no time spent on relationship building outside his core team, but he spent some significant percentage of his time talking about relationships within the team and PR (which I do not think has anything to do with relationships other then on the extreme definition of that word).  I have no quibble with this, and generally I would agree that disaster relief work does not depend so much on building relationships, other than at a very low baseline.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That said, other types of work require other skill sets, particularly an ability to build trust-based relationships. In my former work with a legal reform NGO to be successful at my job required absolutely none of the skills which Tales points to.  We wrote many successful grants as a team and never once did we do the slightest bit of regression analysis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I needed to understand who the power-brokers were in Parliament. I needed to understand how to convey the notions of process, political bargaining, policies, and the legal mechanisms which can be used to address imbalances in each of the above.  Being successful at that did not require me to understand statistics in the slightest, it required me to understand humanity and legality.  Now when the time came to discuss specific policy choices which the parliamentarians were considering, at that time, my statistics background (gleaned from engineering undergrad classes and bolstered by self-learning and ensuring that remain current on development economic trends) although marginal, did serve me well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But the basic point is that to achieve my ends required understanding the relationships around me, developing trust from a group who is heartily skeptical about outsiders because so many have just come for a temporary time and tried to lecture my old clients on how to run their country.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![Notes from The Cult of the Amateur via inju @ flickr][8]][8]&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-does-development-mean">What Does “Development” Mean?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/kenyee/452452505/">http://www.flickr.com/photos/kenyee/452452505/&lt;/a>
[3]: &lt;a href="http://penelopemc.wordpress.com/2010/07/28/on-entrepreneurship-and-ngos/">http://penelopemc.wordpress.com/2010/07/28/on-entrepreneurship-and-ngos/&lt;/a>
[4]: &lt;a href="http://talesfromethehood.wordpress.com/2010/10/31/professional-2/">http://talesfromethehood.wordpress.com/2010/10/31/professional-2/&lt;/a>
[5]: &lt;a href="http://goodintents.org/aid-debates/aid-professional">http://goodintents.org/aid-debates/aid-professional&lt;/a>
[6]: &lt;a href="http://blogs.hbr.org/ideacast/2010/10/leading-through-a-major-crisis.html">http://blogs.hbr.org/ideacast/2010/10/leading-through-a-major-crisis.html&lt;/a>
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/inju/1347959895/">http://www.flickr.com/photos/inju/1347959895/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another ancillary issue which struck me (and is somewhat related to the above) when I was reading the comments below Saundra’s list is that there really is a lack of a precise definitional consensus as to “development sector.”  For instance, I see little to no correlation between what a legal reform NGO does and what an emergency relief NGO/UNOrgan do.  And yet, somehow they are both in the same sector.  I can see from an ultra-macro perspective how they would somewhat be aligned in the same way that wordpress and intel are both in the computer sector.  But the skill sets, backgrounds, knowledge base, and all the rest which are required to work at wordpress and to work at intel are so incredibly divergent.  This is one of the reasons why the existential question which the meme is struggling with strikes me as odd to begin with – it is hard to define what makes a successful project manager in one instance because of the cultural basis into which they are operating.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like the anthropologists who go into villages and then continually navel gaze about observer interaction and whether than changes the situation (there is some term here I’m sure but am too lazy to google it), this conversation – while interesting – does not strike me as especially relevant without first putting some qualifications on what we’re talking about.  Is this about building village wells and schools?  Is this about delivering huge amounts of food to an area of low food security?  Is this about trying to build capacity of an anti-corruption committee?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Without first providing some definitional clarity the meat of the argument seems to go past one another as each assumes that everyone else requires the same things that they do in order to succeed.  Just because we all are Westerners working for NGO’s in Africa doesn’t mean that we are necessarily one “profession.”  We are many professions which are loosely grouped together and continuing to compare our relative apples and oranges.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Decoding the Somali Mind: A Guide for Expats (Anecdotal, Not Definitive Version): Responsibility</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-18-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-responsibility/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-18-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-responsibility/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This is a new series containing a few stories which have stood out in my time here in Somaliland and have helped me to understand a bit more a culture that in many ways is very different from my own, but in many ways is not. This series explores those differences.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I generally prefer to point out the similarities between disparate people.  I enjoy very much the common humanity aspects about my life.  But I equally enjoy learning about the differences.  This post contains more of the latter than the former.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m American and we are taught from a young age that a major part of being an American means that you are individualistic.  Our pop culture and education system celebrate individuality and the human against the odds above many other cultural memes.  Most of the people that have immigrated to America over the years have come to chase something that was related to individual efforts.  Those of us who descend from those who immigrated we have it both from nature and from nurture.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Somalilanders are taught precisely the opposite.   They celebrate communal victories above individual victories in their poetry and dramas and songs.  They rely on communal networks for insurance when things get tough.  Collective responsibility is bred into them as deeply as individual responsibility has been bred into me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Two months ago my Ethiopian watchman stole an SUV that I was borrowing from a friend and he drove it so fast (likely enjoying his own sense of individuality and freedom of the road – something that isn’t a big leap for me to empathize with) that when he had to swerve to hit someone he hit a bump and jumped the SUV, and I mean jumped it, on top of other cars.  Two other cars that were sitting in a used car dealership beside the road.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I was told about it I was pretty crushed because I knew instantly that I would have to pay for the damage.  Even though he had stolen from me.  Even though his job description involved neither driving nor speeding.  Even though I had not the slightest to do with the situation.  Because that is the way that things work.  Everyone is responsible for everyone else.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If the Ethiopian kid had been Somali and the employer was not responsible then the clan would provide the necessary insurance.  If I as the employer had been Somali and I was unable to cover the costs then my clan would have been called upon to provide the insurance.   But neither of us fit into that system.  I paid.  I had no other choice.  I could reason through very easily that in my system I wasn’t liable.  But I wasn’t living in my system.  I gain the consequences of the system but not the benefits.  I guess that is life though and how many minorities throughout history have had that exact thought?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another thing that is fairly prevalent is that senior Somalis working for organizations get held personally liable for all of the actions or non-actions of the organization.  My number two with my old NGO recently had his power shut off because of a dispute between the power company the organization signed a services contract with and the party responsible for paying the final two months electricity bill.  Sure his name isn’t on the invoices, but his name is there in the computer as the responsible party.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This can be very annoying when you are held responsible for the actions of another that you “normally” would not have to be responsible for.  But when you understand the system and you understand that there &lt;em>is&lt;/em> a system, although maybe facially foreign.  Then you can at least navigate it.  But if you’re new to Somalis these are key because how you treat your staff and the pressures that especially your senior staff will face need to be understood.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On Going Local: Relationships</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-16-local-relationships-unofficial-chains/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-16-local-relationships-unofficial-chains/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>On Going Local is a (short) series that I’m running which will attempt to look at my life from an objective perspective as I transition from and NGO worker into an entrepreneur here in the developing world.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?p=421">&lt;img src="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?p=421" alt="PeyoteLeaderCheyenne1927 by Medicinehorse7 @ flickr">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Relationships here in Somaliland are odd, to say the least.  There are two main identifiable cultural divergences.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first is that many relationships are deeper here in Somaliland than similar relationships would be back home.  Deeper in the sense that they are more utilized, more cherished, and more complicated than a similar set of relationships would be in America.  (I will return to these themes, but let me finish my introduction first.  Don’t be in such a hurry!)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The second is that many (other) relationships are shallower that similar relationships would be back home.  They are more shallow in the sense that they are less utilized, less cherished, and less complicated than a similar set of relationships would be in America.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a long time this was opaque to me.  And then the scenery started to open up, but like with the two stories from an earlier &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?p=421">post&lt;/a> on decoding the somali mind there was little cultural alignment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is what I was seeing after I had been here long enough to scratch the surface coating off of the Somalilanders.  On the one hand, I was seeing friends who would actually talk to one another about many different issues.  Friends who would gather and sit and discuss, day after day.  But on the other hand I was seeing romantic relationships that were either business relationships or almost elementary.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="romantic-relationships">Romantic Relationships&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Last week, a woman dumped a jug full of kerosene all over her body and lit herself on fire.  Just 30 meters from the gate of our compound.  Apparently it was because her boyfriend broke up with her. It was in the early evening and there were many people around.  They forced the woman to stop-drop-and-roll.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apparently she survived the initial situation and was taken to the hospital.  Considering the healthcare in this country and her likely third-degree burns I’m unsure whether she survived for very long thereafter. Although my initial reaction was that this was about a passionate, tragic love affair gone wrong – a story which likely any culture can relate to – it was more likely about the stigma which would follow the poor woman after the man refused to marry her after their affair had gone public.  I do not know that for certain, but it is my educated guess.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Relationships between the sexes are tremendously strained here in Somaliland.  While that comes with the territory in many ways, what I’ve noticed is that in many ways relationships, especially romantic relationships, between the sexes are riven with what I would consider immaturities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Twenty-somethings and thirty-somethings that are involved in romantic relationships rarely discuss their relationships, creating a situation of insularity stifling development and deepening of many of the relationships. Of course, arranged marriages are still very customary and prevalent.  In these cases the romance and the business-politics of clan and diyah-paying groups are conflated forcing individuals into catch-22 situations where they are forced to subordinate their own desires for the benefit of their clan or family.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For me personally, it is fascinating to learn about this situation because it seems such a throw-back.  I suspect for much of human history marrying someone for business-political reasons has been more important than many current historians / anthropologists would give credit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A couple of months ago I was chewing with some people including some American-Somalilander diaspora and they were asking me one of the biggest questions I always get: “how do you find Somaliland”?  I like it when diaspora ask me this question because they find themselves in a situation similar to me – somewhere in between the two cultures. Usually when non-diaspora ask me this question I give an white-washed answer.  This time, for whatever reason, I was feeling especially honest.  I replied that for the most part I have not experienced much culture shock as I read and studied a lot before I even arrived.  The thing which has been the biggest cultural shock to me, I told them, has been the cultural response to a widowing. In Somali culture (and I am told but cannot confirm – many Arab cultures) if a husband passes away his brother will be forced to marry the sister-in-law. When I first heard this, I remember shaking my head and furrowing my brow deeply.  But I asked why.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The answer, actually, makes semi-sense.  It is because if the wife remarries someone outside of the family than the children that she had with her deceased husband will be considered outsiders by the new husband and he will abandon them.  So it is a cultural mechanism to ensure that the children were taken care of.  That I can see and understand – to the extent that it is simply a support mechanism.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Later, when I became closer to more Somalis, I asked about the reality and the thing that was really creeping me out – does the brother have to have sex with the former sister-in-law or can it be a show marriage. Their answer was that if the brother doesn’t have sex with the sister-in-law then it isn’t a marriage after all.  Fair enough, but I must say that I’m pleased my own culture has never adopted this situation as it feels too much like incest based upon my own cultural upbringing and proclivities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These anecdotes are a simple reflection of why I say that romantic relationships here in Somaliland are very different than the romantic relationships that I’m accustomed to – tending towards much more shallow.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="friendly-relationships">Friendly Relationships&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>On the other hand, friendly relationships are much deeper than anything that I’m accustomed to.  And here is where I get to the reason for why I chose the picture at the top (aside from his magnificent beauty in austerity).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Somalilanders value their friendships so much.  It is one of the things that I appreciate most about being here.  When you meet someone that you haven’t seen in a while you are guaranteed a big hug, a big smile, a ten minutes of your life you’ll never get back.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The other thing that surprises me is how quickly two people will become friends.  In a short time you go from Mister to Friend to Brother.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For men, especially, there is an avenue by which one can almost fully guarantee they will have a friend for life.  It is what is called fadhigaa or qayilayaa or cunayaa or chewing or sitting together.  Chewing sessions are a great avenue for discussion.  They have a major downside which is that it’s a men’s only club, but that is a deeper issue which I will leave for another time.  Chewing sessions usually last about six hours – although sometimes more, sometimes less depending on the circumstances.  From about 3 pm to 9 pm men will gather in their normal meeting spot.  When you arrive in a majlis (the place for sitting) you get yourself all arranged with your cigarettes in one place, your drinks in another place, your qat over here, your laptop and phone over there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then you sit back take a few deep breathes, and just sit and talk for the next hours.  Like with alcohol or marijuana, qat affects different people differently.  It varies with your state of mind when you begin, with the distinct strain that you always buy, and with your own personal reaction to the qat.  It makes some people retreat into themselves.  You won’t hear from them for hours.  I am not among those.  The other general trend is that it opens people up and is a decent social lubricator.  These people will end up talking and talking and talking much more than when they are sober.  I am among those.  Men come together and listen to the radio, watch BBC or Al Jazeera or the National TV, read the Somali sites, and talk.  This time together in a relaxed environment cements friendships deeply.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On Going Local: Finding Your Happy Place</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-12-local-finding-happy-place/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-12-local-finding-happy-place/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>On Going Local is a new (short) series that I’ll be running which will attempt to look at my life from an objective perspective as I transition from and NGO worker into an entrepreneur here in the developing world.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve been here in Somaliland now for around two and a half years now.  It has been a wonderful time, and I’ve enjoyed every minute of it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are many aspects of Somali / Somaliland society &amp;amp; culture that I have found it easy to adjust too.  But there are a few things which have been difficult.  Not the least of which is the six day work week.  Being an Islamic country, we take Friday off.  But that most people take off.  Going from a two day weekend to a one day weekend with shorter days throughout the six was a big adjustment and I’m not sure that I will ever fully adjust to it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, this is about space.  Physical space.  Like most development workers I lived for a long time in a &lt;a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/caseykuhlman/SomalilandCompound02" title="Gorgorka Luxury Estates">gigantic house&lt;/a> shared among an assortment of other expatriates, cleaners, cooks, guards, and staff.  It can be a fantastically good time having all the excitement of different activities, smells, and languages around you.  For a little while…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a time, though, it becomes stifling.  For one thing, you are never “off duty.”  At any time of the day or night someone may come and knock on your door.  Someone’s family member is sick and they need money; someone’s mobile phone was stolen and they need money; the guards caught two people making out in a dark corner behind the house; all sound tracked to random gunshots due to land disputes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most development or aid workers I know always like to say it’s not a job, it’s a lifestyle.  And that is all well and good, but it isn’t a lifestyle I was very interested in.  Sure you can try to set boundaries, but you don’t want to incentivize the people working with you to not tell you what is happening.   That can lead to all kinds of problems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This balance is incredibly difficult to achieve between having some personal space (when the standard living situation is tenement and shared, college-esque, except we’re not college age anymore) and being “open.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have recently moved out of that mansion into what would be normal to me.  Luckily enough it is also what would be normal to a middle-class Somali.  Instead of ten bedrooms (some of which were office space), I now have three.  Instead of having to walk 15 minutes to get to the kitchen, it now takes me 15 seconds.  I don’t have to worry about staff all of the time as I only have someone who comes to clean for me a few days a week &amp;amp; when I’m at the office.  It is safer this way, as you are a target when you live in a mansion.  You can do what you like without having to worry about being disturbed.  You can metaphorically unpack your bags.  You can find normality in an otherwise frantic existence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The place I’m living now actually feels like a home rather than a dorm.  And that is fantastic.  I love my old roommates dearly, but it is so nice to have something that is “yours.”  And when my wife comes down next year for a bit, my life will be complete!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Decoding the Somali Mind: A Guide for Expats (Anecdotal, Not Definitive Version): Wants v. Needs</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-28-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-v/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-28-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version-v/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This is a new series containing a few stories which have stood out in my time here in Somaliland and have helped me to understand a bit more a culture that in many ways is very different from my own, but in many ways is not. This series explores those differences.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![want need syrup by thebrianmeyer @ flickr][2]][2]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every development worker I’ve ever met, and I can say with confidence, without exception, hates the following phrase with a passion: “What we &lt;em>really&lt;/em> need is….”  Hearing that phrase pretty much ruins your entire day.  Usually, but not always, it is accompanied by a veiled threat of what will happen if the particular worker does not comply.  Well, that happens when one is dealing with governmental clients.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a preliminary (and because despite my non-traditional path I am still a trained lawyer), let me define what I’m talking about when I say “wants” and “needs.”  I would define (for the purposes of this piece only, &lt;em>see supra&lt;/em>) “needs” as those things which are required to perform a given task, whereas I would define “wants” as those things which are not required but would be beneficial to accomplish a given task.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do I “need” internet to survive? No.   Do I “need” internet to do my job? Yes (reasons for this answer will be detailed in a forthcoming post).  I say this almost flippantly, but in any culture it is incredibly easy to conflate these concepts and trying to differentiate between the two will depend largely upon an individual’s perspective.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Especially when it comes to legislative action, determining whether a mechanism or a “thing” is needed or wanted is incredibly difficult to determine with accuracy.  One of the arts of political action is convincing others of one’s perspective as to whether something is a needed requirement or a wanted luxury.  This is one of  the many reasons why so many politicians are trained lawyers – as we get paid to use words to twist concepts to convince individuals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yet, when it comes to Somali society figuring out such a differential is complicated by the Somali language.  In Somali, to say “I want X” one would say “X waan doonayaa,” whereas to say “I need X” one would say “X waan doonayaa.”  The root of the verb (“doon”) means both of the concepts expressed in the English words “want” and “need.”  It isn’t a far leap to see that this makes it even more difficult to differentiate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first time I was running a workshop here in Hargeisa talking to legislators about the differences in these concepts my translator was struggling and I was having a hard time understanding why it was difficult to pose the question to the participants.  At the break I pulled my translator aside and tried to figure out why he was having such trouble getting across what I was trying to say.  He was also extremely frustrated but didn’t say much other than he would do his best.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Months later, when I was learning Somali, it became clear to me that the difficulty my translator had experienced much earlier was a function of the Somali language.  After I had learned a modicum of Somali than I changed some of the curriculum of the workshop from wants and needs to requirements and luxuries.  After that it was much easier for my translator to get the preliminary concepts across so that the participants could have a good discussion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of my favorite all time stories during my years here in Somaliland falls (loosely) under this concept of wants v. needs.  In October, 2008, there were three suicide bombs detonated in different places here in Hargeisa: the Ethiopian Embassy, the UNDP compound, and the Presidential mansion.  After these bombings there were probably four of us expatriates who stuck around while everyone else ran away to Nairobi.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My team and I worked day and night for the two weeks after the bombings preparing a series of documents to help the government and parliament understand the legal mechanisms for reacting to terrorism that have been emplaced under (1) international law; and (2) national laws within the region.  The government told me very early on that they were looking to emplace something like the Somaliland Patriot Act and so we had done tons of research on the topic for the government.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We broke up the delivery of the work product among the different affected clients: namely the Ministry of Interior, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, and the Ministry of Justice.  I was in with the Minister of Justice briefing him on the current problems that they would have if they wanted to prosecute suspected terrorists under their current penal code.  I had included in my briefing a bunch on due process as well as the international human rights mechanisms, which had been imputed into the Somaliland Constitution, that currently limited their ability to move forward with prosecutions prior to further legislative action.  About 2/3d’s of the way through my presentation the Vice Minister of Justice barged into the briefing and sat down.  He waited for about thirty seconds before he turned to me and said the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This is all well and good, but what Somaliland really *needs *is you to call up the CIA and brief them on what is happening here.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Seriously, Mr. Vice Minister, do you really think that I have the CIA’s number on my speed dial?  My sarcastic side said.  For once, I controlled that and tried my best to explain in a temperate tone that I had no contacts with the CIA and that even if I did they wouldn’t listen to me.  I caught the Minister’s eyes rolling slightly while the Vice Minister was on his tirade after my response so I knew I was on OK ground and I just moved along with my briefing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After we finished, and we were leaving the Vice Minister (who I had never spoken to once prior to this exchange) walked out to our vehicle with us.  He told me that he knew exactly who I was and that he was going to hold me personally liable for informing the CIA of what was happening here in Somaliland.  I assured him in the most even tones I could conjure at that moment that there was nothing I could do for him on this issue and that he should use the Minister of Foreign Affairs rather than some external NGO worker.  He was never convinced.  And I wasn’t convinced that he was mentally stable enough to be a Vice Minister.  I left completely flabbergasted.  To this day, there is no Somaliland Patriot Act.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Decoding the Somali Mind: A Guide for Expats (Anecdotal, Not Definitive Version): Introduction</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-21-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-21-decoding-somali-mind-guide-expats-anecdotal-definitive-version/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This is a new series containing a few stories which have stood out in my time here in Somaliland and have helped me to understand a bit more a culture that in many ways is very different from my own, but in many ways is now. This series explores those differences.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![BraiNut 1.0 via sath.es @flickr][2]][2]
via sath.es @flickr&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have lived &amp;amp; worked with Somalis here in Somaliland for over two years now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have, like many expats before me, sat in rooms on the floor with rugs underneath us cushions behind our backs, mauis’s (skirts) on sporting wife-beaters drinking the sweetest teas one has ever drank and (as my wife likes to say) sticking green leaves up our noses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Equally I have sat many nights, like many expats before me, on a veranda, a glass of wine in hand, cool breezes of Hargeisa swirling around, dressed in jeans and semi-glamorous (but always purposively casual) shirts, some ipod attached to portable speakers, listening to music that is on the verge of being hip back home and talking about the deep cultural differences between us and those that fill our daily lives (our clients, our friends, our colleagues, people we meet around).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have had a steady turnover in Hargeisa of expatriates lately.  And over that time there seems to be an increasing amount of tension between the expatriates and the Somalilanders.  I am not sure exactly why this seems to be happening (because this is Somaliland it is spoken of in metaphors and resides fully in the subtextual zone), but it has become increasingly tangible to me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the course of the past year there has been this tit-for-tat between the powerful voices for the expatriates and the powerful voices for the Somalilanders.  The problem is that those of us who aren’t given powerful voices become batted around as the game is played by others.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Something happened to me recently which I would like to use (again cloaked in metaphor and subtext, because this is how to communicate in Somaliland) as a tuusaale (example).  One of my best expat friends here in Hargeisa (who is a development worker) recently had some professional dealings with one of my best Somali friends (who is a mid-level government employee).  Due to forces above and beyond either’s control the dealings did not turn out well and both became frustrated by the situation (for very different reasons but that is beside the point).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a while I was caught in the middle of everything but the biggest problem was that I was getting completely different stories as to what happened from either “side” (so to say).  There was so little alignment between the stories that for a while I wondered if these were two completely different situations involving different people completely.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Later I started to piece it together, to connect the people that were being referenced by one story with how I organize those relationships when I’m talking to the other side, to connect the things that I knew were more important to one side with those that had little emphasis in the other’s side of the story.  I don’t know much about mediation, but I was trying to see these events through each side’s cultural lens and come to some sort of objective understanding of what likely transpired.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was only after spending literally hours trying to dig through and cross-check and re-examine and then start all over again that I was able to ferret out what may have actually happened.  And only after that did I realize that the actualities of the situation were out of the control of either party.  That happens in development work and it is one of the occupational hazards of this work.  However, the relational aspects of the situation were very much aggravated by the cultural differences between the parties.  It is this part – the cultural misunderstandings and their attendant relational aspects which causes (in my mind) undue hardships in development work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is why I wanted to write a few words over the course of the next little while trying to tell a few stories that have taught me a ton about humanity and culture (and which is which).  A few stories which I think of and use when I’m trying to analyze things through a foreign cultural lens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If I had to pick one of the most intellectually satisfying aspects of working here in Somaliland, it has been the opportunity to dig deep into a culture and a way of thinking and seeing the world that is very different than my own.  Each of the cultural differences, while stark at times, belies evidence of our common humanity.  Every time I become frustrated with the cultural differences then something will happen to me which will reinforce the common humanity which is always there.  The tenderness of a father’s reprimand, or a shared joke, or an extraordinarily kind act.  These things accompany each and every one of the cultural differences.  So I hope to share a few of these stories along the way as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Annotated Reading: So THAT is Why I Don&amp;#8217;t Fit In</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-04-annotated-reading-fit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-04-annotated-reading-fit/</guid><description>&lt;p>This week I read a fascinating article which was written by a former high-level DFID individual named Rosalind Eyben.  The title of the piece is, “Hiding Relations: The Irony of ‘Effective Aid.’” It can be found in its entirety [here][2].
[2]: &lt;a href="http://www.oxfamblogs.org/fp2p/wp-content/uploads/ejdr201010a1.pdf">http://www.oxfamblogs.org/fp2p/wp-content/uploads/ejdr201010a1.pdf&lt;/a>
This article spoke to me in a way that not many pieces have recently.  Perhaps it is my transition from an aid receiving NGO worker to the other side of the coin as a private sector social entrepreneur, and the conjunction of the transition with my reading of the article.  Or maybe I am trying to continue to understand a world and a profession which on the surface seems straight-forward (go to Somalia &amp;amp; help) but underneath is complicated, political, and stifles lots of creativity for no reason.
There are many varied reasons for the underlying complications.  Some of the reasons come from other annotated readings that I have put up in the past.  Some of the reasons come from the complications of running world-wide operations with thousands, if not millions of associated partners – not to mentions the hundreds of millions of people involved in the entire operation from politicians, to top-level administrators, to top-level NGO workers, to country-level NGO workers, all the way to the purported beneficiaries of a project.  So, in short, this is a complicated undertaking and requires people who understand complexity theory (an annotated reading which is in the works) and who understand relationships.
The main gist of the piece is that aid should value the relationships which are developed between a recipient population and those individuals mandated with the delivery of the project.  I have always felt that this work requires a complex understanding of the context in which the project is undertaken, and I have always valued the relationships which I have built along the way.  Indeed, the value which I place on those relations is one of the driving forces for my new ventures (see [here][3] and [here][4]).  While I have placed value, as an individual human, on these relationships, I always had this odd feeling whenever I would talk to others within my organization or in donor communities that this was some sort of a remote control SimCity game that had less to do with human beings and more to do with numbers and metrics which never had any application at least in my specific context here in S’land.
[3]: &lt;a href="http://watershedlegal.com">http://watershedlegal.com&lt;/a>
[4]: &lt;a href="http://watershedfarms.net">http://watershedfarms.net&lt;/a>
That said, I have always been impressed when meeting face-to-face with those in my old organization and in the donor community.  On many levels they are bright, well-intentioned individuals.  So I could never quite put my finger on this divergence.  This piece has filled in many of the gaps for me.  So without further introduction, here is the piece.
[![][6]][6]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=394">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=394&lt;/a>
[![][7]][7]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=395">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=395&lt;/a>
[![][8]][8]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=396">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=396&lt;/a>
[![][9]][9]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=397">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=397&lt;/a>
[![][10]][10]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=398">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=398&lt;/a>
[![][11]][11]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=399">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=399&lt;/a>
[![][12]][12]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=400">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=400&lt;/a>
[![][13]][13]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=401">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=401&lt;/a>
[![][14]][14]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=402">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=402&lt;/a>
[![][15]][15]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=403">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=403&lt;/a>
[![][16]][16]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=404">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=404&lt;/a>
[![][17]][17]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=405">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=405&lt;/a>
[![][18]][18]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=406">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=406&lt;/a>
[![][19]][19]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=407">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=407&lt;/a>
[![][20]][20]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=408">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=408&lt;/a>
[![][21]][21]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=409">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/?attachment_id=409&lt;/a>
~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>