<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Linux for Lawyers on underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/Linux-for-Lawyers/</link><description>Recent content in Linux for Lawyers on underWater desert Blogging</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Casey Kuhlman</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/Linux-for-Lawyers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gnome Shell Extensions -- Those Little Bundles of Joy</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-02-21-gnome-shell-extensions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-02-21-gnome-shell-extensions/</guid><description>I have yet to really get into any of the desktop interfaces other than Gnome. I've tried KDE and Unity. I'd like to try Elementary, but probably on an old laptop I'm going to set up for my in laws rather than my primary machine. Since about Gnome Shell 3.2, though, I've done little more than take tours around other desktop interfaces.
In case you did not know, one of the greatest things about Linux is that you can do this.</description></item><item><title>How I Use Multiple Workspaces</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-02-19-using-multiple-workspaces/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-02-19-using-multiple-workspaces/</guid><description>When I first moved to Linux from Windows in Ubuntu 11.10, I was confused about multiple workspaces. I thought, coming from a Windows background, that they would be overkill and require significant resources from my very old at that time laptop. My laptop then was about a 5 year old Dell that Windows Vista barely worked on. One of the huge reasons I decided to try Linux at all was the way that it was reported to be able to handle older hardware with style and grace.</description></item><item><title>Working with PDFs in Linux</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-02-13-pdf-extract/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-02-13-pdf-extract/</guid><description>PDFs are the bane of every lawyer's existence. It is unfortunate that we break free of our addiction to PDFs and this is the thought behind my RMOC project. Until that is a viable option for working with PDFs, here is my suite of free PDF tools that can be used in the stead of the overly engineered Acrobat.
Reading PDFs Most any distro will contain a PDF reader. By default Ubuntu installs Evince which is lightweight and works as a viewer.</description></item><item><title>Remembering Your Packages</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-02-11-remember-your-packages/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-02-11-remember-your-packages/</guid><description>What programs (packages) do I use? This is a perennial problem. It is always easy to remember those packages you use all the time but what about those packages that you do not but you want them there when you need them. Here is a three step system for ensuring that you never forget to reinstall packages you want when you upgrade your system or reinstall you operating system.
Step 1 &amp;ndash; Build an Install Script I have slowly been speaking about the parts of my installation script over the course of most of my Linux for Lawyers series.</description></item><item><title>Conky -- Smooth Operations</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-02-05-on-conky/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-02-05-on-conky/</guid><description>Conky is a tool I have used since about the time I started using Linux. It is a great piece of kit. When you first start using Conky it can be a bit overwhelming because it has a ton of options and configuring it is not terribly straight forward for those who do not like command line and editing files. But once you get over the initial hump it is amazing.</description></item><item><title>Why Using Shells are Great</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-02-04-on-shells/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-02-04-on-shells/</guid><description>I love using the shell; however so many people do not. My argument to others to use your shell more is simply that you see what is happening with your computer a lot easier than you can with a graphical user interface (GUI). Basically, your shell is somewhat like a glass bottom boat to see what your computer is actually doing. On linux, GUI's often have an option to pull up some of what your computer is doing, but for the most part they do not.</description></item><item><title>Linux 4 Lawyers -- Encrypting your hard drives</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-01-23-encrypting-your-hard-drives/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-01-23-encrypting-your-hard-drives/</guid><description>I encrypt my hard drives because it is the right thing to do. I don't need an ethics opinion from my bar association to understand that it is a bad thing to have a bunch of client stuff on an unencrypted drive that is constantly moving around.
[WAIT, what're you talking about?]
OK. So let us take a step back. There are a bunch of ways in which you can secure data.</description></item></channel></rss>