<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>virtual contracts on underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/virtual-contracts/</link><description>Recent content in virtual contracts on underWater desert Blogging</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Casey Kuhlman</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/virtual-contracts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What the Esteemed (and Very Smart) Law Professors Missed at the HLS Ethereum Talk</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-04-16-etherum-visits-harvard/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-04-16-etherum-visits-harvard/</guid><description>![Ethereum Logo]({{ site.url }}{{ site.root }}{{ site.images_dir }}/{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; }}/ethereum.png)
Introduction Yesterday a very interesting event happened. And I had the pleasure to listen in. Primavera De Filippi talked Ethereum at a Berkman luncheon.
For those who do not know Berkman is a center at Harvard University. For those who do not know Harvard, welcome to earth. Berkman is officially the Berkman Center for Internet and Society. It is a joint research center housed in Harvard's Law School with the following mission:</description></item><item><title>Linking Virtual Automatic Contracts to IRL Events</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-03-04-irl-links-with-virtual-automatic-contracts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-03-04-irl-links-with-virtual-automatic-contracts/</guid><description>I have been droning on about virtual automatic contracts for a few posts now.
By the by, today is a bit of an exciting day because later this evening I will be going to the Ethereum meetup in Amsterdam. This will be an interesting opportunity for me to speak with others who are interested in exploring the possibilities of virtual automatic contracts generally and also to see specifically some more details as to how Ethereum smart contracts will work.</description></item><item><title>Automatic Virtual Contracts as Donation Support Mechanism for Humanitarian Crises</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-02-25-automatic-virtual-contracts-for-humanitarian-relief/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-02-25-automatic-virtual-contracts-for-humanitarian-relief/</guid><description>Tomorrow I head to Addis Ababa. It has been a decent wee while since I have been to Addis and I am excited to see where the years have taken it. Ethiopia is far &amp;ndash; very far &amp;ndash; from the We are the World days; yet, that image of Ethiopia is stuck in many people's minds &amp;ndash; which is a shame because it is a beautiful, dynamic, and growing country with a lot to offer.</description></item><item><title>How I Would Structure Automatic Virtual Contracts</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-02-17-structuring-automatic-virtual-contracts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-02-17-structuring-automatic-virtual-contracts/</guid><description>Automatic contracts have been occupying a great deal of my free mental energies for the past few weeks since I first learned that there are platforms in the works that will allow for such things to happen. My thoughts on this are quite nascent, as is the technology, but here are my early observations.
Introduction Automatic virtual contracts are, essentially, small computer scripts which are linked to virtual currency wallets. The basic idea is that a financial transaction and the terms and conditions governing the transaction collapse into a singular instrument &amp;ndash; or script.</description></item></channel></rss>