<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>virtual contracts on underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/virtual-contracts/</link><description>Recent content in virtual contracts on underWater desert Blogging</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/virtual-contracts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What the Esteemed (and Very Smart) Law Professors Missed at the HLS Ethereum Talk</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-04-16-etherum-visits-harvard/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-04-16-etherum-visits-harvard/</guid><description>My reactions to Ethereum's unveiling at a bastion of American legal and technological thought.</description></item><item><title>Linking Virtual Automatic Contracts to IRL Events</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-03-04-irl-links-with-virtual-automatic-contracts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-03-04-irl-links-with-virtual-automatic-contracts/</guid><description>How do virtual automatic contracts know that a real world event took place so that it could take a particular action? This is an interesting question that will need to be explored in some detail before virtual automatic contracts can be workable in real life. Here is my early take on three possible linkages I would recommend lawyer|coders build into smart contracts.</description></item><item><title>Automatic Virtual Contracts as Donation Support Mechanism for Humanitarian Crises</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-25-automatic-virtual-contracts-for-humanitarian-relief/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-25-automatic-virtual-contracts-for-humanitarian-relief/</guid><description>How could we leverage automatic contracts and virtual currency to speed up service delivery to populations affected by humanitarian crises in a way which will entrench local markets rather than displace them? Sounds too good to be true, perhaps it is not.</description></item><item><title>How I Would Structure Automatic Virtual Contracts</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-17-structuring-automatic-virtual-contracts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-17-structuring-automatic-virtual-contracts/</guid><description>EAutomatic contracts have been occupying a great deal of my free mental energies for the past few weeks since I first learned that there are platforms in the works that will allow for such things to happen. My thoughts on this are quite nascent, as is the technology, but here are my early observations.</description></item></channel></rss>