<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>africa on underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/africa/</link><description>Recent content in africa on underWater desert Blogging</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Casey Kuhlman</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/africa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Perspectives on Africa -&amp;gt; Its all about the lens</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-10-25-perspectives-africa-lens/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-10-25-perspectives-africa-lens/</guid><description>When you look at this picture what do you see? I see a man who is satisfied with his situation. Sure there are the tribal markings, the blanket over the shoulder, the bleakness of the background and the stuff on the back of the man’s neck. But what really jumps out, to me at least, is the satisfied look that his eyes and his mouth convey.
Two development pundit bloggers have discussed recently the cultural meme which the photos that are chosen to accompany NGO marketing campaigns, news articles on Africa, etc.</description></item><item><title>I&amp;#8217;m Supposed to Write on Water, but I Don&amp;#8217;t Have Any&amp;#8230;</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-10-15-supposed-write-water-any/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-10-15-supposed-write-water-any/</guid><description>![Broken Pipe via Starbuck Powersurge @ flickr]({{ site.url }}{{ site.root }}{{ site.images_dir }}/{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; }}/262341270_2017b87199.jpg)
Today the Interweb Gods have deemed is World Blog about water day. Or likely more accurately, the brilliant change.org marketers have deemed today as world blog about water:Day. I haven’t read every post I have seen come across my various Twitter wires, but the ones I’ve read talk about the need for us to have water.</description></item><item><title>Chinese Powered Self-Sufficiency in Africa</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-05-26-chinese-powered-self-sufficiency-africa/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-05-26-chinese-powered-self-sufficiency-africa/</guid><description>Ellen Johnson-Sirleaf &amp;amp; Hillary Clinton via @FP_Magazine
Madam President Ellen Johnson-Sirleaf the current President of Liberia did a remarkable thing yesterday. She told the world that in ten years Liberia would be self-sufficient and able to stand on its own feet with only further investment and no aid.
In ten years, Liberia will have been out of its civil war for about fifteen or sixteen depending on how one classifies the end.</description></item><item><title>Understanding War [in Mogadishu]</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-04-17-understanding-war-in-mogadishu/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-04-17-understanding-war-in-mogadishu/</guid><description>This week the World Food Program (WFP) shoved out a press release about how piracy was raising food prices in South-Central Somalia. At first glance, most people who would read such a report will likely think, oh the poor people in Mogadishu. Of course, I share their sentiments.
However, there is a deeper issue at work here. One that I’m not sure many people realize. The conclusion (because I’m a lawyer and we put these things up front) is that this rise in cost of business may have drastically good effects for the conflict in the South.</description></item><item><title>Franchising in Africa: An Annotated Reading</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-02-24-franchising-in-africa-an-annotated-reading/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-02-24-franchising-in-africa-an-annotated-reading/</guid><description>This week's annotated reading is from Dalberg (who I had not heard of before) and it deals with the lack of McDonalds around Africa. Original article here (pdf), my thoughts below.
[![2010_02_24_12_40_30_Page_01][3]][3]
[![2010_02_24_12_40_30_Page_02][4]][4]
[![2010_02_24_12_40_30_Page_03][5]][5]
[![2010_02_24_12_40_30_Page_04][6]][6]
[![2010_02_24_12_40_30_Page_05][7]][7]
[![2010_02_24_12_40_30_Page_06][8]][8]
[![2010_02_24_12_40_30_Page_07][9]][9]
[![2010_02_24_12_40_30_Page_08][10]][10]
[![2010_02_24_12_40_30_Page_09][11]][11]
[![2010_02_24_12_40_30_Page_10][12]][12]
[![2010_02_24_12_40_30_Page_11][13]][13]
[![2010_02_24_12_40_30_Page_12][14]][14]
[![2010_02_24_12_40_30_Page_13][15]][15]
~ # ~
[]: http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e201310f33a239970c-pi []: http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e201310f33a450970c-pi []: http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e20120a8ccbc9f970b-pi []: http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e201310f33a688970c-pi []: http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e201310f33a6dd970c-pi []: http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e201310f33a76c970c-pi []: http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e201310f33eb17970c-pi []: http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e20120a8cd05d4970b-pi []: http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e20120a8cd0703970b-pi []: http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e201310f33edca970c-pi</description></item><item><title>Gates goes to TED and Few Listen</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-02-16-gates-goes-to-ted-and-few-listen/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-02-16-gates-goes-to-ted-and-few-listen/</guid><description>I didn't hear about this until after the fact. Indeed quite after the fact. I was reading tweets about how Gates was blowing people's minds at cocktail parties leading up to his big speech about climate change at TED this year. But then I forgot about them until reading these two articles from Worldchanging.
The first to be published was from Alex Steffen. Money Quotes:
Gates spoke about his commitment to using his massive philanthropic resources</description></item><item><title>Grow &amp;#8211; Venture Capital 2.0</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-02-16-grow-venture-capital-2-0/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-02-16-grow-venture-capital-2-0/</guid><description>Everyone Funding Startups!!! Grow VC
is the first global crowdfunding tool for web and mobile startups.
This is a fantastic idea, which compliments so nicely with Kiva. My only critique is that it is very tech focused. Although it makes a
logical entry point for oversight reasons (primarily), I hope that they
will open it up to other sectors. Everyday I meet business people
here in Africa with fantastic ideas.</description></item><item><title>What it feels like to be invaded</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-02-09-what-it-feels-like-to-be-invaded/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-02-09-what-it-feels-like-to-be-invaded/</guid><description>[]: http://www.irishtimes.com/newspaper/world/2009/1204/1224260043076.html
Last December a bomb exploded in Mogadishu. Actually, it was the 4th of December. I didn’t remember the date until I looked it up just now. Pictures like the one at the left pretty much fit most people’s world view of Somalia. Yet, I live here and I have a completely different view of the situation. I left my house on the day in question about about 2 or so in the afternoon.</description></item><item><title>FP gets it semi-correct on Somalia</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-02-04-fp-gets-it-semi-correct-on-somalia/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-02-04-fp-gets-it-semi-correct-on-somalia/</guid><description>FP usually does really good analysis, but I am concerned by a couple of blog posts they have published recently. The first is here. While I understand that they are trying to simplify a very complex issue, this is just lazy. Especially for a group of mostly informed readers. While I agree with their analysis that Shabaab is running a parallel government (to some extent), it is no where near as pervasive as, for instance, Greater Liberia was.</description></item><item><title>My Own Private Pirate Expedition</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2009-09-09-my-own-private-pirate-expedition/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2009-09-09-my-own-private-pirate-expedition/</guid><description>I am trying to return to some modicum of consistency with respect to the exhibitionist nature of this activity.
In that vein, let me tell you of our next few days. Our roommates (there are a total of five of us, which will constrict to three within a matter of weeks) and Leigh and I will be heading off to “train” the Coast Guard. Actually, we won’t be doing any training, but Scuba Steve will be training the Coast Guard on boat handling techniques (for their one cutter) and diving techniques (still unsure re: this one).</description></item><item><title>An Homage to My Environment (aka Thanks for the Birthday Greetings)</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2009-09-03-an-homage-to-my-environment-aka-thanks-for-the-birthday-greetings/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2009-09-03-an-homage-to-my-environment-aka-thanks-for-the-birthday-greetings/</guid><description>For those which are curious as to a H-town, birthday this is how it broke down.
I woke up to homemade chocolate cake (which L could get all ingredients of locally), a bottle of prosecco (imported on the sly from Dubai) and one of those happy birthday stringers (imported openly from Nairobi). This was served on a tray which we mostly use to take our 24-hour security detail tea in late in the evenings sitting on a low stool I mainly use as an otomon (made from raw camel leather tied to unfinished wood).</description></item><item><title>Tonight the Following Occured&amp;#8230;</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-09-12-tonight-the-following-occured/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-09-12-tonight-the-following-occured/</guid><description>A Masai Bush Pilot attempted to convince me that rural Sudanese women were so turned on by engine noise from his craft that they would masturbate in front of him. But only when the engines were running. I became strangely choked up by the words of a departing Haitian whom I barely know. I discussed the vitality of American Football in relation to Rugby and what that speaks of American v.</description></item><item><title>AFRICOM and WAPO</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-06-03-africom-and-wapo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-06-03-africom-and-wapo/</guid><description>I have been fascinated to watch how AFRICOM develops. Washington Post has a very interesting article the other day about how AFRICOM has been received on the continent. The gist of the article contains two interrelated theorems: (1) that Bush's rhetorical fascination with terrorism has pigeon-holed his foreign policy measures that have little to do with terrorism; (2) that African leaders and American policy makers are like Somali Pirates and French Sailors passing each other quietly in the night with little understanding of the other.</description></item><item><title>Arrival Terminal</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-05-18-arrival-terminal/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-05-18-arrival-terminal/</guid><description>Well, for better or worse, I
guess I’m settled in here now. I am living in a hotel suite for the time
being. In maybe six weeks or so I’ll move either into a villa on the
grounds of this hotel or have been talking to a few people here about the
possibility of getting a compound like we had when I was in Salone. Either
way, the living is pretty decent.</description></item><item><title>Beckham went to Salone</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-02-29-beckham-went-to-salone/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-02-29-beckham-went-to-salone/</guid><description>Here is a video of it. UNICEF: David Beckham surprises young Sierra Leone footballers
[Add to My Profile][2] | [More Videos][3] ~ # ~
[2]: http://myspacetv.com/index.cfm?fuseaction=vids.addToProfileConfirm&amp;amp;videoid=29311413&amp;amp;title=UNICEF: David Beckham surprises young Sierra Leone footballers [3]: http://myspacetv.com/index.cfm?fuseaction=vids.home</description></item><item><title>Brown Gets a Few Things</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-01-21-brown-gets-a-few-things/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-01-21-brown-gets-a-few-things/</guid><description>[![Gordonbrownblurweb][2]][2]
Link: [‘An idea whose time has come’: Brown backs UN security council seat for India | The Guardian | Guardian Unlimited][2].
[]: http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2008/01/21/gordonbrownblurweb.jpg [2]: http://www.guardian.co.uk/guardianpolitics/story/0,,2244153,00.html &amp;ldquo;&amp;lsquo;An idea whose time has come&amp;rsquo;: Brown backs UN security council seat for India | The Guardian | Guardian Unlimited&amp;rdquo;
I know that it is trendy in the UK to bash on Gordon Brown. I agree with his critics, mostly. However this Guardian article points out what things he does seem to get entirely correct.</description></item><item><title>Sliding Liberia</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-01-10-sliding-liberia/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-01-10-sliding-liberia/</guid><description>So, am back from Europe and getting into the swing of things. Sometimes the internet is an amazing thing. I have my RSS Reader set up to automatically search for many things, one of which is for the case that I used to work on. Usually a bunch of trash comes up when I do my news skim each day since Charles Taylor isn’t the rarest of names and it is difficult to filter out all of the trash although I get most of it.</description></item><item><title>Watch This</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-12-20-watch-this/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-12-20-watch-this/</guid><description>Keep an eye on this! [![3307ma4][2]][2]
Last week [Jacob Zuma was elected as head of ANC.][2] He won this election over the sitting president, Thabo Mbeki, who he has had troubles with in the past. Zuma used to be Mbeki’s vice, but was fired in 2005. Last week he has wrested the leadership of the ANC from him after a very acrimonious campaign for the leadership of Nelson’s party. So today, BBC reports that there are rumors that Zuma will be [indicted on corruption charges][3].</description></item><item><title>Zimbabwe</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-11-13-zimbabwe/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-11-13-zimbabwe/</guid><description>If you wondered a bit about what the hell Mugabe is doing, look here. The MDC in Zimbabwe is a political party, so there is a political agenda behind this film, but after hearing the testimonies you may be able to put that aside. The video is below:
~ # ~</description></item><item><title>Sierra Leone bridge house</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-10-25-sierra-leone-bridge-house/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-10-25-sierra-leone-bridge-house/</guid><description>Everytime I wonder about what courage is, now I think of Sierra Leoneans. They are, hands down, the most courageous people I have ever met. I broke Highland’s car on one side of this bridge:
Link: BBC NEWS | Photo journal: Sierra Leone bridge house, Execution site.
~ # ~</description></item><item><title>Sierra Leone&amp;#8217;s New Leader on NPR</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-10-16-sierra-leones-new-leader-on-npr/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-10-16-sierra-leones-new-leader-on-npr/</guid><description>Koroma sure talks a good game. I’m a bit cynical, but yet hesitantly optimistic at the same time. So far no reports of violence during the cabinet changeover, but the hope mandate will likely extend for more months, if not through the middle of next year. You can hear Koroma’s interview for NPR (BBC in the US…sort of) at the link below.
[]: http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/10/16/koroma2_full1.jpg
Link: NPR : Sierra Leone’s New Leader Promotes Law, Order.</description></item><item><title>Liberia: Post-Conflict Dilemma &amp;#8211; Should Health Care Be Free?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-10-13-liberia-post-conflict-dilemma-should-health-care-be-free/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-10-13-liberia-post-conflict-dilemma-should-health-care-be-free/</guid><description>[![Im08][2]][2]
Liberia currently has a system of [Free Healthcare][2], funded by the World Bank. []: http://www.worldpress.org/photo_essays/liberia/pg01.html [2]: http://allafrica.com/stories/200710121098.html
See Salone, this is what happens when you aren’t viewed as corrupt…people give you money to fund services to your populace. Salone should look next door to its south to find out how a country should be run. Not that Liberia is some sort of a West African utopia. But it certainly seems to be doing better…</description></item><item><title>Updated: Gambia</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-10-13-updated-gambia/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-10-13-updated-gambia/</guid><description>Gambia has released the AI investigators. Way to go Gambia. Now they can get back to telling everyone about your exploitive sex industry and your repressive police state. Way to go.
~ # ~</description></item><item><title>Liberian Debt Crisis</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-10-09-liberian-debt-crisis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-10-09-liberian-debt-crisis/</guid><description>Although I think that Bono’s typical analysis of third-world debt is in many cases flat and unnuanced, it is important to look at. At least that analysis that gets reported in the press. The LiveAid concert series was the first time I began to think actively about the topics of poverty and from my current perspective is a watershed moment. I kept thinking, &amp;ldquo;yeah, but…&amp;rdquo; where the ellipses were filled with different theories of mixed carrots and sticks.</description></item><item><title>Brits Should Boycott the Gambia</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-10-08-brits-should-boycott-the-gambia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-10-08-brits-should-boycott-the-gambia/</guid><description>I am a big supporter of The Gambia for somehow convincing everyone to include the &amp;ldquo;The&amp;rdquo; in their name. They also (apparently) have nice typical West African beaches. []: http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/10/08/_39310613_gambia_jammeh203jpg1.jpg
However there are some messed up things going on there. For one it is one of the most repressive dictatorships in West Africa. For another their sex worker industry is patronized by old, dirty people who apparently strut around would lithe young Africans for a weekend at the time and then disappear.</description></item><item><title>Big Weekend for Africa</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-09-18-big-weekend-for-africa/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-09-18-big-weekend-for-africa/</guid><description>[![17sierra600][2]][2]This was a big weekend in the news for two African countries that rarely get much press. Yesterday NYTimes led with [the results][2] of the [Salone election][3]. Ernest Koroma, the opposition leader won. Talked to Highlands yesterday, who is in Salone. She said they had a few minutes heads up that the election results were going to be announced and they went outside. She said as soon as they announced it there was a roar from the streets of Freetown which descended into a party that I wish I could have seen!</description></item><item><title>Salone votes (again) today</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-09-08-salone-votes-again-today/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-09-08-salone-votes-again-today/</guid><description>I’m very nervous, but hopeful. It is now 1830 in Freetown/Salone and BBC has not (yet) reported of any violence. This isn’t terribly surprising to me. I think if violence gets propagated it will be by whoever loses this run-off, which will not be known for a while. []: http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/09/08/_1988075_ap_amputee300.jpg
Link: BBC NEWS | Africa | S Leoneans vote in run-off poll.
BBC also has a heart-breaking photojournalistic piece about Kroo Bay slum.</description></item><item><title>ICR Photoessay</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-08-29-icr-photoessay/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-08-29-icr-photoessay/</guid><description>At the junction of heart-breaking and hope is this photo essay done by the International Rescue Committee. They are a good NGO, I think, at least on the spectrum of NGO’s. I knew some people who worked for them in SL. At least view it.
~ # ~</description></item><item><title>Sub-Saharan Population</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-08-28-sub-saharan-population/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-08-28-sub-saharan-population/</guid><description>listened to an interesting CFR podcast the other day which discussed population levels in sub-saharan africa, which are currently exploding. the guy was interesting to listen to as he was eloquent (it must come with the territory when you are the chair of sociology at NYU) and just when I thought he was going to swing naively left he hit me with an unexpected solution. it was nice to be surprised like that!</description></item><item><title>Sleepy Justice: Sierra Leone&amp;#8217;s Lack of Self-Help in Judicial Sector Reform</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-07-27-sleepy-justice-sierra-leones-lack-of-self-help-in-judicial-sector-reform/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-07-27-sleepy-justice-sierra-leones-lack-of-self-help-in-judicial-sector-reform/</guid><description>have finally finished a paper i’ve been working on for months. it isn’t perfect, but it is done done for now. will take a look at it again when i’ve given it some breathing room. if you have thoughts, send them my way!
Sleep Justice
~ # ~</description></item><item><title>africa&amp;#8217;s past, present and future</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-07-26-africas-past-present-and-future/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-07-26-africas-past-present-and-future/</guid><description>Moeletsi Mbeki gave the keynote speech at the Second Conference of the European Association of Centers of African Studies. This speech is amazing, one of my favorite paragraphs:
Africa’s challenge today is that while the era of dictatorship has
apparently come to an end, African countries do not as yet have
indigenous institutions and leaders that promote cooperation among the
citizens. Developing such institutions is a difficult and costly</description></item><item><title>Liberia Joins Global Natural Resources Transparency Plan</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-07-19-liberia-joins-global-natural-resources-transparency-plan/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-07-19-liberia-joins-global-natural-resources-transparency-plan/</guid><description>[![Ellenjohnsonsirleaf][2]][2]
I was skeptical of ole’ Ellen at the beginning. I’m beginning to come around. Most people [that I talked to][2] on the streets of Monrovia were huge EJS fans. I mean massively supportive of [her motherliness][3], [her toughness][4] (she was actually aligned with Taylor at the beginning of the conflict according to [Steven Ellis][5]‘ book), [her statesmanship][6], and [her overall good governance focus][7]. []: http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/07/19/ellenjohnsonsirleaf.jpg [2]: http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/photos/little_america/1imgp1942.html [3]: http://allafrica.com/stories/200707170966.html [4]: http://news.</description></item><item><title>eu planning peace-keeping mission to chad</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-07-18-eu-planning-peace-keeping-mission-to-chad/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-07-18-eu-planning-peace-keeping-mission-to-chad/</guid><description>[![Africapol][2]][2]
[this][2] is interesting as well. the eu is planning on sending a small peacekeeping mission to eastern chad in order to stop spillovers from the sudan fighting. []: http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/07/18/africapol.gif [2]: http://allafrica.com/stories/200707170844.html
chad is a pretty messed up place in general, withinternal insurgencies, governmental use of child soldiers and the spillover of conflict from sudan. but that isn’t what makes this news story interesting. what interests me is the eu continuing its walk down the federalism aisle.</description></item><item><title>more photos</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-07-13-more-photos/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-07-13-more-photos/</guid><description>have been able to put up most of my photos onto picasa. grab as many as you want.
~ # ~</description></item><item><title>the elections</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-07-13-the-elections/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-07-13-the-elections/</guid><description>during the first month i was in africa i did not want to leave. i was trolling the internet trying to figure out a way that i could stay in west africa. i looked for jobs in salone, liberia, guinea, ghana, wherever, just to stay there. i didn’t care if they paid or not, i didn’t care if they were prestigious or not. as time grew on and i became more and more embroiled in the work i was doing and more and more frustrated with west africa my desires waned.</description></item><item><title>updates</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-06-27-updates/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-06-27-updates/</guid><description>have added little stories and captions to the pictures which were priorly unannotated in the Salone photo album, the Liberia photo album and the Upcountry photo album.
so far holland is much less photogenic and i’ve taken few pictures. but maybe soon, i’ll quit working long enough to take some, and our holiday to georgia/azerbiajan is fast approaching. also added maps of Salone/Liberia so that you can follow along with the adventures.</description></item><item><title>how to say good bye in krio</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-06-07-how-to-say-good-bye-in-krio/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-06-07-how-to-say-good-bye-in-krio/</guid><description>this afternoon i fly out of salone and have no plans to return any time in the next two years. last night i finished packing in my idiosyncratic, logical-but-only-to-me, methodical way. then i put on some nice music and stood on my balcony watching my last salone sunset. like so many others it was underwhelming. the sun faded into clouds, but if you looked to the east the nice purples developed and if you looked to the west, above the clouds, you could see the pinks and oranges.</description></item><item><title>Two Little Stories</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-05-29-two-little-stories/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-05-29-two-little-stories/</guid><description>Have been saving two little stories. Not sure why I have been saving them, but I have. My time is starting to wind down here now and I feel compelled to clean some things up. Not yet sure when I’m going to leave Salone, but it is going to be soon. I think that the absolute latest I will be here will be the 20th, which is only three weeks and two weekends from now.</description></item><item><title>too much&amp;#8230;.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-05-21-too-much/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-05-21-too-much/</guid><description>finally! i got up country. it was beautiful, amazing, heart-breaking, remarkable, human, surprising and wonderful. my friends had been planning for all week to go upcountry, but seeing that it was highlands next to last weekend here and it was looking like we would be able to spend a good deal of time together that was more important to me. i thought i could figure out a way to get upcountry later, even though the rains are coming (btw i know now what the phrase feels like…at least a little bit).</description></item><item><title>my little jazz place</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-04-29-my-little-jazz-place/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-04-29-my-little-jazz-place/</guid><description>so for much of my life i have had this fantasy that i would eventually find a jazz club that would replace in my mind the absence of me not being alive in the late 50′s and early 60′s and being black and living in NYC and therefore unable to stoll down 52d street and hear coltrane and others jamming in real-time and only for themselves. although i’ve been all over the states, i have yet to find anything that feels/is truly authentic.</description></item><item><title>Isle de HOLY Crap</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-04-24-isle-de-holy-crap/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-04-24-isle-de-holy-crap/</guid><description>[![Imgp1749][2]][2] So there were two themes that I wanted to clean-up from the Senegal trip. The first is this little artist community that exists on Isle de Goree a thirty minute ferry ride from Dakaar. The second will come later.
[]: http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/04/29/imgp1749.jpg
Isle de Goree has, at various times, been a defensive position protecting the bay where the port of Dakaar is and/or a slave exporting island. Most times the slave traders would take slaves to islands off the coast of West Africa and then barter with the transportation people there on the island.</description></item><item><title>senegalese music</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-04-06-senegalese-music/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-04-06-senegalese-music/</guid><description>i leave for senegal in just a bit on Sloc, some airline that has a less stellar safety record…apparently. although from what I’ve heard they aren’t as bad as others in west africa, so maybe i’ll be ok. plus they play backstreet boys loud and on the speakers so everyone is able to enjoy the festivities. senegal, from what i can tell, is a mecca for tourists who desire adventure, good music, good food, maybe a pick-pocketing here and there, cafes, bookstores and the beach.</description></item><item><title>still alive</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-03-28-still-alive/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-03-28-still-alive/</guid><description>sorry. not dead, just lost. no days off, but at least the work is interesting. we file april 4th, so i will have a life again after that. looking forward to my trip to senegal and the gambia the 6th through the 15th. right now there is a heated euro politico debate in my office between a right wing german-swiss and a left wing french-swiss. it’s awesome!
check this out. it is kind of a postscript to the movie: Diamonds Move From Blood to Sweat and Tears.</description></item><item><title>i little trip to the mall</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-03-06-i-little-trip-to-the-mall/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-03-06-i-little-trip-to-the-mall/</guid><description>i hate malls. i really really hate everything about them. i hate how large they are. i hate that massive retention ponds must be created to pool the flow of water that is not allowed to seep into the ground properly over a dissipated region, but is instead pooled in isolated areas. the outsourcing of the environmental degredation annoys me. i hate how they all are the same, one or two paradigms determine the layout.</description></item><item><title>leadership challenges</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-02-28-leadership-challenges/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-02-28-leadership-challenges/</guid><description>This post is long overdue. But forgive me, it took a while for me to have a chance to pull the pictures off my phone. Let me introduce you to the people that have a chance, everyday, to steal my shit and for some reason do not. When I was in the Marine Corps, we had a saying that there were no bad Marines, simply bad leaders. It is was a bit self-deprecating of Marine officers to take all the blame for psychotic Marines and their actions, but it is one of the many things that make the USMC such a great organization.</description></item><item><title>Pictures</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-02-28-pictures/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-02-28-pictures/</guid><description>Added more picts today to the album.</description></item><item><title>Beaches &amp;amp; Hospitals</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-02-19-beaches-hospitals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-02-19-beaches-hospitals/</guid><description>[ ![Imgp1261_edited1][2]][2] This series of pictures is from the beach this weekend. For a long time I have considered the statement: it has the best beaches in the world, or at least in Africa
. I would hedge for a couple of reasons. The first is that, of course, I’m not stranger to beaches. Something would be hard-pressed to pass up the beach on the Navy Base in Key West</description></item><item><title>Picts</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-02-15-picts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-02-15-picts/</guid><description>Finally had the bandwidth to upload the rest of the chimp picts.
Will have more tomorrow. Have to run, a full night of family dinner, Rocky 6 and Reggae night.
~ # ~</description></item><item><title>keeping life wild</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-02-12-keeping-life-wild/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-02-12-keeping-life-wild/</guid><description>[![100207_1802][2]][2]so this weekend we went to the chimpanzee reserve. when i was first told about this place i thought it was like a natural park that you could walk through and maybe you would see chimpanzees. then we were told about this one chimpanzee who was the alpha male of the lot who ‘broke out’ and killed one tourist and pulled the arms off of another (who subsequently bled to death).</description></item><item><title>o the banality of it all!</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-02-08-o-the-banality-of-it-all/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-02-08-o-the-banality-of-it-all/</guid><description>having problems posting these picts, wait for it…..OK. getting there.
[![Imgp1156_1_1][2]][2]
[]: http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/imgp1156_1_1.jpg
i have been asked to post some pictures of where i live. consider that done. we have four (total) flatmates that live in an old, square house that looks out over the ocean. i have shown you the views from my personal balcony before. this first picture is of the living room. the furniture is old, and not really that comfortable, but it looks quite nice i guess.</description></item><item><title>i&amp;#8217;m tired&amp;#8230;now its time to work.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-02-06-im-tired-now-its-time-to-work/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-02-06-im-tired-now-its-time-to-work/</guid><description>[![030207_1246][2]][2]
[]: http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/photos/uncategorized/030207_1246.jpg
hello.
this weekend was pretty amazingly long. in a good way i guess. except for i had a lot of work that could have been done, but i never got around to it. it is mitigated by the fact that none of it was actually due this weekend, i just wanted to get started on it. that can happen later i guess.
the weekend basically began on wednesday when we hosted our own welcome aboard party and some friends came over for american game night.</description></item><item><title>the grapefruits have more seeds.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-02-02-the-grapefruits-have-more-seeds/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-02-02-the-grapefruits-have-more-seeds/</guid><description>[![N557965146_50950_9850][2]][2] on sunday afternoon/evening there was a marching band parade and people just went into this compound (the wall is the background of the picture). they paraded to a compound. this picture doesn’t do it justice b/c there were TONS of people. later we found out that it was a thanksgiving parade. each local school has their own thanksgiving holiday where they march to a church. not sure about the significance of it all, but it was funny nonetheless.</description></item><item><title>And the soapboxing begins&amp;#8230;</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-01-30-and-the-soapboxing-begins/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-01-30-and-the-soapboxing-begins/</guid><description>[![Image001][2]][2]
This is the view from my private balcony along one axis.
[![Image003][3]][3]
And from another axis.
This city so far has been exactly what I had expected. It is fulfilling the picture I had in created over the six months or so of anticipation. People who have been here longer than I tend to ask the obvious question to fill the small talk obligation. “So how do you like Freetown.</description></item><item><title>First of Some</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-01-23-first-of-some/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-01-23-first-of-some/</guid><description>Things have been a bit chaotic with getting settled and then having that paper and another project for school hanging over my head. I finished the paper yesterday and the project just now, so I feel very refreshed. Now I can focus fully on the work here and then having fun. The beaches are delightful, apparently, and I’m excited to visit them soon.
Freetown is an amazing place and I am incredibly happy to be here.</description></item></channel></rss>