<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/</link><description>A Site About Resilience and Authoritarianism</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</managingEditor><webMaster>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</webMaster><copyright>All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/africa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Perspectives on Africa -&amp;gt; Its all about the lens</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-25-perspectives-africa-lens/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-25-perspectives-africa-lens/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.how-matters.org/about/">&lt;img src="http://www.how-matters.org/about/" alt="Facial Scarification in Africa in the early 1940s via gbaku @ flickr">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you look at this picture what do you see?  I see a man who is satisfied with his situation.  Sure there are the tribal markings, the blanket over the shoulder, the bleakness of the background and the stuff on the back of the man’s neck.  But what really jumps out, to me at least, is the satisfied look that his eyes and his mouth convey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Two development pundit bloggers have discussed recently the cultural meme which the photos that are chosen to accompany NGO marketing campaigns, news articles on Africa, etc. convey. &lt;a href="http://www.how-matters.org/about/"> Jennifer Lentfer&lt;/a> who runs &lt;a href="http://www.how-matters.org/">how-matters.org&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://glennagordon.com/">Glenna Gordon&lt;/a> who runs &lt;a href="http://www.scarlettlion.com/">ScarlettLion.com&lt;/a>, among other sites, &lt;a href="http://www.how-matters.org/2010/10/24/pity-pictures-and-poverty/">both&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://www.scarlettlion.com/2010/10/just-how-stereotypical-are-images-of-africa.html">posted&lt;/a> on this issue yesterday.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Am not sure exactly, but seems that the beginning of the conversation was Jennifer finding &lt;a href="http://waterwellness.ca/2010/04/28/perspectives-of-poverty/">this&lt;/a> posting from &lt;a href="http://waterwellness.ca/about/">Duncan McNicholl&lt;/a>.  The premise of Duncan’s posting is that the same subject arranged in two different modes conveys two very different emotional responses.  To take it a step further, the argument goes that the types of images which are chosen to be displayed in NGO marketing items, donor reports, media reports, etc. reflect both the world’s pre-conceived image of Africa &lt;em>as well as&lt;/em> furthering the intention of the person or organization which is using the image.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course, this makes sense.  Generally most people would prefer to vindicate held opinions rather than challenge them.  But challenging opinions is the only way to change the cultural lens and changing the cultural lens is one of the post powerful enabling mechanisms for solidifying deep changes within societies.  Indeed, the NY Times ran a great &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/10/24/magazine/24FOB-Footbinding-t.html?_r=2&amp;amp;partner=rss&amp;amp;emc=rss&amp;amp;pagewanted=all">article&lt;/a> in their weekend magazine about this topic yesterday.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The thing is this (he says as he puts on his lawyer hat) it takes a long time to change the perspectives of people.  It takes words, images, experience, and most of all repetition.  It takes emotional arguments, data-based arguments, and logical arguments.   And it is slow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Civil rights, suffrage, abolition, etc. did not come about just because someone in a position of authority said, “yeah this is how it is going to happen.”  They happened because first people worked hard to show the problems with the current cultural lens.  This happened through broad-based approaches (which obviously varied considering the different times and persons involved).  After the cultural lens was changed sufficiently, then legal and political mechanisms were triggered which could provide some accountability around the new cultural norm which was developing.  Those legal and political mechanisms have to be triggered *after *there is sufficiency in the base of people who will believe that what you are arguing for makes sense despite the history and the cultural norms of the moment.  Those legal and political mechanisms &lt;em>have&lt;/em> to be triggered (usually) in order to bring the “rest” into compliance with the cultural norm; in other words, to provide accountability.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But what in the world does that have to do with pictures in shiny brochures?  First, the analogy very much falls apart when probed in depth, so don’t do that.   I bring it up mainly to show that cultural change takes time and effort along many different tracks.  It seems to me that we’re at the beginning of this process with respect to the “world’s” opinion of “Africa.”  Even for development workers and bloggers I still see all too frequently a headline which says, essentially, “wow there’s some good news from Africa and here is what it is.”  It is of lesser import to me the surprise which is consonant in the headlines.  What is of greater import is that the headlines are running.  They are running more and more, at least across my twitter and rss feeds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This base hopefully will in due course enable the triggering of some powerful accountability mechanisms.  Although the accountability mechanisms which can solidify the march towards progress which so many in the cheetah generation deserve and crave will not be as strong as a declaration as (say) an amendment to the US Constitution would be, they will be there.  And their presence will help to change the assumptions of the cultural laggards.  Perhaps more importantly, they will allow the next generation of elites within many countries of Africa to make the difficult decisions and to take the difficult steps which will reduce the income gaps and bring the middle class further along.  And after that, things will take care of themselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is great stuff happening throughout Africa all the time.  People are creating beautiful images, beautiful paintings, and beautiful narratives.  It is fantastic to see, and I appreciate that people are pointing these out.  As more and more people hop onto the train the momentum will grow, not slow.  Some recent examples:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>African Digital Art’s Weekly Inspiration Postings: &lt;a href="http://www.africandigitalart.com/category/african-weekly-inspiration/">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>NYTimes Lens Blog on Dakar: &lt;a href="http://lens.blogs.nytimes.com/2010/10/07/senegals-changing-urban-landscape/">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Peter DiCampo’s Life without Lights series: &lt;a href="http://www.peterdicampo.com/#/life-without-lights/nightly-life/NIGHTLY_LIFE-1">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Sure things are still screwed up in many many ways.  But what is important to me about the meme which is developing is that the baseline assumptions about what the “current state of Africa” is moving.  This will create/has created a base of support among many.  At this point it seems to be coming mainly from development people and Africans themselves who are increasingly using the megaphone of the internet to get their message across.  But it has to begin somewhere.  From this base, a larger base will grow and the meme will extend to laggards within organizations and to laggard organizations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course it will be a long time before the &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/10/24/magazine/24sirleaf-t.html?ref=ellen_johnson_sirleaf">profile&lt;/a> of a ground-breaking woman will not begin with the backdrop of devastation, conflict, and decay.  It will be a long time until even those of us that live here in Africa change our assumptions to reflect the progress which is all around us.  And yet, it is happening.  Slowly but surely, like a nomad moving to a new grazing area, the collective cultural lens is shifting.  For me, for now, that is enough.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PS – Some pictures we’ve taken recently of Hargeisa can be found below. [flickr-gallery mode=&amp;quot;photoset&amp;rdquo; photoset=&amp;quot;72157625029540307&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I&amp;#8217;m Supposed to Write on Water, but I Don&amp;#8217;t Have Any&amp;#8230;</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-15-supposed-write-water-any/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-15-supposed-write-water-any/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today the Interweb Gods have deemed is World Blog about water day.  Or likely more accurately, the brilliant &lt;a href="http://blogactionday.change.org/">change.org&lt;/a> marketers have deemed today as world blog about water:Day.  I haven’t read every post I have seen come across my various Twitter wires, but the ones I’ve read talk about the need for us to have water.  Seems pretty self-evident and so the rhetoric can turn into a polemic rather quickly.  I thought about writing a love post to water, but then I realized that I’m annoyed at water.  We fell out with each other a couple of weeks ago, which by the way was the last time water came through my pipes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The water system in Hargeisa is over stretched, under maintained, now badly managed network, under funded cluster of an organization.  It makes money so the government doesn’t want to privatize it.  And that is likely the right move considering the power system is privatized and is a mess.  It is all the rage to claim that the private sector is going to save Africa, and I while I believe that I’m not a complete free marketer.  The private sector can be just as lazy and dumb as a public sector can be.  The presence of competition does not necessitate innovation and good economic behavior in and of itself.  But that is a different story and before I go down that road, let me tell you about my pipe problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The pipes that supply Hargeisa were buried about an 1 deep all willy nilly throughout the place.  Whenever you go off of the main roads it is inevitable that you’ll have to drive over one.  That isn’t a structural economic problem.  That has little to do with Ministerial efficiency or World Bank proclamations.  It is just stupid and lazy workmanship.  It doesn’t have anything to do with a depressed education system or beleaguered healthcare system.  it is just stupid and lazy workmanship.  Nothing more, nothing less.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And because these pipes were not buried deep enough, and because I live near a bus station, the pipes that come to my house often are broken by buses running over them.  And then we have to pay for a plumber to come fix them.  The Water Agency this time even refused to drive a plumber up here even after we agreed to pay for the plumber.  And then after we brought the plumber up here to our sector of Hargeisa, the guy wanted $20, TWENTY DOLLARS, to do the fifteen minutes of work it would require to cut a new pipe, tap it, and tighten it onto the new pipe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I told the guy to f-off.  He laughed, I rolled my eyes, he said ten, I agreed.  And then he fixed the pipe.  But since that time no water has come through the pipes.  I don’t think they’re broken as we can usually tell.  In the morning when we drive to work if the water has come and the pipe is broken it just pools uselessly in the muck at the main intersection of the bus station.  In a desert country with small water resources no one seems to give an F about this water just sitting there.  But that hasn’t happened in the past week or ten days since we paid the plumber to fix the water.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why is that the case?  Because I live near a hotel.  You know the kind, one of the few places in town known to cater to expats.  They are all in one shape or form the same.  But the guy who owns the hotel pays the guy who controls the water in our sector a little bit more each month and so the water guy reroutes almost all of the water to the hotel.  The old Hargeisa water manager was a friend of ours and when we told him our hypothesis in this regard he investigated, found it to be true, fought tooth and nail (I heard directly many of the conversations between him and the sector manager who is below him) for us, and still was only moderately successful in getting us water.  Since he was sacked for unknown reasons which had nothing to do with his competence but basically boiled down to the other dude supported the government than won the recent election and had to be rewarded somehow, since that time we have gotten water through the pipes on only a couple of occasions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So water and I have seemingly broken up.  And that is not cool with me.  It isn’t cool in a way that  has nothing to do with what any policymaker or bureaucrat or large NGO marketing department wants me to think.  It isn’t cool and it has nothing to do with funding levels (throwing more money at the sector isn’t going to get the pipes buried deeper, repaired faster, or micro-managed more equitably), bold statements, or glossy web sites.  It isn’t cool and much of it comes down to stupidity and laziness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Excuse me, I gotta run, the dude that drives the donkey cart with the ex-oil drum on the back is here to deliver my water.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chinese Powered Self-Sufficiency in Africa</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-05-26-chinese-powered-self-sufficiency-africa/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-05-26-chinese-powered-self-sufficiency-africa/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://blog.foreignpolicy.com/posts/2010/05/25/liberias_ellen_johnson_sirleaf">&lt;img src="http://blog.foreignpolicy.com/posts/2010/05/25/liberias_ellen_johnson_sirleaf" alt="Johnson-Sirleaf &amp; Clinton via @FP_Magazine">&lt;/a>
Ellen Johnson-Sirleaf &amp;amp; Hillary Clinton via @FP_Magazine&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Madam President Ellen Johnson-Sirleaf the current President of Liberia did a remarkable thing yesterday.  She &lt;a href="http://blog.foreignpolicy.com/posts/2010/05/25/liberias_ellen_johnson_sirleaf">told &lt;/a>the world that in ten years Liberia would be self-sufficient and able to stand on its own feet with only further investment &lt;em>and no aid&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In ten years, Liberia will have been out of its civil war for about fifteen or sixteen depending on how one classifies the end.  And if Liberia were to achieve it, they would have accomplished something remarkable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To provide some context Rwanda is now about sixteen years after their conflict.  They have had a President that in many ways can be analogized to Johnson-Sirleaf.  Kagame is pro-business, pro-US, and takes a rational approach to China.  And Rwanda is by all metrics doing very well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But they are not, yet, self-sufficient.  Liberia has distinct advantages that Rwanda does not.  More resources and sea-access are the main advantages.  So it may not be completely accurate to compare the two.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I especially appreciate her stance on China.  Many people in the development world wring their hands about China’s involvement in Africa.  This always comes across to me as protectionism of our fiefdoms.  There is &lt;em>no way that China can teach Africa anything, all they will do is steal their resources&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let us not forget that Western companies have been stealing Africa’s resources for years.  I know plenty of Africans who are happy about the way that China interacts with their country.  They feel that the Chinese treat them more equally and less antagonistically than most donor agencies and iNGOs (especially governance iNGOs).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ellen really seems to pinpoint the African meme towards China with this quote:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“China’s fast,” she explained. “They know what they want and they do it quickly.” Building schools, building roads, signing contracts, and offering loans — all of it can be done in weeks or months, not years as some donors and Western investors might take. In short, “China’s flexible.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And this speed is critical.  Opportunities for reform or development often open and close before Western donors can get an RFP published, much less funded, contracted, distributed, and the agency beginning to reform or development agenda.  China is much quicker, and while Westerners may question their motives, at least their motives are clear to everyone: them and their partners.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In summary, this clarity makes it easier for them to operate.  I doubt it is frequent that Chinese in Africa are accused of being spies.  Meanwhile, I have been accused of being a spy nearly every day for two years – something that has deeply affected the receptivity to my work and a story for another day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Understanding War [in Mogadishu]</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-04-17-understanding-war-in-mogadishu/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-04-17-understanding-war-in-mogadishu/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.wfp.org/content/somalia-pirates-target-food-pushing-prices">&lt;img src="http://www.wfp.org/content/somalia-pirates-target-food-pushing-prices" alt="">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This week the World Food Program (WFP) shoved out a &lt;a href="http://www.wfp.org/content/somalia-pirates-target-food-pushing-prices">press release&lt;/a> about how piracy was raising food prices in South-Central Somalia.  At first glance, most people who would read such a report will likely think, oh the poor people in Mogadishu.  Of course, I share their sentiments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, there is a deeper issue at work here.  One that I’m not sure many people realize.  The conclusion (because I’m a lawyer and we put these things up front) is that this rise in cost of business may have drastically good effects for the conflict in the South.  Here’s how I get there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Those brains who study war break themselves into two-sides of the same coin (since they are academics largely they have to classify and camp-ify themselves in order to create non-existent academic conflict to drive conscriptions to their own camp to drive their own popularity to drive their tenure track – but that is a story for a different day).  I’m too lazy to look up what the classifications of the two sides are, but generally one camp focuses on the structural conditions for conflict to begin (guns, poverty, etc.) and another camp focuses on the social conditions for conflict to begin (ethnic diversity, natural resources, etc.).  Or something like that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These camps have outlined pretty logical paths for those who seek to mitigate, manage, or militate conflict to follow.  If conflict A is characterized as an X conflict than follow path Z to recovery.  Fair enough, and it has worked in several instances.  In Liberia (prototypical charasmatic leader led conflict), once Charles Taylor left then the conflict subsided almost instantaneously.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The difficulty for conflict academics and practitioners (and no I didn’t mistype that) when it comes to Somalia is that every category for conflict can be found.  Not only can every one be found, but the primacy of each driver of conflict into primary, secondary, tertiary, etc.  driver of the conflict will depend on the time and location in which one analyzes the conflict.  The drivers are like a kaleidoscope which is constantly fluctuating over time in each location.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is a post-modern hell for people who study these things – which answers my own question about the lack of detailed academic research on Somalia (that and the difficulty in getting correct information).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After living here for two years and studying and thinking through the conflict at length (because there is little else to do during a Somalia evening), and despite the kaleidoscopic nature of the conflict, a few themes can be extracted.  The first of which is that in the far south around the major rivers the conflict is really and truly about natural resources and land.  Which is why my organization has put in to do a project focused on conflict mitigation of natural resources driven low-level conflicts throughout Somalia – but particularly in that region.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The other major theme, and how this connects with the WFP report, is that the business community in Mogadishu is quite happy with the anarchical situation.  Let me explain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If Somalis were Americans a large percentage of them would be mid-nineties salesmen.  The ones that would drive the 2.0 Trans Am, sport their cell phones in belt holsters, and have lunch meetings at Hooters.  They are quite money focused (certainly more than many from West Africa), and this has some good consequences.  Here in the north the private sector is very vibrant and is driving much of the development; there remains a good environment for doing business – certainly better than the neighbors in the region.  However, the focus on money can make many a bit myopic as they are always chasing pennies and don’t see the dollars.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have met businessmen from the south who laugh at their colleagues here in the north who &lt;em>only&lt;/em> make 67% profit (I’m referencing the telecom sector here) as opposed to in the south where they make double that. There are tons of instances in the history of the southern conflict where it has been oscillating towards some resolution but the business community ensures that instability returns quickly.  They are convinced that the anarchy allows them to live like kings and do whatever they want – in their minds make more money.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yet from my point of view they are looking at the wrong metric.  I think they should be looking at the total amount of profit.  Sure they can make a higher percentage in Mogadishu than the guys can here in H-town, but the pot is bigger here so in the end they make more money.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is where the dissonance approaches resonance frequency for me.  The  rhetoric has failed to show these men that peace will inevitably make them richer.  Although their profit margins will fall, their total  revenue will rise at a faster rate and they will end up with more money in their pockets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Simple talking has failed to convince them of such a result, so here is where I’m optimistic about the WFP report.  If the pirates can (ironically) be the ones that raise the costs for the large importers then the effects of that rise in the cost of business will ripple throughout and maybe the arguments for resolution of the conflict will gain more weight.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Or maybe the businessmen will simply launch their own navies as they already have their own armies. I don’t know, but I remain optimistic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Franchising in Africa: An Annotated Reading</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-24-franchising-in-africa-an-annotated-reading/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-24-franchising-in-africa-an-annotated-reading/</guid><description>&lt;p>This week's annotated reading is from Dalberg (who I had not heard of before) and it deals with the lack of McDonalds around Africa.  Original article &lt;a href="http://bit.ly/dtXImV">here &lt;/a>(pdf), my thoughts below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![2010_02_24_12_40_30_Page_01][3]][3]&lt;br>
[![2010_02_24_12_40_30_Page_02][4]][4]&lt;br>
[![2010_02_24_12_40_30_Page_03][5]][5]&lt;br>
[![2010_02_24_12_40_30_Page_04][6]][6]&lt;br>
[![2010_02_24_12_40_30_Page_05][7]][7]&lt;br>
[![2010_02_24_12_40_30_Page_06][8]][8]&lt;br>
[![2010_02_24_12_40_30_Page_07][9]][9]&lt;br>
[![2010_02_24_12_40_30_Page_08][10]][10]&lt;br>
[![2010_02_24_12_40_30_Page_09][11]][11]&lt;br>
[![2010_02_24_12_40_30_Page_10][12]][12]&lt;br>
[![2010_02_24_12_40_30_Page_11][13]][13]&lt;br>
[![2010_02_24_12_40_30_Page_12][14]][14]&lt;br>
[![2010_02_24_12_40_30_Page_13][15]][15]&lt;br>
~ # ~&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e201310f33a239970c-pi">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e201310f33a239970c-pi&lt;/a>
[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e201310f33a450970c-pi">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e201310f33a450970c-pi&lt;/a>
[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e20120a8ccbc9f970b-pi">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e20120a8ccbc9f970b-pi&lt;/a>
[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e201310f33a688970c-pi">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e201310f33a688970c-pi&lt;/a>
[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e201310f33a6dd970c-pi">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e201310f33a6dd970c-pi&lt;/a>
[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e201310f33a76c970c-pi">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e201310f33a76c970c-pi&lt;/a>
[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e201310f33eb17970c-pi">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e201310f33eb17970c-pi&lt;/a>
[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e20120a8cd05d4970b-pi">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e20120a8cd05d4970b-pi&lt;/a>
[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e20120a8cd0703970b-pi">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e20120a8cd0703970b-pi&lt;/a>
[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e201310f33edca970c-pi">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e201310f33edca970c-pi&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gates goes to TED and Few Listen</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-16-gates-goes-to-ted-and-few-listen/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-16-gates-goes-to-ted-and-few-listen/</guid><description>&lt;p>I didn't hear about this until after the fact.  Indeed quite after the fact.  I was reading tweets about how Gates was blowing people's minds at cocktail parties leading up to his big speech about climate change at TED this year.  But then I forgot about them until reading these two articles from &lt;a href="http://www.worldchanging.org">Worldchanging&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/worldchanging_fulltext/~3/raJq_tNDaA0/010976.html">The first&lt;/a> to be published was from &lt;a href="http://twit.com/alexsteffen">Alex Steffen&lt;/a>.  Money Quotes:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Gates spoke about his commitment to using his massive philanthropic resources&lt;br>
(the Gates Foundation is the world's largest) to make life better for people&lt;br>
through public health and poverty alleviation (&amp;ldquo;vaccines and seeds&amp;rdquo; as he put&lt;br>
it). Then he said something he's never said before: that is it &lt;em>because&lt;/em>&lt;br>
he's committed to improving life for the world's vulnerable people that he now&lt;br>
believes that climate change is the most important challenge on the planet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even more importantly, he acknowledged the only sensible goal, when it comes&lt;br>
to climate emissions, is to eliminate them: we should be aiming for a&lt;br>
civilization that produces no net emissions, and we should be aiming to live in&lt;br>
that civilization here in the developed world by 2050. . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To do that, we need an &amp;ldquo;energy miracle.&amp;rdquo; We need energy solutions that don't&lt;br>
yet exist, released through a global push for clean energy innovation. That, in&lt;br>
turn, demands that a generation of entrepreneurs push forward new ideas for&lt;br>
renewable energy, unleashing &amp;ldquo;1,000 promising ideas.&amp;rdquo; He described one of his&lt;br>
own investments, but went on to note that we need hundreds of other ambitious&lt;br>
companies as well, and he plans to put his own efforts into this arena.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why is this important? The news stories focused largely on the clean energy&lt;br>
aspect of the speech, and certainly the world's most successful businessman&lt;br>
announcing that clean energy is the next frontier is a big headline. However, I&lt;br>
think though that the real breakthrough was not Gates&amp;rsquo; answer to the problem,&lt;br>
but his definition of success: zero.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bright green advocates understand that we need &lt;a href="http://www.worldchanging.com/archives/010070.html">prosperity without&lt;br>
planetary impact&lt;/a>. In many of the circles I run in, this is an&lt;br>
uncontroversial idea, and, indeed, the conversation has moved on, to discussing&lt;br>
how we decouple better lives from &lt;a href="http://www.worldchanging.com/archives/006650.html">ecological&lt;br>
footprints&lt;/a> (or even go beyond, and build a society that &lt;a href="http://www.worldchanging.com/archives/004509.html">restores the ecosystems&lt;br>
on which it depends&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To say, however, that the standard of zero impact is not widely understood&lt;br>
and endorsed would be a whopping understatement. Most people rarely see the&lt;br>
things they do, buy and use as directly part of the living systems of the&lt;br>
planet. Few people who do think of their connection to nature have ever&lt;br>
conceived their lives designed to have no impact at all. For most people, a ten&lt;br>
percent or twenty percent improvement sounds like a big deal — in large part&lt;br>
because the improvements they're most familiar with involve giving things up.&lt;br>
When they do encounter it, the idea of &amp;ldquo;zero&amp;rdquo; looms like a giant wall of&lt;br>
deprivation in front of them. The idea that zero might not be the end of the&lt;br>
good life, but in fact the beginning of a much better way of life, is simply&lt;br>
inconceivable to the vast, vast majority of them. When we talk zero, we sound&lt;br>
crazy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But when Bill Gates talks zero, he sounds visionary. Gates, whatever else he&lt;br>
did Friday, just made the most important idea on the planet mainstream credible.&lt;br>
That's a big, big deal.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This was all well and good and at this point in the article I was thinking, yeah, so what.  None of this is new and we have litigated it and people with my belief system about the world seem to be largely losing at every corner (e.g., see Obama @ Copenhagen).  At the end of the article Steffen wrote something that truly resonated with me and largely fits squarely within my own unique world-view.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The energy intensity of any given form of prosperity can, I believe, be improved&lt;br>
quite a bit; but the idea that E can be dramatically improved without improving&lt;br>
the kind of prosperity we're attempting to provide is the very definition of&lt;br>
what I call &lt;a href="http://www.worldchanging.com/archives/010947.html">The&lt;br>
Swap&lt;/a>. The Swap doesn't work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And we don't need it to. The idea that contemporary suburban American&lt;br>
lifestyles (the kind of prosperity most people around the world aspire to,&lt;br>
thanks to Hollywood and advertising), the idea that McMansions, SUVs and fast&lt;br>
food chicken wraps somehow represent the best form of prosperity we could&lt;br>
possibly invent is, of course, obviously ludicrous.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We can reinvent what prosperity means and how it works, and, in the process&lt;br>
both reduce the ecological demands of that prosperity and improve the quality of&lt;br>
our lives. In most cases, this is a smarter approach than simply improving&lt;br>
efficiency.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The answer to the problem of cars and automotive emissions, for instance, &lt;a href="http://www.worldchanging.com/archives/007800.html">isn't designing a&lt;br>
better car, it's designing a better city&lt;/a>. The answer to the problem of&lt;br>
overconsumption isn't recycling cans or green shopping, it's changing our&lt;br>
relationship to stuff, so that everything we use and live with is designed for&lt;br>
&lt;a href="http://www.worldchanging.com/archives/008176.html">zero waste&lt;/a>, and&lt;br>
either meant to last (&amp;ldquo;heirloom design&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;durability&amp;rdquo;) or to be shared&lt;br>
(&amp;ldquo;product service systems&amp;rdquo;) or both. The best living we've ever had is waiting&lt;br>
beyond zero. What looks like a wall to many people from this side of zero, looks&lt;br>
to like a trellis from the other side, a foundation on which &lt;a href="http://www.worldchanging.com/archives/006915.html">new thinking&lt;/a> can&lt;br>
flourish.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cities are the tools we need for reinventing prosperity. &lt;a href="http://www.worldchanging.com/archives/010941.html">We can build&lt;br>
zero-impact cities&lt;/a>, and we need to. Any answer to the problem of climate&lt;br>
change needs to be as focused on reinventing the future as powering it.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This, I must say, is one of the biggest things I've learned while living in Africa.  Here I understand *exactly *where my water comes from.  I've gone to see the system of wells and the water pipes which run them the 30 km or so here to H'town.  I've seen the power generation plants for the city and talked with their engineers.  I know exactly where my food and the things I see in the market come from (all I had to do was walk around lower Dubai for 20 minutes).  I know exactly where my trash ends up (burned or lying outside my gate in a pile. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Africa has taught me in a way that being Green in America never could, that all the crap that is around.  That crap comes from somewhere and it goes somewhere.  Sure, I've seen huge dumps in America as I've driven around.  But those don't have anywhere near the impact on my personal consumption as does seeing a burnt can of probably beans that I ate twelve months ago sitting in a pile outside my compound which I have to drive past every day.  That did, in fact, make a huge impact on my personal consumption.  Not necessarily driving me to deprivation, but driving me to seek more authenticity in my actions – grow your own vegetables, build things for yourself. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>I see the value in the flaws of the things around me which I've built and despite their flaws (or maybe because of them) I value these things more.  Sure, maybe my tomatoes are small, but I grew them in a way that not only helped out the longevity of the soil they were grown in but also in a way which positively affected those within my community.  For every one tomato I eat, my staff eat ten or twenty.  Instead of buying so much meat and rice they have all expanded their diets due to the ease and proximity of our garden.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another massive thing which Africa has taught me is that really to change behavior you have to change the incentive structure.  And this is where I think Steffen gets it correct.  Because for whatever reason of utility America and by extension the world value suburbia, McMansions and whatever else he said.  When I was small I remember those being my metrics for success.  When I was in college I remember telling people that those were the types of things that I wanted. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yet, I have realized that now I don't necessarily want those things.  What I do want is authenticity and to be in harmony with the community and ecosystem around me.  The one thing I will say, and the biggest problem I have with suburbia is this notion of authenticity.  It just predominately lacks soul, &lt;em>and a bit of stank&lt;/em>.  &lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I've realized how I changed my own behavior I have tried my best to extend that into my day job by always trying to change the behavior patterns of politicians by helping them to realign their own incentive structures.  More on that for another day.  Suffice it to say for now, but I am not shy about stating that fact.  At its core governance work in the developing world boils down to an intellectual conflict between the way the developed world thinks about its citizens and how the developing world thinks about its citizens.  I'm speaking broadly here and of course there are contrarian anecdotes, but in any event that is how I see things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/worldchanging_fulltext/~3/lmi5w0ft-Qc/010978.html">second article&lt;/a> was more mainstream green thinking.  I didn't see to much in it that resonated with me personally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Grow &amp;#8211; Venture Capital 2.0</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-16-grow-venture-capital-2-0/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-16-grow-venture-capital-2-0/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Everyone Funding Startups!!! &lt;a href="http://www.growvc.com/main/index.html">Grow VC&lt;/a>&lt;br>
is the first global crowdfunding tool for web and mobile startups.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This is a fantastic idea, which compliments so nicely with Kiva.  My only critique is that it is very tech focused.  Although it makes a&lt;br>
logical entry point for oversight reasons (primarily), I hope that they&lt;br>
will open it up to other sectors.  Everyday I meet business people&lt;br>
here in Africa with fantastic ideas.  The capital flight from Africa has&lt;br>
created a situation where they cannot get access to mid-level funding. &lt;br>
Grow VC fills a very important gap in the finance world and I wish&lt;br>
them nothing but success.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the notion of capital flight, this is a major problem.  I heard a&lt;br>
story recently about a high-level East African politician who had&lt;br>
acquired a large sum of money but was having trouble getting the French&lt;br>
banks to accept it.  Number one comment: good for the French banks.  But&lt;br>
number two: if the African elites continue to put their money in developed&lt;br>
world banks, their SMEs are going to continue to lack access to&lt;br>
capital.  If they could decide to bring some of that money back and then&lt;br>
the banks in their own countries could leverage that money via lending&lt;br>
to SMEs Africa would develop a lot faster.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Honestly, development has a place but all the weeping for the world&lt;br>
is tiring.  Let us stop whining and act.  Grow VC has done just that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What it feels like to be invaded</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-09-what-it-feels-like-to-be-invaded/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-09-what-it-feels-like-to-be-invaded/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://http://www.irishtimes.com/newspaper/world/2009/1204/1224260043076.html">&lt;img src="http://http://www.irishtimes.com/newspaper/world/2009/1204/1224260043076.html" alt="Photograph: Farah Abdi Warsameh/AP">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://www.irishtimes.com/newspaper/world/2009/1204/1224260043076.html">http://www.irishtimes.com/newspaper/world/2009/1204/1224260043076.html&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last December a bomb exploded in Mogadishu.  Actually, it was the 4th of December. I didn’t remember the date until I looked it up just &lt;a href="http://http://www.irishtimes.com/newspaper/world/2009/1204/1224260043076.html">now&lt;/a>.  Pictures like the one at the left pretty much fit most people’s world view of Somalia.  Yet, I live here and I have a completely different view of the situation. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>I left my house on the day in question about about 2 or so in the afternoon.   I walked out of the gigantic green gate which is the entrance to our compound via the embedded regular sized door and stopped for a few moments to chat with my body guards who would be walking with me the 200 m or so to my friend’s house. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>As one left to go grab a jacket and something to drink, another of them and I were chatting in Somalglish.  He told me that there had been a bomb that day in Mogadishu.  I didn’t think that much about it as bombs are always going off in Mogadishu.  I replied, “OK.”  If I got too worked up every time I heard that someone had died violently, or that a militia was now mobilizing, or that this area or that area was on the verge of complete and utter dissolution then I would have gone insane long ago. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moments after the guard who would be accompanying me returned and we headed off to my friends.  I have no idea what I may have been pondering during the time, but it surely was brilliant and had nothing to do with the bomb. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I arrived at my friend’s house everyone was particularly chatty that day.  I took my assigned seat in the circle which all eight or so of us occupy with regularity.  We sit on the floor due to a legend that if you chew qat while sitting on cushions you’ll get indigestion.  No one was that worked up, but the radio had not yet come on and the power in my friend’s house doesn’t turn on until 4 pm or so. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think that it was about 3 when VOA Somali is aired.  My friend Maal loves his little radio and he loves the VOA – which has only been operating for the past six months or so.  Prior to that everyone received their news via BBC Somali’s radio service.  When VOA came in, for whatever reason, they tromped BBC – which swelled my national pride at the expense of my wife’s. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyway, VOA came on and everyone listened with horror to the headline.  There had been a suicide bomb at a medical school graduation in Mogadishu that day.  Slowly the information came out.  And then the power came on and we instantly turned on al Jazeera.  The pictures were horrible.  As the afternoon wore on I grew angrier and angrier by the moment. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the one had there was the human tragedy part of the story.  The kids that were graduating had known war their *entire *lives.  Most likely they had heard gun shots almost everyday that they’ve been born.  They had likely been subjected to the sounds of mortars at least once a month going into the depths of their memories. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>They had been subjected to social pressures unimaginable to me. Sure, we all have to deal with peer pressure, but many of the peers of these kids were beyond violent gangsters long, long ago.  They had rejected the pressure to take up a gun – and they had found a way to stay in school.  Likely they did not always finish their homework as when it got dark, it got *dark.  *They probably did not have working generators for significant portions of their childhoods – making studying after sunset next to impossible unless you can catch some cars driving by (but this is Mogadishu and there aren’t that many of them).  The list goes on and on, and kids all over Africa have gone through these horrors which make our childhood complaints so minuscule.  &lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yet, these kids had rejected the easy route that so many of those their age had taken on.  Indeed, they had not only rejected the route of violence, they had taken a decided opposite route.  I make this joke about how after graduating undergraduate with an engineering degree I decided to become a Marine and blow things up instead of building them.  These kids made the correct choice, which is the opposite of mine.  They decided to put *people *back together instead of blowing people up.  &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let us not look at this with rose colored glasses and think that, well, they had made a financial decision.  Doctors in south-central Somalia are like teachers in the US, well-respected but under-compensated. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>But this day, this day was a chance to celebrate.  A chance to turn their finely tuned sense of danger off.  A chance to relax their tension for a small time.  A chance for their parents who equally sacrificed throughout to engage in the age old parental paradigm: to be proud of their offspring.  A chance for redemption, that they had beaten all the forces which have colluded against their academic success. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then…. B    O    O     M.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have no way to imagine.  Now, almost two months after the event my heart still breaks when I try to imagine the scene. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>That day, here with my friends, almost all eight of us were brought to tears.  The rest of them are all older Somali men.  And not prone to over-sensitivity. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>I oscillated.  My emotions swung from extreme horror and sadness about the actual explosion to anger because of what had cause the explosion.  Back and forth through the afternoon.  Back and forth as the information came out.  Back and forth as the videos were shown on al Jazeera.  Back and forth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The anger stemmed from the realization that this is a new phenomenon in Somalia.  See, Mogadishu has been an utter mess for well over twenty years.  However, it has been a mess that has been (by all Somali accounts) largely navigable.  Things were oddly predictable if you understood the situation well.  The Somali conflict has been (prior to the most recent couple of years) largely distinct from other African conflicts.  Civilian casualties have been quite low.  Rape, mass slaughter, amputations, rampant drug use, cannibalism, all of the horror that sells newspapers and funds NGOs has largely been absent from the Somali conflict.  I do not try to minimize the trials of those in Mogadishu, I’m simply saying that vis a vis Sierra Leone for instance things are very different.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Those that have lived in Mogadishu have been able to more or less live, despite the limitations. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>But, things have been changing rapidly in south-central Somalia.  The “invasion” by the Ethiopians did not spawn it.  In fact, that was quite conventional warfare mixed with a conventional insurgency.  It was after the Ethiopians withdrew when Mogadishu experienced its first suicide bomb.  If I remember correctly it was a vehicle-borne IED detonated in front of an AMISOM compound – no one was hurt. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few months later, in October 2008 three coordinated suicide bombs went off here in the capital of the north.  It was a dark day, and a pivotal day.  In more ways than the devastation, it was Somalia’s 9/11.  By that I mean it was a watershed event and marks a disjunctive point in time where everything before and everything after must be interpreted in very different ways. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Admittedly the frequency of suicide attacks and other advanced insurgent tactics based upon the violence against civilians is much lower in Mogadishu than in Afghanistan or Iraq.  And, yet, the frequency is steadily increasing.  Here in the north, in the town that marks the boundary between the north-eastern and northern sections of what the world knows as Somalia has been a mess for the past few weeks. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>A suicide bomber strapped himself up, and gave his friend the remote detonator.  He intended to walk into the hotel where some Ministers and other officials were staying and have his friend detonate him.  This tactic was largely developed by the Palestinians to ensure that the human delivering the explosive did not get cold feet about the situation.  However, and for whatever reason, the friend pushed the remote detonator when the strapped friend was 200 m or so from the hotel.  No one was hurt, except for the strapped friend.  The legs of that man are intact, but the rest was decimated. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>This all represents the genesis of my anger on that day last December.  For years and years, Somali society like the kids who stayed in school, have resisted the more awful aspects of war.  Yes all war is terrible, but in my mind there are degrees.  And suicide bombings is about the lowest one can get tactically.  For whatever reason, Somali society has not been able to hold back the tendency to engage in these tactics.  Maybe it is foreign fighters coming in.  Maybe AQ is there in the south and training fighters.  Maybe it is copycat-ism. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have no idea, but it makes me angry.  Because the only result of this situation is that more people.  Real people.  People that do not deserve to die.  Will die. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>No many people who grew up on my circumstances of life – middle-class in the developed world – understand what it feels like to have a country you love invaded.  But there, on that floor, on that day I began to understand what the Iraqis may have felt when a friend of mine hoisted an American flag over Saddam’s face. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>What struck me the most, besides the anger and the sadness, was the utter feeling of hopelessness.  Long ago I put down a gun and picked up books.  I decided that my brain and my words were the weapons that I personally wielded the best.  Part of me, on that particular day, regretted that decision.  Because I just wanted to &lt;em>do something&lt;/em>.  And yet, what can words or logic or reason achieve?  That is the question.  &lt;/p>
&lt;p>All I do know is that I have to continue to hope and to try.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>FP gets it semi-correct on Somalia</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-04-fp-gets-it-semi-correct-on-somalia/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-04-fp-gets-it-semi-correct-on-somalia/</guid><description>&lt;p>FP usually does really good analysis, but I am concerned by a couple of blog posts they have published recently.  The first is &lt;a href="http://blog.foreignpolicy.com/posts/2010/02/01/somali_insurgents_announce_their_allegiance_to_al_qaeda">here&lt;/a>.  While I understand that they are trying to simplify a very complex issue, this is just lazy.  Especially for a group of mostly informed readers.  While I agree with their analysis that Shabaab is running a parallel government (to some extent), it is no where near as pervasive as, for instance, Greater Liberia was.  Shabaab have not issued their own currency, do not enforce “borders” in the same manner, etc. etc. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>The other thing which troubles me is that they seem to assume that just because Shabaab has announced that they are al Qaeda, that means that they are.  While the specifics of this are less than opaque, the evidence they point to is rather dismal.  There is a lot of counter-evidence that Shabaab is largely peopled by Islamist wannabes.  Personally, I lean toward the latter.  I think that largely Shabaab is a rebranded insurgency with Islamist claims in order to secure financing.  Yet, it is complex, as there are solid reports that some of the leadership of Shabaab has been trained by AQ and retains its linkages.  This leads me to believe that there is a split within the organization, but more on that at a latter date. &lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This is big news for anyone still trying to read the tea leaves on the Somali insurgency, not least becuase in all honesty, this is really no insurgency at all. It's a parallel government. On any day of the week, it would be easy to point to a map and argue that more of Somalia's territory is run by Shabaab and its allies control than by the Transitional Federal Government (despite rather &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/aponline/2010/01/30/world/AP-AF-Somalia.html">optimistic claims&lt;/a> to the contrary). So if Shabaab is the al Qaeda affiliate it claims to be, that means that Somalia is being de facto run by a terrorist group. Yikes.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The paragraph below I heartily endorse and agree with from what little I’ve seen.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I have to wonder if the United States really gets all of this. As the last decade of conflict has shown us, chaos — a category in which Somalia has no competitors –  is perhaps the best predictor of 21st Century security ills. And from civil conflict to terrorism to refugees and the plight of disease, Somalia has it all. But it's precisely for that reason that the Somalia portfolio has been a hot potato within the U.S. government — bouncing from agency to agency and advisor to advisor with no clear owner or no clear line. It's probably less that U.S. policymarkers are &lt;a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/idUSTRE60U18B20100131">ignoring Somalia&lt;/a> (as the African Union suggested this weekend) as they are overwhelmed. A fair excuse, but a dangerous one as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The second article is &lt;a href="http://blog.foreignpolicy.com/posts/2010/02/03/are_the_pirates_linked_to_the_islamists">here&lt;/a>.  This, I think, is even lazier reporting. &lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Somalia has two big scourges these days: Islamist milititas the run most of the country (and are &lt;a href="http://blog.foreignpolicy.com/posts/2010/02/01/somali_insurgents_announce_their_allegiance_to_al_qaeda">linked to al Qaeda&lt;/a>) and piracy off the coast. (The combination yields a desperate humanitarian situation sandwiched in between.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But what if the two scourges are linked? That was the  suggestion of the Kenyan Vice President Kalonzo Stephen Musyok, speaking at the &lt;a href="http://www.newamerica.net/events/2010/kenyan_somali_border">New America Foundation&lt;/a> today. &amp;ldquo;Piracy is another issue which I think has a  direct link with these extremist militant groups,&amp;rdquo; he told the audience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It's an odd idea at first. Al Shabaab has built its image on the harsh brand of Sharia that they hope to impose, and during the Islamic Courts government earlier this decade (of which al Shabaab was a part, piracy was banned. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not anymore. Last December, a &lt;a href="http://www.nationalpost.com/news/story.html?id=2295946">Canadian intelligence report&lt;/a> indicated that Shabaab was in fact training pirates for their &amp;ldquo;duties.&amp;rdquo; Further reporting from &lt;em>Jane's&lt;/em> (&lt;a href="http://centralasiaonline.com/cocoon/caii/xhtml/en_GB/features/caii/features/2009/04/16/feature-03">summarized here&lt;/a>) notes how taxes are levied on the pirates&amp;rsquo; booties. Yes, the pirates and the Islamists are definitely in cahoots.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One way they know that both are getting worse? &amp;ldquo;[I]n Nairobi today, property prices today are still rising, and we think this has a direct link with the piracy.&amp;rdquo; In other words, all those wealthy pirates are &lt;a href="http://blog.foreignpolicy.com/posts/2010/01/04/somali_pirates_driving_up_kenyan_real_estate_prices">buying up fancy homes&lt;/a>. And they've got a lot of cash to spend.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>While I cannot disagree with the quotes, the real evidence that I see exists on a map.  The major pirate networks are not in the south, which is where Shabaab is.  They are in Puntland, which has seen Shabaab incursions recently, but nowhere near to the level that I see this linkage blossom.  I do agree with Dickenson’s analysis that this is something to watch closely.  However, the evidence that pirates are buying houses and driving up property prices in Nairobi (in Isley neighborhood specifically) shows me nothing other than they have nothing else they can buy in Puntland.  Sure there are a few pirate networks that have developed in the South, but these pale in comparison to the networks which are operating with impunity up north.  Perhaps the cited Canadian intel report is correct, but that barely proves the point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This illustrates one of my major beefs with living and being here.  The analysis is so shotty.  On the one hand, there are complex issues here, and Somali society isn’t the easiest to figure out.  Yet it isn’t the most complex society to figure out, and when you have a handle on it, it is relatively easy to work out what is happening. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>So maybe I need to do more commenting, with the hopes that it may be able to change some of the rhetoric and analysis a small bit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Own Private Pirate Expedition</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2009/2009-09-09-my-own-private-pirate-expedition/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2009/2009-09-09-my-own-private-pirate-expedition/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am trying to return to some modicum of consistency with respect to the exhibitionist nature of this activity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In that vein, let me tell you of our next few days.  Our roommates (there are a total of five of us, which will constrict to three within a matter of weeks) and Leigh and I will be heading off to “train” the Coast Guard.  Actually, we won’t be doing any training, but Scuba Steve will be training the Coast Guard on boat handling techniques (for their one cutter) and diving techniques (still unsure re: this one). &lt;/p>
&lt;p>A while ago we bought a Pirate flag as a joke when we were in Scotland.  I am hoping to fly this from the cutter as we are zooming along.  There is this corner, near Djib, of S-land that Leigh and I have always wanted to visit.  It is apparently one of the most beautiful parts of this country.  There are two major islands off the coast, where Muslim missionaries first crossed from the peninsula into Africa.  There is an ancient ruin of the mosque they used on the one island where we are hoping to camp.  Also there will likely be sea turtles and whale sharks, and some of the best reef diving in the world.  As my roommates are similiar to my family – which is to say nuts about photos – I’m sure there will be numerous photos for posting afterwards. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are hoping that the cruise will contain a short diversion up to Djib where we can acquire wines and other select items not available in our locale.  The S-land Coast Guard are having some sort of a meet and greet with the Djib Navy, so that should be interesting to be a part of. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>The pirates shouldn’t be too much of a concern.  I will be posting myself with binos on the bow gatling for much of the trip, or at least for a few photos.  Plus the closer to Djib, where the anti-piracy fleet is “stationed,” one gets the safer one becomes. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>We should be completely out of contact from Thursday until Monday.  After that, inshallah, there will be tons of stories of nuts adventures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are hoping to see T-Pain somewhere along the way….&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>An Homage to My Environment (aka Thanks for the Birthday Greetings)</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2009/2009-09-03-an-homage-to-my-environment-aka-thanks-for-the-birthday-greetings/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2009/2009-09-03-an-homage-to-my-environment-aka-thanks-for-the-birthday-greetings/</guid><description>&lt;p>For those which are curious as to a H-town, birthday this is how it broke down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I woke up to homemade chocolate cake (which L could get all ingredients of locally), a bottle of prosecco (imported on the sly from Dubai) and one of those happy birthday stringers (imported openly from Nairobi).  This was served on a tray which we mostly use to take our 24-hour security detail tea in late in the evenings sitting on a low stool I mainly use as an otomon (made from raw camel leather tied to unfinished wood). &lt;/p>
&lt;p>My staff came in early to wish me happy birthday, but also to continue our two day marathon security planning for possible al-qaeda attacks which will be targeted against….well, we're not quite sure who is the target or whether they are even possible to attack anything.  But nevertheless, we are forced to plan for it. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>A some point in the day, I have been offered a massage.  The offeror's hands had, five mintues before the offer, been hydro-peroxide-and-q-tiping a cat's ass.  Literally. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>This evening we will attend a BBQ which will likely be of a local goat or lamb variety.  There will be other food there – mostly imported from Dubai where all of our delicies arrive from.  The drinks will be supported by many attendees (booze potlucks being the operative social norm), as well as a couple of cases of bad beer (which L likes) imported in Land Cruisers driving over dirt roads from neighboring Ethiopia.  There will be music which will be from someone's iPod amplified by whosever computer speakers are closest. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>The four of us in my house (L and I and our roomates – a Swedish former-rugby-player, current-governance-sector-ngo-worker and his American wife current-schoolteacher) will drive 30 minutes to the other side of town dodging, goats, random children who don't look both ways, potholes the size of Orlando, al-Qeada operatives, chickens, donkeys pulling the only source of water for many, men sitting quietly together in open-air teashops listening to BBC, and likely a few crazy homeless people. The Swede, who will likely be driving (a consequence of my prepartying which will result in the violation of above stated social norm) will squint and be blinded multiple times due to the unlit roads throughout town.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tomorrow we will arise late as it is my one day a week off.  All in all, one of my favorites.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tonight the Following Occured&amp;#8230;</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-09-12-tonight-the-following-occured/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-09-12-tonight-the-following-occured/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>A Masai Bush Pilot attempted to convince me that rural Sudanese women were so turned on by engine noise from his craft that they would masturbate in front of him.  But only when the engines were running.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I became strangely choked up by the words of a departing Haitian whom I barely know.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I discussed the vitality of American Football in relation to Rugby and what that speaks of American v. European culture.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I was nearly fondled by a drunken Rwandan-Austrian who, despite his family, we are all convinced is gay.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I was nearly fondled by a drunken Kosovar who no one disputes is gay.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I was taught dance steps by a good Kenyan friend named Daniel.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I learned of the intricacies of kidnappings near Mogadishu and how the groups there seemingly fail to understand the integral part of such a venture: the ransom.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I learned of the historical reasons for Greenland remaining a colony of Denmark.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I was chided by a Ugandan named Daniel for not knowing some word that began with psycho and ended in gibberish.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I convinced a Zimbabwean acquaintance that Highlands is all of the following: decedent of Apache royalty, Tajikistani Interior Designer, Uzbekistani Fish Farmer, and currently residing in Mongolia integrated into women's martial arts training.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>my nearly ever-present proclivity towards sarcasm I say the following without any hint of it.  Gawd Damn, I Love living in Africa.  And I mean Love.  With a capital L.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AFRICOM and WAPO</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-03-africom-and-wapo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-03-africom-and-wapo/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have been fascinated to watch how AFRICOM develops.  &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2008/05/31/AR2008053102055.html?nav=rss_email/components">Washington Post&lt;/a> has a very interesting article the other day about how AFRICOM has been received on the continent.  The gist of the article contains two interrelated theorems: (1) that Bush's rhetorical fascination with terrorism has pigeon-holed his foreign policy measures that have little to do with terrorism; (2) that African leaders and American policy makers are like Somali Pirates and French Sailors passing each other quietly in the night with little understanding of the other.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think the quote that sums up the article is:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Under Africom, one command will consolidate military responsibility for&lt;br>
all of Africa, excluding Egypt. Although it encompasses the volatile&lt;br>
Horn of Africa and the U.S. Navy's forward operating base in Djibouti&lt;br>
and will take over training tasks on the continent, it has no other&lt;br>
dedicated troop components. &amp;ldquo;There are very few scenarios which would&lt;br>
create a U.S. military intervention&amp;rdquo; in Africa, said one Africom&lt;br>
officer who was not authorized to speak on the record. &amp;ldquo;Arguably, there&lt;br>
are no scenarios.&amp;rdquo;
With its headquarters on the continent, liaison groups of 20 to 30&lt;br>
military personnel established in key countries and U.S. units brought&lt;br>
in to help with development and relief tasks, the command was&lt;br>
envisioned as an example to Africans of how their own armed forces and&lt;br>
civilians could work together for the good of their nations.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The trouble was, no one consulted the Africans. &amp;ldquo;Very little was&lt;br>
really known by the majority of people or countries in Africa who were&lt;br>
supposed to know before such a move was made,&amp;rdquo; said retired Kenyan army&lt;br>
Lt. Gen. Daniel Opande. Worry swept the continent that the United&lt;br>
States planned major new military installations in Africa.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;If you know the politics of Africa,&amp;rdquo; said Opande, who has headed&lt;br>
U.N. peacekeeping forces in Sierra Leone and Liberia, &amp;ldquo;you know there&lt;br>
are certain very powerful countries who said, no, we are not interested&lt;br>
in having a headquarters here.&amp;rdquo; South Africa and Nigeria were among&lt;br>
them, and their resistance helped persuade others.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Over the past seven years, the administration has more than tripled&lt;br>
U.S. assistance to Africa, to about $9 billion annually, nearly half of&lt;br>
which is spent on prevention and treatment for HIV-AIDS. U.S. military&lt;br>
training for African forces has steadily expanded, and U.S. troops have&lt;br>
undertaken humanitarian missions in several countries — digging wells,&lt;br>
building schools and providing medical care. Africom's budget request&lt;br>
for 2009 is about $400 million.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>But despite the promise of new development and security&lt;br>
partnerships, many Africans concluded that Africom was primarily an&lt;br>
extension of U.S. counterterrorism policy, intended to keep an eye on&lt;br>
Africa's large Muslim population.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I think everyone thought it would be widely greeted as something&lt;br>
positive,&amp;rdquo; the Africom officer said. &amp;ldquo;But you suddenly have wide&lt;br>
publics that have no idea what we're talking about. . . . It was seen&lt;br>
as a massive infusion of military might onto a continent that was quite&lt;br>
proud of having removed foreign powers from its soil.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The United States &amp;ldquo;equates terrorism with Islam,&amp;rdquo; senior Kenyan&lt;br>
diplomat Bethuel Kiplagat said, and few African governments wanted to&lt;br>
be seen as inviting U.S. surveillance on their own people.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Russell Feingold (D-Wis.), who chairs the Senate Foreign Relations&lt;br>
African affairs subcommittee, thought Africom was &amp;ldquo;something that would&lt;br>
show real respect for Africa.&amp;rdquo; But there was no question, Feingold&lt;br>
said, that the concept had &amp;ldquo;a neocolonialist feel to it.&amp;rdquo;
~ # ~&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Arrival Terminal</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-05-18-arrival-terminal/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-05-18-arrival-terminal/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well, for better or worse, I&lt;br>
guess I’m settled in here now.  I am living in a hotel suite for the time&lt;br>
being.  In maybe six weeks or so I’ll move either into a villa on the&lt;br>
grounds of this hotel or have been talking to a few people here about the&lt;br>
possibility of getting a compound like we had when I was in Salone.  Either&lt;br>
way, the living is pretty decent. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>My suite has a TV with&lt;br>
satellite connection (CNN, BBC, Al Jazeera English and some Dubai channels that&lt;br>
show movies in English and a sports channel that has soccer on a lot), sitting&lt;br>
room  with fridge, a bedroom with a big bed (hard as a rock) and a desk&lt;br>
for me to do some work on. &lt;br>
The hotel is a fairly big&lt;br>
compound and I think I’m able to put human smuggling as a room charge, since I&lt;br>
seem to be able to charge everything else on my room!  There is a restaurant&lt;br>
and a little convenience store where I can get a few supplies.  All&lt;br>
chargeable to my room.  There is wireless internet, although it seems to&lt;br>
come and go.  The water runs and the&lt;br>
electricity seems fairly constant without a loud generator.  So I’m in the&lt;br>
lap of luxury! &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sort of.   &lt;/p>
&lt;p>The town is very poor.  I&lt;br>
told Highlands that it is like Freetown without the natural beauty.  It&lt;br>
is sort of in a bowl, surrounded by smallish hills on all sides.  My hotel&lt;br>
sits on one of them and I have a great view of the town.  The surroundings&lt;br>
are very much like when I was in 29 Palms, desert.  Although here it has&lt;br>
rained most days and is a bit cooler than in 29 Palms, and here it is a bit&lt;br>
flatter than it was in Cali.  The infrastructure in the town is somewhat&lt;br>
better than Freetown, at least here most have running water and&lt;br>
electricity.  Some people even have cable TV.  The roads are worse, most are dirt and the few that are&lt;br>
paved are riddled with pot holes.  Luckily we have a Land Cruiser with&lt;br>
good suspension and a driver who has a lead foot (for once that wasn’t sarcasm,&lt;br>
I actually like him to drive faster on the roads b/c we miss many of the&lt;br>
bumps). &lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is very little to do,&lt;br>
unfortunately.  We went to an NGO/UN party last night, but left at 1130&lt;br>
and were harassed at five checkpoints on the way back.  The police&lt;br>
couldn’t fathom that we would want to be out that late!  So, there may be&lt;br>
some cultural growing to do.  Maybe I’ll do it at the local theater that I&lt;br>
drove by today on my way to the market!  Guess I’m going to get my fill of&lt;br>
reading, writing and working until Highlands gets here, and likely&lt;br>
afterwards. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>The people seem very&lt;br>
relaxed.  They actually seem to like that I’m American.  It is an odd&lt;br>
feeling.  They are much less aggressive and much more reserved than the&lt;br>
West Africans (from what I’ve seen).  Today I went to the market to get&lt;br>
some coffee and some veggies and was only asked for money once (by an old lady&lt;br>
who had polio).  In Freetown I would have been asked at least 10,000 times&lt;br>
for money.  They are also less gregarious and a bit harder to joke&lt;br>
with.  We’ll see, I need to figure out what makes them tick before I am&lt;br>
able to really develop a rapport with them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My partner is nice.  From&lt;br>
what I can tell he and I are getting along.  At the party last night I&lt;br>
started to meet some in the local NGO/UN community.  It is extraordinarily&lt;br>
small, all things considered.  But they all seemed like the others&lt;br>
I met in West Africa.  I guess it takes a weirdo mind to get into this&lt;br>
work and stay in it.  At least at the party there was a bit of beer.&lt;br>
It is a dry country!!!!! &lt;/p>
&lt;p>All in all, there is the good&lt;br>
and the bad, but I’m OK.  Once I get my feet under me I’ll be able to&lt;br>
really assess whether I like it here, whether I like this work, etc.  But&lt;br>
for now I’m happy and healthy, which is all I can ask for.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In case you were looking for pictures, I cannot&lt;br>
provide them!  My camera has either been appropriated by some customs&lt;br>
official along the way or was left behind for some insane reason.  Luckily&lt;br>
I had recently cleaned off the card!  Not to fret, my graduation splurge&lt;br>
for myself is going to be a nice DSLR that I will try to have someone get for&lt;br>
me and ship over in a month or two.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Beckham went to Salone</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-29-beckham-went-to-salone/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-29-beckham-went-to-salone/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here is a video of it. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://myspacetv.com/index.cfm?fuseaction=vids.individual&amp;amp;videoid=29311413">UNICEF: David Beckham surprises young Sierra Leone footballers&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[Add to My Profile][2] | [More Videos][3]
~ # ~&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[2]: &lt;a href="http://myspacetv.com/index.cfm?fuseaction=vids.addToProfileConfirm&amp;amp;videoid=29311413&amp;amp;title=UNICEF:">http://myspacetv.com/index.cfm?fuseaction=vids.addToProfileConfirm&amp;amp;videoid=29311413&amp;amp;title=UNICEF:&lt;/a> David Beckham surprises young Sierra Leone footballers
[3]: &lt;a href="http://myspacetv.com/index.cfm?fuseaction=vids.home">http://myspacetv.com/index.cfm?fuseaction=vids.home&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Brown Gets a Few Things</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-01-21-brown-gets-a-few-things/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-01-21-brown-gets-a-few-things/</guid><description>&lt;p>[![Gordonbrownblurweb][2]][2]&lt;br>
Link: [‘An idea whose time has come’: Brown backs UN security council seat for India | The Guardian | Guardian Unlimited][2].&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2008/01/21/gordonbrownblurweb.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2008/01/21/gordonbrownblurweb.jpg&lt;/a>
[2]: &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/guardianpolitics/story/0,,2244153,00.html">http://www.guardian.co.uk/guardianpolitics/story/0,,2244153,00.html&lt;/a> &amp;ldquo;&amp;lsquo;An idea whose time has come&amp;rsquo;: Brown backs UN security council seat for India | The Guardian | Guardian Unlimited&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I know that it is trendy in the UK to bash on Gordon Brown.  I agree with his critics, mostly.  However this Guardian article points out what things he does seem to get entirely correct. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are two particular things that I like about his stance:  (1) his willingness to open up the power structure to a few more voices in recognition of their growing importance; (2) his (apparent) understanding of the intricacies of post-conflict transitions. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the first point.  It seems to me that the time is coming where it is unavoidable that the &amp;ldquo;winners&amp;rdquo; in WWII are going to have to cede some of their relative monopoly on power.  This will create a shift in international politics as the center of gravity shifts from somewhere around the mid-Atlantic to somewhere else.  Brown is lobby for India, Brazil, Germany, Japan and an African State to be named later to get permanent seats on the Security Council.  Realists in America and Russia have resisted this and it is likely that they will continue to resist, at least through the end of the Bush administration which seems to understand little about the world outside of their mansions.  But it will be interesting to see if we can get an administration into the White House with a different notion of international politics how it will play out.  An arrangement such as this will complicate negotiations when action needs to be streamlined and quick, but I think that the SC is fairly impotent as it is and the addition of a few voices and the recognition that moving forward we need to integrate these voices (on top of the addition of Germany and Japan will put to bed much of the WWII winners/losers stuff) into the discussion outweighs additional difficulties in negotiations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the second point.  I have been thinking for a while about a task force to go in under a UN mandate that is more than only delegations from DPKO to help in post-conflict transitions.  I have been wondering, essentially, why this hasn’t happened, because to my ignorant eyes it seems like a fantastic po-mo solution.  Brown’s idea is this:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Today, on the final day of his tour of India and China, Brown will&lt;br>
announce plans for a UN crisis prevention and recovery fund, worth&lt;br>
$200m (£102m), which would put judges, police and fire service staff on&lt;br>
standby to support countries immediately as they come out of conflict.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And I think that it is very forward thinking.  Sovereignists will likely argue that it is and internationalization of the rule of law and essential services that will take away too much authority from the state and propagate brain-drain and a welfare culture among developing countries.  Done wrongly, they are right.  However, done correctly they could be wrong.  We are seeing in Kenya now that much of the violence (although tribal based) is based upon land redistribution issues.  Sending in a small team of judges to rule ON KENYAN law, but untainted by tribal allegiances may be able to make a huge positive contribution to resolution of the core problems which are causing the violence.  The teams must be careful  when establishing their mandates as I see a big difference in sending judges in to rule on land redistribution issues and meddling in something completely politicized (like the legitimacy of the election results).  Something of this magnitude will have other effects such as politicizing decisions of when do they  go into a country, what do they do, etc.  But the hopes of cross-cultural experience and cultivation of institutions may outweigh the downsides in my mind.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sliding Liberia</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-01-10-sliding-liberia/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-01-10-sliding-liberia/</guid><description>&lt;p>So, am back from Europe and getting into the swing of things. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sometimes the internet is an amazing thing.  I have my &lt;a href="http://www.newsgator.com/Individuals/FeedDemon/Default.aspx">RSS Reader&lt;/a> set up to automatically search for many things, one of which is for the case that I used to work on.  Usually a bunch of trash comes up when I do my news skim each day since Charles Taylor isn’t the rarest of names and it is difficult to filter out all of the trash although I get most of it.  Nevertheless, today I found out about a surfing movie made in Liberia this summer (which must have been shortly after &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/photos/little_america/index.html">Urs and I were there&lt;/a>). &lt;/p>
&lt;p>The trailer is below.  The website is &lt;a href="http://www.slidingliberia.com/">here.&lt;/a>  See it if you get a chance. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Watch This</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-12-20-watch-this/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-12-20-watch-this/</guid><description>&lt;p>Keep an eye on this! &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![3307ma4][2]][2]&lt;br>
Last week [Jacob Zuma was elected as head of ANC.][2]  He won this election over the sitting president, Thabo Mbeki, who he has had troubles with in the past.  Zuma used to be Mbeki’s vice, but was fired in 2005.  Last week he has wrested the leadership of the ANC from him after a very acrimonious campaign for the leadership of Nelson’s party.  So today, BBC reports that there are rumors that Zuma will be [indicted on corruption charges][3]. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/12/20/3307ma4.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/12/20/3307ma4.jpg&lt;/a>
[2]: &lt;a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/world/africa/7152542.stm">http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/world/africa/7152542.stm&lt;/a> &amp;ldquo;BBC NEWS | World | Africa | &amp;lsquo;No revenge&amp;rsquo; call after Zuma win&amp;rdquo;
[3]: &lt;a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/world/africa/7153250.stm">http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/world/africa/7153250.stm&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Love of corruption is the root of all evil in my eyes, but I’m conflicted here.  Maybe he did it, in which case then things need to be reevaluated.  Maybe there should be a new election for head of ANC.  But even if he did, and there was a prosecutorial decision in 2005 not to prosecute him, then it just feels like blackmail. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are many interesting political dimensions to this.  One is that South Africa is looked up to throughout most of Africa as the (relative) bastion of good governance (see, e.g., &lt;a href="http://allafrica.com/stories/200712200230.html">this&lt;/a>) in the same way that Nigeria is held up as the bastion of what not to do (see, e.g., &lt;a href="http://allafrica.com/stories/200712190100.html">this&lt;/a>).  At least for the Anglophone countries this largely appears to be the case.  But South Africa’s importance goes way beyond simply an example, it is THE key to all of Southern Africa, if not most of sub-saharan Africa.  Despite Nigeria’s desires, the key regional powers in the AU from the sub-saharan countries are: well, South Africa, and to a lesser extent Kenya, Tanzania and Nigeria. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![P_south_africa_2010][7]][7]&lt;br>
The 2010 World Cup is to be held in South Africa and is thought of widely as a way to focus attention on Africa in a very positive light for the first time in a long time.  The entire continent seemingly feels ownership over these games in a way that could not be the case if they were elsewhere – in the developed world.  So, what happens if the next year and a half goes badly politically for South Africa?  The entire continent may suffer from a failed opportunity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://www.fifa.com/worldcup/index.html">http://www.fifa.com/worldcup/index.html&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maybe I’m making more of this than is really here.  If the ANC does implode because of an internal power struggle, maybe that shifts the domestic political dynamics but does not really affect the status of the country.  Like, I say, keep an eye on it. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Zimbabwe</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-11-13-zimbabwe/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-11-13-zimbabwe/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you wondered a bit about what the hell Mugabe is doing, look &lt;a href="http://www.soros.org/resources/multimedia/zimbabwe">here&lt;/a>.  The MDC in Zimbabwe is a political party, so there is a political agenda behind this film, but after hearing the testimonies you may be able to put that aside.  The video is below:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sierra Leone bridge house</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-25-sierra-leone-bridge-house/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-25-sierra-leone-bridge-house/</guid><description>&lt;p>Everytime I wonder about what courage is, now I think of Sierra Leoneans.  They are, hands down, the most courageous people I have ever met.   I broke Highland’s car on one side of this bridge:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Link: &lt;a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/shared/spl/hi/picture_gallery/07/africa_sierra_leone_bridge_house/html/1.stm" title="BBC NEWS | Photo journal: Sierra Leone bridge house, Execution site">BBC NEWS | Photo journal: Sierra Leone bridge house, Execution site&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sierra Leone&amp;#8217;s New Leader on NPR</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-16-sierra-leones-new-leader-on-npr/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-16-sierra-leones-new-leader-on-npr/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/templates/story/story.php?storyId=15278868" title="NPR : Sierra Leone's New Leader Promotes Law, Order">&lt;img src="http://www.npr.org/templates/story/story.php?storyId=15278868" alt="Koroma2_full1" title="NPR : Sierra Leone's New Leader Promotes Law, Order">&lt;/a>&lt;br>
Koroma sure talks a good game.  I’m a bit cynical, but yet hesitantly optimistic at the same time.  So far no reports of violence during the cabinet changeover, but the hope mandate will likely extend for more months, if not through the middle of next year.  You can hear Koroma’s interview for NPR (BBC in the US…sort of) at the link below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/10/16/koroma2_full1.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/10/16/koroma2_full1.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Link: &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/templates/story/story.php?storyId=15278868" title="NPR : Sierra Leone's New Leader Promotes Law, Order">NPR : Sierra Leone’s New Leader Promotes Law, Order&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Liberia: Post-Conflict Dilemma &amp;#8211; Should Health Care Be Free?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-13-liberia-post-conflict-dilemma-should-health-care-be-free/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-13-liberia-post-conflict-dilemma-should-health-care-be-free/</guid><description>&lt;p>[![Im08][2]][2]&lt;br>
Liberia currently has a system of [Free Healthcare][2], funded by the World Bank. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://www.worldpress.org/photo_essays/liberia/pg01.html">http://www.worldpress.org/photo_essays/liberia/pg01.html&lt;/a>
[2]: &lt;a href="http://allafrica.com/stories/200710121098.html">http://allafrica.com/stories/200710121098.html&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See Salone, this is what happens when you aren’t viewed as corrupt…people give you money to fund services to your populace.  Salone should look next door to its south to find out how a country should be run.  Not that Liberia is some sort of a West African utopia.  But it certainly seems to be doing better…&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click on the Photo for a Photo-essay that will break your heart…in a good way.  If you still question why I want to disappear into the dark continent after viewing the essay, submit questions in written form to me and I will respond in kind.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Updated: Gambia</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-13-updated-gambia/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-13-updated-gambia/</guid><description>&lt;p>Gambia has &lt;a href="http://www.amnestyusa.org/document.php?lang=e&amp;amp;id=ENGUSA20071012002">released the AI investigators&lt;/a>.  Way to go Gambia.  Now they can get back to telling everyone about your exploitive sex industry and your repressive police state.  Way to go.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Liberian Debt Crisis</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-09-liberian-debt-crisis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-09-liberian-debt-crisis/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://blogs.cgdev.org/mt/mt-tb.cgi/981">&lt;img src="http://blogs.cgdev.org/mt/mt-tb.cgi/981" alt="Bono">&lt;/a>Although I think that Bono’s typical analysis of third-world debt is in many cases flat and unnuanced, it is important to look at.  At least that analysis that gets reported in the press.  The LiveAid concert series was the first time I began to think actively about the topics of poverty and from my current perspective is a watershed moment.  I kept thinking, &amp;ldquo;yeah, but…&amp;rdquo; where the ellipses were filled with different theories of mixed carrots and sticks. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/10/09/bono.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/10/09/bono.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since then, and since coming to law school my analytical abilities and knowledge of the both the problems and possible solutions have been slightly refined.  I am very, very ignorant on this topic, but I have been able to form philosophical views on a few third-world poverty issues and back those up with real reasoning, something that I couldn’t do on the sunny sunday afternoon in Aspen with the mountains behind me and my deck to sit on, smoke and think while the TV behind me blared Green Day and Bruce Springsteen and other left leaning celebrities who didn’t really know what they were arguing for except that they were getting widespread coverage. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>One thing that I now think is that there are countries it is worth saving.  That statement has a lot of nuances to it, I realize, but suffice it for here because I have to go to class soon, that Liberia is one of those countries.  Take the time to tell the IMF that Liberia is worth saving if you agree with what is written by&lt;a href="http://blogs.cgdev.org/mt/mt-tb.cgi/981"> this dude&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This should not be read to be an indictment of Bono’s analytical skills, cause everyone that knows me knows that I totally want to be Bono.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Brits Should Boycott the Gambia</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-08-brits-should-boycott-the-gambia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-08-brits-should-boycott-the-gambia/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/world/africa/7033715.stm">&lt;img src="http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/world/africa/7033715.stm" alt="_39310613_gambia_jammeh203jpg1">&lt;/a>&lt;br>
I am a big supporter of The Gambia for somehow convincing everyone to include the &amp;ldquo;The&amp;rdquo; in their name.  They also (apparently) have nice typical West African beaches. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/10/08/_39310613_gambia_jammeh203jpg1.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/10/08/_39310613_gambia_jammeh203jpg1.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However there are some messed up things going on there.  For one it is one of the most repressive dictatorships in West Africa.  For another their sex worker industry is patronized by old, dirty people who apparently strut around would lithe young Africans for a weekend at the time and then disappear.  Lastly, the tourist areas are completely shut off from the people. The dictator, to ensure his tourism revenue, does not allow the normal populace go near the tourist areas.  IT IS THEIR F’ING COUNTRY….makes me mad.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now &lt;a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/world/africa/7033715.stm">they’re accusing AI people of spying&lt;/a>.  That isn’t the way to make friends…especially with Britian who sends you most of your tourism revenue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Big Weekend for Africa</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-09-18-big-weekend-for-africa/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-09-18-big-weekend-for-africa/</guid><description>&lt;p>[![17sierra600][2]][2]This was a big weekend in the news for two African countries that rarely get much press.  Yesterday NYTimes led with [the results][2] of the [Salone election][3].  Ernest Koroma, the opposition leader won.  Talked to Highlands yesterday, who is in Salone.  She said they had a few minutes heads up that the election results were going to be announced and they went outside.  She said as soon  as they announced it there was a roar from the streets of Freetown which descended into a party that I wish I could have seen!  Not sure how much Koroma will really be able to do, but in Salone simply the illusion of hope is more than they often have.  So I’m happy, happy that they’re happy.  One of the best things that I’ve seen, substantively, is that Koroma is going to focus his economic policies to develop agriculture (Salone used to be a net exporter of rice and is now a net importer b/c of cheap asian rice) and tourism (we talked about it so much, a few million dollars and the peninsula around Freetown could be a flipping paradise, when combined with efficient flights down from London could bring tons of Brits and other Anglophones down).  This is exactly where I think the domestic economy should go, but, again, i know very little.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/09/18/17sierra600.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/09/18/17sierra600.jpg&lt;/a>
[2]: &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/aponline/world/AP-Sierra-Leone-Election.html">http://www.nytimes.com/aponline/world/AP-Sierra-Leone-Election.html&lt;/a>
[3]: &lt;a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/world/africa/6998687.stm">http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/world/africa/6998687.stm&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also in the news was Liberia.  Today NYTimes led with &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2007/09/18/nyregion/18liberians.html?ei=5087">a story &lt;/a>about the [Liberian TRC][5].  Have yet to read the article, but I’ve skimmed the major points and it will be an interesting read.  The Boston Globe also had [an editorial ][6]about what Ellen is doing.  It, like most Liberian’s I’ve talked to, are lauding everything that she is doing while cautioning that when a country has this long to go progress takes time to ramp up before a country can harness exponential growth curves. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;amp;em=&amp;amp;en=2e8025e277014d1e&amp;amp;ex=1190260800&amp;amp;adxnnl=1&amp;amp;adxnnlx=1190127815-81PpDqnGevfxLM7 PyMiAg
[5]: &lt;a href="http://www.trcofliberia.org/">http://www.trcofliberia.org/&lt;/a>
[6]: &lt;a href="http://www.boston.com/news/globe/editorial_opinion/oped/articles/2007/09/13/liberias_small_steps_on_reform/">http://www.boston.com/news/globe/editorial_opinion/oped/articles/2007/09/13/liberias_small_steps_on_reform/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lastly, Tanzania has been &lt;a href="http://allafrica.com/stories/200709180860.html">given a large MCA grant&lt;/a> which should be good news as I’d love to go to Tanzania and now there will be more US development money rolling into that country!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Salone votes (again) today</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-09-08-salone-votes-again-today/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-09-08-salone-votes-again-today/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/africa/6984697.stm" title="BBC NEWS | Africa | S Leoneans vote in run-off poll">&lt;img src="http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/africa/6984697.stm" alt="_1988075_ap_amputee300" title="BBC NEWS | Africa | S Leoneans vote in run-off poll">&lt;/a>&lt;br>
I’m very nervous, but hopeful.  It is now 1830 in Freetown/Salone and BBC has not (yet) reported of any violence.  This isn’t terribly surprising to me.  I think if violence gets propagated it will be by whoever loses this run-off, which will not be known for a while. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/09/08/_1988075_ap_amputee300.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/09/08/_1988075_ap_amputee300.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Link: &lt;a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/africa/6984697.stm" title="BBC NEWS | Africa | S Leoneans vote in run-off poll">BBC NEWS | Africa | S Leoneans vote in run-off poll&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BBC also has a heart-breaking &lt;a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/shared/spl/hi/picture_gallery/07/africa_sierra_leone_slum/html/1.stm">photojournalistic piece&lt;/a> about Kroo Bay slum.  I used to look out over Kroo Bay slum.  I would stand out on my balcony and look out over beautiful Freetwon and watch the sunrise in the mornings, cup of coffee or tea in hand and then look down at the bay.  I could see the vast stretches of rubbish and I would just shake my head.  There simply isn’t any place to put all that trash. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>The sign on the very last picture is at the &amp;ldquo;top&amp;rdquo; of Kroo Bay slum and at the &amp;ldquo;bottom&amp;rdquo; of my street, King Street.  I used to &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/underwater/2007/03/i_little_trip_t.html">walk/drive&lt;/a> (after starting dating Highlands and her car) past that sign a couple of times a day.  It is nice to see the Krio again.  I really, really miss Africa in general, Salone in specific.  How soon can I get back?  Highlands gets to go back for a month, she leaves on monday…..&amp;ldquo;LUCKY.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now I work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ICR Photoessay</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-08-29-icr-photoessay/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-08-29-icr-photoessay/</guid><description>&lt;p>At the junction of heart-breaking and hope is &lt;a href="http://us.oneworld.net/external/?url=http://www.theirc.org/resources/essays/back-to-school-for-darfur.html">this&lt;/a> photo essay done by the International Rescue Committee.  They are a good NGO, I think, at least on the spectrum of NGO’s.  I knew some people who worked for them in SL.  At least view it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sub-Saharan Population</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-08-28-sub-saharan-population/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-08-28-sub-saharan-population/</guid><description>&lt;p>listened to an interesting &lt;a href="http://www.cfr.org/publication/13839/conley.html">CFR podcast&lt;/a> the other day which discussed population levels in sub-saharan africa, which are currently exploding.  the guy was interesting to listen to as he was eloquent (it must come with the territory when you are the chair of sociology at NYU) and just when I thought he was going to swing naively left he hit me with an unexpected solution.  it was nice to be surprised like that!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>urbanization (and other factors) is being blamed for a dramatic increase in the population in sub-saharan africa.  the problems with this should be self-evident.  poverty in this region is incredibly rampant and governments cannot use the few resources (mainly involving agricultural land which is lacking region wide, despite is prevalence in western africa) to feed and build their economies at the current population levels.  fertility rates are much higher in africa than in the other world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>traditional responses to population control have been to develop the country in concert with gender-equality measures.  the thinking is that women who are working will have less time to make babies as they have other things to do.  there may be something to this as in most industrial democracies women have much lower fertility rates.  yet, in africa people have been trying to develop the economies of the continent for years and they’re still in the position that their in economically despite those efforts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>another traditional response has been to force condoms, but this has very little likelihood of success as most african’s see it as the white people telling them not to have sex and they don’t really use the condoms.  it has worked for aids awareness, but not for population control.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>china just killed babies and outlawed procreation.  i don’t see that happening either.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>so, while listening to this i must admit that a horrible, cynical thought was creeping into my mind.  i thought, well if the health system stays as awful as it is in most countries i don’t see a crisis cause so many people die.  maybe it was a big conspiracy to suppress populations. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>to my surprise the commentator said the exact opposite of what i was thinking.  he said that we should put even more emphasis on reducing infant mortality rates (which was the opposite of what i had been thinking during his analysis of the problem).  he argued that this would allow people to self-regulate in that they would know that they were going to have surviving heirs to take care of them in their old age without having to make five babies to get one to survive and have a good, long life.  i agree with him as it is positive and forward thinking….maybe a bit unrealistic in the short term, but that epitomizes my life anyway!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sleepy Justice: Sierra Leone&amp;#8217;s Lack of Self-Help in Judicial Sector Reform</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-27-sleepy-justice-sierra-leones-lack-of-self-help-in-judicial-sector-reform/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-27-sleepy-justice-sierra-leones-lack-of-self-help-in-judicial-sector-reform/</guid><description>&lt;p>have finally finished a paper i’ve been working on for months.  it isn’t perfect, but it is done done for now.  will take a look at it again when i’ve given it some breathing room.  if you have thoughts, send them my way!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/underwater/files/final_draft_2.doc">Sleep Justice&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>africa&amp;#8217;s past, present and future</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-26-africas-past-present-and-future/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-26-africas-past-present-and-future/</guid><description>&lt;p>Moeletsi Mbeki gave the &lt;a href="http://allafrica.com/stories/200707250737.html?page=2">keynote speech&lt;/a> &lt;em>at the Second Conference of the European Association of Centers of African Studies&lt;/em>. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>This speech is amazing, one of my favorite paragraphs:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Africa’s challenge today is that while the era of dictatorship has&lt;br>
apparently come to an end, African countries do not as yet have&lt;br>
indigenous institutions and leaders that promote cooperation among the&lt;br>
citizens. Developing such institutions is a difficult and costly&lt;br>
business that takes a long time. It is made even more complex by the&lt;br>
fact that firstly, the re-democratisation of African countries from the&lt;br>
mid 1990s was brought about to a significant extent by interventions of&lt;br>
Western donors rather than primarily by pro-democracy actions of&lt;br>
African organisations or parties. The main exceptions which prove the&lt;br>
rule being Uganda and Rwanda, and possibly Nigeria.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Another of my favorites, and how he opens the speech:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The world has done just about everything it could do to help Africa to&lt;br>
develop but has very little positive results to show for its efforts.&lt;br>
While most of the world, especially Asia, is forging ahead in the&lt;br>
development stakes, Africa is marking time at best, and marching&lt;br>
backwards in some instances.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>ok back to proofreading.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Liberia Joins Global Natural Resources Transparency Plan</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-19-liberia-joins-global-natural-resources-transparency-plan/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-19-liberia-joins-global-natural-resources-transparency-plan/</guid><description>&lt;p>[![Ellenjohnsonsirleaf][2]][2]&lt;br>
I was skeptical of ole’ Ellen at the beginning.  I’m beginning to come around.  Most people [that I talked to][2] on the streets of Monrovia were huge EJS fans.  I mean massively supportive of [her motherliness][3], [her toughness][4] (she was actually aligned with Taylor at the beginning of the conflict according to [Steven Ellis][5]‘ book), [her statesmanship][6], and [her overall good governance focus][7]. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/07/19/ellenjohnsonsirleaf.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/07/19/ellenjohnsonsirleaf.jpg&lt;/a>
[2]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/photos/little_america/1imgp1942.html">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/photos/little_america/1imgp1942.html&lt;/a>
[3]: &lt;a href="http://allafrica.com/stories/200707170966.html">http://allafrica.com/stories/200707170966.html&lt;/a>
[4]: &lt;a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;amp;ct=:ePkh8BM9E-IE2gHSaMAKNz8PYj4D2C6Y4UYCz7hE9j9_9fVOy0G7RZqR7k4AOhYPEw/0-0&amp;amp;fp=469f024d24983b2a&amp;amp;ei=ARufRpW6AZC8oAOhj_SBAQ&amp;amp;url=http://www.voanews.com/english/Africa/2007-07-19-voa8.cfm&amp;amp;cid=1118268009">http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;amp;ct=:ePkh8BM9E-IE2gHSaMAKNz8PYj4D2C6Y4UYCz7hE9j9_9fVOy0G7RZqR7k4AOhYPEw/0-0&amp;amp;fp=469f024d24983b2a&amp;amp;ei=ARufRpW6AZC8oAOhj_SBAQ&amp;amp;url=http://www.voanews.com/english/Africa/2007-07-19-voa8.cfm&amp;amp;cid=1118268009&lt;/a>
[5]: &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Mask-Anarchy-Destruction-Religious-Dimension/dp/0814722385/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1/102-9786824-3826564?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1184832710&amp;amp;sr=8-1">http://www.amazon.com/Mask-Anarchy-Destruction-Religious-Dimension/dp/0814722385/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1/102-9786824-3826564?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1184832710&amp;amp;sr=8-1&lt;/a>
[6]: &lt;a href="http://news.google.com/archivesearch/url?sa=t&amp;amp;ct=res&amp;amp;cd=3-0&amp;amp;url=http://allafrica.com/stories/200702140972.html&amp;amp;ei=xRufRoOwLpmE6AH87cGWDg&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNEXsEkb1Uy5KbSKcWUoVoaOh2SK4g">http://news.google.com/archivesearch/url?sa=t&amp;amp;ct=res&amp;amp;cd=3-0&amp;amp;url=http://allafrica.com/stories/200702140972.html&amp;amp;ei=xRufRoOwLpmE6AH87cGWDg&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNEXsEkb1Uy5KbSKcWUoVoaOh2SK4g&lt;/a>
[7]: &lt;a href="http://news.google.com/archivesearch/url?sa=t&amp;amp;ct=res&amp;amp;cd=9-0&amp;amp;url=http://allafrica.com/stories/200606290520.html&amp;amp;ei=xRufRoOwLpmE6AH87cGWDg&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNFlZQ_Evt-jNVzEYxysH_cJYaY5Rg">http://news.google.com/archivesearch/url?sa=t&amp;amp;ct=res&amp;amp;cd=9-0&amp;amp;url=http://allafrica.com/stories/200606290520.html&amp;amp;ei=xRufRoOwLpmE6AH87cGWDg&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNFlZQ_Evt-jNVzEYxysH_cJYaY5Rg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now the woman known as either Ellen or Ma on the streets of Monrovia has added another thing to her growing CV in the mind of me. She has &lt;a href="http://africa.reuters.com/wire/news/usnL18112308.html" title="News | Africa - Reuters.com">joined&lt;/a> the &lt;a href="http://www.eitransparency.org/">Extractive Industries Transparency Initiative&lt;/a> set up by Tony Blair in 2002 which will progress transparency in the extraction of natural resources.  The website says this about EITI:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The Extractive Industries Transparency Initiative (EITI) supports&lt;br>
improved governance in resource-rich countries through the verification&lt;br>
and full publication of company payments and government revenues from&lt;br>
oil, gas, and mining.  The Initiative works to build multi-stakeholder&lt;br>
partnerships in developing countries in order to increase the&lt;br>
accountability of governments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good governance is a precondition for converting large revenues from&lt;br>
extractive industries into economic growth and poverty reduction. When&lt;br>
transparency and accountability are weak, the extractive industries may&lt;br>
instead contribute to poverty, corruption, and conflict—the so-called&lt;br>
“resource curse.” The EITI is an important step in defeating this&lt;br>
“curse.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The links between good governance and the ability of a government to alleviate the poverty in their country are &lt;a href="http://www.typepad.com/t/trackback/2401758/20081356">nearly synonymous&lt;/a> and i’m writing a long paper on them right now.  Suffice it for here to say that when countries have good governance not only do they spend what little money they have &amp;ldquo;well&amp;rdquo; in the sense that they spend it on things that will help in the short-, medium-, and long-term to alleviate poverty, not only are they traditionally less corrupt, but they also get more money from donors.  these three things usually create a symbiotic causal linkage whereby donors will see exponential returns on their money in the form of poverty reduction. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>that is all for now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>eu planning peace-keeping mission to chad</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-18-eu-planning-peace-keeping-mission-to-chad/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-18-eu-planning-peace-keeping-mission-to-chad/</guid><description>&lt;p>[![Africapol][2]][2]&lt;br>
[this][2] is interesting as well.  the eu is planning on sending a small peacekeeping mission to eastern chad in order to stop spillovers from the sudan fighting. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/07/18/africapol.gif">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/07/18/africapol.gif&lt;/a>
[2]: &lt;a href="http://allafrica.com/stories/200707170844.html">http://allafrica.com/stories/200707170844.html&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?q=chad&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;ll=13.923404,18.720703&amp;amp;spn=38.774747,71.71875&amp;amp;t=h&amp;amp;z=4&amp;amp;om=1">chad&lt;/a> is a pretty messed up place in general, with&lt;a href="http://allafrica.com/stories/200707170344.html"> internal insurgencies&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.mg.co.za/articlePage.aspx?articleid=314156&amp;amp;area=/breaking_news/breaking_news__africa/">governmental use of child soldiers &lt;/a>and the &lt;a href="http://english.aljazeera.net/NR/exeres/6E28B770-9BDE-4241-A1F8-D5E4C4F56840.htm">spillover of conflict from sudan&lt;/a>.  but that isn’t what makes this news story interesting.  what interests me is the eu continuing its walk down the federalism aisle.  i’m not sure if their motivations are that they are of a singular mind with regards to foreign policy or if it is simply that in this case they could be of a singular mind with regard to the point.  taking these disparate countries who used to see the &lt;a href="http://ec.europa.eu/index_en.htm">EC&lt;/a> as merely an economic body and to watch the (almost) acquiesce to a constitution and then a reworking of the treaty to strengthen it further.  now the EU opens diplomatic missions and embassies in many small countries, rather than the individual countries performing the duties.  now the &lt;a href="http://europa.eu/index_en.htm">EU&lt;/a> sets monetary policy and development goals wherein the member countries are enabled to layer on top more support, but the EU is setting the minimum donor allocation to given countries.  for a long time the EU has participated in peace-treaty missions, but now it is acting with more &amp;ldquo;force&amp;rdquo; outside its normal sphere of influence (which kosovo admittedly was and i feel that that is a different situation in that there were spillover concerns as well as, likely, concerns about the possibilities for future former communist bloc states.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>the act of sending peace-keepers with an EU mandate i find inherently fascinating.  this is a fundamental (in my mind) difference from sending peace-keepers with a mandate from the UN or a regional international organization of which the affected country is a part of.  this is neither the OAU or the UN (chad is a member of each and therefore has ceded sovereignty to those organizations), but this is the EU acting with Chad’s blessing, but in a forceful way, creating peace and policing borders of a state which is not a member state of the IO’s. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>historically, at least since post WWII, the UN has been the organization with the mandate to maintain and restore the peace.  it has retained that mandate, but it has been watered down due to inefficiencies in the system, the lack of engagement by the powerful countries on the security counsel, and simple international politics and power-games.  at least in africa what has filled the gap have been regional international organizations.  for instance in western africa there is the economic community of west african states or &lt;a href="http://www.ecowas.int/">ECOWAS.&lt;/a>  ecowas started (like the EC) as a regional economic organization and eventually blossomed into the realm of peacekeeping when it sent the ECOWAS Military Observation Group or ECOMOG into Liberia (and subsequently other member states).  the ECOWAS member states argued in 1991 just before ECOMOG went into Liberia, that it was in the economic interest of the member states to build and maintain peace in each country of the member states.  similarly, the &lt;a href="http://www.africa-union.org/">OAU&lt;/a> and the &lt;a href="http://www.thecommonwealth.org/">Commonwealth&lt;/a> have also performed peacekeeping missions inside member states.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>again each of these makes sense to me as the &amp;ldquo;targetted&amp;rdquo; state has signed up for a given international organization and has a say in what they do.  the EU deployment to chad is different in that it is more like a bilateral partnership with the US, the UK, or the like.  but how can the EU which is a multilateral organization create bilateral partnerships without the member states of the multilateral organization either: (1) having a say in each and every decision which is wholly impossible especially in a peacekeeping mission with too many decision points (i say this in contrast to signing a services contract where the decisions points are up front and then maybe at renegotiation), or (2) the member states outsourcing decision making to the peacekeeping force itself or to the international organization.  the latter is what happens in the US where the individual states have outsourced all foreign policy matters to the federal government. see &lt;a href="http://coalitionfordarfur.blogspot.com/2007/07/chad-eu-must-agree-to-strong-mandate.html">this&lt;/a> for a discussion of the mandate that the EU will likely/should have.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>europe is definitely not to that point, (despite how flattering it would be for them to go that far) but i question how far it will get along the road before the policies of the member states become divergent.  it is easy for the member states to agree on the norm against genocide or crimes against humanity.  it is another thing if the EU wants to adopt a nuanced foreign policy position with regards to Russia’s response to &lt;a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/uk_news/politics/6902046.stm">Britain kicking out the Russian Diplomats&lt;/a>!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i don’t know where it is heading, and of course being american i am not so much of a stake holder, but it is interesting to watch nonetheless.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>more photos</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-13-more-photos/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-13-more-photos/</guid><description>&lt;p>have been able to put up most of my photos onto &lt;a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/caseykuhlman">picasa.&lt;/a> &lt;/p>
&lt;p>grab as many as you want.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>the elections</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-13-the-elections/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-13-the-elections/</guid><description>&lt;p>during the first month i was in africa i did not want to leave.  i was trolling the internet trying to figure out a way that i could stay in west africa.  i looked for jobs in salone, liberia, guinea, ghana, wherever, just to stay there.  i didn’t care if they paid or not, i didn’t care if they were prestigious or not.  as time grew on and i became more and more embroiled in the work i was doing and more and more frustrated with west africa my desires waned.  at the beginning i think it was more a manifestation of my frustration with the states, nashville, law school, etc. than it was a desire to never leave africa again. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>over time my feelings about africa turned from an infatuation into something like a better understand more akin to love where faults are recognized rather than painted over and beauty becomes completely subjective. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>one of the jobs that i researched at the beginning and would have considered doing throughout my waxes and wanes of desire to stay (but wouldn’t have done in the end as i came to europe for other reasons) was to monitor the elections that were originally supposed to be in july and have now been pushed back to august.  i emailed the carter group as well as the national democratic institute to see if either of them was monitoring the elections (nDi was) and if they needed help/volunteers/interns (they didn’t at the time, but that was early february).  ever since i arrived it was a hot button issues and whenever i was talking to saloneans and i ran out of topics like the weather and the fact that i was white but not likely to be able to sponsor their education in london through the graduate level and world news, i would turn to politics.  they were always happy to engage in a nice political debate and to give you their perspective on the political landscape as they saw it.  it was funny how authoritative they would speak about it.  i have since realized how &amp;ldquo;african&amp;rdquo; their speeches were.  they would nearly always begin at the beginning and give me the entire landscape with all its attendent complicating and simplifying factors from the 1968 elections up to the currently scheduled election, the traditional lines of support and the various tribal and chiefdom factors as they applied traditionally and currently.  one thing that struck me is how simple, yet complex within a given culture and situation, the game of politics is.  it is very straightforward and seemingly easy to play.  yet one must still remain within the systemic and cultural constraints, and these often provide the complications. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>the international crisis group has just yesterday published a &lt;a href="http://www.crisisgroup.org/home/getfile.cfm?id=3016&amp;amp;tid=4942&amp;amp;type=pdf&amp;amp;l=1">report&lt;/a> about the upcoming elections.   if you are interested in a western synopsis of the above, granted without the flair of the happy krio accent and grandiose hand gestures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>there are three main candidates: solomon berewa, charles margai and ernest koroma.  berewa is the current vice-president, leader of the SLPP and current frontrunner.  he generally represents a semi-compentence with a bit of international credibility, yet he has essentially been running the country since 2002 and so represents the status quo to many saloneance.  margai is the old gadfly who has been buzzing about salone politics for years, formerly SLPP and currently the leader of the newly formed PMDC.  he seems to have much to prove and overly eager, there is something about him that seethes corruption to me.  koroma is the wild-card and head of the APC.  no one seems very sure of him, although he is a bit younger than the others they all represent (to most saloneans i spoke with) shades of gray.  no one brings any true hope or really engages the imagination of the people.  this is a shame on all levels i can possibly think of.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>updates</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-06-27-updates/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-06-27-updates/</guid><description>&lt;p>have added little stories and captions to the pictures which were priorly unannotated in the &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/photos/colonialism/index.html">Salone&lt;/a> photo album, the &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/photos/little_america/index.html">Liberia&lt;/a> photo album and the &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/photos/visiting_cannibals/index.html">Upcountry&lt;/a> photo album.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>so far holland is much less photogenic and i’ve taken few pictures.  but maybe soon, i’ll quit working long enough to take some, and our holiday to georgia/azerbiajan is fast approaching. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>also added &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/underwater/maps_of_salone.html">maps&lt;/a> of Salone/Liberia so that you can follow along with the adventures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>back to this flipping paper i have to do for school.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>how to say good bye in krio</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-06-07-how-to-say-good-bye-in-krio/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-06-07-how-to-say-good-bye-in-krio/</guid><description>&lt;p>this afternoon i fly out of salone and have no plans to return any time in the next two years. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>last night i finished packing in my idiosyncratic, logical-but-only-to-me, methodical way.  then i put on some nice music and stood on my balcony watching my last salone sunset.  like so many others it was underwhelming.  the sun faded into clouds, but if you looked to the east the nice purples developed and if you looked to the west, above the clouds, you could see the pinks and oranges.  it makes a nice metaphor for my final week here.  so much excitement, disappointment, frustration and sadness wrapped into each moment.  it wasn’t the finality of leaving a beautiful place that got to me, it was everything else.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>on sunday 22 people died in a helicopter crash, but the only friggin’ reason that the damn bird was flying was because the owner of the heli company bribed the transportation minister after the last fire to let his company keep on flying.  two days ago the manager of the reservoir company which supplies the water to freetown was driving into freetown and saw some men filling their fire truck with public water to sell to lebanese and expat compounds.  they were stealing his water, and he is the one blamed whenever there is a shortage of water in freetown.  this practice is pervasive in the firemen community, apparently.  when the engineer stopped and told them not to do it, they beat him. to death. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>in a lot of ways it is time for me to leave here.  i feel that i have exhausted the good that i can do at this level of power which i currently possess.  i also feel, exhausted.  it is difficult, madening, and just tiring to live here.  but i love it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>the people are wonderful.  this morning martha was crying as i popped in my friends car buoyed by the prospects of my final adventure, undaunted by her tears lingering on my shoulder from our hug moments before.  i sat there and thought about the moment for a bit before i pulled out of my compound for the final time.  to me this has been an adventure, an exercise.  to saloneans, this is their life.  it breaks my heart.  a heavy cloud of sadness decending from the threatening rainclouds over my psyche. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>yesterday i drove with some friends through a tropical drenching with waterfalls all around tossing mud and trash onto streets and bridges making it all but passable.  the car had no a/c so the windshield was completely fogged at times, but people sauntered gingerly, just trying to keep their nice shoes from getting too mud splashed in the torential downpour with umbrellas to keep their beautiful, bright, colorful clothes pristine.  it blows my mind how long suffering these people are with their current state of existence. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>to me it is not surprising that there was a war, i’m only surprised that it actually ended and that it didn’t begin before it did. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>i drove up to leischeter peak this morning after leaving my compound for the final time.  i liked the circularity of it.  brett and i were driven up there on our first real day in salone.  it has a gorgeous view of the entire city, but when we arrived the harmatan winds had left the city opaque due to sahara dust.  today, because of the rains, the clarity hurt my eyes.  there were things that you couldn’t see, from the viewpoint you cannot see many of the larger slums throughout the city, and the beauty blows your mind.  the only sounds were birds and the clinks of people far below me whose only occupation is to break big rocks into smaller rocks…for something like $5 a week. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>up there i reflected upon how much i have learned here.  living one of the poorest countries in the world is doable.  you can create certain things if you know how to do it, you can host a party, you can get your car fixed, you can order catering.  you just have to know how to do it.  i finally feel like i reached the tipping point where i know how to do nearly everything that would need to happen, or at least i know who to talk to to get the number of someone that can do it for me.  it is a good feeling to feel settled and at ease with your surroundings.  it is surreal that those surroundings are not a new city or state in america, but rather one of the poorest countries in the world. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>this is it, this experience was a gamble.  if i had come to salone and hated my existence here all my pontifications and career decisions up to now would have been for naught.  but i have loved it here, and all those have been crystallized.  it is what i want to do.  here is why:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>last night i was sitting on the concrete surrounded by eight young african men all talking in krio.  i understood most of what they were saying, and they didn’t even bother to translate or keep me in the loop.  i laughed at their jokes.  i gave the approriate krio exclamatory statements.  i felt a part of their community.  two of my old gaurds had come by along with some others that were not currently on duty to farewell me.  we were just sitting.  one of them had a portable cd player and was playing a cd i gave him, the most famous salone artist: emerson.  the fifth track on the song is titled, miss you.  it is about giving a lover a second chance, fairly non-complex lyrics.  they one by one fell silent until one of the young ones stood up and did a little dance to the song.  then he asked me whether i knew what the song was about.  i lied and told him no.  he told me the first part of it and then said that it meant something to him, that they were all going to miss me.  then i quoted that part in krio where the singer says that the lover should give him a second chance.  i meant that at some point i’ll be back.  they all laughed and then kept on taking the piss out of one another.  i will remember that moment for a very long time. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>now, for the next adventure.  sweet salone, i bid you adieu.  let’s do this again sometime very soon, but for now i need to go do some other things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Two Little Stories</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-05-29-two-little-stories/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-05-29-two-little-stories/</guid><description>&lt;p>Have been saving two little stories.  Not sure why I have been saving them, but I have.  My time is starting to wind down here now and I feel compelled to clean some things up.  Not yet sure when I’m going to leave Salone, but it is going to be soon.  I think that the absolute latest I will be here will be the 20th, which is only three weeks and two weekends from now.  The soonest I’ll be able to leave will be mid-week next week.  For a lot reasons I’m over this place.  People are leaving at the speed of naught, the rains are coming and we have no Tv, new people are replacing the old and I cannot be bothered to get to know them when I’m such a short timer, and at any event no matter where you are it is difficult when you are a short timer.  I just want to do the few remaining things and get the muck out of here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first story is about a light.  A small little light, not hidden under a bush oh no.  I used to tell the first part of the story at dinner parties as I thought it was a nice picture of lost in translation, but then I realized that it wasn’t lost in translation and felt really bad.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When we first moved here the lights in the kitchen didn’t work.  In order to cook we had to leave the door to the refrigerator open to light the kitchen.  There were a lot of problems with this, not the least of which is that the refrigerator is only on during the night anyway and whatever is in there tends to partially cook during the day and so will only stay good for a very short time.  In addition the little of cool air that the food gets in the evening is compromised by having the door open.  Another in furiating thing is that the light coming out of the fridge was not very bright and it was still quite dreary.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a few nights I put my foot down.  Generally I like to think that with a little extra effort you can achieve a decent standard of living, and so along those lines I told our &amp;ldquo;landlord&amp;rdquo; that we just needed a light in the kitchen.  It was of no moment to me that she has a cook who she treats like shit and we cook for ourselves, I wasn’t bothered by the fact that she was never in there.  We were and she needed to provide a lamp for us.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So she conceded to buy a lamp and she told Ibrahim to go out the next day and buy a lamp.  Backflash a few days.  The light in Brett’s room wasn’t working and he had asked Ibrahim to buy a small reading light for him.  So Ibrahim had recently bought this little reading light for Brett, one of those small things that you clip onto the books.  But Brett’s also had a stand and you could plug it in. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>When the landlord asked Ibrahim to buy a lamp for the kitchen he bought another of these little reading things.  It didn’t light the kitchen as well as the small light in the fridge, but at least we didn’t have to leave the door open to the fridge and let our food further spoil!!!!  I used to tell this story as a funny bit to illustrate how easily things could get lost in translation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then a bit later I walked out of my compound and was heading down the hill to congo cross (the big intersection) to catch a cab and go somewhere…posh, i’m sure, and as I passed one of the little shack-villes i saw that there were seven people sitting around one of these little lights. it clicked for me then that it wasn’t lost in translation, this was what they knew.  Ibrahim didn’t know any better, I think.  To him that was a lamp to light a room. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>It broke my heart for a lot of reasons. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>The second story ends with the following phrase: so at least now I’ve had my alone, car broke down, no money and no phone in a third world country miles from no where story.  You’ll have to ask me that one over a beer! &lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>too much&amp;#8230;.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-05-21-too-much/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-05-21-too-much/</guid><description>&lt;p>finally!  i got up country.  it was beautiful, amazing, heart-breaking, remarkable, human, surprising and wonderful.  my friends had been planning for all week to go upcountry, but seeing that it was highlands next to last weekend here and it was looking like we would be able to spend a good deal of time together that was more important to me.  i thought i could figure out a way to get upcountry later, even though the rains are coming (btw i know now what the phrase feels like…at least a little bit).  then due to some work-related B.S. it turned out that highlands was going to have to work ALL weekend. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>i thought that it would then be ridiculous to stay here and just sit on my bum all weekend when everyone else that i cared about was upcountry having fun.  so i decided to go.  the only question was how the hell to get up country to meet them.  they had a car that blazed our identity to anyone who knows just a little bit.  the license plate is blue and has a nice code which reveals our identity to all who know.  yet, they were already in bo the second largest city in sierra leone.  and i was six hours away in freetown.  i put my white boy-ness aside for a bit and thought that africans are doing it all the time.  so i went downstairs to talk to my guards about the who/what/when/where/why.  they told me that if i got on the poda-poda bus at like 4 in the morning i could get up to bo by 8 or so.  i decided it was all systems go.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>woke up at four in the morning on saturday to begin the adventure.  hopped on the back of a motorcycle taxi to go downtown to the place where the buses are.  met up with some folks to find out the correct bus.  at about 5:30 the bus finally got underway.  they sit us five across, so i did not have enough room to get the money out of my pocket to pay (later in the morning).  for the first part it was quiet as everyone was sleepy.  but it was still like every movie i’ve ever seen with the one white human on the developing country bus.  i was smooshed in with all the africans who were going to see family and what not.  it was loud and hot and bumpy and hot and dusty and hot and smelly and hot.  it was great!  i had my bag on my lap and just gaiped through the entire five hour ride.  got up to bo about 1030 in the morning, hopped on a different motorcycle taxi and met up with my friends.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>all along the ride i was surprised at how open everything was.  freetown is really really congested, but once you get outside of freetown there is so much space and air.  the space feels larger due to all the deforestation (but that is a different post entirely).  feng shui aside, it was beautiful countryside.  will put up picts when i can get some bandwidth.  the little villages we passed along the way were neat and orderly.  the houses were all in lines not helterskelter, there was zero trash lying around, the cooking pits and wells and toilets were all clearly dilineated, even to my eye as 60 kph on a bus with dust covered windows.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>we trolleyed off in the car after i met up with them towards kenema.  on our way we saw all these kool villages and decided to stop at one.  these villages were the real deal.  i mean it was AFRICA.  it was authentic.  it was real.  it hasn’t changed in centuries.  they live in clay houses.  first they build with sticks cut down from medium-sized trees with machetes a lattice-work and then they fill in the holes with mud.  it is like building with bricks, but not.  they put on a roof of palm fronds which doesn’t really work in the rainy season.  we sat around in their community center chatting with them about the seasons, voting preference, voting knowledge, how to farm corn, what it is like to have cobras biting your chilren when they are supposed to be learning their three R’s, the perils of having people use the toilet wherever they like, the intricacies of soccer in the bush, proper cutlass (machete) technique, stories old legends and other topics which i cannot currently remember.  there were a few men eloquent in english and the rest sort of stood around and listened.  we toured the place and took tons of pictures.  they have, in this village of less than 200, a mosque and a church.  they pay for their own teacher as it is too far for the kids to walk to school.  they grow rice and beans and corn and other vegetables and coconuts and mangoes and papaya.  they cook as a community.  it was crazy. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>i would have stayed there all afternoon just talking, but we had other things to do.  rolled out and rocked up to kenema town.  there wasn’t much of a place to park, except for at the radio station.  we got out and of course tons of africans piled out to see the aputus (white people in mende). since we continually pay the complexion tax and get charged more for everything we buy i figured we should turn in some of that so i asked if we could get a tour of the radio station.  they were happy to comply.  so we got a tour of the little kenema radio station which broadcasts for a quarter of this country the bbc feed and other local programming.  the station manager gave me some good leads on good, older SL music. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>we walked around in the stifling heat, sweating.  saw crazy, sketchy diamond dealers, a few other notable things.  then we rocked out of town to see this catholic mission.  it was beautiful and wide open with lines of coconut palm trees planted in orderly fashion, old buildings in a college like campus environ.  the beautiful hills were backset and the beautiful people were foreset.  it was wonderfully relaxing.  we all thought it would be brilliant if freetown had a place where you could go, sit outside in the shade on a blanket and read a book or take a picnic too.  but alas, freetown is too crazy for that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>then we wanted to see some diamond mines.  it was the ostensible reason for the trip, so we decided to do it.  we hired a motorbike taxi to lead us out to this famous place, tongo fields.  but first a sidebar.  there are two types of mining that are done in SL, the first is alluvial mining.  this is the sifting of the river that you saw in blood diamonds, over the years the diamonds work their way to the surface and then flow down the rivers.  this is done by two man crews.  the second is called kimberlite mining, this is the more traditional &amp;ldquo;mining&amp;rdquo; where there are veins which are diamond rich and the company has to bore down into the earth to get it.  this is industrial with caterpillars and dynamite etc.  if you want to read more check &lt;a href="http://www.reliefweb.int/library/documents/2001/pac-sie-jan00.pdf">here&lt;/a>.  tongo fields which is outside of kenema town is the largest kimberlite vein in SL.  after talking to person after person we worked our way out to tongo fields, past a couple of alluvial, artisinal mining pits and many artisinal miners.  we first had to go to the main diamond office, it was the certification people who are in charge of ensuring that the diamonds are certified as conflict free.  they work for the government.  the first guy took us to his bosses house.  the boss was having a bbq in the back yard with some friends.  there were a few beers around and a deer head on the fire pit.  i’m not kidding. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>this guy took us to another guy who worked at the koidu holdings diamond mine (the big, industrial one).  that guy took us to the gate. we talked to the security gaurds and then to a policeman and then to another governmental certification guy and finally to the chief of security for the entire mine.  we weren’t able to talk our way inside, neither were we able to bribe our way inside. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>so we got back in the car as we wanted to return to bo before nightfall and had a long way to go.  had a low tire on the way home, but filled it up and luckily it held air so we kept going and made it back to the &amp;ldquo;hotel&amp;rdquo; in bo.  it wasn’t bad, similar to a shitty roadside hotel in nowhere’sville ar-kansas.  had a bit of dinner which was two small fishes bbqed over coal pit and some rice and a little salad which will likely fill me with typhoid virsuses.  then, having been up since four in the morning, i was too exhausted to stay awake to debrief for the day so i fell asleep.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>the next morning we got up with the intention of just driving home; little did he know what adventures lay before him.  after a breakfast of toast and a fried egg and some butter we piled in the car.  this day it was my day to drive.  there were three of us who wanted to drive, urs drove the first day, jason drove the second day, and it was my turn the third day.  lynn didn’t want to drive and brett doesn’t know how to drive manual.  idiot. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>first we toured, quickly the city of bo, including a stop to put in some diesel in the tank of a land cruiser that we were driving.  also had to fill up the tire again which was still holding on, but had gone a little low over the night.  then we got a wild hair that we wanted to go see the grave of one of the warlords that was indicted by the court here and has recently died.  he is a legend and a very controversial figure b/c most SL’s think that he was the only thing that kept this country together and most of them wonder why he was indicted by the court.  that, also, is another post entirely.  but in the part of the country where we were the court is NOT liked one iota.  and here we were rocking out with a vehicle that might as well have our employer’s name posted on the side like the NGO’s that rock around here.  we figured it was stupid so why not. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>in bo we hired another motorbike taxi to take us out to this village that was &amp;ldquo;eight&amp;rdquo; miles away (read 38) down this bush road.  he led and i followed in the tank down bush road after bush road.  at one point the bush grass formed, essentially, a tunnel that i was forced to go through.  if i can get the video up here i will.  the grass was smacking the car on both sides and i have zero clue what the hell i was supposed to do if there was oncoming traffic.  luckily the only thing we saw oncoming was a few men on bikes loaded down with water and fuel jerry cans. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>we drove down the roads and got to the village where we had to turn off.  we rocked up to the police station and talked to some elders of the village that were standing outside the station, then we drove down a couple of houses to talk to the paramount chief (read..essentially…major of the county), this was the guy who replaced the legendary warlord.  after a little talking to a bunch of people and exchanges of gifts and a beer we piled an ex-combatant nephew of the warlord into the passenger seat and then surrounded ourselves with four motorbikes loaded down with the warlord’s followers for the three mile drive up to his grave.  it was a four-wheel-drive road up into the hills and it was brilliantly beautiful. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>we finally got to the warlord’s village and took pictures with his brother at his mausoleum.  then hightailed it out of there.  the nephew, who lives in freetown, asked a couple of us under his breath what our &amp;ldquo;real mission was&amp;rdquo;.  we’re pretty sure that he knew who we worked for but didn’t say anything to anyone else, or if he did, they didn’t care.  we dropped off the nephew at the bottom of the hill to continue their ceremony of the five year anniversary of his father’s death party/gathering that we had interrupted when we rolled up.  he said we were the first white people since the burial to roll out there.  very interesting!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>then the road, if possible, got even more hairy.  we passed by this town really, truly in the bush called yele.  there was an SDA mission there with a primary school and a secondary school.  they were actually quite large.  i thought maybe i could stop and meet someone from andrews or southern, but decided against it.  we got up the road farther and stopped in a village to confirm that we were going the correct way and asked them how much further to this one town…of course the answer was only a few miles.  SLeans are good at some things, but they are AWEFUL at distances, everything was 5 miles…even when it is 30 miles!  anyway the guy said yeah it is just up the road five miles, you go past the ferry and then you’ll see it.  i started to pull the car away and then something clicked…ferry?  so i reversed and asked him what he meant about ferry and he said that it was a town named ferry.  my heart slowed down.  that would have been too much adventure.  my foot was already getting tired from constantly shifting up and down.  i know, i know, i’m kind of a pansy, but this was 6 hours into a long bush drive where the longest i was in one gear was only a matter of minutes. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>the road becomes impossible and suddenly we come up to a bridge that we think has a huge hole in it.  but it was only our perspective, actually there were logs covering the hole.  so jason got out to inspect and he thought everything was OK.  i thought, hell the drop is only 15 feet if it collapses.  everyone gets out of the vehicle save me.  i remember wondering as i drove slowly onto the bridge whether the tank had airbags or not.  luckily i never had to find out, the logs held the tanks and i got across without incident.  that, to me, was the most sketchy thing about the bush roads, what if one of the bridges we were crossing every five minutes went out.  i mean we had 4WD, but still….anyway we get on up through village after impossibly small village…all deserted b/c it was sunday and most of them (we think) were at church. then we pass through a larger town with a market, i go around a road block, down a gorge and suddenly there is a river and there is no bridge over it.  the FERRY!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>the ferry is essentially a huge wooden barge and there is a cable that runs from one bank to another that the barge is clipped too.  there are men who man the barge and they manually pull it from one side to the other by tugging on the cable.  so they tug across to ourside and then the tank, us and some bike dudes drive/walk/ride onto the barge.  then the rest of them pulled her across the river…wait till you see the picts of this!  i’m not even to the hairy part of this oregon trail journey yet.  on the other side they couldn’t get the landing ramp fitted onto the bank correctly b/c there was a gigantic hole which i wasn’t going to be able to drive the tank across!  but eventually they got some logs situated and jason (who by the way works in northern canada as a manager of oil rigs and is here visiting lynn (his fiance) for a few months as they cannot really work right now while the land is defrosting) supervised it, so i felt better.  across the tank went and then up the hill.  4Low baby!  then we had good roads all the way back to freetown, rolled into town to a gorgeously clear day where the bay was glistening with the nice sunset. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>FABULOUS!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>my little jazz place</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-04-29-my-little-jazz-place/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-04-29-my-little-jazz-place/</guid><description>&lt;p>so for much of my life i have had this fantasy that i would eventually find a jazz club that would replace in my mind the absence of me not being alive in the late 50′s and early 60′s and being black and living in NYC and therefore unable to stoll down 52d street and hear coltrane and others jamming in real-time and only for themselves.  although i’ve been all over the states, i have yet to find anything that feels/is truly authentic.  everything just seems, kitchy or not good enough to be authentic and have great jaz artists.  i think i came close, in my mind at least, to finding the proper environs in this smoky little underground club on the left banc of paris.  but the artists that cam and i saw there were not totally up to par with my fantasy!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i found my place, though, in the oddest of locations: dakar.  i know that many of you may be quite over my raving about dakar, but deal with it.  this place (picts coming soon right now there are technical difficulties) is amazing.  it is a little bar with a tiki hut thing in the middle of it with a small stage on the front right and just tables everywhere.  they are so relaxed about everything…the artists, the staff, the patrons.  brett at one point jumped on stage with a band and started playing the marraccas along with the band in the most arrogant and stupid and hillarious display of white-boy-ness that i’ve seen in….a long flipping time. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>although the environment was not closed and was not velvetty and was not terribly smokey given that it was open air and there were palm trees growing in the veranda/patio/open air area, the music made it almost complete.  the first night we were there we listened to &lt;a href="http://www.allmusic.com/cg/amg.dll?p=amg&amp;amp;sql=11:wpfqxqt5ldfe">orchestra baobab&lt;/a>.  they had this tenorman that i wanted to sire his children, he was so chill, so beat, so amazing.  the band was powerful with afro-cubano roots and a lot of straight jazz influence, it was improvisational, serene and over the top in its grandiosity. the second night we listened to &lt;a href="http://www.waflash.net/">waflash&lt;/a>.  she was seductive, a billy holiday of west african beats.  wonderfully relaxed, sexy environs for a nice sunday evening listen.  then the last night we heard &lt;a href="http://www.allmusic.com/cg/amg.dll?p=amg&amp;amp;sql=11:diftxqwhld0e">cheikh lo&lt;/a> who is one of the god fathers of senegalese music.  he is a drummer and a singer.  he is a rasta.  he had this nice band. he played straight senegalese music, straight west african tunes. he had crazy native dancers with him that did stuff i’ve never, ever seen the human body do. he was the spiritual leader of his entire crowd.  i drank a soda with him at via roma at 5 in the morning after his show. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>listen, listen, listen to these people.  they are all on itunes.  also the most famous godfather of them all yousou n’dour is on itunes as well.  buy all of their music. it will blow your mind. i know it is copywrite infringement and i don’t care. below is a song that could turn the grinch into mary poppins as far as i’m concerned. it is by yousou n’dour.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/underwater/files/track_12.mp3">Download track_12.mp3&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>on the final night we were in dakar we were walking from just for you, the main music venue where we saw all of these people, aka my jazz bar to a place called: the jazz bar which was around the corner.  there we had heard some decent reggae and had heard that this old guitar dude was supposed to go on late…on our way i found this house half way between the two on a nice quiet street. i want it. it has joined this house in the keys that i fantasize about owning whenever i pass it as one of the houses i would give most anything to own.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>dakar is THAT good. now back to talking about where i currently am: crazy, crazy Sierra Leone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Isle de HOLY Crap</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-04-24-isle-de-holy-crap/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-04-24-isle-de-holy-crap/</guid><description>&lt;p>[![Imgp1749][2]][2] So there were two themes that I wanted to clean-up from the Senegal trip.  The first is this little artist community that exists on Isle de Goree a thirty minute ferry ride from Dakaar.  The second will come later.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/04/29/imgp1749.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/04/29/imgp1749.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Isle de Goree has, at various times, been a defensive position protecting the bay where the port of Dakaar is and/or a slave exporting island.  Most times the slave traders would take slaves to islands off the coast of West Africa and then barter with the transportation people there on the island.  This was safer than doing it on the mainland as the slaves couldn’t escape back into the jungle.  Also the traders didn’t know exactly when a new ship would be coming to pick up a new load of people to take away to historical and continued oppression and exploitation. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![Imgp1750_2][3]][3] So all along the coast of West Africa there are these islands.  Isle de Goree markets itself as one of these, but in truth the garrison on the island is small enough that it could only have held a small number of people, therefore the modern historical perspective on the island is that it was a slave trading post, but always a minor one. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/04/29/imgp1750_2.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/04/29/imgp1750_2.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then you get to the other historical role for the island.  On the island there was a colonial era fortress, WWI cannons and WWII shore guns, all coexisting in various spots on the island.  The colonial one faced the shore, likely because their range was short and they’d want to get the ships as they were approaching the port before wasting their ammunition.  The WW guns with their further ranges were facing out to see. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![4382455][4]][4] Currently the island is a tourist trap for people wanting to reconcile the history of slavery.  But many of those people, myopic in their pilgrimage miss much of the modern beauty of the island.  Now it is full of art, which is mostly located one end of the island.  There is this one hill on the seaward side of the island that has this huge hill, it is where the WW guns are facing out to sea. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/04/29/4382455.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/04/29/4382455.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you come to the bottom of the hill you see all kinds of painted wall art.  Beautiful primary colors in traditional senegalese motifs.  It was, by far, the best art I’ve seen in Africa.  As you wind your way up the switchbacks on the side of the hill you transition slowly such that at the tip, intertwined with the bunkers of war and the desolate, abandoned guns is the junk art. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![Imgp1743][5]][5] Along the way you meet may rastafarians and other truly hip people that live on this island.  Most of the guys who make the junk art at the top of the hill live in the bunkers under the guns and they all have one teacher: the professor.  The professor sold me a piece of work that is going to go to Brian. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/04/29/imgp1743.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/04/29/imgp1743.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is the most truly beat place I’ve ever been, Isle de Goree.  I have often wondered if Kerouac and Cassady and the rest were alive today where would they be?  Would modern transportation possibilities have altered their fascination with America and their intention to dominate it by seeing all of it?  I’m not sure. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![Imgp1754][6]][6]I think that at a minimum it would have tightened their cycles such that everything would happen faster, they would have gotten bored faster since they would have been able to see many things quic ker.  So I think that many of them may have focussed outside the US.  But maybe not.  Nevertheless, if they did, I think many of them would have dug the beat characters that I found on the Isle. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/04/29/imgp1754.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/04/29/imgp1754.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now if I could just find a willing art dealer in the states I could start my own import business of Senegalese art.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>senegalese music</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-04-06-senegalese-music/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-04-06-senegalese-music/</guid><description>&lt;p>i leave for senegal in just a bit on Sloc, some airline that has a less stellar safety record…apparently.  although from what I’ve heard they aren’t as bad as others in west africa, so maybe i’ll be ok.  plus they play backstreet boys loud and on the speakers so everyone is able to enjoy the festivities. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>senegal, from what i can tell, is a mecca for tourists who desire adventure, good music, good food, maybe a pick-pocketing here and there, cafes, bookstores and the beach.  i crave all of the above.  but mostly i’m looking forward to being able to run up my credit cards even higher!  here i am limited by a completely cash based economy.  there, i’ll be able to ruin my credit rating further!  sa-WEET. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>more on the craziness of that country when i arrive!  also will likely touch mauritania and The Gambia whilst there.  OUTTY!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>still alive</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-03-28-still-alive/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-03-28-still-alive/</guid><description>&lt;p>sorry. not dead, just lost.  no days off, but at least the work is interesting.  we file april 4th, so i will have a life again after that. looking forward to my trip to senegal and the gambia the 6th through the 15th.  right now there is a heated euro politico debate in my office between a right wing german-swiss and a left wing french-swiss. it’s awesome!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>check this out. it is kind of a postscript to the movie: &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2007/03/25/world/africa/25diamonds.html?_r=1&amp;amp;oref=slogin" title="Diamonds Move From Blood to Sweat and Tears - New York Times">Diamonds Move From Blood to Sweat and Tears&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>i little trip to the mall</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-03-06-i-little-trip-to-the-mall/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-03-06-i-little-trip-to-the-mall/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/underwater/images/190207_1921.jpg" alt="190207_1921">i hate malls. i really really hate everything about them. i hate how large they are. i hate that massive retention ponds must be created to pool the flow of water that is not allowed to seep into the ground properly over a dissipated region, but is instead pooled in isolated areas. the outsourcing of the environmental degredation annoys me. i hate how they all are the same, one or two paradigms determine the layout. i hate the food they sell. i hate that they are owned by all of us who own mutual funds and don’t really care where our money goes to except for the fact that we get something towards our retirement golf community dream.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>but malls in africa are different. there are two markets in freetown. i have written about those earlier. i guess what i’m describing in this post is more like the grocery store. but, for the most part, everything that my soap boxing deals with is applicable to grocery stores. except for the fact that i do, in fact, go to those without bitching and moaning like a child who doesn’t want to go ski.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>almost every evening i walk out the gate of my compound and down the dirt road towards king street.  sitting along this road is lance.  he sits in his second story balcony looking out onto frazier-davies dr (which is the dirt road, off king street). usually if i go early they are praying, his building is sort of an all-purpose store, mosque, residence.  it is odd that lance is rarely not outside.  when it is dark it is even more odd, b/c he will just be sitting there.  i often wonder what old lance is thinking about.  regardless, he is always friendly to me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![240207_1659][3]][3]king street is narrow and fairly steep. when two cars pass each other, you want to have nothing to do with that. the ditches are deep on either side of king street and sidewalks are a luxury that only the cotton tree foundation (some sort of an educational NGO, but i personally think is a front for some tax right-off from the developed world as it is the nicest house on king street but none of my guards or the locals that i now know in the area have seen anyone going into the cotton tree foundation complex…they also keep it lit up like a beacon of misplaced hope at night, which is pleasant for me as there are no street lights on king street.) can afford.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/240207_1659.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/240207_1659.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>the tenuous part is not only the fact that the ditches are really quite deep and filled with sewage, but also the fact that when it is really dark and the taxicab drivers are incompetant and always have their brights on, so the effect is that your night vision is constantly getting fucked with and when you look down to see where the ditch has gone to now you cannot see your feet b/c the rods and cones are dazzled by the brilliance of the taxicab driver’s incompetence. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![240207_1701][4]][4]king street is steep, but not too bad. if you make it down to the bottom (~300 meters) you reach congo cross.  congo cross is the marker by which we tell all cabbies how to get us home.  everyone knows it.  during the freetown invasion of 1999 the bridge over the congo river was the demarcation line where the nigerian troops that were ostensibly defending the democratically elected government (for better or worse) made their stand.  most things west of that bridge stayed relatively safe (save for some minor insurgent activity), and east of that bridge it was completely and utterly fucked. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/240207_1701.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/240207_1701.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>in utter freetown style, however, the congo cross roundabout which everyone knows as congo cross is a mile from where the bridge actually goes over the bridge.  the roundabout has some creepy statute on it, which i’ll have a pict for you shortly.  it is also the worst designed roundabout i’ve seen in a long time.  i think they may have imported the DC urban planners to create that flippin’ round about.  traffic is continually congested along king street heading down towards congo cross (see first pict) and if i head home on the seven o’clock transport (which, lately, has been more rare) when i walk down king street there is a line of polio victims asking for &amp;ldquo;small, small.&amp;rdquo;  usually i have a little something, but more usually when i return i give them something tangible, like bread or fish. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![240207_1703][5]][5]congo cross is a festival of sounds. people yelling, cops &amp;ldquo;directing traffic&amp;rdquo; (which is really an excuse to get the cabbies to give them money), whistles, horns, beeps of the pimped out cabs and &amp;ldquo;poda poda’s&amp;rdquo; (more about this freaks later), kids running around and laughing, usually people are singing in one of the seven churches that are within earshot of the roundabout. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/240207_1703.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/240207_1703.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i usually start by going all the way across the roundabout to bah the egg man, usually i have to spend a few minutes joking with his friends ibrahim and cherry pie (my nickname for a name that i cannot pronounce, plus the day i first met him he was wearing a red shirt, and he hates the nickname, becuase it sounds too effiminate to him…therefore i continually do it…often time accompanied by a little rendition of the song). from bah i buy most of the staples, eggs, crackers, bisquits (the british version, not the southan version), etc.  then i start working my way up the street to the left.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>next stop is aunty may who sells me my grapefruits and mangos.  she likes to try to stiff me, jokingly giving me half my change and then pretending to walk away. she turns around, however, too early…this is b/c she is old and only has enough energy to take the joke so far.  she is always one of the most appreciative traders about the fact that i come down with my own bag and i don’t need a &amp;ldquo;plastic.&amp;rdquo; &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![240207_1704][6]][6]next stop is usually alex, the bread man.  the bread here is really good, but you have to buy it fresh as they don’t use any preservatives, so at most they will keep fresh for a day or 36 hours from when i buy them.  though younger than i, alex has a gigantic tumor on the side of his head.  it looks like a portobello mushroom growing out of his right cheek.  i’m not sure what it is, but when joe comes (another story entirely, but JOE IS COMING…end of may) i’ll introduce them. maybe, but doubtfully, there is something joe could do for him. jared, likely could do something for him, being that jared is a face surgeon and all, but not sure jared can or would want to come.  alex is a quiet man who unfortunately has his stall sited at the end of the row of traders. not sure why i started buying bread from him, but i like him and whenever the others try to sell to me, i just shake my head…by now they know not to even ask.  i’m loyal to ole’ alex…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/240207_1704.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/240207_1704.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![240207_1705][7]][7]after alex i have one more stop. the kwality store (yes, it is spelled phonetically). the kwality store is run by mohammed, who is a lebanese. there is a lebanese mafia around here that runs most of the high level trading (which is why i prefer to do as much shopping at the local stalls as i can, and only like to go to the real grocery stores for things i cannot buy at the stalls, like cheese and pasta and decent shampoo…this way my money stays in the country AND doesn’t fund hezbollah). i’m ok buying from mohammed though because he just has a small store, not gigantic.  from mohammed i buy any canned goods i need (especially tomatoes, spinach, mushrooms, which aren’t as good out of the can, but won’t give me typhoid) and bottles of water and sodas.  every night i buy my gaurds sodas. prince likes &amp;ldquo;GinGA BEEr&amp;rdquo; which he nearly screams, because he get so excited about it. prince likes these strawberry shake things. ibrahim and francis are boring and take cokes. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/240207_1705.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/240207_1705.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>after that then i trudge up king street loaded down with the day’s worth of groceries and happy. i love talking to the people. i love the way at first they were confused about this white boy who actually walks around, but now they are getting used to my visits. i love how the people that aren’t used to me like to call me &amp;ldquo;white boy&amp;rdquo; and i say, &amp;ldquo;wow, you are quite observant&amp;rdquo; and then the people that do know me laugh….see mom…sarcasm IS the international language!  when i get up to the white international school sign (see pict 5) and take a left i’m usually sweaty and itchy (there are so many toxins in the air that whenever my pores open i get a bit itchy). b/c there is no air in the kitchen by the time i finish cooking and eating i may have stopped sweating….but not always.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i work now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>leadership challenges</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-28-leadership-challenges/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-28-leadership-challenges/</guid><description>&lt;p>This &lt;img src="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/underwater/images/160207_0812.jpg" alt="160207_0812">post is long overdue.  But forgive me, it took a while for me to have a chance to pull the pictures off my phone.  Let me introduce you to the people that have a chance, everyday, to steal my shit and for some reason do not. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I was in the Marine Corps, we had a saying that there were no bad Marines, simply bad leaders.  It is was a bit self-deprecating of Marine officers to take all the blame for psychotic Marines and their actions, but it is one of the many things that make the USMC such a great organization.  We tempered the saying when we were around the Marines who were trouble by calling them &amp;ldquo;leadership challenges.&amp;rdquo; &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![140207_0804][3]][3]since i’ve been here my dreams have been riddled with USMC references.  this, i’m sure is due to a lot of things.  not the least of which is the larium which turns my dreams most nights into a kaliedoscopic cinema that i never experience without drugs. usually, i rarely think about the marine days.  in a lot of ways i have closed that part of my life off.  there was a lot to it.  it made me, for better or worse, the human i am today. but i’ve moved on mentally and philosophically.  and yet i keep dreaming with references to those times and those feelings that i experienced during my nine year interaction with that institution.  much of it, i’m sure is that i’m an intern at a war crimes tribunal working a case that is in the pre-trail stages.  all i do all day long is read about war. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/140207_0804.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/140207_0804.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![160207_0813][4]][4] but there is another reason, i think as well.  that is that i’m forced to use a lot of the leadership techniques that i developed as a marine officer.  the help around the house is not that much different than an infantryman and, frankly, dealing with my &amp;ldquo;staff&amp;rdquo; (for lack of a less pejorative term i’ll rest on that term) feels the same.  i think those three things all cut towards having lots of USMC references in my dream-scape.  but i’ve rattled too much, now to the introductions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/160207_0813.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/160207_0813.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>first there is martha (spelled, pronounced like a rasta would say matter…ma-TA).  she runs the entire show.  she cleans, washes, coordinates everything.  a couple of months before we arrived she had a baby.  after she got pregnant her b/f left her.  she, apparently, didn’t care.  she was just so happy to have a child on the way, b/c before this latest b/f she was married for a few years and could not concieve.  she was shunned by her family and his. finally they got divorced, citing the lack of children as the primary reason.  so when she became pregnant, finally, she felt vindicated of everything people had spoken about her.  she told me that she didn’t even care when her b/f left her.  she named her daughter blessing.  i named her story, bible-esque.  blessing is quiet…i have yet to hear an african baby cry, not once, they seem to have the silent resolve of everyone around here bred rather than beat into them…and cute as can be.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![240207_1706][5]][5]next there is ibrahim, our caretaker.  we have settled on a supervision scheme wherein i’m responsible for supervising the outside the house guys and another housemate is responsible for the inside the house ladies.  so far, it is working out fine.  ibrahim is not a bad guy, but he is lazy.  again, no different than all the marines i knew.  he pressed me at the beginning of when i took over supervision of him. when i called him out and corrected him, he fell in line just fine.  i am very clear and precise with him. i don’t ask a lot out of his cognizance. and it is fine.  we haven’t had a single issue with him not being around or available or not meeting a deadline since i’ve taken over responsibility.  a little hands on goes a long ways. ibrahim has a wife and a three y/o son, but he stays many nights at the house.  he is honest and i would trust him with nearly anything i own, which is good b/c he carries a keyring full of every key to every door in the house!  he speaks quite good english, and sometimes has to work as my krio interpreter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/240207_1706.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/240207_1706.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>the next pict is of patricia.  patricia is the cook for one of our housemates.  she doesn’t cook for brett and i, but we are thinking of hiring her for a little while.  our housemate is leaving for a few weeks to return to the states and patricia is the only breadwinner for her family that has three boys.  unfortunately her husband was recently laid off due to lack of work (i’m not sure what he did).  her boys come with her as they go to school down the street.  they are 11, 8, and 6.  also very cute and respectful little dudes.  i get a kick out of them.  my main interactions with patricia are as my krio (pronounced similar to creole, only faster and lazier) teacher.  every morning she teaches me some new krio or reminds me of what i forgot that she told me the day before. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>finally we get to &amp;ldquo;the boys.&amp;rdquo;  unfortunately i only have a picture of one of the boys, fouday (pronounced &amp;ldquo;foodie&amp;rdquo;).  that is him sitting outside the gate to our compound reading his textbooks and waiting for me to come back from the market with his coke.  we have three night gaurds that rotate.  each night only two of them are on. we have one main day guard, and one that comes during his days off.  the day guard i rarely get a chance to talk to, as mornings are usually filled with me telling ibrahim what i need him to do during the day and other errands.  the night, guards, however i’ve gotten fairly close to.  they call me school teacher, b/c they say when i’m talking to them i adopt these speech patterns that remind them of a lecturer.  it is the only way i know how to talk so that they can understand, though. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>fouday is in college studying to be an accountant.  he is a wily little one, but friendly and trustworthy.  frankly he is the only one of the bunch that has any initiative.  he was the second person in his constituency to register to vote when that started earlier this week.  he is in school every morning and works for us at least five nights a week.  he tells me he has a girlfriend, but the others aren’t so sure as no one has been able to see this young lady before.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>francis. oh francis.  i wish i had a picture of him, as he is a piece of work!  francis is the most emotional non-french-man i’ve ever met. in fact he might be the most emotional man i’ve ever met.  when he talks, he talks EXACTLY like a southern baptist preacher talks. exactly. and yet i can never understand what the fuck he is saying.  he has the most distinct krio accent of any of them.  i still can usually only make out the gist of what he is saying, so most of his nuances are lost on me.  francis’s twin sister just passed away two days ago and he will be up-country for a couple of days for the funeral.  she died giving birth, and the baby is currently living, but mama has passed on.  it is really sad and horrible.  but it is life here.  francis told me earlier this week (pre-sister’s death, when happy francis was with us) that he was reserving who to vote for in the election until god spoke to him.  he said we have no president, god is our president, only He can lead us…or something to that effect, again, the nuances are usually lost.  i thought that he hadn’t been told by his preacher who to vote for yet…but will be soon! francis is very religious (obviously). he is also very superstitious. his father is what is called a paramount chief of Bo district, in the eastern part of the country (here they divide up the chiefdoms, which are presided over by chiefs (think counties) and then districts, which are presided over by paramount chiefs (think states) and has seven wives.  francis is one of 19 (i think) children of his father. 19. shit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>and finally there is prince.  prince is shorter than the other guys and he always wears this chicago bulls winter cap. i always tease him about how hot it is here and why the hell is he wearing that hat.  prince was really quiet when we first arrived. in fact the first full night i was here i went out to visit with the guards and he was reading Gone With the Wind under a light near the gate.  he didn’t really talk for the first two weeks, but now he is opening up.  he and i talk about the stars.  he comes from a village in the northern part of the country.  he told me about eclipses and how nothing good comes after them.  he told me of the few african constellations. he finished Gone with the Wind and I gave him a book that I brought over about the CIA setting up the Shah in the 50′s in Iran.  he really likes it so far. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>well that is it for now. the introductions are made and now i can speak about them without making the requisite backstory.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pictures</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-28-pictures/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-28-pictures/</guid><description>&lt;p>Added more picts today to the album.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Beaches &amp;amp; Hospitals</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-19-beaches-hospitals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-19-beaches-hospitals/</guid><description>&lt;p>[ ![Imgp1261_edited1][2]][2] This series of pictures is from the beach this weekend.  For a long time I have considered the statement: it has the best beaches in the world, or at least in
Africa&lt;/p>
&lt;p>.  I would hedge for a couple of reasons.  The first is that, of course, I’m not stranger to beaches.  Something would be hard-pressed to pass up the beach on the Navy Base in
Key West&lt;/p>
&lt;p>or the beach near Sunshine Key or 1000 Steps in
California&lt;/p>
&lt;p>.  The second is that, I’m not even sure what that phrase means.  Usually I hate getting wrapped around minor semantical differences.  I really am not bagging on the verbiage choices, what I mean is that I don’t understand how one could even make the claim?  What would one base it upon?  Sand/Surf/Beer/People/No-People/Views? &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![Imgp1265][3]][3] It is amorphous, because each of these things seemingly has an ideal on the spectrum that a beach, were it personified in a blog, should strive for.  White, sandy beaches. Clear Water.  Consistent good weather.  But there are other categories which the ideal cannot as easily be classified.  It depends on whether one wants people around or deserted in order to classify an ideal.  It depends on whether one wants a bar and restaurant on the beach or not in order to classify an ideal.  Nevertheless this beach was pretty damn kool.  Around the corner from where this picture runs out was a little lagoon that was gorgeous.  I went around the corner and there was a woman walking topless with her back to me.  I turned around to be polite and as I was turning saw her boyfriend.  I felt bad for interrupting their quiet time. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![Imgp1267][4]][4]So I went and played among the rocks that you can see at the far left of this photo, all the while singing a Jimmy Buffett song, &amp;ldquo;I’m a tidal pool explorer….from the days of my mis-spent youth….&amp;rdquo;  After I saw them returning to the main area of the beach I went to explore.  I saw a hut with a grass roof that was not built by Disney for ambiance but was really functional.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These two little girls were very cute.  They came and sat next to us for a while and just looked at us.  Later we asked them what they were doing, etc.  They wanted our beer cans so they could melt them down into pots for cooking.  It was the second time this past week that I was asked for cans in order to melt them down for a pot.  A friend was wondering if it is a smart thing to melt these down for pots, wouldn’t one get poisoned slowly with all the additives in the aluminum cans.  I replied that here they likely crave things that can kill you slowly, b/c there are so many that can kill you quickly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![Imgp1273][5]][5]For one thing we were the only white people on the beach (or as the locals pronounce it: BEEtch, which half the time I think they are calling me a bitch, a nice repose from the normal honky or white boy accompanied by a hissing sound that here is equivalent to hey, or excuse me, or a wave in america).  For another thing the water was clean and the surf made swimming a joy.  I think that the salinity of the water here seems different, at times it seems more salty and at others less salty.  Likely this is just a perception thing. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![Imgp1272][6]][6]The [area around Freetown][6] is a peninsula.  We have been going to the series of beaches that is along the southern part of the peninsula for a while now.  We went to the closest one first and have been working our way out further and further.  This week we went to Kent, Sierra Leone which was the farthest out.  It was the end of the line so to speak.  Our systematic beach-ride-mooching has left one beach yet to visit.  Likely we will go there next weekend.  That beach is the most famous beach in all of Sierra Leone, River Number Two.  We’ll have a review for you soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![Imgp1279][8]][8]S/L still has the lowest life expectancy of any country in the world.  Mainly this stems from much of the country having very little access to healthcare in much of the country.  Even in Freetown access is extremely limited for much of the population.  Although people can get themselves or their unhealthy loved one to the clinic, there are major issues with the cost of health care in this country.  For instance, I am concerned that if I get sick it will blow my entire budget.  I have heard unconfirmed reports that a night in the Chinese run hospital will cost around $300.  Now, i’m not living on a complete shoe string here, but without real health insurance getting typhoid and getting laid up in a hospital for three nights like one friend did could be disasterous.  Think about the person who lives on $80 a month. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![Imgp1266][9]][9] On top of the cost is the actual care given.  There is no level one trama facility in the entire country.  So GWB can forget about coming. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have a friend, Sam, who is the executive director for a coalition of faith-based health clinics throughout the country.  He has told me that in order for this country to &amp;ldquo;develop&amp;rdquo; (whatever that means will depend on one’s perspective) it has to have better access to health-care.  Duh.  But I’m not really sure how you do it.  The problems extend from the infrastructure to the care-givers (who I’m told generally cannot be bothered to help sick people) to the cost and the web grows from there.  But maybe it is low on the government’s wishlist, it seems that when you cannot get any power through the lines to your capital city maybe the people’s political platform is slightly skewed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So if you have medical skills and want to make a massive impact, come visit Sam…he’ll put you to work!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/imgp1261_edited1.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/imgp1261_edited1.jpg&lt;/a>
[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/imgp1265.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/imgp1265.jpg&lt;/a>
[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/imgp1267.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/imgp1267.jpg&lt;/a>
[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/imgp1273.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/imgp1273.jpg&lt;/a>
[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/imgp1272.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/imgp1272.jpg&lt;/a>
[6]: &lt;a href="http://www.lib.utexas.edu/maps/africa/freetown_58.jpg">http://www.lib.utexas.edu/maps/africa/freetown_58.jpg&lt;/a>
[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/imgp1279.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/imgp1279.jpg&lt;/a>
[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/imgp1266.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/imgp1266.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Picts</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-15-picts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-15-picts/</guid><description>&lt;p>Finally had the bandwidth to upload the rest of the chimp picts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Will have more tomorrow.  Have to run, a full night of family dinner, Rocky 6 and Reggae night.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>keeping life wild</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-12-keeping-life-wild/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-12-keeping-life-wild/</guid><description>&lt;p>[![100207_1802][2]][2]so this weekend we went to the chimpanzee reserve.  when i was first told about this place i thought it was like a natural park that you could walk through and maybe you would see chimpanzees.  then we were told about this one chimpanzee who was the alpha male of the lot who ‘broke out’ and killed one tourist and pulled the arms off of another (who subsequently bled to death).  they were american’s i think.  it made the news, although i do not remember it.  after the incident the chimps escaped into the bush and have not been seen since.  they are on the fly.  this made me very excited about going to the reserve, except for the getting your arms pulled out part.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/100207_1802.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/100207_1802.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>but i still didn’t have a clear picture of what the hell was going on.  when we got there the tour guide told us that it was really a rehabilitation center for chimps who had been orphaned and then kept as pets.  usually they were found by people or the authorities and usually they were malnourished and neglected.  apparently the charm of having your own ape wears out fairly quickly for the expats and locals that pay $40 for one.  $40 can you imagine?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>the center quarantines the chimps for three months and then slowly integrates them into the five distinct social groups they have on the campus.  the eldest group is in a 15 acre enclosure.   the youngest is in a 5 acre enclosure.  there are a couple in between.  the place seems to take good care of their 85 apes with three squares a day and the like.  the standard joke around is that the chimps live better than the average sierra leonian.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i have posted the pictures, but i don’t really have any analysis for you.  the place was interesting to just watch.  i would have prefered if it was really a national park, but maybe next time. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![100207_0011][3]][3] in other news we went to a party up at the european council.  in these smaller countries the EU is establishing, essentially, consolidated embassies for the EU countries.  it makes some sense, especially in post-colonial countries.  although there is a possibility for it to salve some colonial wounds, i think it actually salts them.  here there is the british high commission and the EC.  those are the only embassies i’ve seen from europe.  i think that it serves to reinforce the colonialism here b/c the EC is small and out of the way, the BHC is large, magnificent and in the middle of it all.  anyway, the picture above is from that party where they had a burning pile of liquor where you would dip your finger in it and then put your firey finger in your mouth.  it was hot.  and then my friend claimed she didn’t see it so i had to do it again. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/100207_0011.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/100207_0011.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>o the banality of it all!</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-08-o-the-banality-of-it-all/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-08-o-the-banality-of-it-all/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>having problems posting these picts, wait for it…..OK.  getting there.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>[![Imgp1156_1_1][2]][2]&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/imgp1156_1_1.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/imgp1156_1_1.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i have been asked to post some pictures of where i live.  consider that done.  we have four (total) flatmates that live in an old, square house that looks out over the ocean.  i have shown you the views from my personal balcony before.  this first picture is of the living room.  the furniture is old, and not really that comfortable, but it looks quite nice i guess.  at least i was impressed upon first viewing.  there is a large cabinet that houses our small tv and tempestuous dvd player. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>off to the right of the picture is where the dining room and kitchen are.  off to the left of the picture is where the main entrance is (looking down the main entrance from the landing is picture number 2).  last pictures are of my room which is at the top of the stairs, first one on the right.  it is kind of small and when i first moved in everything seemed to break at first touch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![Imgp1155_1][3]][3] the first time i went to check the water in the shower the hot water handle fell off, it fell off, it fell, the f*ck, off.  [it is from a comedy bit] then after that the a/c went on the fritz which i think was due to bad generator fuel or maybe not.  i would turn on the a/c with the little remote that we have and the fan would slowly turn on, but then after a few seconds when (i think) the compressor would kick in, i could hear the generator start to drag decently (it is just an old diesel engine) and then the a/c would beep and the red light would not be lit.  so i would have to turn it back on again.  after about 28 times of turning it on and it turning itself off then the thing would finally stay on for a bit.  also there was no mosquito net or hangers or shower curtain in the room when i moved in.  now i can understand the mosquito net, maybe that is a ‘personal’ item.  but to take the hangers and the shower curtain?  that’s just dirty.  so for the first night when i moved in i made a mess in the shower area b/c there was hot water coming out of the handle and there was no shower curtain.  eventually that all got under control.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/imgp1155_1.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/imgp1155_1.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![Imgp1165_1_1][4]][4] then only a matter of days after we got that fixed i wake up to a gigantic pool of water in the bathroom.  i’m telling you, it is a mess.  of course it was a sunday, and no one was working.  so i just mopped it the best i could and then waited it out until monday morning when they could get someone out to fix it.  i couldn’t tell at the time, but it must have been the bidet because when i came home that night there was a huge amount of chaulk around it and there has been no more water.  i haven’t yet used the bidet, b/c i’m american and incompetent.  however a new, little pool is forming around the sink from where the return pipe goes into the wall.  so i think that one is coming. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/imgp1165_1_1.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/imgp1165_1_1.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![Imgp1153_1][5]][5] i was also asked what my diet has been like.  i’ve stayed veggie. but it has been really hard. the seafood looks out of this world. usually fruit for breakfast, rice and salad for lunch and then pasta with spinach or beans or something similar. more carbs than i would like, but i’m doing yoga pretty consistently and regulating my portions so i stay a lean mean typing machine. lots of fruit, but very few veggies. salad is hard b/c of the typhoid water, etc. you have to be extraordinarily careful, especially with leafy greens. tomatoes are not too difficult, although we don’t have a very sharp knife in the house, so peeling them can become onerous. drinks? lots of tea and a bit of coffee, and of course beer. the wines are either horrible or wonderful. hit or miss, like much here. there are lots of lebanese around, so when we go out the middle eastern food is generally very tasty.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/imgp1153_1.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/imgp1153_1.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ok enough of the mundane, you may like reading it, but likely you don’t.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>i&amp;#8217;m tired&amp;#8230;now its time to work.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-06-im-tired-now-its-time-to-work/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-06-im-tired-now-its-time-to-work/</guid><description>&lt;p>[![030207_1246][2]][2]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/photos/uncategorized/030207_1246.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/photos/uncategorized/030207_1246.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>hello.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>this weekend was pretty amazingly long.  in a good way i guess.  except for i had a lot of work that could have been done, but i never got around to it.  it is mitigated by the fact that none of it was actually due this weekend, i just wanted to get started on it.  that can happen later i guess.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>the weekend basically began on wednesday when we hosted our own welcome aboard party and some friends came over for american game night.  we played catchphrase (the bastard child of taboo and hot potato) and beer pong (the bastard child of many college greecians). &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![030207_1343][3]][3] thursday we went out to copacabanas (written about earlier).  on friday we heard from a friend that the embassy was having happy hour at atlantic.  atlantic is a large club on right on the beach that is usually the friday night hang out.  we had been there last friday night and it was filled with british military boys (who are here to train the SL military and police and have been for years) and locals.  this night, when we walked in, there were approximately eight people in the entire joint.  all of them were us embassy workers and none of them knew us.  but we saddled up to the table.  after an oddly awkward exchange with some people the ambassador asked my friend and i to sit across the table from him and his wife. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/photos/uncategorized/030207_1343.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/photos/uncategorized/030207_1343.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![040207_1430_2][4]][4] so there we were, rapping with the ambassador and his wife.  they were almost iconic in their precision to my vision of an ambassador and his wife in a poor african country.  smart, insightful, bubbly, a vision of all the good things about our country.  they had met here in sierra leone while in the peace corps in the sixties, fell in love and have been globe trotting together ever since.  we ended our experience at atlantic by grabbing a taxi to paddy’s.  paddy’s is a famous place and the place that is the model for the amalgam of the beach bar ‘profiled’ in the film [blood diamond][4].  the owner of paddy’s has been knighted by the queen of england for, essentially, providing hookers and beer to brit expats and military trainers here throughout the war and reconstruction years.   but apparently none of its ‘famous’ patrons were there on friday nights…&lt;em>see&lt;/em> &lt;em>supra.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/photos/uncategorized/040207_1430_2.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/photos/uncategorized/040207_1430_2.jpg&lt;/a>
[4]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/underwater/2006/10/fuck_hollywood.html">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/underwater/2006/10/fuck_hollywood.html&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![Imgp1174_2][6]][6] saturday.  what happened?  o yeah.  i slept in.  our housemate fired our caretaker at six in the morning over loud arguing whilst we were trying to sleep.  then i went back to sleep.  after i awoke for real we got called that we had a ride to the market.  we had yet to go.  it is an experience.  tight alleyways filled to the brim with kiosks selling everything that i ever donated to goodwill.  there were tons of pirate dvd’s and cd’s bubbling over with african jams that i’ve gotten to know at the above mentioned venues, brilliant fruits, and very few things worth buying.  the first two pictures i posted are from this market.  i was able to come across a french press and a can opener that actually works.  both purchases make me happy.  haggling for them does not.  i am not wired to haggle.  i like the fact that a price is a price.  i don’t make a good car purchaser or any other purchaser.  it feels just off to me, i feel creepy when i do it.  i’m not sure why.  but i made the purchases. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/imgp1174_2.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/imgp1174_2.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>spent the afternoon rapping with some friends while watching cricket on satelitte tv.  then we had a group that cooked a good italian dinner.  then we went out.  again.  to a party.  again.  afterwards to paddy’s.  again.  the second time tho was fundamentally different.  paddy’s is happening on saturdays.  we arrived home at 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>again there was drama with our housemates and the help first thing in the morning.  again, i didn’t care.  again, i went back to sleep afterwards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![N557965146_57200_4735][7]][7] sunday we went to the beach.  it was the second beach we had gone to.  at this one there was a haven set back from the beach and separated from the beach by a fordable river.  it was shady and delicious.  you can see the patio where we ate.  i had some pasta with a cream sauce and mushrooms, then i had ice cream, then i had coffee.  then i felt like a colonialist. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/n557965146_57200_4735.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/n557965146_57200_4735.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>at the end of the day.  i did not spend much time in my room….maybe another weekend i will.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>the grapefruits have more seeds.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-02-the-grapefruits-have-more-seeds/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-02-02-the-grapefruits-have-more-seeds/</guid><description>&lt;p>[![N557965146_50950_9850][2]][2] on sunday afternoon/evening there was a marching band parade and people just went into this compound (the wall is the background of the picture).  they paraded to a compound.  this picture doesn’t do it justice b/c there were TONS of people.  later we found out that it was a thanksgiving parade.  each local school has their own thanksgiving holiday where they march to a church.  not sure about the significance of it all, but it was funny nonetheless.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/photos/uncategorized/n557965146_50950_9850.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/photos/uncategorized/n557965146_50950_9850.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i feel odd when people ask me to tell them stories, because i don’t have many.  right now my life has been fairly boring.  just work, home, go out (maybe) and repeat. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>we cannot really talk about work, but i can say that it is interesting and intense stuff.  home is boring.  that leaves going out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>last night we went out to a place that went to during our first night here.  it was a nice difference to see how comfortable we have become in two weeks.  people say that freetown is the smallest 1M person city they have ever known.  i’m quickly finding that to be the case.  especially among the expat community.  when i first arrived here i was awed by the number of and symbols of ngo’s &amp;amp; io’s that were plastered onto the old land rovers driving the packed, diesel-fume-filled streets of this tight city.  every0ne that i had ever heard about was here: oxfam, usaid, unicef, british high council, save the children, and the list goes on and on.  it was like my entire folders of web links that have to do with activism, social entrepeneurship, and ID was plastered onto the side of small, inconspicuous, dilapidated signs for my eyes to graze as i drove or walked around this city.  at first it was daunting.  eventually i realized that it is a fairly small community. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>there were two things that i always envisioned myself doing.  one was living on vacation.  after two years of ski bumming and river ratting and being unemployed and writing and living a pretty outdoor lifestyle, i think that i can check that block.  the other was spurned by reading too much hemingway during my formative years (whatever the hell those are) and that was to live as an expat.  there is something magically romantic to me when the answers to where are you from come in the form of countries and accents are measured in degrees of separation from britian or paris or berlin or moscow as opposed to whether or not you watch nascar and go to church on sunday.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>that is it for now.  i have piles on my desk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>And the soapboxing begins&amp;#8230;</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-01-30-and-the-soapboxing-begins/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-01-30-and-the-soapboxing-begins/</guid><description>&lt;p>[![Image001][2]][2]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the view from my private balcony along one axis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![Image003][3]][3]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And from another axis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This city so far has been exactly what I had expected. It is fulfilling the picture I had in created over the six months or so of anticipation. People who have been here longer than I tend to ask the obvious question to fill the small talk obligation. “So how do you like Freetown.” “I like it fine, it is pretty close to what I had expected.” And so the conversations tend to begin. The amount of latent physical beauty that surrounds this place is stunning. And yet it is hard to make the claim that this city, at least, is idyllic because of the human tragedy and suffering that currently exists. You look one way you see one thing. You look another way you see something different. And often these two are as disparately disconnected as these two pictures are from one another. And yet this had been expected. What hadn’t been expected is the low amount of harassment by beggars for money. I was prepared for it to be constant considering that the last time I was in Jamaica it was some of the worst amount of begging I’ve ever experiences and considering that much of the original population of Sierra Leone were freed Jamaican slaves. They have had extremely divergent experiences, but at least they come from the same blood lines. But I must be careful b/c that is a completely different tangent which I do not want to progress in this short introductory note. Instead of not being able to walk anywhere for wading through crowds of outstretched hands, instead of that we are barely noticed as my housemate and I make our daily walks to the Lebanese supermarket. I must write in a future post about the Lebanese mafia in this town. They fascinate and frighten me. But they have good pita breads, and bobaghanous in a can and hummus in a can and olives, and chocolates, and nice teas and nice coffees and a few other niceties. There is no produce in the supermarket. For a while I was confused by this, until I realized that I have to talk to the lady out in the parking lot who had her wares assembled for my viewing and smelling pleasures. It is tropical here, so the citrus is great, the mangoes are to die for, the bananas are odd but tasty the guavas and cucumbers and star fruit etc are all delightful. There aren’t many tomatoes, but you can find them if you know where to look. Luckily I’ve found someone on my walk who sells nice tomatoes, even if they are a bit underripe. I like them that way, ripened to my precise specifications. We walk home up the hill loaded down with that evening’s groceries and a few bottles of water. Camels plodding up to the trough. It is usually dark by then, but it is strangely nice to be walking in the heat, loaded with groceries. You feel a part of it all. Although we do not carry our stuff on our heads. It is cliché I realize to associate that with Africa in general, but it is a way of life here. Kids will carry dining tables on their heads, men will carry two cement bags on their heads, women will carry bundles of 12 foot long poles on their heads. It is amazing. But we don’t carry them on our heads. We do, however, sweat. We are always sweaty heaps when we knock on our gate and the guards let us in our compound. Without fail we will bring the two on duty a soda. We feel that it is just a good way of living our lives. Maybe they would prefer a little extra cash, but Cokes taste pretty good on a hot evening. Not to me though, as I’m still soda free. More disconnection coming in the future. I just wanted to give you a small sampling. ~ # ~&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/photos/uncategorized/image001.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/photos/uncategorized/image001.jpg&lt;/a>
[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/photos/uncategorized/image003.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/photos/uncategorized/image003.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>First of Some</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-01-23-first-of-some/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-01-23-first-of-some/</guid><description>&lt;p>Things have been a bit chaotic with getting settled and then having that paper and another project for school hanging over my head. I finished the paper yesterday and the project just now, so I feel very refreshed. Now I can focus fully on the work here and then having fun. The beaches are delightful, apparently, and I’m excited to visit them soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Freetown is an amazing place and I am incredibly happy to be here. The people in the office are passionate and smart and caring. The people in town are warm and friendly, despite my whiteness. There is a bunch of pickpocketing, but other than that places are safe to go. We’re just being smart and being safe and all is good. Wait until I can break out the camera (maybe this weekend) and send you some pictures from here. It is so surreal to be in a place where people are walking around with bundles on their head, where creole is spoken everywhere, where the only water many have access to is runoff, where the colors of the buildings blow your mind, where the dust gets blown down from the sahara and mixes with the ocean breezes to create a thick haze that makes it difficult to see the ocean.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Off to watch the film Blood Diamond in Freetown with the people that have been prosecuting and defending and adjudicating and living it for years.  Talk about surreal!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>