<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>television on underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/television/</link><description>Recent content in television on underWater desert Blogging</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Casey Kuhlman</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/television/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Thank You Al Jazeera For a Masterpiece</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2011-02-12-al-jazeera-masterpiece/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2011-02-12-al-jazeera-masterpiece/</guid><description>![The Revolution via bilal.randeree @ Flickr, screenshot of Al Jazeera English's Coverage of Egypt]({{ site.url }}{{ site.root }}{{ site.images_dir }}/{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; }}/5433441055_e2319e2936.jpg) You have to think that if you’re the executive editor or another high level person within the Al Jazeera organization that you’ve been waiting for this chance. The chance to take your now 6 year old new organization to the next level. AJE was a regional power, had a lot of money behind it, but is still banned in the US and largely doesn’t have the legitimacy of CNN and BBC.</description></item><item><title>My Show is Back!</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-06-15-my-show-is-back/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-06-15-my-show-is-back/</guid><description>[]1</description></item><item><title>Best Political Team Gets Giddy</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-06-06-best-political-team-gets-giddy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-06-06-best-political-team-gets-giddy/</guid><description>Rude Pundit has one of the funniest TV pundit exchanges that I have ever (not) seen where Borger invokes the &amp;ldquo;Money Shot.&amp;rdquo; Be Aware! It is pretty graphic. As is everything he does…. Video here, although the video is pretty low:
[]2 The other funny exchange I could hear, but not see as the signal was scrambled. It took some waiting and searching on YouTube, but I found it today. Anderson Cooper tells Donna Brazille he wants to be her boo….</description></item><item><title>Chinese Strike Back</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-03-27-chinese-strike-back/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-03-27-chinese-strike-back/</guid><description>[![2355403254_b3474bb9ba][2]][2] [Chinese Bloggers declare war on Western media’s Tibet coverage][2].
[]: http://www.flickr.com/photos/cpj/2355403254/ [2]: http://www.globalvoicesonline.org/2008/03/24/china-bloggers-declare-war-on-western-medias-tibet-coverage/ &amp;ldquo;Global Voices Online » China: Bloggers declare war on Western media’s Tibet coverage&amp;rdquo;
The Tibetan protests, the crackdown by the Chinese and the backlashes from civil societies around the world offer me a good opportunity to explore differing viewpoints. Essentially, I know so little of what is going on there that I hesitate to offer comments. But the link above struck me because it is very counter–philosophy.</description></item><item><title>Super Bowl</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-02-04-super-bowl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-02-04-super-bowl/</guid><description>Congratulations Giants Fans. This was my favorite Super Bowl Advert.
[]1
 ~ # ~</description></item><item><title>mTv in dockers</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-09-15-mtv-in-dockers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2005-09-15-mtv-in-dockers/</guid><description>today during my lunch i decided to watch some bubble gum, so i flipped using my ever so handy quatro-surf buttons on my remote control to the preprogrammed (so you don’t even have to remember the channel number, as a side note in what context are we now required to remember ANY number….I cannot think of such a context myself, my cell contains phone numbers, my car contains addresses, my tv remote contains my favorite channels, shit what else is there to life?</description></item></channel></rss>