<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/</link><description>A Site About Resilience and Authoritarianism</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</managingEditor><webMaster>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</webMaster><copyright>All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/television/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Thank You Al Jazeera For a Masterpiece</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-02-12-al-jazeera-masterpiece/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-02-12-al-jazeera-masterpiece/</guid><description>&lt;p>You have to think that if you’re the executive editor or another high level person within the Al Jazeera organization that you’ve been waiting for this chance. The chance to take your now 6 year old new organization to the next level. AJE was a regional power, had a lot of money behind it, but is still banned in the US and largely doesn’t have the legitimacy of CNN and BBC. But this was their chance, and they absolutely nailed the coverage. It was spectacular in every way I can think of, and for all my friends I only wish you could have seen the narrative unfold.
The first night I paid attention to Egypt was Jan 28, the first Friday after it all began.  That was the day that everything seemed to blossom.  That was the day when the police cracked down but then were beaten down.  That was the day the army took to the streets and no one was sure how they would react.  That was the day that they shut down the internet.  So much happened.
From the balcony of AJE’s offices we watched the building of the ruling party burn, we watched a police APC stopped, tried to get thrown in the nile, and eventually burned in place (two weeks later I was awed by the continued presence of the carcass in a sweeping shot meant to show something else).
There are too many reasons why AJE’s coverage of Egypt was an absolute masterpiece of television and journalism, something that should be studied not only in journalism schools but also in film schools.  It was brilliant in its ability to capture the emotions of what was happening.
&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/aljazeeraenglish/5413058725">![Egypt political crisis via Al Jazeera English @ flickr]({{ site.url }}{{ site.root }}{{ site.images_dir }}/{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; }}/5413058725_d416628f87.jpg)&lt;/a>
On Thursday Mubarak spoke. The world watched in collective silence and about two or three minutes into the speech it became clear that he was entrenching himself.  Within about ten seconds of me hearing that, AJE slowly fed in the audio from Tahrir square where things were going nuts side by side with its translator continuing to do his thing.  It was subtle and it was brilliant.
[This NYT’s][3] article today compares their coverage to MSNBC and CNN and the others. It talks about another of the moments of brilliance. On Friday after Sulieman announced that Mubarak had stepped down the anchor simply said, “he’s gone.” And then it was just radio silence from talking.  All we saw and heard was sweeping shots of hundreds of thousands of people in the biggest celebration of their lives.  No words could describe it.
[3]: &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/02/12/world/middleeast/12watch.html?_r=1">http://www.nytimes.com/2011/02/12/world/middleeast/12watch.html?_r=1&lt;/a>
[![][5]][5]
[]: &lt;a href="http://www.caseykuhlman.com/entry/al-jazeera-masterpiece/scr1">http://www.caseykuhlman.com/entry/al-jazeera-masterpiece/scr1&lt;/a>
I know I’m in danger of fawning here, which is never attractive, but it is difficult to contain myself. The final thing that was so special about this coverage, was that most of the reporters that AJE brought in were Egyptian diaspora. They all had a personal stake in what was happening around them, but they never let that come through and color their commentary in any way. In the end the anchor had to force them, and even then as the NYT’s article says they were true human beings with some staying steadfastly professional, and some more emotional. Get yourself some of their good journalism (please, if only so I can watch it when I am back in the States as I’m not sure I can stand American news/punditry for more than about 30 seconds of its screaming overly emotional coverage of anything) by [clicking here][5] and putting in your zip code. And watch some of the videos.
[5]: &lt;a href="http://english.aljazeera.net/">http://english.aljazeera.net/&lt;/a>
The final thing I will say is this: [Ayman][6] [Mohyeldin][7] is now among my favorite reporters. They guy was absolutely unbelievable from the beginning to the end.
[6]: &lt;a href="http://english.aljazeera.net/category/person/ayman-mohyeldin">http://english.aljazeera.net/category/person/ayman-mohyeldin&lt;/a>
[7]: &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/#!/aymanm">http://twitter.com/#!/aymanm&lt;/a>
So from all of us here in my house: Al Jazeera English, thank you for putting together a masterpiece and for letting me experience the roller-coaster in such a fantastic way.
~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Show is Back!</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-15-my-show-is-back/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-15-my-show-is-back/</guid><description>&lt;p>[]&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/OyazVH5101A&amp;amp;hl=en" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">1&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Best Political Team Gets Giddy</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-06-best-political-team-gets-giddy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-06-best-political-team-gets-giddy/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://rudepundit.blogspot.com/2008/06/great-moments-in-punditry-jack-cafferty.html">Rude Pundit&lt;/a> has one of the funniest TV pundit exchanges that I have ever (not) seen where Borger invokes the &amp;ldquo;Money Shot.&amp;rdquo;  Be Aware!  It is pretty graphic.  As is everything he does…. Video here, although the video is pretty low:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/DF0QtK6zWC4&amp;amp;hl=en" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">2&lt;/a>
The other funny exchange I could hear, but not see as the signal was scrambled.  It took some waiting and searching on YouTube, but I found it today.  Anderson Cooper tells Donna Brazille he wants to be her boo….  Which had very funny undertones since AC is both pretty and gay. Video here:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/vxUaWUz9VcI&amp;amp;hl=en" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">3&lt;/a>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/vxUaWUz9VcI&amp;amp;hl=en" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">3&lt;/a>
~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chinese Strike Back</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-03-27-chinese-strike-back/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-03-27-chinese-strike-back/</guid><description>&lt;p>[![2355403254_b3474bb9ba][2]][2]  [Chinese Bloggers declare war on Western media’s Tibet coverage][2].&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/cpj/2355403254/">http://www.flickr.com/photos/cpj/2355403254/&lt;/a>
[2]: &lt;a href="http://www.globalvoicesonline.org/2008/03/24/china-bloggers-declare-war-on-western-medias-tibet-coverage/">http://www.globalvoicesonline.org/2008/03/24/china-bloggers-declare-war-on-western-medias-tibet-coverage/&lt;/a> &amp;ldquo;Global Voices Online » China: Bloggers declare war on Western media’s Tibet coverage&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2008/03/28/world/asia/28tibet.html?ref=world">Tibetan protests&lt;/a>, the &lt;a href="http://www.praguepost.com/articles/2008/03/26/protests-rightly-focus-on-the-olympic-games.php">crackdown by the Chinese&lt;/a> and the &lt;a href="http://www.baltimoresun.com/news/opinion/editorial/bal-ed.olympics27mar27,0,6054956.story">backlashes from civil societies&lt;/a> around the world offer me a good opportunity to explore differing viewpoints.  Essentially, I know so little of what is going on there that I hesitate to offer comments.  But the link above struck me because it is very counter–philosophy. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>I like going to &lt;a href="http://www.globalvoicesonline.org/">Global Voices &lt;/a>because they usually have excellent links to interesting prose and other voices.  So running an article about how the Chinese Bloggers are defending their government and deriding the poor, peaceful Tibetan protesters who only want to get on with their Buddhist meditations adds an interesting twist to my thinking.  Of course there are many sides to this story.  Duh. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>I associate Free Tibet Movement with other early 90s civil society ideas (which seemed to fail or remain stagnant more often than &amp;ldquo;succeed&amp;rdquo; however that could be measured) such as Save the Whales and Save the Rainforest and End Apartheid.  My concept of the situation is shaped from voyeuristic understanding of the situation.  I am more focussed on poverty and Africa rather than self-determination and Asia.  At the end of the day, the Free Tibet movement is off my radar screen.  That said I still find it fascinating. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Global Voices piece could simply be exposing Chinese Government surrogates who &amp;ldquo;blog&amp;rdquo; neutrally, or it could be proffering a different view on the situation.  I know not which it is, but still love the fact that it has added an additional, nuanced layer to the debate.  Hopefully to the betterment of the Movement. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>If the Movement takes this as an attack on its existence rather than an opportunity to engage in a good debate about what it is doing than I challenge it to stop playing by a conservative dichotomized playbook and join the pomo crowd who makes up much of its membership (I suspect).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Super Bowl</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-04-super-bowl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-04-super-bowl/</guid><description>&lt;p>Congratulations Giants Fans.  This was my favorite Super Bowl Advert.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]&lt;a href="http://www.spike.com/efp" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">1&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> 
~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>mTv in dockers</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-09-15-mtv-in-dockers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-09-15-mtv-in-dockers/</guid><description>&lt;p>today during my lunch i decided to watch some bubble gum, so i flipped using my ever so handy quatro-surf buttons on my remote control to the preprogrammed (so you don’t even have to remember the channel number, as a side note in what context are we now required to remember ANY number….I cannot think of such a context myself, my cell contains phone numbers, my car contains addresses, my tv remote contains my favorite channels, shit what else is there to life?  the study of ancient bath techniques and rub downs as a greecian mating ritual/alpha male dominance performance….besides that one.) channel for MTV.  ahhh, laguna beach usually makes me cough, curse and flip back to VH1, OLN HGN or BET but that wasn’t the case today as the only quote i heard was, &amp;ldquo;i’m like so totally stoked we’re going up to mammoth.&amp;rdquo;  well this could be interesting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>it wasn’t.  however it did remind me of EVERYTHING i loved and hated about that place at the same time.  they were intertwined like those two icky snakes in the hypocritic oath thingy.  i’m glad we get scales instead of snakes.  HURRAY FOR LAW. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>i other news this has been a fairly slow week and i took time out to golf today with e.  now this must have been the first time i’ve golfed in…..oh….i don’t know…..five years.  give or take a couple of days.  nevertheless it has been a long time.  (intended to put something creative in there but the wording just couldn’t work smoothly.)  i’m conflicted on golf.  on the one hand you have to get outside any way you can, and at least you are walking around some grassy knoll.  but on the other hand it has such middle class, no life having, dockers wearing, wife apathetic-y, horrible connotations.  and such hauty tauty i’m too good for you so i keep you outside the gates to my countryclub, you swine connotations.  i don’t know.  but i did it.  and some balls flew and some balls dribbled. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>this weekend i hope to get away for a little walk in the woods.  have driven something like 100 miles in the past 4 weeks since school has started.  am i still me?  need to get away from this fucking city.  need to drive, need to wall, need to see trees and waterfalls and rocks and birds and maybe some babboon ass.  do they sell that in mass quantities?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>well, i’ve gotten through another post successfully and by success i’m measuring it in terms of a complete lack of lawyering terms and references.  will i ever stop analyzing myself and everything around me on at least two levels?  shit man just live your life.  really all is well, am in a good mood tonight.  we’ll see if i still have a back when i wake up tomorrow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>