<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>going local on underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/going-local/</link><description>Recent content in going local on underWater desert Blogging</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/going-local/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I&amp;#8217;m Supposed to Write on Water, but I Don&amp;#8217;t Have Any&amp;#8230;</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-15-supposed-write-water-any/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-15-supposed-write-water-any/</guid><description>Today the Interweb Gods have deemed is World Blog about water day. Or likely more accurately, the brilliant charity:Water marketers have deemed today as world blog about water:Day. I haven't read every post I have seen come across my various Twitter wires, but the ones I've read talk about the need for us to have water. Seems pretty self-evident and so the rhetoric can turn into a polemic rather quickly. I thought about writing a love post to water, but then I realized that I'm annoyed at water.</description></item><item><title>On Going Local: Finding Your Happy Place</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-12-local-finding-happy-place/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-12-local-finding-happy-place/</guid><description>On Going Local is a new (short) series that I’ll be running which will attempt to look at my life from an objective perspective as I transition from and NGO worker into an entrepreneur here in the developing world. This post is about finding some personal space.</description></item><item><title>On Going Local: Water</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-17-local-water/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-17-local-water/</guid><description>On Going Local is a new (short) series that I'll be running which will attempt to look at my life from an objective perspective as I transition from and NGO worker into an entrepreneur here in the developing world. The first entry dives into the intricacies of getting water into your house.</description></item></channel></rss>