<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/</link><description>A Site About Resilience and Authoritarianism</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</managingEditor><webMaster>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</webMaster><copyright>All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/going-local/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I&amp;#8217;m Supposed to Write on Water, but I Don&amp;#8217;t Have Any&amp;#8230;</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-15-supposed-write-water-any/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-15-supposed-write-water-any/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today the Interweb Gods have deemed is World Blog about water day.  Or likely more accurately, the brilliant &lt;a href="http://blogactionday.change.org/">change.org&lt;/a> marketers have deemed today as world blog about water:Day.  I haven’t read every post I have seen come across my various Twitter wires, but the ones I’ve read talk about the need for us to have water.  Seems pretty self-evident and so the rhetoric can turn into a polemic rather quickly.  I thought about writing a love post to water, but then I realized that I’m annoyed at water.  We fell out with each other a couple of weeks ago, which by the way was the last time water came through my pipes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The water system in Hargeisa is over stretched, under maintained, now badly managed network, under funded cluster of an organization.  It makes money so the government doesn’t want to privatize it.  And that is likely the right move considering the power system is privatized and is a mess.  It is all the rage to claim that the private sector is going to save Africa, and I while I believe that I’m not a complete free marketer.  The private sector can be just as lazy and dumb as a public sector can be.  The presence of competition does not necessitate innovation and good economic behavior in and of itself.  But that is a different story and before I go down that road, let me tell you about my pipe problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The pipes that supply Hargeisa were buried about an 1 deep all willy nilly throughout the place.  Whenever you go off of the main roads it is inevitable that you’ll have to drive over one.  That isn’t a structural economic problem.  That has little to do with Ministerial efficiency or World Bank proclamations.  It is just stupid and lazy workmanship.  It doesn’t have anything to do with a depressed education system or beleaguered healthcare system.  it is just stupid and lazy workmanship.  Nothing more, nothing less.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And because these pipes were not buried deep enough, and because I live near a bus station, the pipes that come to my house often are broken by buses running over them.  And then we have to pay for a plumber to come fix them.  The Water Agency this time even refused to drive a plumber up here even after we agreed to pay for the plumber.  And then after we brought the plumber up here to our sector of Hargeisa, the guy wanted $20, TWENTY DOLLARS, to do the fifteen minutes of work it would require to cut a new pipe, tap it, and tighten it onto the new pipe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I told the guy to f-off.  He laughed, I rolled my eyes, he said ten, I agreed.  And then he fixed the pipe.  But since that time no water has come through the pipes.  I don’t think they’re broken as we can usually tell.  In the morning when we drive to work if the water has come and the pipe is broken it just pools uselessly in the muck at the main intersection of the bus station.  In a desert country with small water resources no one seems to give an F about this water just sitting there.  But that hasn’t happened in the past week or ten days since we paid the plumber to fix the water.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why is that the case?  Because I live near a hotel.  You know the kind, one of the few places in town known to cater to expats.  They are all in one shape or form the same.  But the guy who owns the hotel pays the guy who controls the water in our sector a little bit more each month and so the water guy reroutes almost all of the water to the hotel.  The old Hargeisa water manager was a friend of ours and when we told him our hypothesis in this regard he investigated, found it to be true, fought tooth and nail (I heard directly many of the conversations between him and the sector manager who is below him) for us, and still was only moderately successful in getting us water.  Since he was sacked for unknown reasons which had nothing to do with his competence but basically boiled down to the other dude supported the government than won the recent election and had to be rewarded somehow, since that time we have gotten water through the pipes on only a couple of occasions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So water and I have seemingly broken up.  And that is not cool with me.  It isn’t cool in a way that  has nothing to do with what any policymaker or bureaucrat or large NGO marketing department wants me to think.  It isn’t cool and it has nothing to do with funding levels (throwing more money at the sector isn’t going to get the pipes buried deeper, repaired faster, or micro-managed more equitably), bold statements, or glossy web sites.  It isn’t cool and much of it comes down to stupidity and laziness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Excuse me, I gotta run, the dude that drives the donkey cart with the ex-oil drum on the back is here to deliver my water.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On Going Local: Finding Your Happy Place</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-12-local-finding-happy-place/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-12-local-finding-happy-place/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>On Going Local is a new (short) series that I’ll be running which will attempt to look at my life from an objective perspective as I transition from and NGO worker into an entrepreneur here in the developing world.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve been here in Somaliland now for around two and a half years now.  It has been a wonderful time, and I’ve enjoyed every minute of it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are many aspects of Somali / Somaliland society &amp;amp; culture that I have found it easy to adjust too.  But there are a few things which have been difficult.  Not the least of which is the six day work week.  Being an Islamic country, we take Friday off.  But that most people take off.  Going from a two day weekend to a one day weekend with shorter days throughout the six was a big adjustment and I’m not sure that I will ever fully adjust to it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, this is about space.  Physical space.  Like most development workers I lived for a long time in a &lt;a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/caseykuhlman/SomalilandCompound02" title="Gorgorka Luxury Estates">gigantic house&lt;/a> shared among an assortment of other expatriates, cleaners, cooks, guards, and staff.  It can be a fantastically good time having all the excitement of different activities, smells, and languages around you.  For a little while…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a time, though, it becomes stifling.  For one thing, you are never “off duty.”  At any time of the day or night someone may come and knock on your door.  Someone’s family member is sick and they need money; someone’s mobile phone was stolen and they need money; the guards caught two people making out in a dark corner behind the house; all sound tracked to random gunshots due to land disputes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most development or aid workers I know always like to say it’s not a job, it’s a lifestyle.  And that is all well and good, but it isn’t a lifestyle I was very interested in.  Sure you can try to set boundaries, but you don’t want to incentivize the people working with you to not tell you what is happening.   That can lead to all kinds of problems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This balance is incredibly difficult to achieve between having some personal space (when the standard living situation is tenement and shared, college-esque, except we’re not college age anymore) and being “open.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have recently moved out of that mansion into what would be normal to me.  Luckily enough it is also what would be normal to a middle-class Somali.  Instead of ten bedrooms (some of which were office space), I now have three.  Instead of having to walk 15 minutes to get to the kitchen, it now takes me 15 seconds.  I don’t have to worry about staff all of the time as I only have someone who comes to clean for me a few days a week &amp;amp; when I’m at the office.  It is safer this way, as you are a target when you live in a mansion.  You can do what you like without having to worry about being disturbed.  You can metaphorically unpack your bags.  You can find normality in an otherwise frantic existence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The place I’m living now actually feels like a home rather than a dorm.  And that is fantastic.  I love my old roommates dearly, but it is so nice to have something that is “yours.”  And when my wife comes down next year for a bit, my life will be complete!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On Going Local: Water</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-17-local-water/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-06-17-local-water/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>On Going Local is a new (short) series that I’ll be running which will attempt to look at my life from an objective perspective as I transition from and NGO worker into an entrepreneur here in the developing world.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I first arrived here in S’land, and I would go out to eat, I would use the minimum amount of water possible to wash my hands before and after eating with them.  It is desert afterall.  But later, towards the end I realized that I had adapted and was using more water – letting the water run as I was soaping, washing my face also.  It was never a conscious decision, I just started using more water.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But here at the house, I have always remained conscious of how much water we are using – primarily because at the house we have to pay for the water and it is EXPENSIVE. It is desert afterall.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I just wanted to share a bit about how the water works.  Here in Hargeisa we have a decent supply of water, but it is getting strained by the continuing population growth of the city.  There is this beautiful area about 30 km to the north of Hargeisa, in the Golis Mountains where most of the water comes from.  One of the main problems is that the area is a couple hundred meters of elevation lower than Hargeisa.  That means PUMPS generators performing the difficult job of getting the water up here to Hargeisa.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Hargeisa Water Agency has identified two other locations which could supply Hargeisa and both are higher and would require less pumping power.  The problem is getting the infrastructure built.  The Agency has a difficult time amassing enough capital to even upgrade the pipe network from the original series of wells into Hargeisa.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once the water gets to Hargeisa then it gets routed to different zones.  Typically one or two zones within Hargeisa will get water on a given night, and then the Agency will rotate zones over the course of the week.  Once the water is released to the zones then the zone manager is responsible for routing it into particular customers of the agency.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The irregularity of the water supply means that most compounds have built their own water reservoirs and then we watch these like a hawk.  Our reservoir is underground.  Because it is a totally passive system, what we have to do is each day we check supplemental tanks which are on the highest part of the house.  These tanks provide the house with water pressure, but do it passively.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pretty much each day we pump water from the underground reservoir to the upper holding tanks.  This means that we only have to use the electricity to pump the water up once a day rather than running it continuously (which is important because electricity is also EXPENSIVE).  The system works quite well most of the time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The only problem comes when we let the upper holding tanks run dry.  What happens (because the system is passively pressurized) then is that air runs down through the water lines in the house.  After we fill the upper holding tanks the air pressurizes from the weight of the water above it and keeps the water from flowing through the plumbing system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many of you living in Africa may have experienced this problem.  So here is what you do when the water won’t flow through your house.  You go to the bottom most taps in your system and open all of them that you can find.  This will bleed the air pressure from the system.  When those taps are running well, then you can go upstairs and turn one a couple of taps.  This should bleed the rest of the air from the system and then water should fill all of the lines.  Then you have to run around the house turning off all of the taps because you hate wasting water!  You may have to fiddle with your hot water heaters (if you are lucky enough to have them) as they sometimes become a hassle to bleed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But this is a small hassle – and after a while it becomes second nature to bleed the lines when you know that the upper tanks have run dry.  This is one of my favorite parts of living in the developing world.  You are forced to learn about the world around you which you so often take for granting living in the developed world where you never have to understand fluid dynamics and watershed elevation limitations in order to take a shower!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>