<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/</link><description>A Site About Resilience and Authoritarianism</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</managingEditor><webMaster>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</webMaster><copyright>All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Latent, Natural Synergies Between Virtual Currencies, Open Data Schemes, and International Development</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-20-the-latent-natural-synergies-between-cryptocurrencies-opendata-development/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-20-the-latent-natural-synergies-between-cryptocurrencies-opendata-development/</guid><description>&lt;p>I like it when disparate things work well together. Like fish farming and hydroponic vegetable growing for instance (aka aquaponics). I see some increasing levels of synergy between virtual currencies, open data schemes and international development.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="virtual-currencies">Virtual Currencies&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For those that do not know, virtual currencies or cryptocurrencies are an ecosystem of transmitting value similar in nature to traditional or fiat currencies (dollars, yen, yuan, pounds, euros, etc.) except with added levels of convience and security which you do not get when you want to transmit value by giving someone a piece of paper.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The community which uses virtual currencies is small but growing at a substantial rate, so we are far from adoption. However, one of the exciting aspects of virtual currencies for application in developing countries is the ability of anyone with any feature or smart phone to instantly conduct international transactions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>People who follow Somalia|Somaliland will well remember that last summer there was a huge kerfuffle because Barclays indicated that it was going to revoke Dahabshiil's accounts. Dahabshiil, for those who are not Somalia watchers, is the largest money transfer and financial services provider in the Somali region. Its business model outside of Somalia is very similar in nature to Western Union's traditional money transfer system (you bring your neighborhood agent cash and they transmit it to whomever you determine). Inside of Somalia Dahabshiil acts more along the lines of a traditional bank. Most people keep their money in a Dahabshiil account rather than in cash. So the kerfuffle with Barclays would mean that people in Europe|America|Canada|Australia, wherever would have to change how they were sending money to Somalia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For some this was a huge problem because they may live in a place where other options are not available. Although, since Western Union does have agents in Somalia I always felt that much of the kerfuffle was overblown. I was pleased to see the activist community successfully push for a Barclays to change their position, but the bottom line is Dahabshiil has an outdated business model and has been very conservative in pivoting from that position which opens up an innovation space for other, more nimble companies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Enter virtual currencies. With Bitcoin, a diaspora can easily purchase Bitcoin in their home country in their home currency from either an &lt;a href="http://37coins.com">SMS transaction&lt;/a> or an online &lt;a href="http://kraken.com">bank&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://coinbase.com">transfer&lt;/a>. Once the diaspora has Bitcoin they can then easily transfer the Bitcoin to anyone in the world as long as the recipient has a Bitcoin wallet (which can be set up nearly instantly with a system like 37 Coins offers). Boom. Remittance system blockage overcome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What is really exciting me, though, for a development perspective is the next level of innovation that is happening with virtual currencies which will allow the building of smart contracts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The idea of smart contracts, or virtual automatic contracts, is that you can build arbitrary, neutral triggers which will then be able to transmit value from one place to another when the triggers happen.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="open-data-as-a-neutral-indicator-of-things-happening">Open Data as a Neutral Indicator of &amp;ldquo;Things Happening&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>What is further exciting is that open data movements are beginning to succeed in at least getting some amount of neutral data widely available. This is beginning to be a wave with European governments showing real leadership in this space (in particular, the UK government is doing great work here).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Open data with proper APIs will be able to provide smart contracts with the link between the &amp;ldquo;real world&amp;rdquo; and the virtual world which the contracts can see. So let's take a system like crop insurance. Within the year, a coder|lawyer could easily build a smart contract which would pay out based upon an inverse relationship to the rainfall (or other neutral, accessible data metric) in a given location.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="social-bonds-as-smart-contracts">Social Bonds as Smart Contracts&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>One of the ideas which the &lt;a href="http://www.cgdev.org">Center for Global Development&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.cgdev.org/page/development-impact-bond-working-group">others&lt;/a> are working on is the idea of a Develpment Impact Bond. &lt;a href="http://www.cgdev.org/blog/what-if-you-could-invest-development">Here&lt;/a> is a good overview by Owen Barder, and &lt;a href="http://www.socialfinance.org.uk/work/developmentimpactbonds">here&lt;/a> is another from Social Finance. The basic idea for Development Impact Bonds is that you build a bond structure which any company, organization, government, or individual can invest in and that will pay out upon certain, pre-determined metrics being hit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Social Finance is in the midst of working on a pilot for this in the UK where they have asked the Ministry of Justice to commoditize how much recidivism is worth to the UK economy. So when people go back into jail that costs society and if you can put a price on that cost then you can aggregate and float that price with some level of discount to any group that says they can reduce recidivism. After that, the organization who is the recipient of the bond can then determine the best way to achieve the outcome stated by the terms of the bond. Of course there will be some implementation limits built into the bond contract but for the most part those will be increasingly fewer over time. The advantage which the bond holder will get is that it will have an asset which it can leverage in interesting ways, and use fundraise in interesting ways (as it could be used as collateral).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is an idea which is intellectually appealing to me, but in practice would require a lot of human oversight. Enter smart contracts. Smart contracts could oversee the entire process automatically with no human interaction if they were properly built. This would be powerful tool for accelerating outcome based development mechanisms.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="smart-contracts-as-cash-on-delivery-mechanisms">Smart Contracts as Cash on Delivery Mechanisms&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Another interesting and important idea which the CGD has been interested in for years is the &lt;a href="http://www.cgdev.org/initiative/cash-delivery-aid">cash on delivery&lt;/a>. COD has a lot of relevance to impact bonds but on a more decentralized basis. Here's what CGD says about COD:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Cash on Delivery is a new approach to foreign aid that focuses on results, encourages innovation, and strengthens government accountability to citizens rather than donors. Under COD Aid, donors would pay for measurable and verifiable progress on specific outcomes, such as $100 dollars for every child above baseline expectations who completes primary school and takes a test.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>But here's the interesting way which smart contracts could do this. With COD you have a neutral outcome based metric (kids butts in school chairs). This metric can be aggregated with an open data push and a proper API. Then you have a payout schedule which could be per day, per week, per month, per quarter, per year, whatever. The payouts are structured based upon meeting the criteria determined in the metric. Again, smart contracts could be built which would manage this with minimal human interactivity (as long as you could get the data that is).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The interesting thing which you can do with smart contracts is that it would be trivial to have payouts to a million recipients or one recipient (once you add the addresses of the recipients &amp;ndash; as is currently being piloted in many ways with mobile money). So you could structure the COD mechanism so that A portion of the money will be paid to the central government; B portion to the regional government; C portion to the local school itself; and D portion to each parent of the students.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Incentives matter and behavioral economists are continuing to find new and interesting ways to structure incentive models for positive societal change. With some minimal investment into using virtual currencies and smart contracts alongside open data initiatives we will soon reach a point where to test different incentive models will require a simple change of a few lines of code, some time, and some analysis of the outcomes in R (all of this done from anywhere in the world) to determine the viability of the incentive structure to address the problem one is trying to address. Compare that to the way in which an implementing agency today would have to pivot in order to test, pilot, or scale a hypothesis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We in the development world &lt;em>should&lt;/em> know that speed and nimbleness are just as important for development workers as they are for businesses and smart contracts + open data would dramatically increase the speed at which certain things could be addressed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On Chasing Chaos: The best book about "The Life" I've read in ages.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-10-16-on-chasing-chaos/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-10-16-on-chasing-chaos/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Disclosure: On a few occasions I have been known to partake in beverages with the author. Not on many, but on a few. Oh, and my wife is an amalgamated character in the book.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chasing Chaos examines the lives that aid workers lead and the work which aid workers do in vivid clarity and with honesty, clarity, and warmth. Highly recommended book; and not only because I know Jess.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When someone says they work for a law firm, most people who are not lawyers have certain cultural benchmarks in which to orient themselves around some idea of what that lawyer's life may be like. Whether it is because the non-lawyer was an English major and read One L as they considered law school, because they watched L.A. Law, Ally McBeal, Boston Legal, or Suits, or because they have watched Erin Brokovitch or any of Grisham's books/movies &amp;ndash; no matter the case, most are able to comprehend to a certain degree what the lawyer's life is like. Sure cultural benchmarks are subject to Hollywood mandated arbitrary drama which often fails to portray the fuller reality of its subject matter. But at least these benchmarks provide an icon in which to begin discourse. Similarly, when someone says they are a doctor, people can refer to the cultural benchmarks of ER or Grey's Anatomy or Scrubs. Finance? Wall Street, and any of the recent movies which came out after the 2008 crash. Firefighters. Policeman. Nurses. Teachers. These are all easy to talk about when meeting people because icons from popular culture provide an entry point to begin communicating what one &amp;ldquo;does&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Those of us who live the life which I live do not have such a luxury. The aid and development businesses are foreign to many folks not only because of the &amp;ldquo;exotic&amp;rdquo; locations in which aid and development take place, but because the work that aid and development workers do is not fully understood within mainstream Western culture. It is certainly well understood in mainstream Asian, African, and Latin American cultures as they have lived through, or are living through, the arc of how modern aid and development works. Chasing Chaos is a book which explains the life that I live &amp;ndash; with all its contradictions, tensions, nuances, stresses, pleasures, and excitement &amp;ndash; much better than I ever could.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When Jess asked me if I would read an early copy of the book, I told her I was happy to and that her publisher should send a copy to our temporary apartment in Nairobi which we are so rarely at, that the caretaker called Leigh the other day to ask if we were still living there; both of us recently have been &amp;ldquo;on mission&amp;rdquo; a lot. Exotic Apartments, Ngong Road (Across from Nairobi Baptist Church), Nairobi, Kenya is the address I facebook messaged to Jess. At the time I thought, if her publishers wondered whether she was going to go all A Million Little Pieces on them, perhaps sending early review copies to the above address may make them more comfortable as to her credence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jess does not have the most field cred of any one I've ever met. Yet she has certainly done some hard time. One of the most refreshing things about the book, and one of its most worthwhile aspects is that Jess is honest about that fact, as well as everything else. While the book is peppered with hilarious anecdotes &amp;ndash; Jess being at the farther end of the funny people bell curve on the storytelling front &amp;ndash; its is also salted with tears. Honest, genuine, heartfelt tears. This life and this work that aid and development workers embark upon so often oscillates wildly between stomach bursting laughter and shoulder seizing weeping &amp;ndash; Chasing Chaos captures these oscillations, and the doldrums in between the ends of the spectrum, perfectly. It illustrates how it feels to be exhausted, filthy, drenched in sweat, and have to deal with yet another problem that you did not anticipate. It also illustrates the joy which very few have an opportunity to understand, the joy of how even small victories feel when achieved despite obscene obstacles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Perhaps my favorite aspect of the book is that Jess never loses sight of the humanity of this business. Fundamentally humanitarian aid and development are about helping people. It is certainly an imperfect industry. Of course for those of us in this industry it is easy to get more hung up on the fact that we cannot go to Starbucks on our way to work and spend more time focusing our mental energies on our personal deprivations than on the people we are supposedly helping. Between the outwardly selfless actions we are supposed to be performing and the (at times) inwardly selfish motivations which drive us to take those actions it becomes very easy for us to lose sight of the human beings around us &amp;ndash; whether those are national colleagues not entitled to evacuation if it all goes south, or the beneficiaries who are so often not given a voice in the matter at all. What Jess is able to accomplish in her memoir is to examine both sides of the outwardly selfless and inwardly selfish equation without losing her focus on the people she has met along her own journey. Everyone in the book, no matter where they come from, their class or stature or background, is treated as an individual, unique human being. In the haze of travel and constantly changing environments, in the blur of the mountains of work we very often face, this is a difficult challenge even for the most altruistic of aid workers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As Jess is tracing her own career development, during the latter portions of the book, the narrative turns to a more reflective examination of the aid business. Her examination of the contradictions and tensions underlying the work, I suspect, will resonate with many. These are the things which we talk about at expat parties and other gatherings of those of us who live &amp;ldquo;The Life&amp;rdquo; whether in New York, Geneva, London, the Hague, Nairobi, Monrovia, Colombo, Khartoum, Aceh, Kabul, Bratislava, or Mogadishu. Like other groups of professionals, when we gather we are bound to talk about work. She illustrates clearly many of the things that have been, and are, wrong with and many things that are right about the aid business in language which those who have not attended such an expat party and participated in such discussions can easily understand. The book does a fine job of using the human elements of its narrative to illustrate her larger perspective as to where aid is at this particular moment in time. Her points, while not unfamiliar to most in the business, are easily approachable to those who are not &lt;em>in&lt;/em> the business.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chasing Chaos is a book which provides a holistic view of our world, our jobs, and our lives. If you are currently living &amp;ldquo;The Life&amp;rdquo; you should read this book for the stories &amp;ndash; which I am positive will resonate deeply with your own experiences and journey. If you are thinking about getting into &amp;ldquo;The Life&amp;rdquo; then you should certainly read this book as it provides the best glimpse I have read as to what this is like. If you have loved ones or friends in &amp;ldquo;The Life&amp;rdquo; you should very much read this book as it will explain in a way that perhaps your loved one or friend cannot what their life is like: what they think about, how they feel, and what they actually do. Personally, I have never given my mother or father any book in this genre, until now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Taking the E out of M&amp;E for Governance Projects</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-07-12-taking-the-e-out-of-mande/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2013/2013-07-12-taking-the-e-out-of-mande/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/70292973@N07/7192964074">&lt;img src="http://blog.caseykuhlman.com/assets/images/2013/7192964074_130e7bfb3f_z.jpg" alt="Monitoring Results at a Health Center by The Reboot @ flickr" tit="Monitoring Results at a Health Center by The Reboot @ flickr" />&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As part of my work for &lt;a href="http://law.vanderbilt.edu">Vanderbilt Law School&lt;/a>&amp;lsquo;s &lt;a href="http://law.vanderbilt.edu/academics/academic-programs/international-legal-studies/index.aspx">International Legal Studies Program&lt;/a> I recently pushed a grant application to a US Government Agency that was all about increasing the capacity of an institution to perform its mandated functionality. It was a relatively straight-forward submission &amp;ndash; the safest I've been involved in lately as it had the least amount of innovation I have built into a submission in years. For these reasons, I feel we have a relatively high chance of success.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The part I like least when it comes to developing grant applications is the monitoring and evaluation (M&amp;amp;E) portion of the grant response. It is not because I feel that M&amp;amp;E is worthless. Indeed, the contrary is true. I fully buy into the notion that development programs must &lt;em>monitor&lt;/em> their implementation based on measurable metrics. Further, I fully buy into the idea that development programming is simply a means that is an attempt to achieve some (other) identifiable end and I fully buy into the idea that we should develop a theory for how the programming will lead to the desired results portfolio and we should &lt;em>evaluate&lt;/em> the project based on those outcomes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Despite intellectually understanding the need for and efficacy of M&amp;amp;E, I detest writing M&amp;amp;E frameworks. Mostly, I suspect this is due to the sector I work in. If I worked in education, health, agriculture, or some other sectors of the development world perhaps M&amp;amp;E would be less of a motivational hurdle for me; perhaps not, to be honest I have no idea. There are two reasons why I think this could be true. First, these sectors can more easily be measured. Second, these sectors present programs with a quicker ROI where success or failure of the program can more easily be measured.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If we can all agree that the ability to measure success is one of the more important elements to the design of any M&amp;amp;E framework, then we need to (as practitioners) build M&amp;amp;E frameworks that can be measured. Duh. Yet, if the goal is to &amp;ldquo;build institution X&amp;rdquo; or to &amp;ldquo;build the capacity of policymakers within area Y&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;provide technical support to the reform of policy sector Z&amp;rdquo; how can we craft metrics which are easily measured? Governance work (which I am referring to in isolation from democracy &amp;amp; governance work) usually boils down to one of those three goals. Either the donor and the beneficiary government want an institution to be built, want the capacity of the individuals comprising an institution to be bolstered, or want to achieve a longer-term legal or policy reform.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When we look at measuring the implementation and the success of any development programming (I'm not a fan of the intervention jargon with respect to governance work), there are basically two ways in which we can measure things. We can measure &lt;em>what has been done&lt;/em>. These are commonly called &lt;strong>output variables&lt;/strong>. Examples of output measurement: How many memos were written and given to policymakers? How many schools were built? How many police units were outfitted with advanced investigation kit? Output variables commonly measure things that are usually well within the control of the implementing agency or consortium. We can also measure &lt;em>what has happened&lt;/em>. These are commonly called &lt;strong>outcome variables&lt;/strong>. Examples of outcome measurement: How much better is the institution performing? How many more students are graduating from the impact area? How many few crimes were committed within the impact area? Outcome variables commonly measure things that are not so easily within the control of the implementing agency or consortium.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Between the two (output and outcome) it is more beneficial to the implementing agency or consortium to measure the outputs. The implementer can more easily control the output as the delivery of the output is usually well within the decision space of the implementer. It is self-evident that no implementer wants to show that they did not deliver on a project when the delivery on that project was a result of things outside their control. Most humans would find it within the realm of normality to have their performance evaluated based upon what they actually did. Output variables are simply a measurement of what the implementer has done, and therefore easier to measure and also easier to say, &amp;ldquo;evaluate me on &lt;em>this&lt;/em>.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Between the two (output and outcome), however, it is more beneficial to the environment in which the program is being implemented to measure the outcomes. Outcome variables are a method which more precisely measures the &lt;strong>results&lt;/strong> of the program that was implemented. The overarching mission of what we, as development workers, should be doing is to produce results that positively affect the environment. While purchasing advanced investigation kit for police units and training personnel on that kit's usage is important that is not necessarily a result (it is an output). That purchase and training effort will not, of itself, positively affect the environment. However, if the police are empowered to use the kit and training to reduce crime within the impact area, then we are looking at a result that positively affects the environment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While they may be more beneficial to build into M&amp;amp;E frameworks, it is often not a simple matter to measure outcomes &amp;ndash; particularly when we are talking about building and/or reforming institutions. The real problem that I often face when I am trying to think through building an M&amp;amp;E framework is the same reason why, psychologically, governance work can be wholly unsatisfying for those who dedicate their professional lives to it. I am sure that social scientists and development thinkers with more brains and experience than I have some lingo for it, but I just call it the &amp;ldquo;gratification delay.&amp;rdquo; When the effort you are embarking upon is about transmitting knowledge, it will take time for you to see the results of that effort. This is self-evident and we all see it in our every day lives. If we are talking about building an institution we are talking about transmitting knowledge in how to run that institution much more than we are talking about building some physical structure, and so we are facing a situation where the real gratification for the effort cannot be measured until some non-specific time in the future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This gets me to the biggest problem I have with the evaluation portion of any M&amp;amp;E framework. It is not that it is difficult to build the framework, it is that is exceptionally short sited of donors to require implementing agencies to evaluate the project within the timeframe of the project. So in other words it is simply a paper tiger. It wreaks to me of work for work's sake, rather than work that will end with the satisfaction of some logical goal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For my own purposes, I would love if a donor said that I should submit a grant application and build an M&amp;amp;E framework into that submission but that my &amp;amp;E portion will be conducted by another organization at some reasonable time following the conclusion of the project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Almost every project that I have seen or been a part of is behind from the beginning and is rushing towards the end to deliver on its promises. Even where those projects have built the final quarter of the project as M&amp;amp;E time to properly evaluate the project, the best they can do within that timeframe is simply to get a very early picture of the results. So why do donors not simply extend out the &amp;amp;E part to four, six, eight quarters following the completion of the project? I am sure there are reasons, but I surely do not know what they are.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>For Business or for Pleasure: Which is Aid?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-04-18-for-business-or-for-pleasure-which-is-aid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2011/2011-04-18-for-business-or-for-pleasure-which-is-aid/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748704425804576220524034207558.html">&lt;img src="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748704425804576220524034207558.html" alt="Cropped version of Wisconsin: Open for business. Closed for people. by BlueRobot @ flickr">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This week two interesting articles (to me) have been published and they have given me the push to return to commenting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The articles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first was an &lt;a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748704425804576220524034207558.html">Op-Ed&lt;/a> that was recently published by a publication which is not exactly known for its do-gooder tendencies, the WSJ. It was written by a man I know of, but surprisingly have never run into in the very small expat community we have here in Hargeisa, Jonathon Starr. It was a rage against the machine of the aid industrial complex, something that I can generally get behind. There were parts of the article I agreed with and parts which I disagreed with. Jonathon attacks aid, which is his right – even though I would argue he is an outsider. I am unimpressed by some his more self-righteousness (I took no salary and expect my staff to do the same). He also makes the general broad-side attack of an industry that is very much fodder for an Op-Ed but lacks the detail and bite of a genuine argument which make me think and reflect. The basic gist of the article is that aid is fundamentally flawed because the lack of a profit motive therein causes inefficiencies in its delivery.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="http://talesfromethehood.com/2011/04/18/big-business/">second&lt;/a> was a response to Jonathon’s piece by one of my favorite aid-bloggers, J, who maintains the &lt;a href="http://http://talesfromethehood.com/">Tales from the Hood&lt;/a> blog (as well as the uber hilarious &lt;a href="http://stuffexpataidworkerslike.com">Stuff Expat Aid Workers Like&lt;/a>). J does not have the nicest take on what Jonathon originally wrote. He attacks Jonathon as an outsider who never learned about aid (a meme that he often comes back to and one in which I only partially buy). But more to the point, he defends aid by saying that it should not be run as a business.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-thoughts">The thoughts.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I would enjoy a response from Jonathon to J.  But in the event (a phrase I am increasingly enjoying), I think that if a discussion were to develop they may be arguing past each other. I have a decent understanding of what Jonathon is doing here. It is a small town, and even smaller where the expats are concerned; as with all small towns, we’re in each other’s business to the point of dysfunction. What he is doing is not really what I would classify as aid work. That is to say, it isn’t NGO work as I would classify such. I would call it non-profit work. I make this distinction because Jonathon isn’t really struggling with the same things that most people I know who are EAWs struggle with. It is a subtle distinction, running a program focussed on opening schools and opening a school, but it is a distinction nonetheless. I should clarify this more but it is getting late and I’m lazy. Let us leave it at this: the scale, the tensions, the accounting, the partners – all of these are very different. That aside, Jonathon is clearly an intelligent man and whether he lacks or possesses epistemic authority as an insider to back his argument he originally crafted it and I would hope that he is willing to engage, defend, respond, and converse.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think they both could agree on one point, and it is a point which &lt;a href="http://owenabroad.com">Owen Barder&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://http://www.oxfamblogs.org/fp2p/">Duncan Green&lt;/a> have made eloquently. Owen has made it numerous times, and &lt;a href="http://www.owen.org/blog/4018">here&lt;/a> is one example. I cannot seem to find Duncan’s, but I remember he has written at least one very good piece on it. The upshot of their argument is that aid is fundamentally lacking feedback mechanisms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This, it seems to me, is what Jonathon was originally trying to say. He rightly identifies one of the major problems with aid (its lack of feedback), but he misplaces the meat of his argument by equivocating (wrongly I think) a profit motive with feedback. Yes, in some businesses the bottom line is one of the feedback mechanisms to show whether there is uptake of the goods or services. But the key is not the presence or absence of a profit motive, the key is the presence of ANY feedback loop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>J rightly defends some of the current state of aid affairs by saying that indeed aid is not business and some efforts to make it more business-like would be misplaced. Such a reformation would in many instances leave out the real points of aid which is delivery of services to under-serviced sectors – sectors which the profit driven world has, for whatever reason, missed. That would be precisely contrary to what the aid world should be doing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Learning from different sectors is one thing. When I was a Marine, I knew others who got the opportunity to go be seconded to a big company or to the stock exchange for a year or so. They brought back with them their lessons learned and they improved some things within the Corps. And that was fine. That is simply organizational learning. But the reformation which Jonathon proposes is quite a different thing. I fail to see where the presence of a profit motive would truly affect the delivery of NGO services. I see for-profit clinics and schools all around me during my drive to work every day. And I also see tons of kids unable to afford those schools therefore playing in the streets at school time and old ladies too sick to walk to the clinic and unable to afford the clinics anyway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The profit motive is not what is wrong with aid. What is wrong with aid is that it has built into itself neither feedback loops nor accountability. I do not know of a single industry more isolated or insular than aid. There are those inside the echo chambers of twitter and blogs and they are each trying their best to improve the accountability and the feedback mechanisms, but the bottom line is that aid is an industry which is out of site and out of mind for everyone who is not an insider. And what incentive to any of the insiders have to change things other than simple altruism which is never a very powerful motivator? If aid fundamentally changed and if aid accomplished its mission many of the insiders would be out of jobs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And so the cycles spin and people (like J) scream how aid needs professionals in order for it to be delivered correctly. While I do not quibble with what he is saying, I think that outsiders need to engage more. I appreciate the courage which Jonathon displayed in making his original argument. The more outsiders disrupt, the more insiders disrupt, the more improvements we will hopefully see.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are lots of spaces to fill. There are spaces which aid (at least of the international, relatively big-money variety) deserves to be, where it can properly fit and prosper. There are spaces where locally oriented non-profits deserve to be, where they can properly fit and prosper. And there are spaces where businesses should be. If each continues to share lessons learned and if there continues to be a good conversation between the many camps and factions then hopefully what we are all searching for, a reasonable chance for those we wee around us, will come ever closer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But let us not turn our comparisons of apples and oranges into app-ange juice because even though I have never drank that I’m not sure it would be delicious.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>