<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>development on underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/development/</link><description>Recent content in development on underWater desert Blogging</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Casey Kuhlman</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Latent, Natural Synergies Between Virtual Currencies, Open Data Schemes, and International Development</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-02-20-the-latent-natural-synergies-between-cryptocurrencies-opendata-development/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-02-20-the-latent-natural-synergies-between-cryptocurrencies-opendata-development/</guid><description>I like it when disparate things work well together. Like fish farming and hydroponic vegetable growing for instance (aka aquaponics). I see some increasing levels of synergy between virtual currencies, open data schemes and international development.
Virtual Currencies For those that do not know, virtual currencies or cryptocurrencies are an ecosystem of transmitting value similar in nature to traditional or fiat currencies (dollars, yen, yuan, pounds, euros, etc.) except with added levels of convience and security which you do not get when you want to transmit value by giving someone a piece of paper.</description></item><item><title>On Chasing Chaos: The best book about "The Life" I've read in ages.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2013-10-16-on-chasing-chaos/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2013-10-16-on-chasing-chaos/</guid><description>![Chasing Chaos by Jessica Alexander c/o Amazon]({{ site.url }}{{ site.root }}{{ site.images_dir }}/{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; }}/51ln21GGC7L.SY300.jpg)
Disclosure: On a few occasions I have been known to partake in beverages with the author. Not on many, but on a few. Oh, and my wife is an amalgamated character in the book.
Chasing Chaos examines the lives that aid workers lead and the work which aid workers do in vivid clarity and with honesty, clarity, and warmth.</description></item><item><title>Taking the E out of M&amp;E for Governance Projects</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2013-07-12-taking-the-e-out-of-mande/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2013-07-12-taking-the-e-out-of-mande/</guid><description>As part of my work for Vanderbilt Law School&amp;lsquo;s International Legal Studies Program I recently pushed a grant application to a US Government Agency that was all about increasing the capacity of an institution to perform its mandated functionality. It was a relatively straight-forward submission &amp;ndash; the safest I've been involved in lately as it had the least amount of innovation I have built into a submission in years. For these reasons, I feel we have a relatively high chance of success.</description></item><item><title>For Business or for Pleasure: Which is Aid?</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2011-04-18-for-business-or-for-pleasure-which-is-aid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2011-04-18-for-business-or-for-pleasure-which-is-aid/</guid><description>This week two interesting articles (to me) have been published and they have given me the push to return to commenting.
The articles.
The first was an Op-Ed that was recently published by a publication which is not exactly known for its do-gooder tendencies, the WSJ. It was written by a man I know of, but surprisingly have never run into in the very small expat community we have here in Hargeisa, Jonathon Starr.</description></item></channel></rss>