<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>africa on underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/africa/</link><description>Recent content in africa on underWater desert Blogging</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Casey Kuhlman</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/africa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Latent, Natural Synergies Between Virtual Currencies, Open Data Schemes, and International Development</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-02-20-the-latent-natural-synergies-between-cryptocurrencies-opendata-development/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2014-02-20-the-latent-natural-synergies-between-cryptocurrencies-opendata-development/</guid><description>I like it when disparate things work well together. Like fish farming and hydroponic vegetable growing for instance (aka aquaponics). I see some increasing levels of synergy between virtual currencies, open data schemes and international development.
Virtual Currencies For those that do not know, virtual currencies or cryptocurrencies are an ecosystem of transmitting value similar in nature to traditional or fiat currencies (dollars, yen, yuan, pounds, euros, etc.) except with added levels of convience and security which you do not get when you want to transmit value by giving someone a piece of paper.</description></item><item><title>Perspectives on Africa -&amp;gt; Its all about the lens</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-10-25-perspectives-africa-lens/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-10-25-perspectives-africa-lens/</guid><description>When you look at this picture what do you see? I see a man who is satisfied with his situation. Sure there are the tribal markings, the blanket over the shoulder, the bleakness of the background and the stuff on the back of the man’s neck. But what really jumps out, to me at least, is the satisfied look that his eyes and his mouth convey.
Two development pundit bloggers have discussed recently the cultural meme which the photos that are chosen to accompany NGO marketing campaigns, news articles on Africa, etc.</description></item><item><title>I&amp;#8217;m Supposed to Write on Water, but I Don&amp;#8217;t Have Any&amp;#8230;</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-10-15-supposed-write-water-any/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-10-15-supposed-write-water-any/</guid><description>![Broken Pipe via Starbuck Powersurge @ flickr]({{ site.url }}{{ site.root }}{{ site.images_dir }}/{{ page.date | date: &amp;ldquo;%Y&amp;rdquo; }}/262341270_2017b87199.jpg)
Today the Interweb Gods have deemed is World Blog about water day. Or likely more accurately, the brilliant change.org marketers have deemed today as world blog about water:Day. I haven’t read every post I have seen come across my various Twitter wires, but the ones I’ve read talk about the need for us to have water.</description></item><item><title>Chinese Powered Self-Sufficiency in Africa</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-05-26-chinese-powered-self-sufficiency-africa/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-05-26-chinese-powered-self-sufficiency-africa/</guid><description>Ellen Johnson-Sirleaf &amp;amp; Hillary Clinton via @FP_Magazine
Madam President Ellen Johnson-Sirleaf the current President of Liberia did a remarkable thing yesterday. She told the world that in ten years Liberia would be self-sufficient and able to stand on its own feet with only further investment and no aid.
In ten years, Liberia will have been out of its civil war for about fifteen or sixteen depending on how one classifies the end.</description></item><item><title>Bono Writes About Africa (My Eyes Begin to Roll)</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-04-18-bono-writes-africa-my-eyes-roll/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-04-18-bono-writes-africa-my-eyes-roll/</guid><description>I desperately wanted to hate this op-ed which the NYT published yesterday and Bono wrote, but at the end it was a rather good piece. There is this narrative which is beginning to form which is the first coherent, resonant, and positive narrative on Africa that I’ve heard.
Bono’s piece encapsulates the narrative quite well actually, but let me summarize. Africa is getting to get its act together. Although outliers like here where I live will remain, the rest of the continent (led by countries like Senegal, Ghana, Tanzania, and Botswana) are really moving forward.</description></item></channel></rss>