<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/</link><description>A Site About Resilience and Authoritarianism</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</managingEditor><webMaster>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</webMaster><copyright>All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/africa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Latent, Natural Synergies Between Virtual Currencies, Open Data Schemes, and International Development</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-20-the-latent-natural-synergies-between-cryptocurrencies-opendata-development/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014/2014-02-20-the-latent-natural-synergies-between-cryptocurrencies-opendata-development/</guid><description>&lt;p>I like it when disparate things work well together. Like fish farming and hydroponic vegetable growing for instance (aka aquaponics). I see some increasing levels of synergy between virtual currencies, open data schemes and international development.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="virtual-currencies">Virtual Currencies&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For those that do not know, virtual currencies or cryptocurrencies are an ecosystem of transmitting value similar in nature to traditional or fiat currencies (dollars, yen, yuan, pounds, euros, etc.) except with added levels of convience and security which you do not get when you want to transmit value by giving someone a piece of paper.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The community which uses virtual currencies is small but growing at a substantial rate, so we are far from adoption. However, one of the exciting aspects of virtual currencies for application in developing countries is the ability of anyone with any feature or smart phone to instantly conduct international transactions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>People who follow Somalia|Somaliland will well remember that last summer there was a huge kerfuffle because Barclays indicated that it was going to revoke Dahabshiil's accounts. Dahabshiil, for those who are not Somalia watchers, is the largest money transfer and financial services provider in the Somali region. Its business model outside of Somalia is very similar in nature to Western Union's traditional money transfer system (you bring your neighborhood agent cash and they transmit it to whomever you determine). Inside of Somalia Dahabshiil acts more along the lines of a traditional bank. Most people keep their money in a Dahabshiil account rather than in cash. So the kerfuffle with Barclays would mean that people in Europe|America|Canada|Australia, wherever would have to change how they were sending money to Somalia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For some this was a huge problem because they may live in a place where other options are not available. Although, since Western Union does have agents in Somalia I always felt that much of the kerfuffle was overblown. I was pleased to see the activist community successfully push for a Barclays to change their position, but the bottom line is Dahabshiil has an outdated business model and has been very conservative in pivoting from that position which opens up an innovation space for other, more nimble companies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Enter virtual currencies. With Bitcoin, a diaspora can easily purchase Bitcoin in their home country in their home currency from either an &lt;a href="http://37coins.com">SMS transaction&lt;/a> or an online &lt;a href="http://kraken.com">bank&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://coinbase.com">transfer&lt;/a>. Once the diaspora has Bitcoin they can then easily transfer the Bitcoin to anyone in the world as long as the recipient has a Bitcoin wallet (which can be set up nearly instantly with a system like 37 Coins offers). Boom. Remittance system blockage overcome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What is really exciting me, though, for a development perspective is the next level of innovation that is happening with virtual currencies which will allow the building of smart contracts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The idea of smart contracts, or virtual automatic contracts, is that you can build arbitrary, neutral triggers which will then be able to transmit value from one place to another when the triggers happen.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="open-data-as-a-neutral-indicator-of-things-happening">Open Data as a Neutral Indicator of &amp;ldquo;Things Happening&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>What is further exciting is that open data movements are beginning to succeed in at least getting some amount of neutral data widely available. This is beginning to be a wave with European governments showing real leadership in this space (in particular, the UK government is doing great work here).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Open data with proper APIs will be able to provide smart contracts with the link between the &amp;ldquo;real world&amp;rdquo; and the virtual world which the contracts can see. So let's take a system like crop insurance. Within the year, a coder|lawyer could easily build a smart contract which would pay out based upon an inverse relationship to the rainfall (or other neutral, accessible data metric) in a given location.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="social-bonds-as-smart-contracts">Social Bonds as Smart Contracts&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>One of the ideas which the &lt;a href="http://www.cgdev.org">Center for Global Development&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.cgdev.org/page/development-impact-bond-working-group">others&lt;/a> are working on is the idea of a Develpment Impact Bond. &lt;a href="http://www.cgdev.org/blog/what-if-you-could-invest-development">Here&lt;/a> is a good overview by Owen Barder, and &lt;a href="http://www.socialfinance.org.uk/work/developmentimpactbonds">here&lt;/a> is another from Social Finance. The basic idea for Development Impact Bonds is that you build a bond structure which any company, organization, government, or individual can invest in and that will pay out upon certain, pre-determined metrics being hit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Social Finance is in the midst of working on a pilot for this in the UK where they have asked the Ministry of Justice to commoditize how much recidivism is worth to the UK economy. So when people go back into jail that costs society and if you can put a price on that cost then you can aggregate and float that price with some level of discount to any group that says they can reduce recidivism. After that, the organization who is the recipient of the bond can then determine the best way to achieve the outcome stated by the terms of the bond. Of course there will be some implementation limits built into the bond contract but for the most part those will be increasingly fewer over time. The advantage which the bond holder will get is that it will have an asset which it can leverage in interesting ways, and use fundraise in interesting ways (as it could be used as collateral).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is an idea which is intellectually appealing to me, but in practice would require a lot of human oversight. Enter smart contracts. Smart contracts could oversee the entire process automatically with no human interaction if they were properly built. This would be powerful tool for accelerating outcome based development mechanisms.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="smart-contracts-as-cash-on-delivery-mechanisms">Smart Contracts as Cash on Delivery Mechanisms&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Another interesting and important idea which the CGD has been interested in for years is the &lt;a href="http://www.cgdev.org/initiative/cash-delivery-aid">cash on delivery&lt;/a>. COD has a lot of relevance to impact bonds but on a more decentralized basis. Here's what CGD says about COD:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Cash on Delivery is a new approach to foreign aid that focuses on results, encourages innovation, and strengthens government accountability to citizens rather than donors. Under COD Aid, donors would pay for measurable and verifiable progress on specific outcomes, such as $100 dollars for every child above baseline expectations who completes primary school and takes a test.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>But here's the interesting way which smart contracts could do this. With COD you have a neutral outcome based metric (kids butts in school chairs). This metric can be aggregated with an open data push and a proper API. Then you have a payout schedule which could be per day, per week, per month, per quarter, per year, whatever. The payouts are structured based upon meeting the criteria determined in the metric. Again, smart contracts could be built which would manage this with minimal human interactivity (as long as you could get the data that is).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The interesting thing which you can do with smart contracts is that it would be trivial to have payouts to a million recipients or one recipient (once you add the addresses of the recipients &amp;ndash; as is currently being piloted in many ways with mobile money). So you could structure the COD mechanism so that A portion of the money will be paid to the central government; B portion to the regional government; C portion to the local school itself; and D portion to each parent of the students.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Incentives matter and behavioral economists are continuing to find new and interesting ways to structure incentive models for positive societal change. With some minimal investment into using virtual currencies and smart contracts alongside open data initiatives we will soon reach a point where to test different incentive models will require a simple change of a few lines of code, some time, and some analysis of the outcomes in R (all of this done from anywhere in the world) to determine the viability of the incentive structure to address the problem one is trying to address. Compare that to the way in which an implementing agency today would have to pivot in order to test, pilot, or scale a hypothesis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We in the development world &lt;em>should&lt;/em> know that speed and nimbleness are just as important for development workers as they are for businesses and smart contracts + open data would dramatically increase the speed at which certain things could be addressed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Perspectives on Africa -&amp;gt; Its all about the lens</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-25-perspectives-africa-lens/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-25-perspectives-africa-lens/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.how-matters.org/about/">&lt;img src="http://www.how-matters.org/about/" alt="Facial Scarification in Africa in the early 1940s via gbaku @ flickr">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you look at this picture what do you see?  I see a man who is satisfied with his situation.  Sure there are the tribal markings, the blanket over the shoulder, the bleakness of the background and the stuff on the back of the man’s neck.  But what really jumps out, to me at least, is the satisfied look that his eyes and his mouth convey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Two development pundit bloggers have discussed recently the cultural meme which the photos that are chosen to accompany NGO marketing campaigns, news articles on Africa, etc. convey. &lt;a href="http://www.how-matters.org/about/"> Jennifer Lentfer&lt;/a> who runs &lt;a href="http://www.how-matters.org/">how-matters.org&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://glennagordon.com/">Glenna Gordon&lt;/a> who runs &lt;a href="http://www.scarlettlion.com/">ScarlettLion.com&lt;/a>, among other sites, &lt;a href="http://www.how-matters.org/2010/10/24/pity-pictures-and-poverty/">both&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://www.scarlettlion.com/2010/10/just-how-stereotypical-are-images-of-africa.html">posted&lt;/a> on this issue yesterday.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Am not sure exactly, but seems that the beginning of the conversation was Jennifer finding &lt;a href="http://waterwellness.ca/2010/04/28/perspectives-of-poverty/">this&lt;/a> posting from &lt;a href="http://waterwellness.ca/about/">Duncan McNicholl&lt;/a>.  The premise of Duncan’s posting is that the same subject arranged in two different modes conveys two very different emotional responses.  To take it a step further, the argument goes that the types of images which are chosen to be displayed in NGO marketing items, donor reports, media reports, etc. reflect both the world’s pre-conceived image of Africa &lt;em>as well as&lt;/em> furthering the intention of the person or organization which is using the image.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course, this makes sense.  Generally most people would prefer to vindicate held opinions rather than challenge them.  But challenging opinions is the only way to change the cultural lens and changing the cultural lens is one of the post powerful enabling mechanisms for solidifying deep changes within societies.  Indeed, the NY Times ran a great &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/10/24/magazine/24FOB-Footbinding-t.html?_r=2&amp;amp;partner=rss&amp;amp;emc=rss&amp;amp;pagewanted=all">article&lt;/a> in their weekend magazine about this topic yesterday.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The thing is this (he says as he puts on his lawyer hat) it takes a long time to change the perspectives of people.  It takes words, images, experience, and most of all repetition.  It takes emotional arguments, data-based arguments, and logical arguments.   And it is slow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Civil rights, suffrage, abolition, etc. did not come about just because someone in a position of authority said, “yeah this is how it is going to happen.”  They happened because first people worked hard to show the problems with the current cultural lens.  This happened through broad-based approaches (which obviously varied considering the different times and persons involved).  After the cultural lens was changed sufficiently, then legal and political mechanisms were triggered which could provide some accountability around the new cultural norm which was developing.  Those legal and political mechanisms have to be triggered *after *there is sufficiency in the base of people who will believe that what you are arguing for makes sense despite the history and the cultural norms of the moment.  Those legal and political mechanisms &lt;em>have&lt;/em> to be triggered (usually) in order to bring the “rest” into compliance with the cultural norm; in other words, to provide accountability.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But what in the world does that have to do with pictures in shiny brochures?  First, the analogy very much falls apart when probed in depth, so don’t do that.   I bring it up mainly to show that cultural change takes time and effort along many different tracks.  It seems to me that we’re at the beginning of this process with respect to the “world’s” opinion of “Africa.”  Even for development workers and bloggers I still see all too frequently a headline which says, essentially, “wow there’s some good news from Africa and here is what it is.”  It is of lesser import to me the surprise which is consonant in the headlines.  What is of greater import is that the headlines are running.  They are running more and more, at least across my twitter and rss feeds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This base hopefully will in due course enable the triggering of some powerful accountability mechanisms.  Although the accountability mechanisms which can solidify the march towards progress which so many in the cheetah generation deserve and crave will not be as strong as a declaration as (say) an amendment to the US Constitution would be, they will be there.  And their presence will help to change the assumptions of the cultural laggards.  Perhaps more importantly, they will allow the next generation of elites within many countries of Africa to make the difficult decisions and to take the difficult steps which will reduce the income gaps and bring the middle class further along.  And after that, things will take care of themselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is great stuff happening throughout Africa all the time.  People are creating beautiful images, beautiful paintings, and beautiful narratives.  It is fantastic to see, and I appreciate that people are pointing these out.  As more and more people hop onto the train the momentum will grow, not slow.  Some recent examples:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>African Digital Art’s Weekly Inspiration Postings: &lt;a href="http://www.africandigitalart.com/category/african-weekly-inspiration/">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>NYTimes Lens Blog on Dakar: &lt;a href="http://lens.blogs.nytimes.com/2010/10/07/senegals-changing-urban-landscape/">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Peter DiCampo’s Life without Lights series: &lt;a href="http://www.peterdicampo.com/#/life-without-lights/nightly-life/NIGHTLY_LIFE-1">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Sure things are still screwed up in many many ways.  But what is important to me about the meme which is developing is that the baseline assumptions about what the “current state of Africa” is moving.  This will create/has created a base of support among many.  At this point it seems to be coming mainly from development people and Africans themselves who are increasingly using the megaphone of the internet to get their message across.  But it has to begin somewhere.  From this base, a larger base will grow and the meme will extend to laggards within organizations and to laggard organizations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course it will be a long time before the &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/10/24/magazine/24sirleaf-t.html?ref=ellen_johnson_sirleaf">profile&lt;/a> of a ground-breaking woman will not begin with the backdrop of devastation, conflict, and decay.  It will be a long time until even those of us that live here in Africa change our assumptions to reflect the progress which is all around us.  And yet, it is happening.  Slowly but surely, like a nomad moving to a new grazing area, the collective cultural lens is shifting.  For me, for now, that is enough.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PS – Some pictures we’ve taken recently of Hargeisa can be found below. [flickr-gallery mode=&amp;quot;photoset&amp;rdquo; photoset=&amp;quot;72157625029540307&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I&amp;#8217;m Supposed to Write on Water, but I Don&amp;#8217;t Have Any&amp;#8230;</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-15-supposed-write-water-any/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-10-15-supposed-write-water-any/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today the Interweb Gods have deemed is World Blog about water day.  Or likely more accurately, the brilliant &lt;a href="http://blogactionday.change.org/">change.org&lt;/a> marketers have deemed today as world blog about water:Day.  I haven’t read every post I have seen come across my various Twitter wires, but the ones I’ve read talk about the need for us to have water.  Seems pretty self-evident and so the rhetoric can turn into a polemic rather quickly.  I thought about writing a love post to water, but then I realized that I’m annoyed at water.  We fell out with each other a couple of weeks ago, which by the way was the last time water came through my pipes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The water system in Hargeisa is over stretched, under maintained, now badly managed network, under funded cluster of an organization.  It makes money so the government doesn’t want to privatize it.  And that is likely the right move considering the power system is privatized and is a mess.  It is all the rage to claim that the private sector is going to save Africa, and I while I believe that I’m not a complete free marketer.  The private sector can be just as lazy and dumb as a public sector can be.  The presence of competition does not necessitate innovation and good economic behavior in and of itself.  But that is a different story and before I go down that road, let me tell you about my pipe problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The pipes that supply Hargeisa were buried about an 1 deep all willy nilly throughout the place.  Whenever you go off of the main roads it is inevitable that you’ll have to drive over one.  That isn’t a structural economic problem.  That has little to do with Ministerial efficiency or World Bank proclamations.  It is just stupid and lazy workmanship.  It doesn’t have anything to do with a depressed education system or beleaguered healthcare system.  it is just stupid and lazy workmanship.  Nothing more, nothing less.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And because these pipes were not buried deep enough, and because I live near a bus station, the pipes that come to my house often are broken by buses running over them.  And then we have to pay for a plumber to come fix them.  The Water Agency this time even refused to drive a plumber up here even after we agreed to pay for the plumber.  And then after we brought the plumber up here to our sector of Hargeisa, the guy wanted $20, TWENTY DOLLARS, to do the fifteen minutes of work it would require to cut a new pipe, tap it, and tighten it onto the new pipe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I told the guy to f-off.  He laughed, I rolled my eyes, he said ten, I agreed.  And then he fixed the pipe.  But since that time no water has come through the pipes.  I don’t think they’re broken as we can usually tell.  In the morning when we drive to work if the water has come and the pipe is broken it just pools uselessly in the muck at the main intersection of the bus station.  In a desert country with small water resources no one seems to give an F about this water just sitting there.  But that hasn’t happened in the past week or ten days since we paid the plumber to fix the water.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why is that the case?  Because I live near a hotel.  You know the kind, one of the few places in town known to cater to expats.  They are all in one shape or form the same.  But the guy who owns the hotel pays the guy who controls the water in our sector a little bit more each month and so the water guy reroutes almost all of the water to the hotel.  The old Hargeisa water manager was a friend of ours and when we told him our hypothesis in this regard he investigated, found it to be true, fought tooth and nail (I heard directly many of the conversations between him and the sector manager who is below him) for us, and still was only moderately successful in getting us water.  Since he was sacked for unknown reasons which had nothing to do with his competence but basically boiled down to the other dude supported the government than won the recent election and had to be rewarded somehow, since that time we have gotten water through the pipes on only a couple of occasions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So water and I have seemingly broken up.  And that is not cool with me.  It isn’t cool in a way that  has nothing to do with what any policymaker or bureaucrat or large NGO marketing department wants me to think.  It isn’t cool and it has nothing to do with funding levels (throwing more money at the sector isn’t going to get the pipes buried deeper, repaired faster, or micro-managed more equitably), bold statements, or glossy web sites.  It isn’t cool and much of it comes down to stupidity and laziness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Excuse me, I gotta run, the dude that drives the donkey cart with the ex-oil drum on the back is here to deliver my water.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chinese Powered Self-Sufficiency in Africa</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-05-26-chinese-powered-self-sufficiency-africa/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-05-26-chinese-powered-self-sufficiency-africa/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://blog.foreignpolicy.com/posts/2010/05/25/liberias_ellen_johnson_sirleaf">&lt;img src="http://blog.foreignpolicy.com/posts/2010/05/25/liberias_ellen_johnson_sirleaf" alt="Johnson-Sirleaf &amp; Clinton via @FP_Magazine">&lt;/a>
Ellen Johnson-Sirleaf &amp;amp; Hillary Clinton via @FP_Magazine&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Madam President Ellen Johnson-Sirleaf the current President of Liberia did a remarkable thing yesterday.  She &lt;a href="http://blog.foreignpolicy.com/posts/2010/05/25/liberias_ellen_johnson_sirleaf">told &lt;/a>the world that in ten years Liberia would be self-sufficient and able to stand on its own feet with only further investment &lt;em>and no aid&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In ten years, Liberia will have been out of its civil war for about fifteen or sixteen depending on how one classifies the end.  And if Liberia were to achieve it, they would have accomplished something remarkable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To provide some context Rwanda is now about sixteen years after their conflict.  They have had a President that in many ways can be analogized to Johnson-Sirleaf.  Kagame is pro-business, pro-US, and takes a rational approach to China.  And Rwanda is by all metrics doing very well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But they are not, yet, self-sufficient.  Liberia has distinct advantages that Rwanda does not.  More resources and sea-access are the main advantages.  So it may not be completely accurate to compare the two.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I especially appreciate her stance on China.  Many people in the development world wring their hands about China’s involvement in Africa.  This always comes across to me as protectionism of our fiefdoms.  There is &lt;em>no way that China can teach Africa anything, all they will do is steal their resources&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let us not forget that Western companies have been stealing Africa’s resources for years.  I know plenty of Africans who are happy about the way that China interacts with their country.  They feel that the Chinese treat them more equally and less antagonistically than most donor agencies and iNGOs (especially governance iNGOs).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ellen really seems to pinpoint the African meme towards China with this quote:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“China’s fast,” she explained. “They know what they want and they do it quickly.” Building schools, building roads, signing contracts, and offering loans — all of it can be done in weeks or months, not years as some donors and Western investors might take. In short, “China’s flexible.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And this speed is critical.  Opportunities for reform or development often open and close before Western donors can get an RFP published, much less funded, contracted, distributed, and the agency beginning to reform or development agenda.  China is much quicker, and while Westerners may question their motives, at least their motives are clear to everyone: them and their partners.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In summary, this clarity makes it easier for them to operate.  I doubt it is frequent that Chinese in Africa are accused of being spies.  Meanwhile, I have been accused of being a spy nearly every day for two years – something that has deeply affected the receptivity to my work and a story for another day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bono Writes About Africa (My Eyes Begin to Roll)</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-04-18-bono-writes-africa-my-eyes-roll/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-04-18-bono-writes-africa-my-eyes-roll/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/04/18/opinion/18bono.html?pagewanted=1&amp;amp;hp">&lt;img src="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/04/18/opinion/18bono.html?pagewanted=1&amp;amp;hp" alt="photo from maaarine via flickr">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I desperately wanted to hate &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/04/18/opinion/18bono.html?pagewanted=1&amp;amp;hp">this&lt;/a> op-ed which the NYT published yesterday and Bono wrote, but at the end it was a rather good piece.  There is this narrative which is beginning to form which is the first coherent, resonant, and positive narrative on Africa that I’ve heard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bono’s piece encapsulates the narrative quite well actually, but let me summarize.  Africa is getting to get its act together.  Although outliers like here where I live will remain, the rest of the continent (led by countries like Senegal, Ghana, Tanzania, and Botswana) are really moving forward.  Last year was the first time since the 1960s where average per capita income for the entire continent rose.  Arts are flourishing, people are beginning to move up Maslow’s hierarchy which is developing a strong and engaged middle-class.  In summary, it is an exciting time in Africa for all the reasons it has always been exciting, but for new ones too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I did like some of the imagery in the piece.  Particularly how at Ghana University Mo Ibrahim was the rock star and Bono was the apprentice.  I like how Bono day dreams of owning NBC and NYT (but I wonder why NBC).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the end of the day, the taste that resides in my mouth is of optimism.  And that, in and of itself is a big step forward. Because the rest of this is going to take work, lots of work and hope will be the fuel of that engine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>