<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>africa on underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/africa/</link><description>Recent content in africa on underWater desert Blogging</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/tags/africa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Latent, Natural Synergies Between Virtual Currencies, Open Data Schemes, and International Development</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014-02-20-the-latent-natural-synergies-between-cryptocurrencies-opendata-development/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2014-02-20-the-latent-natural-synergies-between-cryptocurrencies-opendata-development/</guid><description>I like it when disparate things work well together. Like fish farming and hydroponic vegetable growing for instance (aka aquaponics). I see some increasing levels of synergy between virtual currencies, open data schemes and international development. Here's why.</description></item><item><title>Perspectives on Africa -&amp;gt; Its all about the lens</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010-10-25-perspectives-africa-lens/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010-10-25-perspectives-africa-lens/</guid><description>The collective cultural lens which reflects some important baseline assumptions about &amp;lsquo;the state of Africa&amp;rsquo; are slowly beginning to change. The evidence is in economic publications, in NGO marketing documents, and in artistic memes. This is an important predicate for enabling the accountability mechanisms which will solidify progress to be triggered.</description></item><item><title>I&amp;#8217;m Supposed to Write on Water, but I Don&amp;#8217;t Have Any&amp;#8230;</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010-10-15-supposed-write-water-any/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010-10-15-supposed-write-water-any/</guid><description>Today the Interweb Gods have deemed is World Blog about water day. Or likely more accurately, the brilliant charity:Water marketers have deemed today as world blog about water:Day. I haven't read every post I have seen come across my various Twitter wires, but the ones I've read talk about the need for us to have water. Seems pretty self-evident and so the rhetoric can turn into a polemic rather quickly. I thought about writing a love post to water, but then I realized that I'm annoyed at water.</description></item><item><title>Chinese Powered Self-Sufficiency in Africa</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010-05-26-chinese-powered-self-sufficiency-africa/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010-05-26-chinese-powered-self-sufficiency-africa/</guid><description>Madam President Ellen Johnson-Sirleaf the current President of Liberia did a remarkable thing yesterday.  She [told ][2]the world that in ten years Liberia would be self-sufficient and able to stand on its own feet with only further investment &lt;em>and no aid&lt;/em>.</description></item><item><title>Bono Writes About Africa (My Eyes Begin to Roll)</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010-04-18-bono-writes-africa-my-eyes-roll/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010-04-18-bono-writes-africa-my-eyes-roll/</guid><description>I desperately wanted to hate [this][2] op-ed which the NYT published yesterday and Bono wrote, but at the end it was a rather good piece.  There is this narrative which is beginning to form which is the first coherent, resonant, and positive narrative on Africa that I’ve heard.</description></item></channel></rss>