<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/</link><description>A Site About Resilience and Authoritarianism</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</managingEditor><webMaster>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</webMaster><copyright>All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/film/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>&amp;#8216;Goonies 2&amp;#8242; an &amp;#8216;Absolute Certainty&amp;#8217;</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-09-goonies-2-an-absolute-certainty/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-09-goonies-2-an-absolute-certainty/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.iwatchstuff.com/2007/10/goonies_2_an_absolute_certaint.php" title="I Watch Stuff - 'Goonies 2' an 'Absolute Certainty' for Disappointment">&lt;img src="http://www.iwatchstuff.com/2007/10/goonies_2_an_absolute_certaint.php" alt="Goonies2certain" title="I Watch Stuff - 'Goonies 2' an 'Absolute Certainty' for Disappointment">&lt;/a>&lt;br>
I agree with everything this dude writes.  Especially the following line:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/10/08/goonies2certain.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/10/08/goonies2certain.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>They’ve developed an entire culture based on wanting me to punch them in the face.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Link: &lt;a href="http://www.iwatchstuff.com/2007/10/goonies_2_an_absolute_certaint.php" title="I Watch Stuff - 'Goonies 2' an 'Absolute Certainty' for Disappointment">I Watch Stuff – ‘Goonies 2′ an ‘Absolute Certainty’ for Disappointment&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kite Runner Movie</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-09-19-kite-runner-movie/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-09-19-kite-runner-movie/</guid><description>&lt;p>Just found out that Mark Forster, who directed Stranger Than Fiction, Finding Neverland and Monster’s Ball is directing the film adaptation of Kite Runner.  A very reputable NGO, International Rescue Group, who focuses on refugee issues among other things, has been consulting on the film.  I’m not sure if that lends the film an inordinate amount of credibility, but I think that it certainly lends some.  Hosseini co-wrote the screenplay so it may have a good following of the novel, which I haven’t read.  It is to be released state-side the beginning of November according to IMDb.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/Tm5e6AqrNF8" title="Click here to block this object with Adblock Plus">1&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>dirty pretty things</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-03-01-dirty-pretty-things/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-03-01-dirty-pretty-things/</guid><description>&lt;p>[![Dirtypr1][2]][2] the other week, i mean tuesday, we watched [dirty pretty things][2] at the expat hangout which i cannot decide whether i like or not.  it does have a real dartboard. and chicken wing sauce which is nice to dip fries in. and a real greek salad with kalamatas, and real feta cheese, and herbs and a nice dressing. i have dreams about the greek salad and the sauce, but not together b/c that would be just weird. yet, there aren’t any locals there, and it is expensive. and i feel wierdly priveleged when i walk in there. whatever. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/dirtypr1.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/dirtypr1.jpg&lt;/a>
[2]: &lt;a href="http://imdb.com/title/tt0301199/">http://imdb.com/title/tt0301199/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>the movie was interesting, although bit melodramatic in its ending.  it was about illegal immigrants in britain and the faustian bargains they are forced to seal.  it is worth a view….for a british flick.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>the dude abides.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-10-31-the-dude-abides/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-10-31-the-dude-abides/</guid><description>&lt;p>i don’t know about you….but this gives me hope.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![N4710044_31055129_4056][2]][2]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/photos/uncategorized/n4710044_31055129_4056.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/photos/uncategorized/n4710044_31055129_4056.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[![N4710044_31055143_6495][3]][3]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/photos/uncategorized/n4710044_31055143_6495.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/photos/uncategorized/n4710044_31055143_6495.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Update.</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-10-25-update/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-10-25-update/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;a href="http://www.nypost.com/seven/10232006/gossip/pagesix/pagesix.htm" title="STUDIO TOO FAR OUT ON A LIMB - New York Post Online Edition: Seven">New York Post&lt;/a> reports that a charity, after hearing about the horrific corporate, imperialistic exploitation of the children paid for the prosthetics.  If Warner Brothers does decide to get off their fat asses, walk across their plush carpetting on their two good (but fat) legs, pick up the phone with either of their good (but plump) hands and place a call to their fat bankers to wire a measly amount of throw-away money (likely less than they spent on condiments for the Leo trailer) to these children, that the charity will instead give the money for prosthetics to 27 other deserving children.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I didn’t include it earlier, but Warner’s alleged response when questioned by the children when their legs were coming was: &amp;ldquo;You will have to wait for December, when the movie comes out, so we can get some publicity out of it.&amp;rdquo;  Are you fucking kidding me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I implore you to &lt;a href="http://www2.warnerbros.com/web/main/help/fan_mail.jsp">email&lt;/a> Warner Bros. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pirate!</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-07-10-pirate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-07-10-pirate/</guid><description>&lt;p>i saw pirates friday night.  it was….it was.  not disappointing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>it was more violent than the first, and there was less of johnny depp’s witticisms.  the special effects were tremendous, the costume/set designers should both be oscar contenders.  the plot line was much more linear than the first movie.  there was also a different narrative arc that is the archetype for these movies, the tension was frontloaded and then like a good mile runner they just tried to ride out the momentum until the end.  i left feeling….odd.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>but there were a few things off about the movie.  first, it is long.  second, it is gross, which was fine but i thought once it got around the soccer mom circuit that it could dampen the movie’s core demographic of 12-15 year old boys (evidently i was initially proven wrong since they are projecting it to smash spider man’s opening weekend record, but we’ll see how long the movie’s legs are).  third, the ending.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>don’t get me wrong, the ending is fucking terrific.  terrific.  just odd.  i understand that it is the middle movie in a trilogy, but disney is taking a different tactic than most of the studios who have produced trilogies with what they have done with the second movie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>for some reason i kept picking out homage’s to other great movies.  there was a scene between depp and kiera that if you changed from pirates to outer space could have been taken directly from the first star wars trilogy.  some of the fight scenes were probably homages to flying daggers and other ground breaking movies from the kung fu genre.  but that is to be expected, hollywood can only be so original, so long.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>all in all i have no complaints.  it was a different movie going experience, which i suspect is why its rotten tomatoes rating is lower than i expected it to be.  i’m not sure what the critics have liked or disliked about the movie, but there is plenty on both sides of that issue to pinpoint.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>go. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>working on a feeling</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-07-working-on-a-feeling/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2006/2006-06-07-working-on-a-feeling/</guid><description>&lt;p>[![740759036_l_1][2]][2] tonight i saw this movie.  you should too.  it contains a decent soundtrack and one of my favorite vehicles for a narrative framework: the roadtrip.  some of the scenes in it were so spot on i didn’t know what to do.  i lapsed in to an analysis of the femine/masculine perspectives on life but was torn out of it when i realized that all the women around me were laughing at the things happening just as often as i was. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://www.thepuffychairmovie.com/screenings.html">http://www.thepuffychairmovie.com/screenings.html&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>there was one scene where they had just finished a long day’s drive and the boy is tired.  they climb into bed and all he wants to do is sleep, she is glowing from him even asking her to accompany him on the trip and in general and presumably had been sleeping the entire time .  she turns to him after he has expired the light and asks him if he loves her, &amp;ldquo;yes, baby, of course.&amp;rdquo; he  manages to mumble.  &amp;ldquo;what is it about me that you love?&amp;rdquo; she asks.  he is so taken aback that she wants to have a serious conversation that he immediately is put on the defensive and is ostensibly thinking &amp;ldquo;what the fuck did i do wrong now?&amp;rdquo; she is presumably bolstered by the intimacy (whether faux or real, whether imposed by the societal implications of many family journeys or not) that a road trip inevitably entails and wants to bask in that glow with conversation, the feminine fuel.  but his tanks are dry and all he wants to do is to get some fucking sleep. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>i flashed back to every relationship i’ve ever had.  it was a magnificent scene.  i thought that the beginning was fucking brilliant, the middle was honestly great, and the ending was OK. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>and that is my first movie review….deal with it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>cities</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-11-22-cities/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2005/2005-11-22-cities/</guid><description>&lt;p>tiny cities ARE made of ashes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>