<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/</link><description>A Site About Resilience and Authoritarianism</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</managingEditor><webMaster>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</webMaster><copyright>All Content Licensed CC BY-NC-SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/environment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Nice Photo Essay</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-04-nice-photo-essay/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2010/2010-02-04-nice-photo-essay/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AtlanticFood/~3/uezYTKIxnp0/click.phdo">Water Vanishes on Western Farms&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This photo essay captures the drying of California's Central Valley, where irrigation is a matter of life and death.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Eco-Labelling Biofuels</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-08-21-eco-labelling-biofuels/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-08-21-eco-labelling-biofuels/</guid><description>&lt;p>Geez, hippies love their eco-labeling.  Perhaps it comports with their world-view of non-force-ment of normatively superior products.  Perhaps it gives them something to talk about at parties, a consumer status-symbol.  Whatever the case, now there is a labeling standard for biofuels.  From &lt;a href="http://www.triplepundit.com/pages/major-parties-agree-on-global--003420.php">Triple Pundit&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Manufacturers and other parties involved with biofuels have agreed on a global&lt;br>
green biofuel standard. The &lt;a href="http://www.bioenergywiki.net/index.php/RSB_Principles_and_Criteria_(version_0)">new&lt;br>
standard&lt;/a> hopefully will eradicate the controversy and confusion that&lt;br>
surrounds biofuels at the moment. Its main guarantee is food security and&lt;br>
signatories include BP and Shell.
The biofuel standard is very similar to the &lt;a href="http://www.fsc.org/">Forest Stewardship Council’&lt;/a>s certification for&lt;br>
different types of paper. The organization behind the biofuel standard is the &lt;a href="http://www.bioenergywiki.net/index.php/Roundtable_on_Sustainable_Biofuels">Roundtable&lt;br>
on Sustainable Biofuels (RSB)&lt;/a>. It is located in Switzerland at the Energy&lt;br>
Center at the Swiss Federal Institute of Technology in Lausanne (EPFL).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The signatories to the new standard include the big league oil companies BP&lt;br>
and Shell as well as more than 300 professionals from organizations linked to&lt;br>
biofuels both in the public and private sector and civil society movements. The&lt;br>
RSB was formed because of all the bad press biofuels are getting and aims to&lt;br>
inform consumers in depth about the good and the bad. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Saddling up the Saharan Sun</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-07-23-saddling-up-the-saharan-sun/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-07-23-saddling-up-the-saharan-sun/</guid><description>&lt;p>[![Solar460x276][2]][2]&lt;br>
[This ][2]is good news, and something that I’ve been thinking about for a while.  The Europeans want to build gigantic solar power stations in the Sahara and pipe the electricity up via high capacity transmission lines under the Med to the European grid system. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e200e553ceb2078834-pi">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e200e553ceb2078834-pi&lt;/a>
[2]: &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/2008/jul/23/solarpower.windpower">http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/2008/jul/23/solarpower.windpower&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although I have to laud this idea, I have two problems/concerns with this.  First, the centralization of the power grid is something that I have philosophical problems with.  All though economies of scale are certainly at work, there are problems when you have fewer nodes in the system.  Also if the plan only calls for a limited amount of transmission lines under the Med then there could be problems centralizing that.  A few depth charges could take out all of Europe’s power, or less nefariously, any technical problems with the transmission lines could have drastic effects throughout an entire region that is vital to the world economy.  I would like this much better if we could figure out a way to transfer the energy physically, by storing it at the solar sight in some way and then shipping it to Europe for energy release onto the grid system.  Although I have no idea if this is scientifically feasible or if the energy losses in the storage and release with the additional energy transfer (solar to “chemical” to electricity rather than solar to electricity) would make it counterproductive, it seems that if that technology could be designed than freeing the grid up around the world would be much, much easier.  My other problem with this is that there is no commitment to enhancing the infrastructure of the African grid system.  The lines could just as easily be run south.  In fact they could be run south easier in many cases (as long as you could get the authority from the sovereigns along the way) as it is overland rather than undersea.  So here the Euros are gripping and moaning about how the Africans have no power and in typical post-imperial fashion are perfectly willing to invest massive amounts of dollars in needed infrastructure improvements but only to the extent that they are able to extract the sunlight for their benefit. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Come ON!  I hope that the pan-Africanists in the North African region will prevail upon the Europeans that if they do grant them the rights to build such a system that they also make commitments to running power lines south.  Yes, I understand that you cannot easily tap into the African grid system (as such a thing does not exist), but if we are going to be tied into grids then this would be an important first step in that direction.  If the Euro’s can make a commitment to building the structures and then provide enough electricity for Africa as well, with the responsibilities on the African nations to come to an agreement on building the transmission lines and some other decentralized nodes to support the system, then I am 100% on board.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Power Grid 2.0</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-28-power-grid-2-0/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-06-28-power-grid-2-0/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.triplepundit.com/pages/wheres-my-wind-outdated-grid-t-003285.php">Here&lt;/a> is a good article about updating the power grid in the US. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is something I’ve been thinking about for a while.  One of the problems when we finally &amp;amp; slowly switch over to a more eco-friendly method of electricity generation is that the power grid will have to substantially change from a few precise nodes in a system to many dispersed nodes in the system.  It is going to have to be decentralized.  Another thing that likely will have to change also is how power is stored and delivered.  Hopefully some solid state power cells can be developed.  The exciting thing is that if that were to happen then much of the world that is in the sunbelt will be able to develop power and charge solid-state devices.  If the transportation networks can support it then places that currently have little natural resources except for sun, wind or waves will be able to develop electricity for the north which has less sunlight but is able to pay for their energy in a way that the sunbelt is not.  However, this is unlikely to happen for a long time due to the lack of effective tech-transfer, despite such provisions being written into every major environmental treaty. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK off to my day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Desalination Update</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-04-29-desalination-update/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-04-29-desalination-update/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you’re like me, you’ve thought long and hard about desalination.  What is the problem?  Why is it taking so long for the Middle Easy countries (especially) to figure out the technology and apply the economies of scale such that desalination costs will fall for the rest of the world?  Well, &lt;a href="http://www.worldwatch.org/node/5720" title="Desalination Raises Environmental, Cost Concerns | Worldwatch Institute">Worldwatch Institute&lt;/a> provides an update.  The summary:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Energy costs, rather than environmental concerns, have been the main&lt;br>
deterrent to desalination plant expansion. Zander said the NRC panel&lt;br>
convened with expectations that technological improvements could lower&lt;br>
the cost of desalination, but they found that the technology is nearly&lt;br>
as efficient as possible at present. The most a plant can reduce its&lt;br>
energy consumption is 15 percent, the report predicts.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It’s all worth reading though.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Way to Go Branson</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-25-way-to-go-branson/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2008/2008-02-25-way-to-go-branson/</guid><description>&lt;p>[![142471][2]][2]&lt;br>
Link: [Biofuel jet makes aviation history][2].&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2008/02/25/142471.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2008/02/25/142471.jpg&lt;/a>
[2]: &lt;a href="http://www.edie.net/news/news_story.asp?id=14247">http://www.edie.net/news/news_story.asp?id=14247&lt;/a> &amp;ldquo;Biofuel jet makes aviation history&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For those that think alt_fuels are SO far off, think about how Branson initiated this program about a year ago…I am amused by the Greenpeace article.  I like it when far left people get their knickers in a twist because something isn’t the perfect solution.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On carbon offsets</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-16-on-carbon-offsets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-16-on-carbon-offsets/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.grist.org/advice/ask/2007/10/15/index.html?source=rss" title="On carbon offsets | By Umbra Fisk | Grist | Ask Umbra | 15 Oct 2007">On carbon offsets&lt;/a>.  This is a hot topic and one that is growing.  The simple solution is a carbon exchange that is modelled on a social justice model.  Basically a domestic, small-scale implementations of the Clean-Development Mechanisms embodied in the &lt;a href="http://unfccc.int/kyoto_protocol/items/2830.php">Kyoto Protocol&lt;/a>.  The theory is that the rich nations help the poor because of the intertwined nature of humanity.  The principle of technology transfer and that the rich pay is embodied in most international environmental treaties, but was interesting in the Kyoto schema in that offsets that assist the development of an emerging market or under-developed country may be applied to the quota for the developed country that pays.  It is a nice integration of standard liberalist philosophy.  I like it when there is overlap.  I am not sure what the economists may say about these mechanisms, but I certainly like them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Big-Head and I had an entire business model worked up for a 501(c)(3) that would do this where the benefits would be local and engaged by the community.  Unfortunately due to a variety of factors we’ve lost the momentum on this and we’re not going to be the ones that can do it.  However I hope that there are people with more time and expertise than me who are willing to implement such a community building schema. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Competition to give green lighting to Africa</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-06-competition-to-give-green-lighting-to-africa/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-10-06-competition-to-give-green-lighting-to-africa/</guid><description>&lt;p>Link: &lt;a href="http://www.edie.net/news/news_story.asp?id=13614" title="edie news centre - Competition to give green lighting to Africa">edie news centre – Competition to give green lighting to Africa&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The world bank is launching a competition to figure out how to light africa with  something other than little kerosene lamps.  They will choose 10 to 20 of the competition participants and give them something like $200k to pursue their plans further.  Not sure what will happen after that, but hopefully something.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The lamps were serene in their simplistic beauty.  You would turn a corner in Freetown and see the flicker of small kerosene lamps lighting up the rows of kiosks of people selling biscuits and fruit and cigarettes.  But the lamps also broke your heart because you knew that that was the only source of light besides the sun that these people had.  Meanwhile Westereners are going blind under the force of our neon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another heartbreaking antidote is that sometimes you would see kids outside right on the narrow streets doing their homework because the lights from the passing cars were the only way they could get something.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If the WB can figure out how to provide cheap lighting that is off the grid (or on a very local grid) that would be fantastic.  But the big if is who is going to finance this.  There are 250 M people here spread over much of a continent…the problems are so vast i sometimes get vertigo when i start to ponder them.  But one bite at a time, maybe the elephant will get eaten….maybe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gorillas head race to extinction</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-09-13-gorillas-head-race-to-extinction/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-09-13-gorillas-head-race-to-extinction/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/sci/tech/6990095.stm" title="BBC NEWS | Science/Nature | Gorillas head race to extinction">&lt;img src="http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/sci/tech/6990095.stm" alt="Gorilla_1" title="BBC NEWS | Science/Nature | Gorillas head race to extinction">&lt;/a>&lt;br>
More good environmental news from BBC.  The worst part is that the gorillas are getting killed in the great lakes area for their meat and for other things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/09/12/gorilla_1.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/09/12/gorilla_1.jpg&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Link: &lt;a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/sci/tech/6990095.stm" title="BBC NEWS | Science/Nature | Gorillas head race to extinction">BBC NEWS | Science/Nature | Gorillas head race to extinction&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Heading to Austin this weekend for &lt;a href="http://aclfestival.com/default.aspx">ACL&lt;/a>.  Quite stoked to see Bloc Party and Indigo Girls.  Don’t fuck with me I’m serious.  I once had a professor in undergrad who moved the final because Dave Matthews was playing, and when he announced this he said that if the Indigo Girls were playing he would have canceled the finals because he loved them so much that he would want to ensure that we went to see them.  Now that’s fan devotion.  Of course Dylan will be there.  I think he will be a gamble, either really good or really bad.  White Stripes and Byork should also be good.  Will hopefully listen to some COW Bell action with LCD Soundsystem, although I hope they play at night as they would not be good to see during the day.  Other highlights: Arcade Fire, Gotan Project, Clap Your Hands, Ghostland Observatory and it goes on and on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>photothermal cells beginning to show promise</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-18-photothermal-cells-beginning-to-show-promise/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>casey@caseykuhlman.com (Casey Kuhlman)</author><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/muniments/2007/2007-07-18-photothermal-cells-beginning-to-show-promise/</guid><description>&lt;p>[![17thermal600][2]][2]&lt;br>
[this][2] has promise.  i’ve heard about it before, but this article in the nytimes breaks it down nicely.  essentially, it uses the sun’s heat to formulate steam to turn generators to produce power rather than using photovoltaic cells which are inefficient and terribly expensive (although the prices are going down quickly and may go down further the more that they are made). photothermal cells produce heat by focussing the sun’s rays onto a specific metallic point. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>[]: &lt;a href="http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/07/18/17thermal600.jpg">http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/07/18/17thermal600.jpg&lt;/a>
[2]: &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2007/07/16/business/16thermal.html?ex=1342411200&amp;amp;en=c1081804c23cb425&amp;amp;ei=5124&amp;amp;partner=permalink&amp;amp;exprod=permalink">http://www.nytimes.com/2007/07/16/business/16thermal.html?ex=1342411200&amp;amp;en=c1081804c23cb425&amp;amp;ei=5124&amp;amp;partner=permalink&amp;amp;exprod=permalink&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>one thing that has always concerned me about solar that currently&lt;br>
concerns me is that there is a massive amount of heavy metals and heavy&lt;br>
chemicals to process the heavy metals that are required to produce&lt;br>
photovoltaic cells  i don’t know that much about the photothermal cells&lt;br>
but they appear to be mirrors more than anything.  if that is the case&lt;br>
then they may be a bit more enviro-friend to make rather than only&lt;br>
enviro-friend to use. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>now i lived in the desert for four years, i’ve felt the power of the sun on metal (most times accidentally, because i’m a klutz) and i know how hot it can get things  the question i have had about this technology since i first heard about it on a podcast about a year ago is whether it would be powerful enough to turn generators enough to have a decent capacity per land use acre.  it seems that it is, as this farm the NYT’s reports on has a higher capacity than even the largest photovoltaic farms.  this capacity is seemingly low…64 megawatts…when compared to an average coal-fired or natural-gas-fired plant which average over 500 megawatts. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>however this concern can be mitigated if the business plan of huge, centralized power plants transmitting power over massive geographical scapes (with the attendant loss of electricity over each mile of power line transmission, which if i remember correctly from my undergraduate coursework is something like 2% or so per mile), to something more localized.  there is a lot of work being done on this that i’ve read and if i can scrounge will post links to, but many scholars are researching whether it would be more efficient to put lots of small energy generating devices around a region rather than centralizing.  it may be more costly for the energy companies as they would have to service more locations, but it may not be as the smaller devices may break down at a slower rate and be less expensive to maintain, also they may be more reliable as redundancies could be placed into the system in more locations with more flexibility.  also there may be environmental benefits by spreading out whatever pollution is created.  nevertheless i’d put a photothermal farm on my roof.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>the most heartening statistic in the entire piece is that the photothermal cells are producing electricity at about 12 to 14 cents per kilowatt-hour where the national average is 10.5 cents per kilowatt-hour.  although that may be after subsidies (it wasn’t exactly clear), they are also subject to inefficiencies due to the nascent status of the technology.  so it seems likely that if the subsidies were tapered off the costs may remain the same or even decrease as it becomes cheaper to make the farms and as they understand the technology more and can tweak its efficiencies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ # ~&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>