<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>environment on underWater desert Blogging</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/environment/</link><description>Recent content in environment on underWater desert Blogging</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Casey Kuhlman</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseykuhlman.com/categories/environment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Nice Photo Essay</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-02-04-nice-photo-essay/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2010-02-04-nice-photo-essay/</guid><description>Water Vanishes on Western Farms
This photo essay captures the drying of California's Central Valley, where irrigation is a matter of life and death.</description></item><item><title>Eco-Labelling Biofuels</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-08-21-eco-labelling-biofuels/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-08-21-eco-labelling-biofuels/</guid><description>Geez, hippies love their eco-labeling. Perhaps it comports with their world-view of non-force-ment of normatively superior products. Perhaps it gives them something to talk about at parties, a consumer status-symbol. Whatever the case, now there is a labeling standard for biofuels. From Triple Pundit:
Manufacturers and other parties involved with biofuels have agreed on a global
green biofuel standard. The new
standard hopefully will eradicate the controversy and confusion that</description></item><item><title>Saddling up the Saharan Sun</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-07-23-saddling-up-the-saharan-sun/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-07-23-saddling-up-the-saharan-sun/</guid><description>[![Solar460x276][2]][2]
[This ][2]is good news, and something that I’ve been thinking about for a while. The Europeans want to build gigantic solar power stations in the Sahara and pipe the electricity up via high capacity transmission lines under the Med to the European grid system. []: http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.a/6a00d83453a81b69e200e553ceb2078834-pi [2]: http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/2008/jul/23/solarpower.windpower
Although I have to laud this idea, I have two problems/concerns with this. First, the centralization of the power grid is something that I have philosophical problems with.</description></item><item><title>Power Grid 2.0</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-06-28-power-grid-2-0/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-06-28-power-grid-2-0/</guid><description>Here is a good article about updating the power grid in the US. This is something I’ve been thinking about for a while. One of the problems when we finally &amp;amp; slowly switch over to a more eco-friendly method of electricity generation is that the power grid will have to substantially change from a few precise nodes in a system to many dispersed nodes in the system. It is going to have to be decentralized.</description></item><item><title>Desalination Update</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-04-29-desalination-update/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-04-29-desalination-update/</guid><description>If you’re like me, you’ve thought long and hard about desalination. What is the problem? Why is it taking so long for the Middle Easy countries (especially) to figure out the technology and apply the economies of scale such that desalination costs will fall for the rest of the world? Well, Worldwatch Institute provides an update. The summary:
Energy costs, rather than environmental concerns, have been the main
deterrent to desalination plant expansion.</description></item><item><title>Way to Go Branson</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-02-25-way-to-go-branson/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2008-02-25-way-to-go-branson/</guid><description>[![142471][2]][2]
Link: [Biofuel jet makes aviation history][2].
[]: http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2008/02/25/142471.jpg [2]: http://www.edie.net/news/news_story.asp?id=14247 &amp;ldquo;Biofuel jet makes aviation history&amp;rdquo;
For those that think alt_fuels are SO far off, think about how Branson initiated this program about a year ago…I am amused by the Greenpeace article. I like it when far left people get their knickers in a twist because something isn’t the perfect solution.
~ # ~</description></item><item><title>On carbon offsets</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-10-16-on-carbon-offsets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-10-16-on-carbon-offsets/</guid><description>On carbon offsets. This is a hot topic and one that is growing. The simple solution is a carbon exchange that is modelled on a social justice model. Basically a domestic, small-scale implementations of the Clean-Development Mechanisms embodied in the Kyoto Protocol. The theory is that the rich nations help the poor because of the intertwined nature of humanity. The principle of technology transfer and that the rich pay is embodied in most international environmental treaties, but was interesting in the Kyoto schema in that offsets that assist the development of an emerging market or under-developed country may be applied to the quota for the developed country that pays.</description></item><item><title>Competition to give green lighting to Africa</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-10-06-competition-to-give-green-lighting-to-africa/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-10-06-competition-to-give-green-lighting-to-africa/</guid><description>Link: edie news centre – Competition to give green lighting to Africa.
The world bank is launching a competition to figure out how to light africa with something other than little kerosene lamps. They will choose 10 to 20 of the competition participants and give them something like $200k to pursue their plans further. Not sure what will happen after that, but hopefully something.
The lamps were serene in their simplistic beauty.</description></item><item><title>Gorillas head race to extinction</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-09-13-gorillas-head-race-to-extinction/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-09-13-gorillas-head-race-to-extinction/</guid><description>More good environmental news from BBC. The worst part is that the gorillas are getting killed in the great lakes area for their meat and for other things.
[]: http://caseykuhlman.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/2007/09/12/gorilla_1.jpg
Link: BBC NEWS | Science/Nature | Gorillas head race to extinction.
Heading to Austin this weekend for ACL. Quite stoked to see Bloc Party and Indigo Girls. Don’t fuck with me I’m serious. I once had a professor in undergrad who moved the final because Dave Matthews was playing, and when he announced this he said that if the Indigo Girls were playing he would have canceled the finals because he loved them so much that he would want to ensure that we went to see them.</description></item><item><title>photothermal cells beginning to show promise</title><link>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-07-18-photothermal-cells-beginning-to-show-promise/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://caseykuhlman.com/posts/2007-07-18-photothermal-cells-beginning-to-show-promise/</guid><description>[![17thermal600][2]][2]
[this][2] has promise. i’ve heard about it before, but this article in the nytimes breaks it down nicely. essentially, it uses the sun’s heat to formulate steam to turn generators to produce power rather than using photovoltaic cells which are inefficient and terribly expensive (although the prices are going down quickly and may go down further the more that they are made). photothermal cells produce heat by focussing the sun’s rays onto a specific metallic point.</description></item></channel></rss>